Well home from the movies at last looks
like a daddy huh well Dada I was a
moving picture tonight mmm lovely mush
that's what it was just a lot of mice
there wasn't anybody kill the whole
thing no Alan I'll stick to these he's
gonna talk that big cluck Norman Maine
was in the picture tonight never does
anything but kiss a lot of girls Norman
Maine is one of the best actors in
pictures you and your movies that's all
you think about you shouldn't be allowed
to go to him at all if you're asking me
feel bad I was so busy in the kitchen I
didn't hear anybody asking you so granny
hello darlin
but of course no one ever listens to me
I do it there within 10 miles of yes
getting around picture shows house all
cut it up with movie magazines and the
other day I caught her talking to a
horse with a Swedish accent us is we're
only young once you know ah Hollywood
you'd better be getting yourself a good
husband and stop mooning about Hollywood
you know what she wants to do she wants
to go to Hollywood I've known it all
along I've seen her making faces in the
mirror and talking to herself that's
what comes of your movies why what would
you do if you did go to Hollywood I'd be
an actress I would I tell you I've
always known I could guys whatever you
wonderful to have a movie star in a
family oh it's like man maybe it or Ram
you may not know about it but you're
practically on your way to bed almond
fudge you're my favorite actors what you
- tell me the secret of your success oh
- let me alone I asked her what's come.
Over you
I'll tell you what's come over her she's
just a silly little girl whose head has
been turned by the movies and the sooner
she forgets the whole thing the better
off she'll be why will I be better off
what's wrong with wanting to get out and
make something of myself what do you do
that's so much better just because
you're satisfied to sit here all your
life you think you can laugh at me yeah
well someday you won't
that me I'm going out have a real life
I'm gonna be somebody now if it was
spring I say give her a good dose of
sulfur and molasses.
I thought I'd find you oh stop that nice
up crime that's gonna do you bit oh I'm
crying because that Malian Ali make me
so mad where they cannot magic first
they're not important
you're the only one that counts Esther
everyone in this world who has ever
dreamed about better things
that means laughter don't you know what
I do but but there's a difference
between dreaming and doing the dream has
just sit around and moon about how
wonderful it would be if only things
were different and the years roll on
when they grow old and buy and buy the
tickets everything even about baby
I would it be somebody oh yeah or you
want to be somebody but you want it to
be easy
oh you're Martin goes give me that when
I wanted something better I came across
those planes in a Prairie schooner with
your grandfather Oh everyone laughed at
us they did it all the other pioneers
they said this country would never be
anything but a wilderness we didn't
believe that we were going to make a new
country besides we wanted to see her
dreams.
Oh granny let's have been wonderful last
one but don't you think for one single
minute that it was easiest budget we
burned in summer and we froze in winter
but we kept right on going and we didn't
complain because we were doing like we
wanted to do can you understand that
yes I can
could you do it could you do it even if
it broke your heart
because remember Esther for every dream
of yours you may come true you'll pay
the price in heartbreak
know what I'm talking about you may not
believe it but I was a young girl once
very pretty young girl a lot prettier
than you are I was in love with your
grandfather
when some engine devil put a bird
through him
that is if it had come right straight
through my heart - and I remembered all
he taught me and I went right arm I
buried him out there on that illusions
with my own hands
I went right on that same day and I get
right on even when your mother was wrong
I would make it with wine
you know Esther they'll always be a will
to mr. Honker maybe Hollywood jewel
wilderness now from all ideas sounds
like it but if you've got one drop of my
blood in your veins you won't let Mattie
or any of her kind break your heart
you'll go right out there and break it
yourself that's your right
yeah oh here here stop that nonsense
yes thank this will go to your house
well I can't take your money or why not
it's your savings
well I was only saving up for my funeral
now I don't think I'm ever going to die.
Oh granny how can I ever thank you
by giving me your word of honor that you
will never tell a living soul where you
got that money I promise
remember if you do I'll have you
arrested for robbing me
Danny oh I can't let it did take blab
goodbye just a little chief he didn't
even wake up I bet you didn't try that
on your own magic whore went well
think of a face when you tell I'm
thinking about it I've waited for that
- chance for 30 years first years girl oh
- thank you.
Come on come on
here's your fairy school.
Oh.
Go on
my granny bye-bye I'll be waitin so you
know me midget no matter how mad you mad
as much as they used to be but my hands
are all right
want to go home now
I don't want to and I will
good afternoon day week or month but
it's a little hard to say you see I'm
going into the movie well you better
take it for a week it'll break your jump
to Beverly Hills our studio is really
near here
all except goemon British I suppose the
best way to get a job is to go straight
to the studios isn't it I am many
illusions you know I'm perfectly willing
to begin with a little bit of a part or
even as an extra six dollars please.
Edith in advance.
I beg your pardon
I'd like to register for extra work how
long have you been in Holiday well it's
about a month now we haven't put anyone
on our books for over two years come
here.
I'd like to show you something
every time you see when those lights
flash somebody asking for a job every
time you hear them say try later it
means there isn't any job now keep the
ghost the switchboard long they go crazy
and one of those little lights thought
- it was going to be a star still want to
- go on the movies.
You know what your chances are one in a
hundred thousand
but maybe I'm that one
any phone calls to me mr. Randall or no
Jesse Lasky and Sammy Goldman must be
writing letters instead how's the
luckily there wasn't any maybe you don't
go out in the right way
nothing Kenny McGwire here he knows the
ropes don't you Danny
sure I've had him around my neck for
years what oh I miss Blodgett Danny.
McGuire aye lieutenant how do you do mr.
McGuire is a big director oh are you
really Oh could you possibly use me in a
picture mr. McGuire because I haven't
had much experience but I don't think
that really matters if you're willing
and I'll listen already in the first
place I'm not a director I'm an
assistant director in the second place
- if I had any jobs to give away I confer
- one on myself and in the third place you.
Should have stayed back home in the
first place
hey wait a minute hey don't be that way
don't do that
gosh I didn't mean to get tough but my
guy thinks he's being kidded when
somebody asked him for a job he hasn't
got one for himself after all I'm not a
big enough shot to hurt your feelings
I'm sorry it wasn't just battle with a
lot of things I'm looking for a job
every day and never getting any nearer
to it I guess I was beginning to get a
little scared
I know lady do I know well there's only
one thing to do for that feeling when
you're tired and sunk and down to your
last nickel come on and I'll buy you a
drink what's not a bed is down to the
last nickel I still got $11 less $11
you're going
buy me a drink come on that's right.
George there's nothing like a little rum
to take away that milk flavor.
I beg your pardon
when I find my contact the first thing
I'm going to do is redirect every
picture on Ian
that's my pal Chris I'm gonna be
perfectly nice about it but I'll just
insist now that's the way to talk
don't let him lick your heart she said
he can't lick me say try anything like
that what
like the cool side now that's right what
have you got to lose another one of
these and we'll open our own studio bill
rendered $24 pass to remit pull up
further delayed me
yeah
lucky
now a fifth race race
hey the programs going to be swell the
night now you take this fella Beethoven
I'm a pushover for him and Chopin well
he's not so dusty either but I kind of
wish that once in awhile that play
something you could sort of go out
whistling you know like but on the
settle let oh well there's a tomb hey
why don't you throw your hat in the air
or something can't you this is a
celebration my job starts tomorrow
I knew it does and I think it's swell in
gee I wish you were in on it too but
I'll know it wouldn't have to be a war
picture when those big novelty numbers a
war picture without any beautiful women
at the fun
oh well something will happen soon maybe
why don't you go home kid Oh
Danny I can't do that I came here and
I've got to stay well now if it's on
account of money I can't thank you
giving me enough already
anyhow this is no time to be worrying
this is our party look at all the people
everybody in the world
it's not a name
he seems to have had that one extra
cocktail
oh thank you
sit down you do't that's the orchestra
leader
mr. main mr. Main put your arm around
miss Regis our offices in the Hollywood.
Bowl more afraid of crowds going door
again what's the matter you're getting
too big to bother with photographers
don't want any pictures taken oh oh is
that so what's a person I take it anyway
well show that brawny number to you is
down your throat thanks
no me come back and sit down everybody's
laughing nama is he always like that
so I suppose he has to sleep sometime oh
it was so wonderful on the screen
champion
leaving that I got a job for you
daddy that's wonderful when do I go to
the studio well you don't exactly go to
the studio location makeup would you
tell me what you get inside help me put
it on you don't exactly need any makeup
you see it's not really affect your job
it's it's well it's being a waitress
oh well it's kind of a picture job if
you look at it right you said it was a
waitress
well that's waitressing for Casey Burke
the big director over in our studio he's
given a party tonight to kind of
celebrate on a kind of finish in the
picture and and he wanted me to get him
an extra waitress and it's five dollars
and I thought of you right away history
teach me well well there's gonna be a
lot of big people at Burt's house that
might not let you there's any number of
big directors and if you're there maybe
they'll notice you I could make a noise
sure you could Esther it's your chance
all right daddy I'll do it oh oh but I
can't I haven't got the right things to
weigh now you don't think the Wardrobe
departments right next to my office for
nothing do you ha ha perfect fit
did you get to the preview last night I
did would you like a lethal order they
are very nice oh thanks what did you
think of the picture you should have
saved it for Thanksgiving
what a turkey will you have two more day
if you do like our dev don't you I think
there's anything so enjoyable as our
dead before supper and these are really
delightful
and at the finish the kid turns around
and sings a lullaby to its mother a
problem that big boys but would you like
a little a harder they say to the best
in town don't tell me I know Mae West
that's a great twist the way you're
gonna find a two months old baby they
can sing hello Oliver Oh dizzy you want
to fire me now wait to see the picture
I'm not a director anymore I'm a male
nurse what's the matter with a picture
guy by the name of Norman Maine his work
is beginning to interfere with his
drinking Bolivar don't tell me I'm too
direct his next picture - mm-hmm you
where my favorite producer now wait a
minute you just go right on with your
directing I'll take care of these stars
I know how to handle them I had to sue
you stop it Norman after that Hollywood
ball occurrence and you don't have to
worry anymore about his behavior you'd
be mr. Niles mr. Libi of your publicity
department is on the telephone he says
most important sir
start mister me thank you oh it's
probably just some little thing mm-hmm
of course Oliver I'll turn on the radio
and see if it's called out the National.
Guard yet hello Lindy what's the good
word
mr. Norman main America's Prince.
Charming was apprehended driving an
ambulance down Wilshire Boulevard with a
siren going full blast he explained he
was a tree surgeon on a maternity case
well duh but will it be in the papers no
it won't be in the papers but that's a
nice expensive hobby of yours keeping
mr. Mane's informal entertainments out
of the public press oh that's fine work
Libby try and see that no one gets to
Norman he's probably home sleeping at
all all of heaven why can't you forget
those dopes at the studio for one night
business business all the time I don't
know what's gonna become of you know why
didn't you call for me
I'll bye darling why didn't I call for
you in case you forgotten I was supposed
to come here with you Oh dad oh that's
all right I got here without any trouble
the only reason I don't slap your face
yes darling I I know
hello John oh hello man what's the
matter with Oliver he looks if he'd had
bad news oh all right what's the matter
oh boy maybe I'm wrong I guess I've been
drinking too much lately already also
caught it Don it's bad stuff scotch and
soda the word you know it's pronounced.
Quinn bad dialogue Oliver rather not
watch this you know best
sorta thank you oh go ahead and say it I
got it coming through don't make it
tougher on me Norman I don't want to
stand here and preach but take a look at
my side of it I'm trying to make
pictures with you I know I know
costs are going up the grosses are going
down no it isn't that
I've made lots of money with you and I
can afford to take a loss but I hate to
see you going the way of so many others
why don't you get Lloyds to insure you
against them you can't get insurance
against a man forgetting who he is
you're a great star nomen but there's
nobody so big they can afford to have
people refused to work with him who
doesn't want to work with me yours quiet
listen I know plenty of people who do
yes and so do I but your real friends
can't stand seeing you start to fall
apart
what do you mean brother the first signs
are always the same not being able to
remember your lines
cameraman struggling to cover your
hangovers and all because you have to
have a good time every day and every
night
listen I've warned you for a long while
you're a swell guy you won't lose any
money on me I'll promise you that I'll
be ready for the curtains when the time
comes
when it does here's my epithet and all I
think kind of Lum have a little drink
scotch and soda
come on come on come on little soda
nothing yes our partner Oh lovely lovely
nor now being a caviar no don't don't go
away huh
I'm starving huh really which which
would you take
I don't know you know all right I don't
know either
it's hard to choose I think I'll take
caviar mr. main doesn't care for any
more do you know me no one army doesn't
care for anymore
think I shall get very drunk indeed
scotch and soap sorry I absolutely.
Oh mind if I help more they miss you
oh no no just look under the table when
they see I'm not there they'll forget
the whole matter
hey what no what's your name
Esther Blodgett my name is mein I know
you doing what what's so funny I was
just thinking about all your fans and
how surprised they be to see you here
helping me put plates away always they
don't know my finest side you'd be
pretty envious of me reading you this
way in person oh thank you do tell me
are are you disappointed whoa Marv you
both oh never mind that that makes the
room look lived in tell me uh boy why
are you disappointed I was sitting
behind you at the Hollywood Bowl the
night you didn't want to be photographed
I'm so like crept into many our heart
that night I could never explain this
you know you have very pretty hair you
- better get out of here that's sensitive
- mom and a charming little thing hey why.
Are you here
said it with the rest of the gifts I'm
just trying to be helpful
I see I'm sure there's no other
attraction well it might be that my old
mania for putting plates away is coming
back on me it's rather odd I always know
where I can find you there's a pretty
girl around not only are it's
embarrassing now being deliberately
insulting Norman I put up now don't lose
your temper
remember we must try to keep the voice
low I know you'll excuse us if we go on
with our work
now see what you've done
come in help me up no more than usual
come on the wolves are honest we gotta
get out this is our finished oh yes a
oh I bet I know what you're gonna say
now what good night good night and
thanks hey wait a minute
wait a minute here you realize it all I
found out about you is that you foolish
enough to want to go into pictures why
the truelist look at you yeah that's
what I mean
no I'm done I'd rather like to go into
this matter a little more thoroughly
well that's awfully nice of you why uh
why don't we go on up to my place and
talk it off.
Oh No thank you very much but I really
must say good night good night
but you're not angry no I'm hungry I
have to go and get something to eat
good night miss Blodgett
good night mr. Name
wait a minute least I can do is to see
in your door I see you again has anyone
ever told you that you're ugly
on Ino
but sir it's hard to say but I want to
say it anyway
you know Armour on the screen I'm a you
know and private life
if you know but whatever I do and I
still respect lovely friends
you're lovely
you understand
thank you and it doesn't that bump on
the head that's doing this I'm glad
good night good night.
Hey
mind if I take just one more look go
away quite impossible I wouldn't even
consider it no no no
hello who is it.
Oh eleven what have you done now
you're not in jail are you oh yes I see
oh it's that again I see she's beautiful
yeah I know you want me to give her a
screen test yeah certainly
she's got wonderful possibilities oh you
know she's got something well you knew
all the other ones had something - oh no
I tell you Oliver she's got that
sincerity and an honest miss and a sense
of sincerity and honest mistakes great
actresses you Oliver I am so sure of
this girl that I want to take the test
with her myself
hmm listen Oliver you were taught you're
entitled to a break okay yes I heard you
anything anything yes yes all of it look
you you try to get a little steep now oh
man you alright alright boy
good good.
Hey
yeah huh phone for me some drug trying
to be funny says who's Norman Boone oh
and this budget would you give them the
message for me tell em it's three
o'clock in the morning
hello oh oh oh yes yes I'll be there oh
thank you hey daddy what do you think
I'm gonna take a test tomorrow
northern means helping me do it hmm I'm
taking one - garbles assisting me
move that going for the silken Akbar.
Norrell the inky this right - Ali okay
pulled out all that 150
get down on that 150
let me an Apple box listen gentlemen
please if you don't mind this is this is
just a test
ready mister already partner ready mr.
Bert running already ready now it's work
all right we're ready mr. Bert all right
let's take it ready Norman yeah you
ready miss uh what's your name
you'll soon know your name Esther the
whole world's going to know it but I'm
so scared you got there not tried to be
oh come on I don't be foolish they
already go through this Harlow Lombard.
Myrna Loy and now Esther Blodgett all
right I'm ready
this is a take rollin quiet Hey.
I may as well tell you that my whole
organization thinks I've gone a little
nuts to sign you maybe they're right
I've been nuts before you see all the
experts seem to think that your type is
a little mild for present-day taste but
I rather believe it tastes change like
eyebrows and I think that also like
eyebrows tastes are going back to the
natural you look like a nice girl I
think I'm going to like you
that's not important I think the public
will like you that is important yes I
see what you mean I I mean I I know it
is all II don't think it's going to be
easy nothing you really want is ever
given away free you have to pay for it
and usually with your heart someone else
told me that one but you still have to
work it out for yourself.
Olo this is just a long way of saying
I'm glad you're with us and good luck to
- you and now I'm going to turn you over
- to our demon press agent Libby don't let.
Him frighten you he has a heart of gold
only harder and for the love of Pete
learn to close your mouth and keep it
closed even in your love scenes
are you a Russian no I was born film one.
North Dakota on tray saw a light of day
in a mountain cabin a trappers Hut high
up in the Rockies go on what I always
wanted to be an actress dreamed of
footlights has lonely kidding are you
sure there's no Russian in your family
positive that's a shame
well what does your father do he's a
farmer
yeah Social Register I'd father fed up
with hypocrisy of 400 short wilderness
for consolation there amidst the
mountain flowers he raised another
blossom his lovely little daughter
what's your name after Victoria Blodgett
greatly appreciating your attention to
this matter very truly do you know what
her name is Esther Victoria Blodgett he
will have to do something about that
right away
Esther Victoria magic well that blood
it's definitely out let's see
Esther Victoria Victoria Vicki how about
Vicki oh I think that's terribly cute
let's see Vicki Vicki what Vicki Vicki
pronounced Vicki Vicki see Esther
bestest Esther desta Fester
oh that's very pretty just two has two
just a Lester Vicki Lester oh I like
that
say Vicki Lester say it again Vicki
Lester say it again Vicki Lester say it.
Peggy laughter Thank You Lester Vicki
Lester Vicki Lester Vicki Lester Vicki
Lester
fetch our benaiah studio discovers New.
Starlet a Cinderella of the Rockies her
name is Vicki Lester those who have
peaked tell me she couldn't be more the
moon the face of an angel and such
natural talents her voice is a symphony
how very walk they tell me is enough to
drive men mad not that way get the lid
out of your feet let them up that's
better
it's terrible but it's better the
quality of mercy is not strain'd it
droppeth as the gentle rain from heaven
sees through the mouths my child through
- the mouth the nose is for smelling roses
- proceed.
Does she have to look surprised all the
time
anyway it's just a rough sketch pretty
small mouth today well you wear that
Crawford Smith
yes who give her that deep
we're on the wrong track she still looks
surprised
listen drunk people we're shooting on
the surface morning not in the
commissary come on stop me noise like me
to Latin company mr. Smith he's not in.
Hackney tracking companies know the mr.
Smith is not it
good morning what can I bring you may
have just shown how long you've been
here.
Mabel bless you how soon are you and I
are gonna be married huh I don't know
you'll have to ask my mother Acme
trucking company I know a mrs. Smythe is
not in the trucking company and no mr.
Smith is not in at me no sniffing in.
Acme tracking company likes me too mr.
Smith mr. Smith is not no man
what's all this between you and Smith
apart it's only one line and it's in the
picture
it's ambition that made you break that
date with me last night I had a PA so.
Ellie this morning so did I
I had to stay up all night to make it
you've got it your picture haven't you
no I was still in my testing stage can't
seem to get the right girl for the lead
hmm you think that all the girls they're
at it yeah I know what this one's got to
be different she's got to be little cute
and sweet intelligent I'll blow me down
what or close my tired old eyes Oh hold
everything come on come on had you been
through a whole casting directory now
weird a night miss nah I'll work with
her Oliver I can be mean or nasty or
anything you want mr. Niall if she
clicks Oliver you've got a star
overnight okay
when you hear them at the end of the
picture.
Kiki groovey noticed by no one they're
much too busy playing at croquet
I've loved you all my life
but we only met two days ago that's when
my life began
hey t cute you know I think she's the
same type I am don't you I think
sweet well it's pretty lastest picture
all right I think she was much better
than he would teach produces a so
horribly down they won't know how good
she is well maybe it's because she's a
good girl
no means that's so bad but it's Vicki
Lester then we go to see Sally taken to
the most precious little thing I've ever
seen hmm
knockout Libby you might mention that
when you write your review that Lester
kids a gold mine didn't you like Norman
Maine was he in it
let me I'm afraid we have another hip
it's in the bag
neatly tied up with beautiful pink
ribbon say where Norman Vicki I don't
know I thought you had them wish they'd
come we're having a party the Trocadero
even it's really running away from
people
no man it's so exciting so new a star is
born come on
wonderful isn't it crazy quilt
it's a carpet that spread for you
all yours from now on comment you're a
success
everything in the world you want
I hope it'll make you happy I've met you
then there was one thing I never had
lots of times I told myself I'd found it
but I always knew I was mine
so I I never stopped looking for it
maybe it'll come
well I think it has come master I only
wish it went too late
but it's not to me so you can't throw
away your life the way I've thrown away
mine have anything left that's good
enough your team
nah man you can
I mustn't tell me that has to
I'm so afraid that I'll believe it
gotcha put your right swell in this
happening what's got together don't you
hear me gotcha.
Oh big move and hit me up though
that reminds me will you marry me thank
you
come on gotcha finishing why what's the
matter
hey short you're late growling your mini
break him up in there break up a pink
Selma cause I quit drinking come on
kasha shoot the lion head all right was
I saved my money
absolutely dependable and all occasion.
Hey
here's a beautiful bike.
Domon what therefore after me I said I'd
marry you well certainly not
I was just supposing we're going to be
married
guess I didn't read that line right I'll
try it again we are going to be married
most of us get to each other what do you
think of that well when we're well we
thought we'd elope in the conventional
manner what's the matter it's trying to
decide whether it's good for the studio
indeed it is and bless you my children
what's it going to happen oh wait are we
just sneaked out sometime we're not
telling anyone but you
listen to this the screens ideal romance
blossomed into breathtaking reality
today when Vicki Lester a Norman Maine.
America's dream lovers slipped quietly
through the portals of holy matrimony
how does it sound horrible but you see
we are going to elope sure yeah
it'll be the biggest elopement this town
ever saw we'll get a tie-up with the
army have you escorted all the way down
to Yuma by 20 of their new bombing
planes keep going with it don't you
think we didn't work this thing out
better alone
no sense in bothering the happy couple
with all the details I'll see to it that
you get a carbon copy of the whole
layout I can hardly wait I'm sorry we
didn't realize that we were in the way
when you're set in the details you don't
mind if I take this woman out buyer
arrange sure go ahead we want everything
legal that's a charming match a nice
scare like vicki and public nuisance
number one now wait a minute Livie.
Norman's alright and if your pardon my
pointing Vicky's businesses are wrong it
- doesn't require any comments I wasn't
- making any comments I just said it was a.
Rotten shame to go ahead and climb the
elopement
oh that elopement stuff is out you can't
get me scoped in that we're gonna have a
wedding will we have it customary place
I believe is a church man it's been done
this has got to be something big the
beach I can visualize him the
bridesmaids in bathing suits 20,000
Santa Monica school children spelling
out the word love
it's a novelty but is it big enough when
at the city hall a police escort of
every motorcycle cop in town sirens
screaming confetti pouring out of
buildings like the Lindbergh reception
in New York only on a big scale and.
Samara isn't it big enough and now if
any man can show just cause why these
two may not be lawfully joined together
let him now speak or else hereafter
forever hold his peace
do you Alfred ankle take this woman as
your lawful wedded wife will you love
comfort honor and keep her in sickness
and health as long as you both shall
live
or will you I beg your pardon do you
establish it take this man as your
lawful wedded husband will you obey
serve love honor and keep him in
sickness and health as long as you both
shall live
I will place the ring on a finger huh a
hurry please now by virtue of the power
invested in me as just as the Peace of.
San bardo Township County of Los Angeles
I pronounce you man and wife
and now I must exercise my prerogative
of office I hope you will be very happy
mrs. Ankle thank you thank you sir thank
you very much
now if you'll please sign the license oh
yeah you know well mrs. Vito I can't
help but believe I've seen you somewhere
before
oh really well I believe this is the
first time I've ever been in a sandbar
oh you know your face is familiar -
thank you very much you're a joke you
hear thank you
goodbye now no I don't owe me nothing oh
yeah I think you got by with it but it
was close that JP was just beginning to
remember where he see this well anyway
we got away from Libby good if you will
be kind enough to glance between my
shoulder blades
mr. And mrs. Henkel you will find there
a knife buried to the hilt on the handle
are your initials Molly duccini Allah
beat Danny
there go a couple of rats I raised four
mice well they got a right to get
married haven't they haven't got any
right to double-cross the public and I
haven't done it yet fine people versus
porky Washington with charged with
violating section 609 yarn can give the
cart operator get me the Los Angeles.
Tribune have a good mind to put you
under arrest when I make the score you
wait to Tribune give me the city desk.
Johnny this is Matt Libby I got a flash
for you Norman Maine and Vicki Lester
were married at 2:30 this afternoon.
Vicki Lester for recess
it.
Gimme hearts and weights big heart and
great big buckaroo and let me walk.
Wow
wha-hoo and wahoo
I don't want to sound immodest but I
think I've stripped the gear well I'll
sit down won't you and let's get
acquainted we'll probably be seeing
quite a bit of each other from now on
might just as well break the ice now is
later hmm
now we're old then see him I might have
time for a shower before dinner ready if
you can find the shower I never can
remember where that thing is does it
pull out or slide on this yeah I think I
can find it nope the linen closet here
it is nice work.
Oh half the time those things are just
luck and I'll see if I can disinfect it
mistake.
ESCA there's no soap yeah thank you
I'll need a wash partly how you fixed to
cigarettes you know I never smoked
underwater hey what what do I do to make
this thing look pull that gadget at the
top and pray for rain all right
I can't reach it I can I can't get my
hands up there you've gone there with
your arm down you'll never get your band
unless you're a contortionist yeah well
I I'm not a contortionist and don't
throw that up to me now
you knew it when you married me you
close this door please thank you no I'm
in here click the car you're gonna huh
here quick quick what click go out and
stop them and ask for help
boy y'all catch cold oh you'll get warm
again yeah dogs do they recognize me I'm
- keep your face down go on that may not
- be another car for a week.
Howdy partner howdy stuck yeah how'd you
guess it can you get us some help well I
reckon not you know it's a long way too
tall we're pretty busy doctor please
well I gotta get out of here I've got my
wife with me and she liked the country
no no and then we're short of food
there's a lot of game in him woods you
know well my life can't shoot well
you're sure up against it sorry I can't
do anything for you wait listen I'll be
frank with you I'm Norman named who.
Norman Maine my name is Jeff Baker
gladinet shit well so long
so your normal name.
I got my prestige to look out for I'm
supposed to be the best publicity man in
the racket and they left themselves sick
when I even try to get a decent mention
of Maine yes I know how sensitive you
are Libby and I don't like to see your
feelings hurt thanks boys now Vicky
there's a dish for free space but if
Maine swam across the Pacific the papers
would keep it a secret
well the exhibitors don't like him the
critics don't like him the public don't
like him and I don't like it
who likes him
oh but darling this is almost too much
of a surprise and there I was my
touching innocent we knew we were going
to live at the beach house.
Oh we'll still keep the place at Malibu
but this is special this is our castle
it used to be in the air well we never
- use any ugly words like contracts and
- pictures and careers when we come in.
Those gates
we'll check the studio outside come on I
got another little surprise for you.
Oh nah man it's lovely
so are you lovely the whole world lovely
hey hold it
that's it caption their honeymoon never
ends
alright let's get some pictures now if
the bride will sit here and the groom's
stand behind her we'll have something
unique now let's go after something
different you sit down and she'll stand
up pretty radical isn't it yeah but in a
nice way
huh okay I don't fire caption their
honeymoon begins in you ah the producer
caption their honeymoon ceases abruptly
hello Oliver let's see oh I'm glad
you're back Thank You Vicki how well
you're looking hello Oliver
am I interrupting yes thank you just
want a couple more pictures that's
enough of both of them what they're
asking for is exclusives are miss Lester
how long oh I see well come on Oliver
let you and me get exclusive see you
later Vicki oh don't worry Otto my
camera smashing days are over
I ain't your only patient over oh hold
that miss Lester gorgeous bother how's
the dividend situation very pleasant I
think we'll show two million our next
quarter Oh smart move of mine to sell my
stock okay well when you need money you
need it
but some people save up for just such an
event it is bound to be a rainy day
occasionally here but as a citizen of
California
I've always refused to admit that yes I
know but still it does rain well anyway
you can thank me for some of those
dividends of yours yeah look at you well
sure sure there's a little too quick.
Oliver matter than chana dal was the
smash hit wasn't a lift it made Vicki a
star overnight nice it sure they're
about me well let's talk about business
at the office Norman beautiful pool you
have here utano let's talk about it here
and they like me well maybe the pot
wasn't just right what was the best part
of the year
look Oliver do you think I'm slipping
can you take it and go ahead the tents
is wrong you're not slipping you've
slipped my fan mail is too big Norman.
Norman fans will write to anybody for a
photograph it only costs 3 cents for a
stamp and that makes photographs cheaper
than wallpaper but every 25 cents they
pay for a theater ticket buys them the
right to be a critic and your last few
performances Norman have not pleased
your critics you remember I told you I
dare you ready for the curtains on the
time cam there it is
let's call off the contract no hard
feelings we're not quitting either of us
there's no explaining these things we've
all seen how the public turns maybe we
can turn them back I've got a swell
script lined up for you what about
Esther if you think that I'm going to
get in her way
well as a matter of fact as it happens
there's no part in this story for her
I'd more or less plan to star her in a
picture of her own with with that young
pemberton opposite her he's coming along
nicely good for young Pemberton all
right Oliver would make a triadic let's
hope it's not too late
no argument
I'll buy those screens most finished out
yet our say he's finished
keeps him away and row
hello No.
Oh miss Lester isn't home as yet no I'm
not the butler well I can take a message
just as well as he can honest oh is that
you Norman
swell listen Norman this is auntie.
Carver hiya kid
swell say I hear you're through with
Oliver Niles
he's head on the level oh please Artie
I'm not news anymore forget it say what
kind of a settlement did you make on
your contract give me a figure so I can
do a story on it there's no money
involved we just called it quits
okay okay I'll fill in my own figure say
by the way I've been trying to get an
interview with Vicki for two weeks but
she's always busy how about you giving
an old pal a break by speaking to her
for me
sure I'll Oscar swell song.
I didn't mean to be late outing but.
Katie yeah now what's new today nothing
and then out of the house let's go
somewhere tonight no you're tired we'll
stay in really oh yes you are
you've got a hard day ahead of it anyway
I see so little of you I'd like to have
you to myself oh but it's a servants
night out we have knitters we have I
fixed a little snack with my own
lily-white hands I learning to cook in
my spare time did I think I'll marry
you want to make an honest cook of me
comes in on wheels in this joint
huh how's it look wonderful huh
that's what I thought Alan don't be
formal just bitchin
huh
I'm afraid my mouth not quite big enough
I'll measure it next time we'll make
them decide a little hard to knit to
their technique I'll take those
measurements right now
that's what I wait for all day that's
why I rush home without even changing my
god
forgetting that we're hungry like a
sandwich
thank you I still have a little work on
this one
yeah where you want to hook my dress I
can't breathe you know all the time I
thought it was the kiss that made you
breakfast a lot of hooks why should I
have a zipper that's a good idea
you got it yeah
don't look down what
I think that guy on your left is in love
with you I'll tell
you
mr. Doorbell is this maybe they'll go
away
oh I never do at a time like this you
custom in India I'll be right back
miss Vicki Lester live here yes I got a
package for now sign for it so who are
you I'm her husband
oh sure hi right here mr. Lester
package filled and by the way I forgot
to tell you what
they want you for a benefit to Shrine.
Auditorium next Wednesday night I told
him I'd ask you and darling how do we
about now
well you better wait left finished work
to get the more the Academy dinner
secretary phone she wants to know if you
want a table reserved for you oh yes
Artie Carver called and asked if I'd use
my influence with you to get him an
interview I told him I'd try
that was all I think Norman don't talk
about those things now
we're forgetting the wonderful food you
put in I'm I'm not very hungry now
I think Karla I'll fix me a little drink.
I was known you can stop were you and
think how nice that statue is going to
look on your mantelpiece
do you suppose anything happened to him
but of course Tov you've just been held
up in traffic you think about that
statuette and now we arrived at the
climax of the annual dinner of the.
Academy of Motion Picture Arts and.
Sciences the highest award within our
power to bestow we have already
applauded with our hearts as well as our
hands while awards have been given those
gentlemen who during the past year have
rendered distinguished service to the
motion picture industry we now pay honor
to the ladies or rather to one lady we
offer to her the academy award for the
finest performance of the past year she
has already had the world's acclaim but
this is the tribute of our fellow
workers the men and women of this
industry it is not only my pleasure but
my privilege to present this award to
the actress who created the
unforgettable Anna in dream without end.
Miss Vicky Lester
what more can we say miss Lester this
says it all for us
ladies and gentlemen when something like
this happens to you and you try to tell
how you feel about it you find that out
of all the words in the world there are
only two that really mean anything
thank you all I can do is to say them to
you for my heart all I can do is to keep
on saying them a very pretty speech my
dear my very pretty
you said the right thing I want to be
the very first one to congratulate you
but I'm not valuable little piece of
brick right now I want to make a speech
gentlemen of the Academy and fellow
suckers I got one of those once for a
best performance they don't mean a thing
people get them every year what I wants
a special award something nobody else
can get I want to statue for the worst
performance of the year in fact I want
three statues for the three worst
performances of the year because I
earned them and every single one of you
that saw those last masterpieces of my
nose that I've earned Libby start to
music what I'm here to find out is do I
get them or do I get up now answer yes
or no
let's go and sit down.
Oh.
Hello hi oh hi.
My dear do we let me congratulate you
must be terribly proud and happy nice
thank you
somebody give me a drink
neither you to come to my desk a new
video oil
I've missed you everyone have a nice
trip well the three months to the
theater circuit scarcely comes under the
head of pleasure but the way they're
screaming for your pictures all over the
country is Leicester if I may talk sharp
you are a nut up thank you
good to hear that we've been crying a
little
how's Norman
well he's trying awfully hard often
letting Norman leave this studio was the
hardest thing I ever did
there was nothing else I could do as you
been
is he alright he's gone to a sanitarium
he really wants to stop drinking and I
think he could only well perhaps if he
could start working again it would be
some encouragement I love a pitcher
could you do that oh thank you but he
might not ever know I told you he won't
know and you mustn't worry I want you to
keep up your good work in this picture
good I love it it's the one thing I can
do for me
if you adjust it here mr. Niles mr. main
brought down thank you brought down
hello Oliver welcome to Liberty wall
hello Norman
oh no no mr. Niles isn't slipping me a
case of scotch cuddle this is just a
handshake
this is cuddles Oliver my social
secretary we go everybody
yeah how are you feeling Norman fine
getting along remarkably well cuddles
tells me he says you ought to see some
of the boys that's it are ya cuddles Lee
we really don't need you touching in cat
bear to have me out of his sight are you
comfortable here Norman comfortable it's
positively luxurious
they even have iron bars in the windows
to keep off the draught ha ha how much
longer are you going to be oh well I'm
really cured now I'm just staying on for
an extra week or two to get in good
shape yeah
after all it no no particular hurry to
return to the camera that's what I
wanted to talk to you about I've got a
script with a fine part for you in it he
however that's great that's great who
who plays opposite me well it is not
exactly the lead young Pemberton's doing
that but I tell you frankly I consider
you apart better than the lead oh I see
it's better than the lead but of course
it isn't terribly long but it's one of
those parts that makes an impression on
you they'll be thinking about you all
through the picture mm-hmm well the
thing is all of our Anmer pretty well
set at another studio and I'm not at
liberty at the moment to tell you which
one you know yourself are those things
of course but it's a big picture he's
one of the biggest of the year and the
pot every act in Hollywood give his
teeth to play huisman okay but let's
find Norman naturally that would tie you
up for a while but we won't get to this
picture for some time and perhaps if you
want to consider it for later on I will
then tell you all away you'd better not
contact me see I've got several pictures
lined up after this when then they're
talking to me about England you know
that they're doing some very interesting
things over there hey what is it Tuttle
speak right out we all love you your
dinner oh here we dine at 5:30 here
makes the nights longer this is kooky
well good-bye Norman I'm glad to see you
getting along so well be off in no time
I'll have to introduce myself all over
to a lot of people leave well know me
when I'm not drinking her goodbye bye.
Nona thanks for dropping in oil cuddles
alone at last.
Oh work Sam how am I am oh hello hello.
Lonnie
let's see you how I hate to run into
these has bins they give me the creeps
me too he was good while he had it and
he had it quite a while now all hello
mister ma'am I haven't seen you in a
long time I've been resting ginger ale
please
ginger ale and twat ginger ale and
ginger ale a new leaf a whole new book
thank you it's not straight hello lovey
why it's mr. America of yesteryear do
they let you wonder about now without a
keeper
oh I I'm I'm a trustee now and expect to
find you at Santa Anita what do they do
with the actors well while you're away
how they cut them into slices and fry
them with eggs I suppose you'll be here
all the time now that you've retired
from the Hailie barely of the silver
screen well living down a Malibu now
pretty lonesome with Esther away working
all day
well I wouldn't squawk about that if I
were you
it's nice to have somebody in the family
making a living Oh
and want to forget to work friend
friends my I say listen I got you out of
jams because I had to it was my job not
because I was your friend I don't like
you and I never have liked you
nothing made me happier than to see all
those cute little pranks of yours
finally catch up with you and land you
and your celebrated tastes but he worked
really always wait to let down then kick
him I don't feel sorry for you you fixed
yourself nice and comfortable you can
live off your wife now
she'll buy your drinks and put up with
you even though nobody else will outside
for you lifetime Norman man that's not
my fault I don't bother to charge the
mouth he's harmless
forever stupid if you say so sure let
him go what can either we can't fight
any better than we can act
give me a scotch double leave the bottle
here.
Vickey you'll be ill why don't you try
to get a little sleep but he's been gone
for days for days not a word although I
can't hello
no there's Oliver Niles speaking what
where thank you
what is this not nothing Oliver tell me
he's in the night Court he's been
arrested on a drunk charge and he's all
right he isn't hurt I'm right I'll get
him I'm going with you Vicki it isn't
any place for you and if it gets in the
papers every I care about the papers I'm
going with you business 30 minutes
before county Los Angeles now in session
the under majority a parish presiding be
seated please
are you able to do anything judge
wouldn't even see me
ready or not I want to advise you that
you're entitled to be represented by
counsel to be confronted by the
witnesses that might testify against you
to compel witnesses to attend on your
behalf to a public and speedy trial by
the court by a jury and the right to be
a bitch to bail call for five
William Gregory plain drunk picked up a
tip in town asleep in the gutter 14
similar offenses in the past six months
still that in triggering how do you
plead I don't feel so good unless you
are you appeal I asked you how you plead
gilli I can't when did you get out the
last time
yes days before Christmas that was how
you laugh to miss New Year's you'll be
out in time for Washington's Birthday 60
days.
Milton rails a plane drunk picked up on
Brooklyn Avenue giving treatment at
receiving hospital then removed to jail
how old are you rails 17 sir did you
take a good look at those men on the
cell with you last night
yes sir and then you're taking a good
look at yourself this morning oh no sir
and I suggested to do $5 in two days
sentence suspended what judge
Alfred Hinkle more commonly known as
Norman Maine drunken disorderly crack
car into tree at sunset in Coronado
evidently been drinking for days
resisted arrest and injured one of the
arresting officers how do you plead
guilty your normal mainly actor aren't
you
you come pretty low haven't you doesn't
the man here who's had the advantages
you've had look what you've done with
them you're nothing but an irresponsible
drunk driving about the streets for the
power to inflict death or injury on
innocent people I think we better deny
you that bar for a while
90 days in the city jail please wait
I'm his wife yes I recognize you miss.
Lester please judge I promise you this
won't happen again I'll be responsible
for him if you just won't send him there
you realize that this man when drunk is
obviously a menace to Public Safety and
you realize too miss Lester the
responsibility you'll be assuming to
this court into the count well I do
seven suspended mister remanded to
custody wife thank you
you can get him at the jail in
transmitting whatever Vegas raindrop
picked up at first main second up and
how do you plead
I think I'm guilty your honor
60 days
I'm so tired of all of it to make
creaking oh no stick to the plan please
your day it's the best thing for him
awful to see this happen to someone you
love
and knowing your heart but it can't get
any better
all I can do now is stay with him and
try to help him so what I between us
take care of it
you're very fond of you might you Oliver.
Hungary found important then I know
you'll understand what I have to tell
you and after what happened last night I
think you already know what it is I
can't do any more pictures and runways
of good with Norman you can't do that
baby
I'm at the very peak of your success and
- you work so hard to achieve it necklace
- in room.
Maybe if I hadn't been away from him so
much last night and what went before it
wouldn't have happened I know it's too
late to think about that now but
it may not be too late to go away with
him and start over somewhere it's your
life you're giving up the game so I can
try to give Norman back his can you
honestly tell me I'm wrong to do it
no Vicky
honestly
then there'll be no more Vicki Lester
you
my walk of the dollar
goodbye to Calista you were a grand girl
good luck mrs. Naumann name
and darling
this is name coming in to apologize
again
I'm sorry of it it didn't you what other
troubles have you got I was just playing
a scene with myself
now look I'm just coming out of the
jitters and you're just going into this
is a swell house though isn't it I tell
you what we'll do
I'll promise to brace up if you go on
the wagon I guess I had been drinking
too much
know what I'm gonna do I'm going to be
an athlete
you mean with great big muscles and
everything No roughly speaking I'm gonna
join the YMCA ah that cost too much I'm
going waiting out in our front yard
sure did you like me to go with you sure
if you'd like to know me I don't think I
will
it might spoil this beautiful natural
way yeah I guess that's right the
darling look up could you have a hot
toddy rip I mean some hot soup for me
and I come back some hot soup and I'll
make some of those nice sandwiches.
I don't stay in too long.
Hey
you mind if I take just one more look
face drink of water he had in 20 years
and then he had to get it by accident
the successor but how are you why
congratulations to the Pacific Ocean
hello Becky
get away can't you come on making that
cu5 Michael for me right this is Norman
hey don't compare Vicki you get over
he wasn't so much
you
do you mind if I check one more look
here are the paychecks for the servants
graves you'll find a very nice bonus in
each one miss master asked me to thank
you feel kindness and service shivered
anything I can do for little lady I
should be glad to do it she would
appreciate your attending to the closing
of the Beverly Hills house down those
trunks put it down I say well where is
she
in the bedroom who are you I'm her
grandmother yeah
ready
dolly oh I'm so glad to see you what did
you come oh I know when I'm needed again
go on how to fit all of you I want to
talk to my granddaughter alone I came
just as quickly as I could but I'm going
home I said you were why yesterday
tada
is it true that you're going to quit the
movies I never want to hear them again
what're you running away from I'm not
running away it's just that I can't go
on my heart is
once I told you if you get what you want
you have to give you a heart in exchange
and you said you were willing you
remember remember it seems to me that
you got more than you bargained for more.
Fame more success even more personal
happiness maybe more unhappiness but you
did make a bargain and now you're pining
over it I don't think I'd feel so very
proud of myself if I were you Esther and
not crazy
and I'm sorry I gave you the money to
come out it just wastes oh but granny I
was proud to be resident I was proud to
be the grandmother of Nikolas it gave me
something to live for
now I know I want to be strong but I I
can't go on you master tragedy is the
test of courage if you can meet it
bravely believe you bigger than its.
Angela if not then you'll have to live
all your life for the coward because no
matter where you may run you can never
run away from yourself I never knew
Norman Maine he wrote me a very sweet
letter when you were married he said you
told him how much I meant to you and I
know just how much you must have meant
to be you know Esther I can't believe
that whatever he is he can be very happy
knowing that his death broke the spirit
of a little girl he praised me so highly
for
and I can't believe that he can be very
proud knowing that all his great love
didn't were you forced to make
quitter the car is ready miss Lester
we'll have to go now to make the Train
the entire picture industry of cover the
Chinese Theatre for this opening tonight
it is comput a tribute to a great star
along the way to return to the screen in
what is involved waited for pause it is.
Comfort a trivet to the girl herself the
girl who has won the heart of Hollywood
the girl who has won the heart of the
world.
Miss Vicky Lester and if I'm not
mistaken this leftist car has just
driven up yes it is
also doesn't scare you too much I scare
very slowly young man just follow please
they'll have your mug I mean your face
plastered across half the papers in the
country tomorrow hmm how do I look oh
you look swell you're a liar but I like
it and here's Miss Lester's grandmother
won't you say a few words with the radio
audience please say something Larry you
know we've got a thing like that back
home where they all listen in on but we
call it a party line won't you say
something please they're listening maybe
some of you people listening in dream
about coming to Hollywood and maybe some
of you get pretty discouraged well when
you do you just think about me it took
me over 7060 years to get here but here
I am and here I mean to stay thank you
very much
miss Lester
this microphone is on an international
hooker throughout the world your fans
are hoping that you'll say a few words
too
hello everybody this is mrs. Norman
Maine