[upbeat music]
[tense dramatic music]
[singing in foreign language]
- Stay right where you are.
[tense music]
Don't move.
Stay there now.
Steady.
Now, sit up!
Get up!
[whip claps]
Sit up, you!
Up you fool, up!
[dramatic music]
[cat meows]
Chicken, I'll show
you who the boss is!
Sit up I said.
Sit up!
[whip slaps]
Up!
[cat growling]
[dramatic music]
[display crashing]
- Really, Mr. Livington?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Please let me help you.
Oh, here.
[cat growling]
Buzz!
Oh Buzz!
- What's the matter?
Buzz!
- Take it easy.
- [Buzz] What's the matter?
- Look!
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
- Take it away.
Not here.
- Wait a minute, take
it easy, Stanley.
This is a harmless
little kitten.
- Buzz, I'm scared of that.
[cat meows]
Ooh, the wild look in his face!
- Oh.
I can't understand why you have
this terrible fear
of animals in you!
What is it?
- When I was a little baby I
was scared by my piggy bank.
- Oh, that's nonsense.
- You wanna hear
something worse?
- What?
- I was 15 years old before I
ate my first animal cracker.
[phone ringing]
- Come on, the store's
about to open up.
Fix up your collar.
Get to work.
[cat meows]
- Come on, go on.
And how.
Yes, sir.
That's the truth.
- How do you do, may I help you?
- Do you happen
to have a copy of
"Dark Safari" by Cuddleferd?
- I'll find out.
- [Customer] Hey bub.
- How do you do, gentlemen?
- [Customer] We'd like
speak to salesman, pal.
- Well, I'm the salesman,
Stanley Livington.
I'm the clerk in charge
of all jungle books.
And at 11 o'clock
I'm giving a lecture.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You got a book by the name of-
- "Dark Safari" by Cuddleferd.
We did have it, but we got
rid of it sometime ago.
I wanna tell you,
gentlemen, I read that book.
I had nightmares
for nine months.
[books thudding]
- How well do you
remember that book?
- Why?
- Do you remember a map in it?
- The map in that book?
Of course I remember it.
- Could you draw it?
- Could I draw it?
- For $1,000?
- Draw that map in
that book for $1,000?
- Mm-hmm.
- For $1,000, I could
draw that map in oil.
- Okay, then meet us in
the alley tonight at 7:30.
- And we'll take you to somebody
who will give you $1,000 the
minute you lay down the pencil.
Is it a deal?
- Shake.
[bones cracking]
[Stanley grunts]
Oh.
- Okay, pal.
- [Man] See you in the
ally tonight at 7:30.
- And be there chum.
Get me?
- $1,000 to draw that map.
- I'm sorry but that
book is out of print.
In fact we sold the
last one some time ago.
- Oh dear, I was afraid of that.
I've been to every
bookstore in the city.
There's a map in that book
that I'd give $2,500 for.
- Will you give me
that again please?
- I said there was
a map in that book
that I'd get $2,500 for.
- $2,500?
Excuse me, I'll be right back.
What are you doing?
- Hey Buzz, this
you'll never believe.
There were two guys in here-
- Look I understand.
Look Stanley, how well
do you remember that book
you read about "Dark Safari"?
- That's what I'm
trying to tell you.
There was two guys in here-
- Now look, you remember
that was a map in it?
- You too?
No, go away, go away, go away.
- What are you doing there?
- I'm drawing that map now.
- Oh, no you don't.
- Wait a minute.
- [Buzz] No, you
can't draw that-
- Buzz, don't tear that up!
I got a chance to make-
- Sh, wait, quiet, quiet.
Come on, follow me.
Take it easy, take it easy.
Madam, you are the
luckiest person
in New York this morning.
Allow me to introduce
Stanley Livington,
one of the world's
greatest wild game hunters.
- Oh, no.
- Well how exciting.
- [Diana] Wild game
hunters are my weakness.
This is really a
thrill, Mr. Livington.
- So nice meeting you
too but I'm really not-
- It might address
you to know that
when Mr. Cuddleferd
wrote "Dark Safari",
Mr. Livington was right there.
- Oh-
- Wonderful!
Then you must be very familiar
with the map that
is in that book.
- A map?
- Yes.
- Oh sure.
That's one map I could draw
in a dark room even
without a pencil.
- You see, your
troubles are all over.
I could make arrangements
to bring him over
to your home this evening.
- Oh, marvelous.
- No, no.
- [Diana] I think
it's a wonderful idea.
My name is Emerson,
Diana Emerson.
- How do you do,
Miss Emerson, but no.
I got a date in the alley.
- She'll have to wait.
- Here's my address.
See you tonight then.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
That's the kind of
girl I dream about,
but you should see the
ones I get [whistles].
- I tell you, boss, the guy
said he knew the map backwards.
So we make a date to meet him,
bring him in, have him draw it.
- Yeah and the little
muzzler never shows up
after us offering him a grand.
- Well you can relax.
I found somebody
myself this morning.
- You did, boss?
Where?
- [Diana] The Kloppers
Department store.
- That's where we found our guy.
- Wait a minute.
Was he a silly-looking
little fat guy?
- [Man] That's him.
- Why that two-timer!
You offer him 1,000 and he
holds out for a higher price.
- The minute he put his
foot through the door,
I'll break every
bone in his hand.
- You'll do no such thing.
When he leaves, you boys
can meet him outside
and get my money back.
- We get you, boss.
- Now go out the side entrance.
I'm closing a deal with the man
who's gonna lead the safari.
Won't you come in, Mr. Beatty?
[perky music]
- This is the place.
Now don't forget she thinks
you're a big game hunter.
- Buzz, why do you keep
getting me in the middle?
I wish you hadn't.
- Why you ingrate.
Here I'm giving you a
chance to make me $2,500.
Is that the way you
want to repay me
for all the things I
could've done for you?
Come on.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, come on.
[perky music]
Stanley, will you come on?
- I'm shutting off the water.
- Well turn it off and come on.
- [Stanley] I stopped it.
- Good, come on up here.
- [Stanley] May I see
you a minute please?
[perky music]
- Now what's the matter?
- My finger's stuck.
- Leave it there and come on.
- Okay.
- What's the matter?
Let me see this.
- Not that one, not that one.
Not that one!
- Shh!
- [Stanley] That one!
- [Buzz] Don't holler.
- Don't pull at that one!
- [Buzz] Shh, wait a
minute, just wait a minute.
- Harry, did you
answer the door?
- No.
Do I have to?
- Answer the door.
- Oh.
All right.
Do everything around here.
Get this off.
It's tight.
I gotta be a cook and a butler.
One of these days I'll just...
Well, that's all.
I'll just do it.
[door knocking]
Yes?
- [Buzz] Mr. Johnson and Mr.
Livington to see Miss Emerson.
- Well come in.
[metal knocking]
Oh, who is knocking?
Well come in!
Miss Emerson is
busy for the moment.
Will you step in the
living room please?
Hats.
- Thank you.
- [Harry] Ow, that hurts.
- That belongs on outside.
- Yeah, I can't get it off.
Help me get it off.
- Will you get your hand-
- Well not so hard.
- Well get your hand
out, I'll pull it out.
Get your hand out of the way.
Now get your hand
out of the way.
Move your hand out
of the way.
- Get it off!
Well get your hand
out of the way,
I'll get it off.
- Naturally I haven't
publicized the expedition
because I could easily
become the victim
of unscrupulous people.
- [Clyde] If that map's one
of the few in existence,
the owner would
practically have you
in the palm of his hand.
- This man coming tonight
is the gullible type,
but fairly intelligent.
If he can remember
the map accurately,
we'll proceed at once.
- [Clyde] That'll be fine
with me, Miss Emerson.
- And now regarding your fee.
Suppose we say 5000 in advance
and 15,000 on completion?
- That's very liberal.
- On the contrary,
money is no object
as long as I get what I'm after.
- Come on, will you?
- Aha, there it is.
- Oh, not that hand, this one!
- [Stanley] Well put
this hand in your pocket!
Ooh.
Get your hand out of there!
Oh.
[water splashes]
- Ooh, sometimes!
- Stanley.
I just found out that
map is worth more
than $2,500 to that woman.
- I can't get over it.
All I did was go like this
and the water came out.
- Are you listening?
Come on.
Come on!
You go in the living
room and wait.
I'm gonna snoop around here
and find out more
about this deal.
Go ahead.
- Who was at the door, Harry?
- Mr. Livington and Mr. Johnson.
- Good, where are they?
- They're in the living room.
- I'll see them in a minute
and we'll have coffee
in the library.
Harry, I'm phoning
Gunner to come over.
Please leave the door open.
- [Harry] Yes ma'am.
- Excuse me.
I didn't know there was
anybody in the room.
I'm awfully sorry.
Say hold it right where you are.
You know you standing in
front of this here picture
reminds me of my last
expedition in Africa?
- Is that so?
- Yes indeedy.
Yes indeedy.
And it was my
dangerous expedition.
We were at the cats.
Big cats, you know
what cats are?
- Lions, I imagine.
- Oh, there's no imagine
about it, my friend.
Lions are lions here or
any place, they're lions.
You can't imagine they're lions.
Oh no indeedy.
I wanna tell you something.
My first afternoon
out I bagged 64 lions.
Gad, what a hunt.
- Really?
- Oh yes.
And then I ran into an old
friend of mine, Clyde Beatty.
- No?
- Yeah and was he hurt.
He didn't bag a
lion for two weeks!
- Really?
[Stanley laughs]
- I bagged 'em all!
He couldn't get one of 'em!
Course when it comes
to handling lions,
he don't know from nothing.
I am the boy right over here.
I wanna tell you something
else too between you and I.
Clyde Beatty is a phony.
On the side, a
pretty nice fella,
but between you and I a phony.
[Stanley chuckles]
Something else I wanna
tell you, friend.
Who do you think tames the lions
that he has inside the cages?
Me, Stanley Livington, the
world's greatest hunter!
- No kidding?
- Yes, sir.
- [Stanley] Well,
one of the greatest.
[Stanley laughs]
By the way, what's your name?
- Clyde Beatty.
Clyde, it's nice knowing you.
I want you to stick around
because I'm gonna tell you
how I used to go in myself
and tame those lions.
Now when it comes to
taming the animals, Clyde.
Clyde!
[Stanley gasps]
- Oh, good evening.
I see you've met Mr. Livington,
our big wild game hunter eh.
- Yes indeed.
- Swell.
- He's just been telling me
about some of his exploits.
- Oh swell, swell, that's fine.
Tell him about the time you
and Clyde Beatty went
tiger hunting in India.
- Yes, I'd like
to hear about it.
- Yeah, yeah I'll do you one.
Stanley tells me that he out
shot Beatty be five to one.
[Stanley gasps]
By the way, I don't think
you've introduced me
to this gentleman.
- Clyde Beatty.
[Buzz stutters]
Clyde Beatty, I'll
be seeing you around.
- Mr. Beatty, I'm sorry for
what I said about Mr. Beatty.
Excuse me.
- Why Mr. Johnson
and Mr. Livington,
please forgive me for
keeping you waiting.
You've met Mr. Beatty.
- It seems Mr. Livington
and I are old hunting pals.
- Won't you gentlemen
have some coffee?
And after coffee we'll have
Mr. Livington draw the map.
- Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Mr. Livington will not
be able to draw the map.
- But he's got too.
The whole success of
my trip depends on it.
- You mean you intend to
take a trip to Africa?
- Very definitely.
I'm planning a safari.
- I wonder if I may be excused.
I know you folks would rather
talk business in private.
- If you don't mind, it
think it would be better.
Mr. Beatty's hat, Harry.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
- Goodnight, old friend.
- Quick, Grapple and
Boots are outside waiting
to slug Johnson and Livington.
Tell them the plans have
changed and to lay off.
- Yes ma'am.
- Look Buzz, let
me draw the map.
We'll get the $2,500
and get out of here.
- Certainly not!
Now if I play your cards right,
we'll get more than $2,500.
Listen, you heard her.
She's organizing a safari.
- I wish I was there.
- Where?
- On the Hoboken
safari right now.
- Stanley, you're
absolutely right.
As you surmised and
to be frank with you,
I don't blame you for
having the desire.
- The desire to what?
- Of course I'll have to
explain everything to the lady.
- Explain it to me!
- Mr. Livington insists on
joining your safari to Africa.
- I insist?
- There you are, you heard
it from his own lips.
- Just a, hello.
Just a minute, how do you do?
- You see with Mr.
Livington in Africa,
he'd feel right at home
and it'd be very simple
for him to draw the map
without any difficulties.
- I think it's an
excellent idea.
- Surely.
- Once we're there, he can
lead us to the East Fork
of the Talabongo
and Okavangy River.
- Lead you to the fork?
- Yes, surely of course.
It'll be the regular
$5,000 fee in advance
and $15,000 on completion.
Of course that
includes my services.
- Splendid.
- That's fine.
- [Diana] And for
your safety I'm going
to assign you my
best follow upper.
- Follow upper?
- [Diana] Yes, he's the man
who follows you in the jungle
and if you miss a shot
at a charging animal,
he shoots and saves your life.
[door crashing]
Oh, that's him now.
Excuse me.
- [Buzz] Surely.
- Listen, Buzz, I'm not
gonna go over there.
You got no right to book
me in a thing like that.
- All this kind of money.
- You're always putting
me right in the middle-
- Don't tell me-
- Don't care what
kind of money it is!
- Don't you give me that line!
- Now listen, [speaks too fast]
- No more arguments.
- I'm not gonna go over
there with all those lions.
- Now, do as I tell you.
[Stanley roars]
- I'm gonna start
going the other way-
- You'll do as I
say, no arguments!
- Oh no, I'm not.
I won't.
- Gunner, I'd like
to have you meet
Mr. Johnson and Mr.
Livington, Gunner Jensen.
- Hi.
- I don't want to
seem inquisitive,
but just what are we
going to Africa for?
- Well, we're going after
an orangutan Gargantua.
- An orangutan Gargantua?
- Excuse me, please?
- Pardon me.
- May I see you?
- [Stanley] What's an
orangutan Gargantua?
- It's a big ape.
- Oh, a big ape.
- Yeah, stop worrying.
- Ape?
Excuse me, excuse me.
- Pardon me, pardon me.
- Big ape?
- Yeah.
- [Stanley] You mean like
the thing I seen in a circus,
like the father to the monkey?
- Yeah, it's only
bigger, bigger.
- Ping!
And he's gonna protect me?
- Mm-hm.
- [Diana] Gunner,
show them how you
can shoot the Winchester.
[gunner crashing]
- You missed a lion.
I raise the gun to my shoulder,
look through the
peep sight and I...
I look through the peep sight,
put my finger on the trigger,
grab for the pump
slide, and I, I...
No pump slide.
- Stanley?
Stanley?
[perky music]
Now, where did he go?
Stanley!
[Stanley thuds]
[clock chimes]
[light dramatic music]
[monkey squeaks]
[elephant roars]
[tense dramatic music]
[singing in foreign language]
[alligator growls]
[water splashes]
- It's a calm river.
You know, Stanley,
suppose a north
wind should come up?
What would you do?
- I'd throw out an anchor.
- If a west wind come
up, what would you do?
- I'd throw out another anchor.
- And a south wind came
up, what would you do then?
- I'd throw out another anchor!
- And an east wind blew
up, what would you do?
- I'd throw out another anchor!
- Where are you getting
all the anchors?
- The same place you're
getting all the wind!
- Will you keep quiet?
[tense music]
Come on, row your boat.
You've been a very bad boy
the last couple of days.
I want you to change,
I'm warning you.
I don't like it a bit.
All you do is snap at me!
- Me snap at you?
Oh, ain't that a laugh!
Me snapping at him!
- [Buzz] Why should you laugh?
- [Stanley] Oh.
[oar bouncing]
- Don't splash!
[Stanley yawns]
[aligator growls]
[tense perky music]
What are you doing?
[blender whirring]
[tense dramatic music]
[singing in foreign language]
[monkeys screeching]
- Say, you.
- What's the matter?
- [Harry] Oh, Gunner!
Look, not me, the post!
- Oh.
- Oh!
- Always complaining.
- [Man] Hello.
- [Diana] Hello.
- The camp's coming
along fine, Miss Emerson.
And in the morning, we'll
start for the interior.
- Very good.
- Well, we've looked
the whole place over.
You wanna know something, boss?
This don't look like a
place to find diamonds.
- You fool!
[face slaps]
Don't you ever mention
the word diamonds!
We're supposed to be
after an orangutan.
- And another thing, boss.
I'm getting awfully
sick of these
two guys you're depending on.
They're always fouling us up.
- Just be patient.
It won't be long now before
the map is in my hands.
- [Buzz] Stanley.
Stanley, drop everything!
- Huh?
- Drop everything!
- [Buzz] Come here,
come here Stanley.
Get up, get out
from under there.
Hurry up and come here.
Come on, Stanley.
- Oh Buzz, just when
I had the tent up!
- Never mind the tent.
Come over here,
and draw that map.
- The map?
- The map.
- [Stanley] If I draw it
will you let me go home?
- Why do you wanna go home?
- I forgot something.
- What did you forget?
- I forgot to stay there.
- Draw the map, come on.
- [Buzz] Boy, oh boy, can
you picture me a tycoon?
Oh, building, yachts, railroad.
I don't know, I might
even buy an airline,
according to how I feel.
My winters in Maine,
summers in Florida.
Oh, it's unbelievable.
- Look at him, he can't
even get his laundry up.
- Have you got it ready yet?
Come on!
You got it?
That a boy.
Oh, this paper here is
worth a million dollars.
- Million dollars?
Well, I mean, I did it, I
got to have something for it.
- Oh, sure, sure.
I intended to.
Here, here's a nickel.
- Thank you.
- That a boy.
- Oh, a nickel!
- [Buzz] Hello, Diana.
- Harry, some tea
for Mr. Johnson.
- And plenty of sugar.
Wonderful day we're having.
You're looking
marvelous yourself.
- You're in fine spirits.
- I have all the reasons
in the world to be.
I've finally persuaded
Stanley to draw the map.
- Oh, well, may I see it?
- I also made some very
interesting discoveries.
Aside from the orangutan,
there are far more
important things
to be found in that
particular territory.
- Really?
- Yes, and due to the facts,
I personally think I'm
entitled to a new deal.
- Well, what kind of a
deal did you have in mind?
- Well, I'd say 20% of the
safari's profits would be fair.
- Very liberal.
In view of your generosity,
may I see the map?
- Oh, yeah, surely,
surely, surely.
Now, this map will
take you right to...
There seems to be
something lacking here.
I'll see Stanley.
There's some detail work,
he hasn't really
completed the map.
I'll be right back.
- Here's your tea, and I
put plenty of sugar in it.
- Drink it yourself!
- Oh, drink it yourself,
drink it yourself!
- Harry, I want to see Boots
and Grappler immediately.
- Come here, come
here, come here.
Wise aleck, huh?
- Now, what's the
matter with you?
- Thought you were putting
something over on me.
This is not the map that
was in Cuddleford's book.
- Oh, yes it is.
- This, this thing
tells you how to get
to Klopper's Department store.
- Well, that's the map.
I used to keep that map
in Cuddleford's book.
- Listen, you
nit-witted numbskull,
these people want a map
of the Bangi territory.
- The Bangi territory?
Bangi territory?
- Yes!
- I was wondering why they wanna
pay all that kind of
money just to find the
directions how I get to
Klopper's Department store.
That I couldn't understand.
- Just a minute,
- [Buzz] do you realize we're in
the most dangerous spot we've
ever been in in our lives?
- Dangerous spot?
- Dangerous spot!
- Buzz?
- What?
- [Stanley] Is it worse than
the time when Skinny Marink
knocked the chip
off my shoulder?
- Ah, certainly!
- Worse than that?
- I should say it is.
- [Stanley] And the time
I drew the line like that?
- Far more.
- Yeah, but that time
he came over the line.
It's worser than that?
- Never mind that,
it's worse than that.
- Oh, are we in trouble.
- Wait a minute, we've
got to do something.
I have it, we've gotta get out.
Come on, hurry up.
- Sure.
- [Grappler] What
ya doing, boys?
- Going somewhere, fellas?
- We were just gonna take these
little trunks inside the tent.
- Get moving.
- Hey.
Go ahead, knock the
chip off my shoulder.
- Not that, your head's
liable to go with it.
- Oh.
- Go on, get moving!
[birds screeching]
- I'm getting sick
and tired of getting
pushed around by you guys.
Did you hear me?
I'm getting sick
and tired of it.
Hey, come on back, come on back.
[Stanley whistles]
Hey, come on back.
Hey!
Step on that side of the line.
Come on.
[head thuds]
- Stanley!
Stanley, no.
- Don't bother me.
- [Buzz] Stanley, you're
not gonna kill anyone.
- Don't hold me back.
- Don't do that.
- Somebody's gotta get it!
And when I get this mad,
somebody's got to get it!
- Stanley.
Fine friend you are.
You bring me way out here
in the heart of the jungle.
Why?
Because you told me that
you could draw the map.
You can't draw it, can you?
You knew you couldn't.
Why'd you bring me way out here?
Now, what am I going to do?
What am I going to with the
boats I was going to buy,
and the buildings
I was going to buy?
The railroads I
was going to buy?
Put that down!
That's a fine how do you do.
Nice goings on from
a pal, from a friend!
I never,
I never expected it from you!
I'll have to go in to
bankruptcy, that's all!
That's all that's
left for me to do!
Then what'll my friends say?
To think that you,
my bosom friend-
Look, where are you
going with the water?
- Oh, my tent's on fire!
- Well, what have you
got to say for yourself?
[triumphant music]
[tense dramatic music]
- Hold it, hold it.
Stop.
Go no further.
- What are you
stopping here for?
It's early yet.
- Well, this is where
Cuddleford stopped.
Now, on the bottom of page
389, according to Cuddleford,
he wrote that he had
a very uneventful day.
Therefore, he made camp on a
bank of the Crocodile River.
Now, over there is
the Crocodile River.
Eh eh, over here.
- You'll have to forgive him.
You see, Stanley is
actually living the book.
- And that's not all.
That night, Cuddleford,
he posted a double guard
because he was nearing
the Bangi country,
which was full of ferocious
animals and cannibals.
- Stanley's right.
This is pretty
dangerous territory.
I suggest we pitch camp
on this side tonight.
- But that means we'll
lose an entire half day.
- Well, if you cross over,
you're going to lose
two days anyway.
- Why?
- Well, according to Cuddleford,
when he crossed the river
he was brought down
by jungle fever,
and he was that
way for 36 hours.
- Miss Emerson, I think
we should look for a
location to pitch camp.
- All right, Mr. Beatty.
- Stanley, come here.
You've got to use
a little more tact
when you talk to Miss Emerson.
You know, she's liable to
send us back to the states.
- Good, good.
You, what's the matter?
Oh, my goodness.
You worrying about that?
That's just a little baby lion.
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
I'll get a hold of him.
Can you imagine that?
- [Stanley] Buzz, don't.
Buzz, don't.
- Here, look at him.
- Remember what happened at
Klopper's Department store?
Don't do it.
- Now, don't get excited.
This little cat
was raised on milk.
- So was I, but I eat meat now.
Take it away.
- Touch it.
- Go ahead, touch it.
- Go back to it's mother.
- [Buzz] Touch it, now
go ahead, touch it.
There you are.
[Stanley whines]
You see?
Go ahead, now, go ahead.
There he is.
Look how cute he runs.
- Hey, I got my finger back.
- What do you mean
you got your finger?
You touched him, didn't ya?
- I touched a real lion!
- That's all there is to it.
- A real lion!
I'm brave too!
- Well that's it.
- Just like that!
- That'll take that
fear out of you.
[both laugh]
- I'm going to capture
that little baby lion,
and I'm gonna bring
it back to Diana.
- Hey, wait a minute.
That's a good idea.
That'll put is in good with her.
- Yeah.
- Go ahead kid, I'll
see you at camp.
[Stanley hums]
[slow perky music]
- Here kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty.
Here kitty, kitty!
Come back kitty!
[Stanley laughs]
Kitty, kitty!
[lion growls]
[Stanley screams]
Hey, Buzz!
Buzz, come on!
[lion roars]
Well, Buzz, I guess we
lost that pussy cat.
Oh, Buzz?
[branches crashing]
Oh no.
Hey, Buzz?
Oh Buzz.
Hey, it's dark down there,
I can't see a thing.
How'd you fall in the trap
anyway, you clumsy boy?
I'm gonna throw you
some rope down there.
Can't see a thing,
so grab for it.
[tense music]
That a boy.
[dramatic music]
[gorilla growls]
That a boy.
Now, Buzz, you
better go on a diet
because you're getting
awful fat and awful heavy.
Give me the other end
of the rope, thank you.
Now, leave it here for
whoever it belongs to.
[suspenseful music]
[gorilla snorting]
Hey.
Oh!
Buzz!
Hey, Buzz!
- We'd better go over
and check on that trap.
- Stanley!
Stanley?
- All right, boys, you've
done a good job now.
Take them back to the truck.
- Come on, boys,
back to the truck.
- Stanley!
Stanley!
- [Frank] Look
out there, fellow.
There's a trap right
there in front of you.
- A trap?
Thanks, stranger.
Say, my name is Buzz Johnson.
I'm looking for a
little chubby guy
by the name of
Stanley Livington.
Have you seen him?
- No, I haven't.
My name is Frank Buck.
- Frank Buck?
Well, I'm certainly
glad to know you.
- I'm glad to see you.
I'm looking for a great big
guy, called orangutan Gargantua.
Have you seen him?
- Oh, no.
- Well, I just built
this trap for him.
Come on, you better get
away from this trap.
- I think we better.
Say, Mr. Buck, is
there really such
an animal as an
orangutan Gargantua?
- Of course, there is.
- There is?
- There's one right
around this district now.
Great big fellow,
about 20 feet high.
Face almost human.
Matter of fact, I've got traps
all around here set for him.
- [Buzz] Mm-hm.
- Hey, Buzz!
- Mr. Buck, I wonder if
you'd help me find my camp?
- Why I'd be very glad to-
[trap crashes]
Trap, the trap!
Boys, come on!
[fast paced music]
Got one!
It's only a baby
though, but we got him!
Boys, bring the
net around there!
Come on now!
Now, get him in the net
there and bring him up.
Pull him up!
Mr. Johnson, that's the
first of the species
ever captured by a human being.
- You two, take the
poles up, drop the net.
[tense music]
- Come on, Bobo, come on.
Get him up there.
Get him up, hoist him up.
- [Man] Take the
slack out of the rope.
Careful boys.
- Is he ferocious?
- Well, we don't know.
- Don't know?
[men screaming]
It's Stanley!
Stanley, where have you been?
I have searched this jungle
all night long for you!
- Last night [stutters].
- There's no time for clowning.
Now, listen,
- Clowning.
- [Buzz] what are
you trying to do?
Make a monkey out of yourself?
- That's it-
- Destroyed all this work
you did for my men here!
- Listen, are you the
guy that dug this hole?
- Yes, I am.
- The least you could have done
was put a red lantern there.
I'm gonna report
you to the African
League for Better
Road Improvement.
I certainly am.
- Now take it
easy, take it easy.
- What are you trying
to build anyway, a trap?
- Yes, a trap.
- You're doing it all wrong.
- What do you mean I'm
doing it all wrong?
- This guy don't know for
nothing about building a trap.
I showed Frank Buck how
to build all his traps!
Everyone of them!
- Oh yeah?
- [Stanley] He listens to me!
I'm one of the biggest game
hunters in the whole world.
That's why I'm over here.
- Will you wait a minute?
- [Stanley] You've
got the whole thing-
Will you keep quiet?
- Will you listen?
- [Stanley] It's
swung over here with-
Will you keep quiet?
After what I saw last
night, I'm the boss!
I know what I'm talking about!
[Stanley stutters]
Who's this character?
- Frank Buck!
[Stanley laughs]
- Frank Buck?
How do you do?
I'll see you later, Mr. Buck.
- Yeah, get on over by the
truck and stand over there.
Boys, set the trap again.
Now, get it all ready.
- Mr. Buck, the boys are
finished resetting the traps.
- All right, go down
the other way now
and set the other ones.
- I'm sorry I fell in your trap.
- [Frank] Oh, that's all right.
- But last night I saw something
like I never saw
before in my life,
not even in a nightmare I
never saw anything like this.
He had a head like that.
- [Buzz] Oh good.
[tense music]
[Stanley stutters]
Eat your food, come on.
[Stanley wheezing]
More sugar.
[gorilla growls]
[Stanley coughs]
[utensils clanking]
[Stanley wheezing]
- [Frank] What makes
you so nervous?
Don't play with it, eat it!
- Buzz.
Buzz.
- [Buzz] What's the
matter with you?
- [Frank] He must be tired.
- Buzz.
- What's the matter?
- You see that thing over there?
- Certainly not.
- Then I got jungle fever.
- I'd better get him
back to our camp.
- I think you'd better too.
Now, just follow the trail
exactly as I told you,
and you won't miss it.
Just look out for my traps.
Oh wait, I think you better
take a gun along with you.
- By George, I think
we can use one.
- Yeah.
- Thanks a lot.
- All right.
- [Buzz] So long, Mr. Buck.
- So long, Mr. Buck.
- [Buzz] Come on, come on.
Take it easy, take it easy.
[tense dramatic music]
- What a business
for a guy to be in.
- Crocodiles and
lions bring a lot of
dough back in the states.
- You can have it.
[crocodile growls]
- Okay boys, you're finished.
Let's go back to the compound.
[crocodile growls]
- Well, Buzz, after this swim,
I'll feel like a
diamond in the rough.
- Yeah.
Diamonds?
- That's right.
- Stanley, I think
Diana's trying
to put something over on us.
Doesn't it seem funny to you
that as soon as Clyde Beatty
goes out to bag lions,
she lets us come down here
to take a swim in the river?
- Oh, tush, tush.
- Never mind the tush, tush.
- I can use it, I can use it.
- Just a minute.
We may be in the
diamond territory.
Maybe she knows where
the diamonds are.
- Buzz-
- Maybe she has the diamonds!
- Buzz, you gotta take it easy.
You need more sleep nights, kid.
Now, forget about diamonds.
- I'm a little worried.
- Don't get worried, hold that.
- I know.
- Come on.
Let's go in and take a bath.
A bathe or something
and swim nicely.
- [Buzz] All right, put
it down, put it down.
- Come on, let's go!
- Well?
- [Stanley] The last
one in is an old maid!
- Wait, wait, wait a minute!
Where are you going?
- I'm going to dive in.
- In there?
- Of course in there.
I ain't gonna dive
in over there.
You'll hurt your
head over there.
- Did you read this sign?
- What?
- Do you know what
that sign says?
- Who's walking on the grass?
- Wait a minute, you
can't dive in there!
There's nothing but
crocodiles in there!
- Oh.
What?
- Crocodiles!
Don't get excited,
don't get excited.
You see over here?
There's nothing but nets.
- I dive inside the net?
- Yeah, the crocodiles
can't get in the nets.
- That's good.
- That's swell.
Go ahead right in
and enjoy yourself.
- [Stanley] Okay.
- Can you make it?
Oh, come on, that's warm.
- It's cute.
- Sure.
That a boy.
Whoa boy, where you going?
[water splashes]
What a belly flop.
- Hey, Buzz?
- What?
- [Stanley] Watch
my impersonations.
- You do impersonations?
- Yeah, watch.
My first one, a seal.
- A seal.
- Here I go!
[water splashes]
[imitates seal]
Pretty good, huh?
[indistinct]
Hey, watch my other one.
- [Buzz] What's this.
- A whale.
- [Buzz] A whale?
That's a whale.
- Yeah, hey, watch
this one, Buzz.
- [Buzz] What's that?
- An alligator.
- [Buzz] Look, I wanna
go in there too you know.
- Wait till I do the alligator?
- Well, let me come in.
- Here I go!
[crocodile growls]
[tense music]
[Stanley growls]
- [Stanley] Buzz?
Buzz?
How do you like that?
The guy couldn't wait,
he had to dive in!
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Hey, Buzz.
Buzz, stop it.
[Stanley laughs]
Stop!
[water splashing]
Stop tickling, Buzz!
He's a playful
little son of a gun.
Buzz, come on.
Buzz, come up wherever you are!
Whoa!
Buzz, will ya...
Buzz.
Will you cut it out!
Buzz, will you stop, I
don't want to play anymore.
Buzz, no more.
[tense music]
Now, will you come
up wherever you are!
Oh, Buzz-
[crocodile growls]
If I ever get my,
if I ever get my...
[dramatic music]
[crocodile growls]
[wood knocks]
[lion growls]
[whip cracks]
- I don't understand why he
has to try those cats out
before he sends them
back to the states.
It worries me.
- Doesn't worry me half
as much as those two
knot-heads you
brought along with us.
- Relax.
[lion growls]
- Buzz, please don't
make me do this.
- You're going to do it!
- I don't wanna.
- You're making a
coward out of me.
- Oh, I'm not making
a coward out of you.
- The gossip that's
going around this camp.
Stanley's a coward,
Stanley's a coward.
Afraid of a little teeny
weeny alligator like that.
- It was a big alligator.
- Oh, stop it.
Are you afraid of that?
- I think so.
- Oh stop, it's only a skin!
Feel it, feel it!
Don't be afraid of it.
- That's enough.
- [Buzz] Now, look, I'm
gonna make a hero out of you,
whether you like it or not.
I'm going down that path,
you know where the water bag is?
- Yeah.
- You meet me there.
I'll be in the skin.
- Uh-huh.
- And make sure you
bring Diana with you.
- Oh, you want me to
get Diana and bring her
over by the path
by the water bag?
[Buzz stutters]
Then you're going to have
the lion skin on, and then-
- That's it!
Just act like Clyde Beatty.
- Okay, Buzz.
- That a boy.
- I'm going over to have
a chit chat with Diana.
I'm gonna show her I'm
a pretty brave kid,
and I don't like this
kind of talk going around!
- Now, you're talking!
- Don't forget by the
path by the water bag.
- I'll be there.
[lion growls]
- Well, boys, in a little while,
we can say goodbye to Mr. Beatty
and his lions and
crocodiles and cages.
- Tag this one for shipment
back to the States.
He's a good one.
And get the other three
ready for the training cage.
I'll be back later
then to work them out.
- [Stanley] Diana?
- Yes, Stanley?
- I would like to have
a chit chat with you,
if you don't mind.
- Of course.
- Excuse us, fellas.
Now, a few things I want
to get straightened out.
- Yes?
- I better tell you over here.
Diana, there's some talk
going around this camp,
and I don't like it.
I don't like it no how.
And I'm getting plenty
peeved about it,
and I have a right too.
Have a drink.
People are going around saying
that I'm afraid of lions.
Well, that's not true.
That's a lie!
I'm one of the finest big
game hunters in the world!
No one surpasses
Stanley Livington!
You think the lions that Clyde
Beatty catches are big ones?
Ha ha!
They're nothing but kittens,
little bitty kittens.
[Stanley whistles]
Why, I wanna tell you something.
I'm going on a big
game hunt myself.
I'm going catch a
lion just for you
to show you how big
I can catch them!
You afraid of lions?
- No.
- Good.
Take a look.
[Diana screams]
- Stanley.
Stanley, what's the
matter with you?
- She scared me.
- Oh, never mind.
Listen, I'm going into the cage,
and you behave yourself.
I can't understand
why he gets so scared.
[tense music]
[lion growls]
- Stand back!
Have no fear, fair lady,
of that wild beast!
I, Stanley Livington, will
protect thee and yous two.
- Get back, Stanley,
I'll plug him for ya!
- Why not let the lion
chew on him for a while?
- No lion's gonna spoil my fun.
- Let him alone, Grappler.
- Nice work, Buzz.
- Look, he's heading
him toward the cage.
- Well, I'll be.
- Come on, come on!
Get in the cage now!
I'll show you who's the boss!
Come on, come on!
[Stanley chuckles]
The key, I need it no more.
Diana, watch.
I'm not afraid of lions.
And the gun, that's
only for Clyde Beatty.
Oh, me oh my.
Don't get scared, I've
got it under control.
- Boy, the stupid little
idiot, showing off like that.
- Come on, Buzz,
get up on the box.
Do a good job.
Come on, stop
stalling, get up there.
Come on, get up there, will you?
That a boy.
Hey, Buzz, this I
got to tell you.
You walked in the
cage like a real lion.
You even hopped around
like a real lion.
You wanna know something else?
You even smell like a real lion,
and that's the part
I don't understand.
Stop breathing down my neck too.
I don't like that.
How do you do?
- Oh, this is gonna be horrible.
- Hey, you come awful close.
Now, cut it out or I'll hit you
right in the puss with a chair!
I'm not afraid of nothing!
How do you do?
I'm a pretty brave kid.
I don't care about kittens,
I don't care how
big the kittens are!
How we doing, Buzz?
[lion growls]
Hey, Buzz, get those
nails filed, they hurt.
Serves you right.
[lion growls]
- I've seen enough.
- Stanley!
Stanley!
Stanley, come out of there!
[Stanley chuckles]
- Hey, Buzz did we fool them?
I wish you could have got
the look on their faces
when they saw you in here.
[Stanley laughing]
- [Buzz] Stanley, come out!
- I can't, I locked
the door over here.
- [Buzz] Well,
throw the key out.
- I threw the key out long ago!
- Where?
- Over there!
[Stanley laughing]
- Stanley.
- Hey, look, hey,
hey, enough is enough,
now go away before you queer it.
- What are you talking about?
- They don't know you're
inside the lion's skin.
- [Buzz] I'll look for the key.
- Oh, the big guy, what
a look on his face!
[Stanley laughing]
[heavy breathing]
Buzz, I want to tell you,
you should have seen
that big guy's face.
[lion roaring]
They didn't know you was
inside the lion skin!
[lion growling]
I know that you're inside...
[Stanley crying]
[speaks gibberish]
[tense music]
Buzz, I'm paralyzed!
[lion growling]
Don't!
- Hey, Stanley, I found the key!
Everything's all right,
you got nothing to worry-
[solemn music]
Stanley.
[lion roaring]
Oh no.
No.
Stanley?
Stanley.
What'd you do with my buddy?
[lion roars]
[tense music]
It's all my fault.
I should've never let him do it.
My bosom pal.
- Why's this cat in here?
And who locked this gate?
[lock clanking]
All right, let the
rest of them in!
[lions roaring]
[whip smacking]
Come on.
[Stanley screams]
Good boy!
Up!
[Stanley screams]
Get up!
Up, up!
All right boys,
let the others in!
[lions growling]
[Stanley screams]
[wood cracks]
[solemn music]
- Oh, this is terrible.
Stanley, Stanley,
it's all my fault.
Don't blame anyone else but me.
Stanley, how was I to know that
a real lion would
go into the cage?
[Buzz crying]
Oh, this is terrible, Stanley.
How can I-
Oh, stop, I just lost the
best friend I ever had.
Oh, if he was only here.
There's a kid's never done
a bit of harm to anyone.
- He was a nice boy.
- What a man he was,
but I never appreciated
him till now.
- No, you didn't,
you was mean to him.
- Now, it's too
late, it's all over.
He's gone.
- Yes.
- The way I used to trap him
and set him into things,
it was all wrong.
I wouldn't send
my worst enemy out
to do the things I
taught him to do.
And the way I used to
cheat him at poker.
- You slapped that poor
kid all over place.
- Oh, I used to cheat him.
- That kid never did
nothing to nobody!
- If he was only here I'd-
- He was a nice boy, that kid.
- Oh, I feel like
jumping off a cliff.
That's what I should do!
- Poor Stanley.
- But no, no, no, I
haven't got the nerve.
If he was only here
to tell me what to do.
Stanley.
What should I do, Stanley?
- I'm Stanley.
- I know what I'll do.
- [Buzz] It's that
lion, that lion!
The one that got him!
I'll spend the rest of my days
right here in this forest.
I'll get that lion!
- No you don't have to-
- [Buzz] I'll get that lion
if it's the last thing I do!
- No, you don't have to-
- I'll spend my life
here in this forest!
- He's a bright man!
- Don't tell me what to do!
- Don't tell me...
- You don't have to get...
- [Stanley] Hello Buzz.
- Stanley.
[slow gentle music]
- What's the matter?
- Stanley?
- What's wrong?
- [Buzz] It's really you.
- Sure, Buzz.
- Wait a minute.
- What?
- [Buzz] Are you all there?
- Sure.
- The lion didn't hurt you?
- No.
- It's really you, Stanley?
- What do you think I am,
a mirage or something?
- You're no mirage?
- I'm no mirage!
- You're real!
- Sure!
- [Buzz] You double-crosser.
[face slaps]
Dirty double-crosser.
[Stanley screams]
What's the matter with you?
What's the matter?
- How do you like that?
I was sitting a piece
of broken milk bottle.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute!
That's a diamond!
- I was gonna throw it away, I-
- No, that's a real diamond!
- That's a real diamond?
- That's what I've
been looking for!
[Stanley stutters]
Oh, don't touch!
Don't get hoggish!
It's mine, I found 'em.
I found the diamond.
- Diamond, that's a piece
of broken milk bottle.
- Don't tell me what it is.
- There's another
piece over there!
I've been looking at that one
for a long time.
- Wait a minute, Stanley.
It's another diamond!
A real diamond, look at them!
Look!
- Whoo-hoo!
- [Buzz] Stanley, look at here.
Come here, follow me.
There's another one.
This is unbelievable!
[birds chirping]
Come on, come on, Stanley.
Stanley, look, another one.
I'm rich.
I'm wealthy, Stanley!
Can you imagine?
Look, Stanley, come here.
Look it here.
Look, Stanley.
Another one!
I can buy buildings!
I can buy polo ponies!
I can buy yachts!
I can buy everything
that my heart desires!
Stanley, do my eyes deceive me?
Look, Stanley.
Stanley, another one!
Stanley, look at that!
Look at the size
of that diamond!
Well, don't stand there,
think of something I
can buy for myself.
Think of something!
Put that away!
Stanley, look it
here, look it here!
Stanley, two of them!
Hold these, hold these, Stanley!
Hold them, don't
drop them, Stanley!
What your eyes see,
your heart must believe.
Two of them!
Real!
What are you doing
with my diamonds?
Trying to steal them?
- Yes!
- Don't touch my diamonds!
[intense music]
Look at the size of them!
Stanley, do you realize?
Look it here!
Stanley, it's another diamond.
Another diamond.
- Buzz.
- We're on the right trail.
- [Buzz] Stanley, we're, look!
Stanley, come here!
Stanley, my back is
broken, pick that up.
Hurry up, put it on here.
- Want to know something?
- [Buzz] What?
- There's another one.
- [Buzz] Well, pick it up!
Put it on here.
I'm watching you.
- Come on.
- Ooh!
- Huh?
- [Stanley] Look!
- Another one?
- Another one.
- [Buzz] Come on,
put it on here.
Boy, oh, boy.
- Another one!
- Can you imagine
nothing but diamonds?
[suspenseful music]
Boy...
Uh oh.
[Stanley humming]
[tribal music]
[speaking foreign language]
[man grunts]
[water bubbling]
- Fine mess you got us into,
all on account of
your lust for money.
- Me?
- Yeah.
- [Stanley] Oh, Buzz.
Now, I know what
they mean when they
say, boy, are you in hot water.
Never thought it was gonna
be anything like this though.
Buzz.
How'd you get yourself untied?
- Quiet.
Quiet!
- You're smart, Buzz.
I take back everything
I've ever said about you.
Good work.
Tell you what you do, Buzz,
I'm going to stay like this.
Don't make a move until
I make a break for it.
I can see 'em.
Get back over there.
Make out your tied.
[speaking foreign language]
[tribal music]
Get ready, they're turning away.
Come on, Buzz!
[perky music]
Come on, Buzz.
- Come here.
- Buzz, come on, will you?
- How can I, I'm still tied?
- You're not tied,
you untied me.
- I did nothing of the kind.
You untied yourself!
- I did not.
- Well, then untie me, come on.
- Are you kidding?
No, he ain't.
- Come on, hurry up!
- Take these down.
- Hurry up, get 'em off.
Get these off, hurry up!
[tense tribal music]
- Hurry up, here he comes!
- Come on!
[head thuds]
- Ooh, god!
[men shouting]
[suspenseful music]
[Stanley screaming]
[hand thuds]
[Stanley grunts]
[perky music]
[Stanley screams]
- What else is on your mind?
- You know, Diana, I
never did go for that
talk of yours about
a 20-foot monkey.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And as for bringing
Clyde Beatty out here
to capture wild animals,
you didn't fool me for a minute.
- Well, just why did I come
to Africa, Mr. Johnson?
- Diamonds.
And I know just where they are.
- And you can lead
us to these diamonds?
- That I can, but first,
we'll talk business.
You and I will cut this
pie right down the center.
- Isn't that rather-
- Now, no bickering,
take it or leave it.
- I don't seem to
have any alternative.
- That you haven't.
So when you make up your mind
just give Buzz a buzz, huh?
Here big boy, hold on to that.
- Boss, about splitting
that pie down the center.
- I'll handle this my own way.
Get ready to break
up camp while I
give Mr. Beatty
his walking papers.
- Hey, boy!
Boy, come here.
Gather up my belongings that
are scattered around here.
I might be moving
to better quarters.
By the way, leave
these things right here
in case that the little fat boy,
you know, little fat boy,
if he does show up, this
is good enough for him.
Go.
[speaking foreign language]
[tense dramatic music]
- Chief wants see head man.
- Yes, sir.
- And so I've decided
there's no such thing
as an orangutan Gargantua.
And now, that we
have enough animals
to have made the
expedition worthwhile,
I'd suggest that
you and your men
prepare to leave for the coast.
- That's all right
with me, Miss Emerson.
I'll go and tell my men.
- All right, Mr. Beatty.
- Miss Emerson, Miss Emerson,
there's some fellows out
there that wanna see you.
They want to hold a conference.
I think you'd better hurry.
- All right, Harry.
- Chief want talk.
- We'll talk in the hut.
[speaking foreign language]
- Chief say, many
white men come to land
of Bangi's for diamonds.
Many white men die.
- [Diana] Why does the
chief want to see me?
- Chief want be your friend.
Chief want to make deal.
Want trade these, diamonds.
- [Diana] What does the
chief want for the diamonds?
- Chief have sweet tooth
for little fat man.
- Him?
- Oh, no.
- [Man] Oh, not him.
Little fat man.
[man grunts]
Strong, strong!
Little fat man, friend
of tall, thin man.
- Oh, Stanley.
Tell the chief he's made a deal.
[speaking foreign language]
- Chief say, deal good.
- [Diana] Excellent.
- She's gonna sell
him on the hoof.
Gunner, Gunner!
- Who is it?
- It's me, Buzz.
Have you seen, Stanley?
Well, if you see him, tell
him to hide until he sees me.
- If I see him I'll tell him,
but so far I haven't
even seen Africa.
How is it?
- Oh, Gunner.
- Hey!
I'll tell him later.
Diana, there's something
I wanna tell you.
We're in very
dangerous territory!
Last night, Buzz and I were
captured by the cannibals,
man eating cannibals!
And you know what they did?
They tied us up to the stakes
and one guy looked at me and
went mmm, mmm, mmm, like this.
And I know that was for no good.
And I wanna tell
you something else,
I escaped and then I
untied Buzz and he escaped.
And then there were
all these cannibals
and I was starting
to fight them.
And I hit one with a right
and another on the right.
I hit one with a fancy uppercut.
I went like this, boom!
And I hit another one
on the right and I,
I kept hitting 'em.
One guy looked just like him.
He had a hat on like that too.
And this guy that had
a hat on like this,
I hit him such a belt.
I went whop,
right on the side of the
head over here I hit the guy.
Oh, he's got the bump.
There it is.
[Stanley screams]
[fast tense music]
- Quick, after Stanley!
[men shouting]
[whimsical music]
- Oh, diamonds!
Diamonds, dropped in my
lap by some kind fate!
[tense music]
[Stanley screams]
- The diamonds.
- Can't let Stanley
know about these.
They're all mine, I won't
share them with no one!
I won't-
[gorilla growls]
- Hey, Buzz!
Buzz!
[slow perky music]
[tense music]
Buzz, come on, quick!
Get up, will ya?
- [Buzz] All right,
take it easy.
- Hey, what's this?
- My diamonds.
- Little fat man got 'em!
- Oh, you snitch!
[men shouting]
[tense music]
- Can you see them, Stanley?
Stanley, what am I going to do?
My diamonds, my diamonds!
That's what they're
after, my diamonds!
Oh, no, they can't take
my diamonds from me.
It would ruin all my dreams!
What would happen to my boats?
My buildings?
Give me my diamonds!
I know what I'll
do, I'll bury them.
I'll hide them!
They'll never find 'em.
I can always come back
and get 'em, Stanley.
Here, here's a good place,
right here.
[Stanley whistles]
Now, I'll mark the tree.
[men shouting]
[tense music]
- Come on, boys, load the truck.
- The men are finished
setting the traps Mr. Buck.
We've got this area
pretty much covered.
- Well, I hope we bag
some big ones here.
[trap crashes]
- [Man] Look!
- [Frank] The cage, come on!
- Get me out of here!
Someone get me out of here!
- All right, all
right, all right.
Come on, raise it,
get her out of there.
- Have you seen a short fat man
and a tall thin man
running through the jungle?
- No, and I don't
want to either.
- Now, I'll never
catch up with them.
- Where are you going?
Wait a minute,
where are you going?
- I've got to find them.
- You're not going to run
around this jungle alone.
You stay right here with me.
[men shouting]
[fast paced music]
- Come on, Stanley.
Stanley, Stanley, I'm going
back for the diamonds,
you keep running.
- How can I keep running?
You got a hold of me!
- Go ahead, keep going!
[tense music]
- Oh, we got him!
That's Stanley!
Keep him covered, Gunner!
Not me, him!
I'll go get help.
Oh, you're such a nuisance!
- Don't give me no
trouble, Stanley.
I shoot and shoot to kill.
- I know you do, Gunner.
I won't give you any trouble.
You won't even know I'm here.
Don't press in so hard.
- Oh, oh, scared, eh?
Look at your face,
it's getting greener
and greener inch by inch.
And you're getting
spots on your kisser.
Stanley, don't force me
to pull this trigger.
I got an itchy finger.
[slow perky music]
[whimsical music]
- Ah, here it is, my diamonds.
Where are my diamonds?
I put 'em here.
My diamonds!
[fast perky music]
Who's that?
It that you, Harry?
- It's me, Harry!
- Oh, he's scared stiff.
He didn't budge an inch.
- He didn't?
- No.
Did you find Boots and Grappler?
- No, I didn't.
I tell you what you do,
keep Stanley covered.
- I got him.
- Keep him covered.
- [Gunner] Got him.
- We'll bring him back to camp.
He's a pretty dangerous
kid, this Stanley.
You did a good job there, kid.
- Oh, not a squawk
out of him, keep walking.
- Let's get him.
- [Gunner] Hands
high, keep walking.
- The diamonds,
they've got to be
around here someplace.
[whimsical music]
Yeah, that's the mark.
Why should this happen to me?
I planted 'em right here.
Me, who's been so
good to his friends.
They've got to be here!
They must be here!
My diamonds are out here!
- Keep walking, keep walking!
How did you ever
get into this mess?
I don't understand it.
Come on, keep walking.
There you are, keep going.
I got my eye on you.
What are you trying to do,
make a monkey out of me?
I see ya.
[tense music]
[Stanley gasps]
[men shouting]
[conch shell wailing]
[monkeys screeching]
[gorilla grunts]
[speaking foreign language]
[tense music]
[monkey screeching]
[monkey's grunting]
- Why don't you watch where
you're going, you clumsy ox!
- Me?
- Yes, you.
- Why, you tripped me with
those big feet of yours.
- I did no such thing!
- [Grappler] What are
you kicking me for?
- Who's kicking who?
- You kicked me!
[tense music]
- I didn't even touch you.
Look, I told you, lay off of me.
I didn't trip you and
I didn't kick you.
So now, leave me alone!
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- I'll leave you alone!
- [Boots] Look, I'll hit you
harder than Louis ever did!
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
[face punching]
[monkeys screeching]
[suspenseful music]
[perky music]
[head thuds]
[monkeys screeching]
- My diamonds.
No, no, no.
Oh, I can't understand it.
I had an empire in
the palm of my hands.
It just slipped
through my fingers.
I can't understand it.
[suspenseful music]
[men shouting]
[suspenseful dramatic music]
[gorilla growls]
[Stanley screaming]
[perky music]
[head thuds]
[monkeys screeching]
[gorilla growls]
- Whew!
[Stanley screams]
- I can't understand it.
My big buildings, my airplanes,
my railroads,
my yachts.
I should be on one of
my yachts right now.
Look, look at that raft.
A raft.
Can't understand it.
- Buzz!
Buzz!
Buzz, where are you going?
- I'm going home!
- But wait for me, take me-
- No, you don't!
I've had enough of you!
- Pull the raft over here
- Pull nothing over there!
- so I can get on!
- [Buzz] You're nothing
but a little jinx!
You've always been a jinx to me!
- I don't understand it.
- You don't understand?
I don't understand!
Go on, get yourself lost.
- Hey, Buzz!
I'm coming on that raft!
[crocodile growls]
So, long, Buzz!
[Stanley crying]
[solemn music]
Now, I'm all alone.
What's gonna happen to me now?
Buzz.
[slow gentle music]
[perky music]
Good morning, sir.
- [Man] Good morning,
Mr. Livington.
- Polish everyone
of the letters,
they're important, you know.
- Yes, sir.
- [Tallulah] Good
morning, Mr. Livington.
- Good morning, Tallulah.
Have you my paper?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
[Stanley humming]
- [Mercer] Morning,
Mr. Livington.
- Morning, Mr. Mercer.
How do we stand on
the gin rummy game?
- Oh, you owe me about $0.22.
- See you at 2:00.
- Yes, sir.
- Don't forget.
[door knocking]
- [Buzz] Can't understand it.
[dramatic music]
- Sunday driver.
- I'm sorry, sir.
Mr. Livington, what
about that raise
I've been asking you about?
- I'll talk to my
partner, if he's in.
- Thank you, sir.
[perky music]
[Stanley whistling]
[tense music]
- He's in!
[light dramatic music]
[upbeat music]