Gosh, but this story of mine
should be great.
I really don't know
how the people can wait. Ha, ha.
Hmm. I have to decide
who the actors will be.
I think I'll make the heroine me.
Ha-ha-ha.
Mm. The hero Aladdin
is handsome and smart.
Why, Popeye the sailor
is great for the part.
I ought to open up a chain store.
Make way for the princess.
Oh. Oh, oh, oh.
Whoa. I better unratchet myself here, huh?
Oh, a pretzel bender, huh?
Thy reign will soon be over
when my secret I unhide.
Then I shall be the ruler
and you shall be my bride.
Yeah.
Let me see. Where was I,
where was I? Yeah.
Ah.
Aladdin shall help me
this lamp to obtain.
Then Aladdin shall never be seen again.
Yes, yes, Aladdin,
the princess has chosen you...
...to procure for her the magic lamp.
Well, she made a good choice
and I'm just the fellow who can do it.
Why only you alone would be on such
a precarious mission, yes, yes, yes.
Say, you're out of "breathe."
You better lay down for a couple years.
Beneath that rock
is a dangerous passageway...
- Is that so?
- ...beyond which you will find...
...a golden lamp.
Bring that lamp back to me.
Bring that lamp back to you, huh?
Anything for the princess.
Mm.
I go for the princess.
Yes, yes, Aladdin. Go on, go on.
Yes. I go.
I'm gone. Ha-ha-ha.
Blow me down. It's perfect.
Boy, lamp the lad. That must be made
out of "sapph-fires," I guess, huh?
Oh, boy. I made good, I made good.
Ha-ha-ha!
Mm. Ah, the suspense is terrible.
I wish Aladdin would hurry
with that lamp.
Hey, mister. Mister, I got the lamp.
All for the princess.
The lamp. Ha-ha-ha.
For the princess.
POPEYE; Yeah, that's right,
for the princess. I got it right...
Oh!
The princess. Ha-ha-ha!
That was only a trick, my fool.
Only you and I know of this magic lamp...
...and soon you will forget. Ha, ha.
Ow!
It's mine. I have it. It's mine.
Ow! Ooh!
My lamp. The lamp.
The lamp. The lamp.
I want the lamp.
Ow! Oh!
Whoa. Hey, what happened? Where am I,
and how do I get out of this place?
That's what I wanna know, yep, yep.
This place looks kind of spooky to me.
Ouch! Ooh!
Ooh, that burns me up.
Ooh, I wish I was lightheaded
so I could see what I'm doing.
Well, here's my last match.
I hope I strike it lucky, that's all.
Oh.
- Whoa. Come on, put up your dukes.
- Oh, for goodness' sake.
Hey, who are you?
Where'd you come from?
Are you the janitor or something, huh?
I am the flame of the lamp.
I come from nowhere,
I go to the no place, and here I am.
You make a wish and I give it.
You want something?
Did you say "a wish"?
A wish, a wish. I can have a wish, huh?
Well, I wish I was out of here.
Can you show me
the entrance to the exit?
- Oh, certainly.
- Well, let's get out of here.
You said it.
Hey, take it easy. Quit your shoving.
Quit your pushing, young fellow.
I hope I know what you're doing.
Wow!
Oh, boy. Ha-ha-ha!
Oh, an escalator.
Women's and ladies' bargain basement
on the top floor.
Main entrance, all out.
Ha-ha-ha!
Boy, I'm glad to get out of
that hole all right. Ha-ha-ha!
Now if only I could find the... Uh? Ooh.
If you don't see what you want,
rub for it.
Hmm. That's a very good idea,
if I say so.
Think I'll try it.
Hey, you.
Oh, for goodness' sake.
You want something?
Yeah. What's all this magical stuff about?
Well, I told you. I could fulfill up
any wish or desire.
Hmm. There's something funny
about this phony. Gotta test him out.
I think I'll give him a tough one.
Okay, I wish I was a wealthy prince.
Ha-ha-ha.
You said it.
Hey, what's going on around here?
Oh, boy.
What can I do for you?
I'd do most anything you asked me to
I'd go and get that pot of gold
From the rainbow.
And bring it where you are.
And then I'd hitch your wagon to a star.
What can I do for you?
Say, how'd you like to have
Your dreams come true?
I'd like to make you happy
Through and through.
'Deed I do.
So what can I do for you?
Thank you, thank you, very much,
all of you. Ha-ha-ha!
Get us gone, Biscuit.
It's Aladdin. He's alive.
He has the magic lamp.
But he shan't have it long.
Oh, I hope the princess is home,
that's all. Ha-ha.
Oh. Well, I got the lamp here.
Oh, rub-a, rub-a, rub-a, rub-a-dub, eh?
- Hey.
- Oh.
At your service.
Bring me up a chest full of precious pearls
and diamonds and stuff...
...and take it to the princess.
To her?
You said it.
Hocus pocus.
Take that to the princess
with my complications, that's right.
Presents from Aladdin for the princess.
Salami, salami, bologna.
Oh.
Oh!
Oh, they're superb. Bliss. Oh!
Oh.
Mm.
That must be Prince Aladdin.
Oh, be still my fluttering heart.
Yoo-hoo! Hello.
Oh, boy, the princess.
Ha-ha-ha! To the rescue.
I got it.
In reverse.
Alley-up. Ha, ha!
Uh, I think you dropped something.
Oh, thank you, big, tall and handsome.
Well, I'm not so tall but...
I better get rid of this sticker. She'll
think I'm a little cut up or something, huh?
Curses.
Oh, uh, fair one, will thou...?
Er, uh... That is, wilst you...?
Yes, yes?
Oh, "yes, yes", huh?
Ooh, I am embarrassed.
I don't know what to say.
I never made love in Technicolor before.
I don't know...
Princess, wouldst it please thee...
- ...or, uh, wouldst it please thou...?
- Oh.
What are you, a thee or a thou, huh?
Fairest one, I was about to ea yest that...
- Yes, I'll marry you.
- Oh, oh, oh!
You will? Oh, she's gonna marry me.
Oh, she's wonderful.
I think she's making a big mistake
but I don't know... Oh!
I go to bring my friends to the wedding...
...but I shall return. Ha-ha-ha!
Oh, don't forget to come back.
Hi de ho, Silver...
...away!
Oh!
Oh, dear. What was that?
Who left that junk laying around here?
The lamp.
I have a plan.
Oh, attendants, attend me.
New lamps for old.
Oh, see if you can help that poor man.
Then send him away.
New lamps for old.
Oh.
Ha-ha-ha. It's mine.
Mm-hm. Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
- Prince Aladdin.
- Hooray.
Aladdin, Aladdin, Aladdin.
Yoo-hoo, princey.
- Yoo-hoo!
- Oh, you came back.
The man who came back, that's me.
Oh-ho.
Thank you. Thank you, very much.
Ah. No one here. Now is my chance.
Come, princess. You'll soon be mine.
- Bah!
- Oh!
You want something?
Go. I command you.
Carry this castle off
to a far and distant land.
You're crazy.
I'm crazy, huh?
Well, you'll do as I say.
I'll whip you within an inch
of your life.
I didn't say I wouldn't.
Then go.
Hey, get up and go. Oof!
What a letdown.
Hey, where's the castle?
Where...? Where's the princess?
Where's my clothes? They're lost.
It's a "lost-suit." Oh!
Now my princess, get inside there.
Aladdin's a faker.
Down with Aladdin.
It's black magic.
Get rid of him.
Whoa!
Unrelease me.
Oh, Popeye... I mean, Aladdin, save me!
I'm pent up in a penthouse.
- Aargh!
- Oh!
Aah! Curses.
Oh! Let me go.
Guards to destroy Aladdin.
Oh, yeah? Spinach to fix the guards.
Oh, hello, you two.
Unh! Take that.
Now for a vulture.
Oh, yeah?
Spinach to cook the vulture's goose.
Then a dragon.
Oh, Grandma,
what big teeth you've got.
You're not so hot yourself.
- Oh!
- Ha-ha-ha!
Where is that guy? Let me get
my hands on him. Wait till I get...
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Where is that fellow? He was here
a minute ago. I saw it with my own eyes.
- Aargh!
- Whoa! Hey, quit sticking me.
Ow! Ooh, it's like a brick wall
here or something. Huh?
Must be a magician or something.
I don't know...
- Ha-ha-ha!
- Whoa!
The tables have turned.
Oh, yeah? Take that. Oh, yeah?
Hey, there must be
an apparition somewhere.
Oh, yeah?
You missed.
Help, I'm a fish.
Give me a moment.
- There we are.
- Oh.
So long, sport.
So long.
So long, toots.
Oh, goodbye.
I said it.
Now, where was I?
Oh, let me think a minute now.
Oh, yes, I remember. Oh.
- Letter for you, Olive.
- Oh, at last.
The picture's finished. Oh.