Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes
Cut it out, Dolores!
Come on in, Mary. We're playing
Blind Man's Buff and you're it.
Wait a minute.
You've got to pay me first.
Always it's the woman who pays,
and pays, and pays.
You think that?
Hey, that's enough of this
come on, leave her alone.
- What's the matter with you.
- Give me a break,
Give you a break, I'll break your neck,
Hey, Kogan!
Pipe down them flaming youth...
or find yourself another flat!
This ain't no speakeasy!
I know it's the Biltmore, but who moved
it over here to 3rd Avenue?
She's funny that way.
Let's pipe down.
Come on, Mary, give me your coat.
Hello, Mary, how are you?
Hello, Mary, what took you so long?
Listen, I know a good quiet game,
if you boys won't dirty it up.
- Oh, no, we won't.
- Let's play Truth.
- What's Truth?
- It's a big moment for the boys.
They can ask you any question they like
and you have to tell the truth.
Whoopee, that's my game!
Ah, local boy gets a break.
I'm going to be dumb and not
learn how.
- Come on, Mary, you take a chance.
- Not me, I'm not here.
Oh, you...
It's gonna be good,
if you know what I mean.
Come on, now.
Well, who are you?
The name is Mary.
And who is Mary?
A working girl.
The kind that heaven protects?
Up to now.
Oh!
- In love?
- Sure.
Who with?
A man.
What's his name?
Even a census taker wouldn't ask
a question like that.
Guess that'll hold you for a couple.
Pass her by, handsome,
I'm a grass widow.
You can go as far as you like.
I'll go.
Pardon me.
The villain still persues her.
Say, that's a swell way to get
acquainted, that game.
Let's go a step further.
I'll buy your violets.
Who's the lucky man?
The one you're in love with.
He's a big paper man.
All wrapped up on your boss,
I know.
You should see my boss.
He's so old that short skirts
came in twenty years too late...
for him to appreciate legs.
Even yours?
- My turn now.
- Shoot.
Name, color, present condition
of servitude.
Ronald Wales, white, poor, honest.
Ambition? Not to have to work
for a living.
So I can go to the south
of France and write a book.
What do you do for a living besides
kissing strange girls in hallways?
I work in a broker's office.
- In love?
- I am not.
Married then.
I don't believe in marriage.
That's not a new line.
Well, now it's my turn.
Did you like my kissing you?
We're playing truth, you know.
Yes.
And yet you say you're in love
with another man.
A man who calls you Miss Landy
when your name is Linden...
obviously isn't on kissing terms.
And I'm human, believe it or not.
I believe it so completely that I'm going
to stake you to another little kiss.
Do I have to?
You do.
Well! Far be it from me, dearie,
but Freddie has established illegal
relations with the drugstore...
and the gin awaits without.
Without us.
He can finish telling you the story
of his life in the kitchen.
I'd be just as safe right here
in the bedroom.
Yes, but with you two in the kitchen,
a girl can powder her nose.
Come on.
Good night, Ronnie.
You must come to the races
with us again sometime.
I'd love to.
- Good Night, Miss uh... Landy.
- Linden, you fool, her name is Linden.
I know, but Mary likes men who
forget her name.
Good night, Dolores.
Good night, Mary.
Oh, scurry.
You certainly fell for Ronnie like the
breaking up of a hard winter.
In the first place, I didn't.
In the second place, what's it matter
when he's just a handsome young Romeo...
with literary ambitions that make him
of practically no use to a girl?
Say that again.
He's just a poor, harmless,
charming young idiot...
who thinks that marriage would ruin
him as an author.
Ronnie Wales is worth
two million dollars.
- What?
- Nice, isn't it?
But call your shots, Mary.
I hear his wife's nice too.
His wife?
I hear the kids are grand.
Twins. Boys.
What a man.
Well, what a sap I've been.
But why would he want to give me
a song and dance like that?
Oh, some say their wives
are in to it.
Some say their wives don't
understand them
And some just say they're
not married.
Ritter and Company.
Just a minute, please.
Oh, Mary. I forgot to send that wire
to the Wisconsin Mills.
- I'll send it after lunch.
- Oh, that's fine.
Say, you know I forgot all about
that sales meeting tomorrow?
The sales department has been notified.
Ritter and Company.
Just a minute, please.
Dolores, you never forget
anything, do you?
- You do, though.
- What now, Mary?
Oh, my medicine. Well, I forgot
that purposefully.
- You take it when you get home.
- Yeah, yeah, all right.
Good night, Mr. Ritter.
You can go on, Dolores. I'll straighten
out the board.
- I have to stay a few minutes anyway.
- Thanks, Mary.
- Good night, Dolores.
- Good night.
There's only one trunk busy.
That sheik in the sales department's trying
to talk another blond out on a date.
Ritter and Company.
Listen, Ed. She's got one of the swellest
figures you ever looked at.
I don't care anything about
her swell figure.
All I want to know is has she
got a friend.
Do you pack a gun, girlie?
Oh, Mr. Duneen.
- Well, well, well, it's Miss, uh...
- Linden.
Sure, Linden.
Would you mind waiting a few moments
in the sales department?
Always glad to oblige.
Well, how are the old man's arteries?
And when's the old duck going to pass
out to give us young fellows a chance?
Mr. Ritter's going to be on hand longer
than some of the rest of us perhaps.
There's a dirty crack in that somewheres
but Duneen passes it by.
The name is Mary, isn't it?
Why don't we get the Crown
Publishing Company's account?
Office hours are from nine
to five thirty.
Did you ever try wearing your hair
a little fluffier?
How close have you come to getting
together with the Crown people?
Say, listen, if I can't sell them,
they can't be sold.
Run your handsome blues eyes
down that.
Hmm, this seems to be a confidential
memorandum...
of the Crown's yearly requirements.
They'll take that order at 3,5%
off list.
Yeah? Then I'll buy $20 gold pieces
for 19 bucks.
Mr. Ritter is going to offer the Crown
people 3,5% off for that order tomorrow.
Say, listen...
Ritter wouldn't offer 3,5% off a...
You know, that's a remarkable
coincidence.
That's my idea exactly.
In fact, I was going to sell him
the model in this combination...
first thing in the morning and send it
forward to prove it.
Then I've just been wasting
your time.
Not at all, girlie, not at all.
You meant well. I was just ahead
of you, that's all.
Mr. Bronson lives at 478, Park Avenue.
He left his office about ten minutes ago.
You can catch him if you go right after him.
Consider that Duneen is on his way.
But why the night work, girlie?
Well, Mr. Ritter not being in
your confidence...
is going to personally telephone Mr. Bronson
that discount at 8:30 a.m.
And you won't get credit for the order.
Hey!
Let me know when I can do you
a favor sometime.
- You can do me one right now.
- Name it, girlie.
Try and remember that my name
is Linden.
Of course it's Linden.
Hey, plug me in on the switchboard,
will you?
I want to break a blonde's heart.
You big businessmen are so brutal.
I know I shouldn't have listened,
but at the same time...
little girls shouldn't give away
confidential tips to cheap salesmen.
Why not give an ambitious
youngster a break?
Jim Duneen is no good.
Hold your job long enough and you'll see
Jim Duneen as head of this company.
Out of this city of 6 million people,
why do you have to pick him?
You weren't here when I first started
two years ago.
It was my first job.
I was scared to death.
I would have run away if it hadn't
been for Jim Duneen.
What did he do? Offer to show you
the pictures in his flat?
He found me crying in the hall.
Kidded me along.
Told me to keep up a bluff.
Everybody in the world was bluffing.
Well, he don't look like no
big brother to me.
So I just tried to pay him back
for how he helped me.
You're goofy about him.
Maybe.
He don't even know you wear
silk stockings.
I'm protecting my job too.
Someday Jim will be the boss here.
Good night, chummy.
Ronnie called you five times today.
Did he?
When a girl gets a sweet opening like Ronnie
she ought to cut herself a piece of cake.
How do you go about that
sort of thing?
Call him up and tell him you've picked
out a swell apartment?
You don't do anything,
you just drift... smilingly.
I'm no drifter. I swim.
Upstream, if necessary.
You darn fool.
Well, John, you need to take
a trip to Europe now...
or in about a year from now
you'll take a ride in a hearse.
- Why... as bad as that?
- Hm-hmm.
Yes?
Just a minute.
- Mr. Robinson.
- Tell him to come in, Mary.
Look here, John, you can't see
anybody else today.
Oh, this is my banker.
He won't get me excited.
Well, all right. Now, remember,
you give up business immediately.
Yes, yes...
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, doctor.
- Well!
- Hello, Ritter, how are you?
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
Well, they tell me you haven't been
downtown for a whole week.
No.
The doctor tells me I've got to retire.
- I'm terribly sorry.
- Sell out my business.
- Go away for a long rest.
- I'm very sorry indeed.
Well, find someone to buy the business.
Well, that's not so easy.
Times are hard.
I read about a man who retired and sold
his business to his employees.
That's a modern method.
Our banks might finance a deal like that
if we were sold on the setup.
And you could keep your name on the
firm where it's been for 40 years.
Well, who's the man to head it?
Well, er... Spaulding, your Chicago man.
Yes, or Gault. He's done very well
with the timber and the mills.
Well, there's that new salesman Jim,
Mr. Duneen.
Oh, he's too young, too fresh.
Young blood's not a bad idea
in an old business.
Right you are.
Oh, well, suit yourself.
If it's the lady, show her in.
You certainly were anxious.
The great Duneen isn't dressed yet.
But come on in, honey.
Well, well, well, if it isn't little old
Mary Linden herself.
I thought it was two other fellows
from Detroit.
- Two other fellows named honey.
- Sure, the famous Honey twins.
Make yourself at home.
Duneen'll grab himself a shirt.
Okay.
Well, it's a pleasure, girlie,
it's a pleasure.
- Like it?
- Yes, it's all right.
How do you like my new apartment?
I suppose it's much smarter
than your old one.
Sure! New contract, new salary,
new flat.
Quite a progression, no?
I think it's pretty swell myself.
Stunning.
Oh, I forgot. You're the prudish type,
who likes women old-fashioned.
You're pretty regular at that.
- I think you're swell.
- You don't know me.
You only know my job.
I smoke sometimes and...
wear an evening dress with
absolutely no back to it.
No!
And have been known to drink
a cocktail, that is, when urged.
I urge you! I beseech you!
Well, rather than have my clothes
torn in a struggle, I will.
That drink doesn't have orange
juice in it?
- I'm sorry, it has.
- No, thanks.
Well, I'm glad to know you, Mrs. Ritz.
And the next time you come we'll have
that sauerkraut you crave.
All kidding aside.
Why don't you and I get
together sometime, huh?
Lets... sometime.
Well, knowing that you don't
love me for my body alone,
I suppose you've come to make me
president of the company, huh?
Well, maybe vice-president.
Mr. Ritter's got to retire.
He can't fire me.
I've got a contract.
Ironclad, airtight and tied up
with pink string.
Robinson of the City Trust could be
sold on the proposition...
to buy Ritter's stock for you
and pay for it out of the profits.
No, it isn't hashish.
Listen to me, Jim Duneen, I know
what I'm talking about.
Robinson wants to keep the
firm in business.
- I know...
- Oh, don't worry,
he'd make something out of
the deal himself.
You have a fine record. Robinson's wide
open for young blood.
I'm not having any pipe dream...
if you've got the stuff to sell
a proposition to Robinson.
I suppose you think I haven't, huh?
What did you think I came here for?
Find out if there's more than one
cough in a carload?
Give me the low down.
Now, here's the way I'd approach him.
Mr. Robinson, you're a businessman.
I'm a businessman.
I feel sure that I can double the firm's
business in the next three years.
Naturally, my efforts would be increased
if I were working for myself.
My plan guarantees... the continuance...
of the relations and profits
you have made with us.
It is not only a bank's privilege
but its duty...
to foster the development of the
concerns with whom its past...
present and future is allied.
That's the speech that will get Robinson.
Mr. Robinson...
you're a businessman...
I'm a businessman.
I feel sure that I can double
the firm's business in the next...
- Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
- Hey, what's the idea?
Oh, here... blot it off.
I'll see if I can find you another one.
Fifteen bucks for that shirt, woman!
That's a fine th...
Here, wear this one.
Say, I aint going to a funeral!
Wouldn't you think a spot of color'd
sort of brighten up the spirits...
and show off the Duneen personality?
Bankers are very conservative.
Well, maybe you're right.
Well, I guess I'll be going now.
Oh, I haven't thanked you yet.
You're just a swell kid.
But then, I'm the only one that could
carry out the scheme.
You'd better change your shirt.
Remember you've got to be there at 9:15.
I'll be on time, don't worry.
And thanks again.
Oh, uh... Mr. Robinson's address
is on this slip of paper.
Leave it on the table.
I'll put my own number here too.
Will you call me up as soon as you
leave Mr. Robinson's...
and tell me how it came out?
From the nearest drugstore, baby.
Hello? Who is this?
- Mr. Duneen.
- Mr. Duneen?
Oh, come right up.
Come on in, I'll be right out.
I can hardly wait to hear
the good news.
Oh, I thought it was someone else.
I intended you to.
Why did you say you were Mr. Duneen?
What do you know about Mr. Duneen?
Oh, he's the one that calls you Landy
when your name is Linden.
How did you find out where I live?
Oh, Dolores.
If Muhammad won't come
to the mountain,
then the mountain must come
to Muhammad.
But this is the first time the mountain
had to wear a false beard.
Do sit down.
Oh, thanks.
And I was just going to bed.
For Mr. Wales she is just going to bed.
For Mr. Duneen, oh, come right up,
come right up!
I don't care to discuss Mr. Duneen.
But I want to talk about Mr. Duneen.
I want to talk about you
and I want to talk about me.
Oh, I know all about you.
Ronnie Wales, poor, white, honest.
Ambition?
Not to have to work for a living,
so that I could go to the south
of France and write a book.
And I don't believe in marriage.
But I am married, you know that.
Well, we haven't lived together
for three years...
As a matter of fact, I haven't
seen her for two.
Where's your cane and your tin mug...
and a little dog to lead you?
And how are lead pencils selling
these days?
Hello? Yes?
Hello, Mary.
I put it over.
Knocked them for a loop.
And listen!
I'm to be vice-president.
Oh, I'm so glad for you, Mr. Duneen.
The bank retains 20%.
The balance for me.
And dividends credited on purchase.
I'm gonna have ten years
to pay it off.
But I'll knock that for a row of ash cans.
Hey, shut off that music!
All right, darling, don't yell at me.
Nice drugstore you're calling from.
Well I, uh... I'm home.
Some people dropped in.
Then don't let me keep you.
I'm entertaining myself.
Go away, darling, how can I talk
business with you mauling me so?
Oh, but darling, I can't keep
my hands off you.
Excuse me!
I'll see you at the office tomorrow.
Can I play some jazz now?
No, I got business to attend to.
Finish your drink and I'll call you a cab.
All right.
- Next time.
- Don't make me laugh.
- Good night, Mary.
- Good night.
- Good morning, Dolores.
- Good morning, Mr. Duneen.
- Good morning, Mary.
- Good morning.
Bring your notebook.
Take a cable to Ericsson.
I have gone to great lengths...
to convince you...
that it would be unwise to open
an agency in this country.
The usual signature.
How does that sound?
Why don't you say something
about our overhead being...
so distributed that it cuts
down costs?
Oh... yeah, put that in.
Make it short, you know.
Anything else?
Uh, let me see.
Excuse me.
Went to a party at Mr. Robinson's
last night. Late.
Uh, by the way, his daughter's name
is Helen, isn't it?
Ellen, I believe.
Oh.
Don't you think we ought to make one
more try for Rainmaker's business?
I closed it last time
at Mr. Robinson's house.
For five years, at 2.39.
- Oh, Jim, that's splendid.
- Not bad, what?
It's more than splendid, it's the biggest
thing you've done.
I'm proud of you.
Hm... yeah.
I'd be proud of myself if I didn't
have this awful head.
It took a lot of champagne
to warm up old Rainmaker.
As my old man used to say,
a hair from the dog that bit you.
Gee...
What a tough time my folks had.
I wish I had my luck while
they were still living.
Were you very poor when
you were a kid?
The greatest tragedy of my life
was graduating from highschool...
with a patch on the seat
of my trousers
And all the other squirts in tuxedos.
You've done remarkably.
From a handicapped start.
Thanks, Mary.
That's nice of you to say that.
Yes?
Just a minute.
It's a Miss Daisy Presby, says she
has an appointment.
Shall I get rid of her?
Uh, no...
No, wait a minute.
Have Miss Presby wait.
I've, uh... I've hired an
assistant for you.
You've been working too many nights.
This girl can take some
of the dictation.
But I haven't complained.
I don't want you to wear
yourself out, you know.
I thought it was my job to engage
the new girls.
This is, uh, this is different.
I see.
Jim, I'd rather not have
an assistant.
I can attend to everything.
I'm not a bit overworked.
I know, but I've hired the girl.
She's to start in the morning.
I'm afraid I must decide on the
adviseability of these things.
Very well.
Well, what else?
By the way, uh,
I was right about tails and white tie
for the Robinsons' dinner, wasn't I?
If there's one thing I flatter myself on,
it's knowing how to dress.
Of course.
I can't understand why this florist bill
should be $100 higher than last month's.
We haven't ordered more than usual.
I'll check it over.
By the way, send a dozen American
Beauty roses do Miss Ellen Robinson.
Very well.
Oh, by the way, how much does
Miss Daisy Presby go in the payroll for?
Uh, put her down for fifty a week.
And see that no one disturbs me.
This is James Duneen's secretary
speaking.
I want you to send two dozen of your
nicest roses to Miss Ellen Robinson.
Yes. Hold the phone a moment,
I'll give you her address.
What?
Oh, you have her address.
Yes, it's the same Miss Robinson.
All right, thank you.
Miss Presby?
Hm-hmm.
Fill out this card, please.
You'll start in the morning.
You'll have the small desk
over there.
Oh, darn these chairs!
There goes my stocking.
Six bucks a pair.
Oh, I picked up a swell combination
at Wimball's,
I'm saving it for my hope chest.
Look.
I ask you.
Isn't that the sin you love to touch?
Lovely.
But they robbed you.
I got the same thing for fourteen.
Oh, don't tell me you wear French
lingerie beneath that flower sack.
What I wear next to my lily-white body...
is, strange as it may seem,
nobody's business.
Soft goes Dempsey and, shock,
he takes it on the chin.
Well, I think I'll just pop in
and say hello to Jim.
Just a minute.
He doesn't wish to be disturbed.
You can't go in when the red
light's burning.
Listen, sugar, I go past all red lights
without even slowing down.
- How do you do, Prentiss?
- Miss Linden.
- Is Mr. Duneen ready for me?
- Expecting you.
Oh, by the way,
hereafter I don't want Mr. Duneen bothered
with any of the household details.
- I'll do the buying myself.
- Yes, Miss Linden.
Fresh flowers in there, please, Prentiss.
Yes, Miss Linden.
- Good morning, Martin.
- Good morning, Miss Linden.
Come.
Good morning.
How do you feel?
Terrible.
And that Cliden business has got
to be settled today.
I got another inside tip.
- Here's the mail for you.
- Oh...
- Anything else, Mr. Duneen?
- That's all, thanks, Martin.
I know that a price of 2.32
was discussed.
If we get the order, Mary...
you'll get a swell new fitted bag.
I'd rather have a raise.
You're jealous because Miss Presby
got one?
Hardly. It's not the same situation.
You're different.
For your sorrow?
She's just a diversion.
She got her salary raised.
I'll say she's diverting.
You hate her, don't you?
Certainly not. But she ruins
the morale of the office.
And from the things she says you'd think
she was one of the board of directors.
You'll get a swell fitted bag
nevertheless.
You look tired, Mary.
Why don't you take a day off?
As a matter of fact, I have an invitation
to spend the weekend at Atlantic City.
Fine, take the weekend off.
You think Daisy can do my work too?
She's a little inexperienced, but...
yeah, I think she can.
I don't think so.
I can postpone my Atlantic City trip.
It's a standing invitation.
Hope you feel better.
Thanks, Mary.
Boo!
Don't do that.
I thought the Black Killer of Basehorder
had got me.
- Theater, eh?
- Started with the theater.
- Ended up by driving on the Post Road.
- Oh, sounds romantic.
- Who is he?
- Jim Duneen.
- How long has this been going on?
- It hasn't gone on.
I've been out with him
once or twice.
- And he sends me flowers.
- Well,
You've a lot in common.
His neckties, for instance.
That's not fair. He's improved
unbelievably.
- He's a very remarkable young man.
- Oh!
Like him pretty much?
Pretty much.
Then in the morning you'll
see a doctor.
Oh, don't be silly!
I'm all right.
No, you're not.
No girl's healthy who prefers a good,
sound businessman to a dancing fool.
But when I really start fiddling,
even Jim Duneen will dance.
Now don't you look forward to an existence
of all afternoon at the horse show...
and all evening at contract with him.
- He's not the type.
- No?
- Just wait till I get him in my clutches.
- Oh.
I'm afraid there's another
woman in his life.
What?
Lip rouge on his handkerchief.
They never learn, do they?
Positively no nonsense.
Unless a contract is lived up to,
it is not a contract.
There is no reason why we cannot
cooperate...
on an issue involving so much
of our mutual welfare.
Yours truly.
Well, what's the matter?
The letter's too strong, Jim.
You've got to be tough with Bueller.
Write it as I dictated it.
Very well.
Well, now what have you got for me?
Oh, Martin says you need shirts.
Any particular choice of color?
Do I ever wear anything
but white shirts?
Who do you think I am,
a shipping clerk?
I beg your pardon.
Oh, Mary, uh...
Martin ordered sort of an
evening tie for me last night.
Narrow, very smart.
Tell him to order a dozen more.
I bought it for you.
Oh, and Mary, uh...
Chase another Bueller.
Tone it down.
That part about positively no nonsense.
Leave that out entirely.
And Mary...
I don't want Miss Presby to take
any more of my dictation.
What's the matter? Is she beginning
to get breach of promising?
Yeah?
- The Burden brothers are here.
- The Burden brothers?
Oh, I have to take them out tonight
and make whoopee with them.
Do you want to come along?
Do you think it's decent of me to take
the place of the dear departed so soon?
Huh?
Are you sure you wouldn't rather
have Miss Presby?
I asked you, didn't I?
I'd love to go.
Shall I show the Burdens in?
Yeah, show 'em in.
And then Father lost money.
Of course the managers were very glad to
have a society girl to go on the stage.
But sometimes I feel it's very degrading
for a girl from an old Virginia family.
And you had to give up that big,
white, colonial mansion.
Oh no, Mama lives there.
I send her part of my salary
every week.
Of course that doesn't leave me
very much for myself.
There, there, Sybil.
Oh, Mr. Burden, but I only just
met you tonight.
Oh well, let's have another drink
and then you'll know me better.
This little girl Sybil has had
a heap of trouble, Jim.
I think she needs something
to brace her up.
Trouble? Trouble?
Oh, I remember that word.
That's what poor people have
when their rent's due.
That's a good joke.
Trouble's only something poor people
have when the rent's due.
Oh, Mr. Burden.
are you really going to pay my rent?
Oh, Mr. Duneen, who's going
to pay my rent?
What did you do?
Blow the rent on that frock?
- What's the matter with this frock?
- Absolutely nothing.
Looks as if you'd been poured in it
and forgot to say when.
I suppose you'd like me to wear this
around the paper and pulp business.
Well, you don't have to dress
the way you do.
- The other girls don't.
- Oh, you notice that, do you?
They make us notice it.
But they can't all crave me.
No, but they can all crave
raises in salaries.
- How much do you get?
- Seventy.
You should have more.
That's sweet.
- Do you dance?
- Even better than I take dictation.
Let's go!
I never knew you had a place
like this, Mary.
- Won't you come in a minute?
- I'd love to.
- Come here.
- Oh...
- Sit down, won't you?
- Thanks.
You know, it's funny, I never figured
out what your private life must be.
I just thought of you as a perfect
machine in an office.
I gathered that.
Mary.
You know, Mary,
I'm very happy that you and I
got together tonight the way we did.
Are you?
I'm terribly fond of you.
Well, how could I help it?
Eight, ten, twelve hours
a day together.
Mostly behind closed doors.
Proving that a working girl can be safe
from the advances of her employer.
Well, I always figured that business
and pleasure don't mix.
That's not it.
You've looked at me a thousand times...
and never saw me until tonight.
I see you now.
And you look pretty good to me.
I wonder if it isn't the dress.
Or perhaps the liquor.
Have another drink?
Oh, would you have liked it
if I'd kissed you in the office...
when you first came to work for me?
A kiss depends upon who's doing it...
and how it's done.
How's this?
You don't need that drink.
I know all you've done for me.
I wouldn't be where I am today
if it weren't for you.
I've been blinded by my own success.
But from now on things are going
to be different.
It's late...
Jimmy, I've got to be a machine again.
It's past three o'clock.
One of us has to be on hand at ten
in the morning. Wyler will be there.
Hang Wyler.
Hang all the pulp and paper
in the world.
Jimmy.
Jimmy...
All right.
Give me a drink and I'll run along.
You're drinking a lot lately.
- It's foolish.
- Let me be foolish tonight.
It's a night of nights, isn't it?
- Pour it?
- Uh... straight.
Thanks, dear.
Well, here's how.
Good night, Mary.
Good night, Jim.
- Yes?
- Bring your notebook.
All right.
Good morning, Jim.
Oh, good morning.
Take a letter to Berman.
Dear Jake,
I cannot understand...
the change in your attitude.
I guess I had a little too much
to drink last night, didn't I?
Did you?
Didn't you notice it?
- No.
- That's good.
I was afraid I might have...
Well, I mean...
Did I get fresh, or make a pass at you,
or anything like that?
Why, no.
That's a relief.
You know, Mary,
I don't remember a darn thing that happened
after about ten o'clock last night.
I cannot understand the change
in your attitude.
Huh?
You were dictating.
Oh, yes, yes...
I cannot understand the change
in your attitude.
in your attitude...
As the weeks roll by...
- Good evening, Miss Linden.
- Good evening, Prentiss.
- Did the flowers come?
- Ready and waiting, miss.
Oh, there they are.
Aren't they lovely.
I'll start with these, Prentiss.
- With those?
- Yes.
Were the monthly bills all right?
Yes, they were nicely checked
and everything's under control.
- Is Mr. Duneen home?
- Not since this morning.
He hasn't been at the office
all day either.
Well, that's understandable.
I hope you don't mind my stepping into
your province fixing these flowers.
Not at all, Miss Linden.
Who's the party for?
Prentiss, I asked who's the party for.
I thought perhaps you'd like
to arrange these also.
Why, what's there?
You finish the flowers, Prentiss.
Yes, Miss Linden.
Hello, Mary.
That lunk Freddie stood me up
so I came over here.
These men are swine, though.
What's the matter?
What are you crying for?
Society girl wins big paper man.
What?
Robinson hooked Jim.
Well, cut my throat.
Wait a minute.
Here, Mary, take a drink of this.
Time for the speeches.
A toast to the bride.
Long may she wave.
Gee, I'd try to help you, Mary, but...
I guess it's better to get it
out of your system.
If it hadn't been for me.
I know.
Oh, don't let anybody in.
I don't care who it is.
Hello...
- What's the matter, Mary?
- Oh, nothing.
Come on, now, tell Ronnie everything.
All right.
I'll tell you.
I haven't got any pride left.
The engagement is announced.
of Miss Ellen Robinson to Mr. James Duneen.
I'm thoroughly licked, Ronnie.
I made him look like a gentleman.
I've taught him to speak
the king's English.
I've shared his troubles and worries.
I've lifted him above the Presbys.
I've stood between him and a dozen
cheap designing women.
But when it comes to a girl with beauty,
and money, and a glamorous position,
I can't do a thing.
A girl of his own class.
The class I gave him.
Now, now, Mary, take it easy.
It isn't that bad.
Take it easy, come on,
come on.
Oh, all right, let's have a drink.
Please don't, Mary.
That isn't going to help you.
Well, Ronnie, the next time...
The next time...
Do you get me?
We won't talk about that now.
Oh, so you're going to spurn
me too, are you?
After a while, we'll talk about that.
Yes?
Oh, send her in.
Miss Ellen Robinson to see you.
Yes, I will.
I'm Ellen Robinson.
Yes, I know.
- You came to see Mr. Duneen?
- No. You.
Oh.
Won't you sit down.
Thank you.
Miss Linden,
when I first decided I wanted
to marry Jim Duneen...
My father and I naturally
talked it over.
I'm sure your father approved.
My father has known you
for a long time.
Only in a business way.
So that's how I happened to know
you're in love with Jim Duneen.
That's not true!
That proves it.
Could I work alongside of Jim Duneen for
years without falling in love with him?
Certainly not.
Get to the point.
Your admission that you're
in love with him,
hardly qualifies you, from
a fiancée's viewpoint,
for further employment.
You want me to quit?
- At once.
- And if I refuse?
I shall tell him you're desperately
in love with him...
and that it would be charitable
to ask you to leave.
You wouldn't do that.
Oh, wouldn't I?
When Greek meets Greek!
What do you mean calling
me a Greek?
Pardon my intrusion.
Well, what do you want?
Mr. Duneen, I think I've been
here long enough.
Why, Mary, what are you
talking about?
I've got a better job. Shorter hours,
more money.
Now, Mary, don't do anything foolish.
- We'll talk this over later.
- There's nothing to talk over.
I've had it in mind for some time.
It was just settled today.
I'm leaving immediately.
It won't inconvenience you any.
Remember you still have Daisy.
Goodbye.
Mary!
Jim!
What are you doing?
Gonna quit?
Get out of here!
I want to be alone.
What's this Presby tells me?
You've quit?
You know what I've done for
Jim Duneen, don't you?
- Sure, but Mary...
- You know that because I've loved him...
I've played straight as a string.
But you've know for some
time that he...
You know that I've met a dozen men.
Nice men, that wanted me.
And what did I tell them?
Like a fool, I'd say, no, no, no,
you can't have Mary Linden.
She's a good girl.
And what did I say to myself?
Like a fool, I said, Mary, you just
keep yourself a nice, fine little girl...
and one of these days Jim Duneen will
realize how good and worthy you are.
Baloney!
But I thought that was all over.
Last night Ronnie told me...
Yes, there's Ronnie.
And I like Ronnie.
And we've had a lot of good
times together.
But when Ronnie offered me everything
in the world a girl could wish for,
what do I do?
I turn him down!
Like the nice, fat-headed, virtuous
little moron that I am.
Well, that's all over, my fine girl.
Mary, quiet! Somebody will hear you.
Let them hear me!
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to Atlantic City!
I'll see you later.
I can't make the grade, Ronnie.
Aren't you just asking for a lot
of trouble and unhappiness?
Can't you put him out of your mind?
He's out of my life.
I'm reconciled with that.
But see this.
A price tag off my nightgown.
I found one of these on the floor
of Jim's bedroom once.
I knew the girl and I despised her
for being cheap and trivial.
I just don't want to be
that cheap myself.
The funny part about it is...
that I am priced at exactly $8 less...
than one of the most obvious
young women I have ever met.
Mary, dear,
if my wife didn't have all the
money in the family,
I swear I'd get a divorce
and marry you.
I didn't ask you to buy my violets.
No.
No!
Well now, Miss Robinson, the Chicago train
arrived a half hour ago...
and I'm sure he'll come direct
to the office.
I'll tell him.
- Did you have a nice trip?
- Horrible!
Leave me alone.
I can still take off my own coat.
Out of the last fourteen nights
I spent nine of them in pullmans.
Well, how are things running?
Oh, everything's perfect.
Did that order go out I wired
on Saturday?
Oh, well, no.
Well, why wasn't it shipped?
It wasn't marked rush.
The other orders I wired,
have any of them been sent?
No, I thought I'd better hold them
till you got back.
Go out and get all that stuff
and get it off right away.
Oh, I can't.
You can't?
Why not?
Well, I put them all in a folder
and took them up to your house.
Telephone my house and have my Martin my
valet bring the folder down here right away.
Well, I'm afraid they got lost
last night in the confusion.
Confusion? What confusion?
In the fire.
Fire? What fire?
The fire in your library.
Fire in my library?
And in your bedroom too.
But some of your clothes
can be salvaged.
What are you talking about?
Well, Martin thinks he can fix
some of your clothes...
as soon as he gets out of the hospital.
Hospital?
How did this fire start?
Well, the firemen were very nasty.
They said it started from my cigarette.
Your cigarette? What were you doing
smoking in my house?
Oh, I just sat down to smoke
a cigarette...
And don't you believe it, Jim,
I didn't fall asleep.
I was just thinking with
my eyes closed.
Are you sure you told me everything?
Think carefully, now.
Has the firm gone into bankruptcy?
Or is my fiancée dead?
Oh no, Miss Robinson's not dead.
She's been calling you for the last week
wondering why she hasn't heard from you.
Get her on the phone.
Now, isn't that a coincidence?
Speak of the devil and here she is.
Get out!
- Hello, darling.
- Well!
What's the matter?
You look a bit wild-eyed.
Nothing, nothing at all, dear.
You must have been busy.
I had no letters from you.
Only three little telegrams.
And not a word for the past five days.
Look, Helen, for the past fourteen days
I've been leaping in and out of pullmans...
and living in lumber camps.
I simply didn't have the time.
Well, I'm glad you don't have
to travel often.
I don't fancy myself as a neglected wife.
I've got to do a lot of travelling.
The paper business is in a critical state.
Newspapers are buying up
their own mills.
Syndicates are being formed.
By next year I'm gonna be a leaping
tuna all over these United States.
But you don't have to do all
the dirty work.
But I do. Nobody else can
do it as well.
I'm not blowing my own horn,
it's simply the truth.
So you might as well face it.
It's much better to say things
in advance.
Isn't it?
Yes, dear.
Now, dear, please run along.
I'm up to my neck in trouble.
Why I ever let Mary Linden
get away from me, I...
I ought to have my head examined,
that's all.
If I could find her now, I'd give her
half the company to come back.
- I think not!
- Huh?
Do you think I want a woman around here
who's madly in love with you?
Mary? In love with me?
Rot!
You did a lot of night work
together, you two.
Say, listen, darling,
you're a little mad.
I'm no saint. I have my moments.
But Mary Linden simply isn't
that kind of a girl, that's all.
Jim!
There's a cop out here and he wants
to arrest me.
The arson squad wants her at
headquarters for a statement...
about the connection between her cigarette
and the fire in your home last night.
I have no suspicions of you, Daisy.
Run along.
You see, nobody has any
suspicion of me.
Come on.
Oh, no.
Nobody has any suspicions of you.
I'm disgusted.
And humiliated.
All the time it's been that
cheap little tart...
and I thought it was Mary Linden.
Did you do anything to get
Mary Linden to leave here?
- Certainly.
- Well how dare you...
interfere in my business affairs!
Business? That's good, a woman
like Mary Linden.
With Mary Linden as a woman, you may
have had a feminine right to be involved.
But with Mary Linden, my private secretary,
you had absolutely no right to interfere.
- I believe you're in love with her.
- Listen,
I fall madly in love with any woman
who displays a least bit of common sense.
And now you must forgive me
if I'm rude, but I'm terribly busy.
- Too busy, I'm afraid.
- Well, I suppose we'll let it go at that.
Get me Mary Linden's apartment
on the wire.
Why, Mr. Duneen, Mary Linden
has moved.
I'm sorry, I haven't the slightest idea
where to reach her.
Hello? Who is it?
It's Dolores. Are you awake?
Yes, I'm awake, you idiot.
Come on up.
- Hi! How's tricks?
- No tricks by me.
What gets you up so early?
Oh, Freddie got jealous last night
and broke all my Rudy Vallee records.
So I threw him out and went
to bed early.
Got a job yet?
Nope.
Well, ain't it about time
you went to work?
No hurry. I don't care if I don't
work for months yet.
Jim Duneen tried to get in touch
with you last week.
He did?
What did you tell him?
Exactly what you told me to.
I wonder what he wanted.
How should I know?
Say, did I tell you Daisy got canned?
- No!
- Uh-huh.
No... nothing there.
The marines have landed and the situation
is well in hand.
Well listen to this.
The forthcoming marriage of
Miss Ellen Robinson...
to Mr. James Duneen has been
called off by mutual consent.
Where, Dolores, let me see, where?
Oh, it isn't in the paper. But it's liable
to be any minute now.
Or I've been listening in over that
switchboard in vain.
- Dolores!
- Mary!
Ain't that great?
Mr. Duneen, are we going to work
again tonight?
These late hours are just ruining
my boyfriend's evenings.
Yes, tonight and every night until
I find a secretary who's satisfactory.
Have you got the answers to those
want ads?
- Yes, here they are.
- Hm.
Hm, this sounds possible.
For three years secretary to the president
of a pulp and paper concern.
Best of references.
Have this Miss Helen Clark come
to come see me this afternoon.
Yes, sir.
- Yeah?
- Helen Clark, by appointment.
Send her in.
Mr. Duneen?
I'm Helen Clark.
Oh, yes, Miss Clark.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you.
I, uh...
I see you've had office experience.
Yes, I left my last employer
because he got engaged.
Mary Linden, take off those clothes
and be yourself!
Oh, Mr. Duneen, do you always.
ask girls to disrobe in your office?
I didn't mean that, you know I didn't.
I mean, take off your coat,
we've got work to do.
But I get $100 a week now.
All right, Mary, of course $100
is all right. Stop joking.
I've got just three days to get
affairs in shape...
so I can beat it up north
and cover next year's supply.
Well... what are you standing
there like that for?
Oh, Mary, please. I need you.
Don't turn me down now.
Grab a notebook and get to work.
Corbin. Don't ring me
no matter who it is.
And you stay at that switchboard ready
to take any calls that come in...
till I tell you you can go.
I'm going to do a day's work.
Come on, Jim.
Take a letter to the Stockholm crowd.
Uh... After due consideration...
of your proposition,
I have decided to...
Ritter and Company.
Oh, Freddie.
I've been waiting for hours for that
big stiff to let me go home...
and he's still dictating.
Shut up, Freddie.
Freddie, will you please shut up!
Shut up till I get my heart
beating properly.
Why do you think?
He ain't dictating.
He's through dictating.
He's gone over to Jersey City
to marry Mary Linden.
Oh, ain't that grand?
Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes