John, let's go to bed.
I want to take the boat out alone.
- I'll be up later.
- No, I'll go with you.
John...
That will is no good.
Your mother's still alive.
We can talk her into changing it.
You were always too greedy, Louise.
I just don't like to see her
exploiting you.
Honey, she's leaving
all of your family's money to charity
in the name of this mysterious Kathleen.
It's ridiculous.
Your mother is crazy.
You don't know anything about it.
I know that music's terrible.
John, you're rowing too hard. Let me row.
You're concerned about me, Louise.
- Is it my heart?
- Stop it.
You're only a member of the family
as long as you're my wife.
If I die before Mother,
you're a stranger...
entitled to nothing.
Now you've done it.
- Where are the pills?
- In-- In the coat.
It's empty, you idiot!
Row faster, Louise.
If I die, there's nothing in it for you.
Shut up.
John?
John!
Now what do I do?
I got to get rid of him.
I'll have to get rid of his things,
say he went back to New York
on business or something.
"Mother...
I am terribly sorry,
but I have received
an urgent...
wire from New York.
Since I must leave tonight,
I will be forced to miss
Kathleen's...
memorial ceremony.
But you all know...
my thoughts
will be with her, in loving...
memory."
"Your loving son, John."
I'll pack the things he would have taken--
A suit, some shirts.
I'm finally rid of him.
I know I can handle his mother
without him around.
She's half-crazy anyway.
I can get rid of her,
one way or the other.
I'd better watch out
for his brothers, though...
especially the older one, Richard.
The typewriter. He wouldn't forget that.
He'd have to write letters on the plane.
I wonder if he'll rot underwater.
Everything, everything.
I'll make her change that ridiculous will.
"Your loving son, John."
Fat John.
I hope everything works out
with John's business.
I'm sure everything will be fine.
Your brother's always had a way
of solving his own problems.
Oh, I'm sorry. We're in your way.
What do you think of Ireland,
and Castle Haloran?
Ireland's fine.
Castle Haloran is a bit perplexing.
A very strange place, really,
old and musty,
the kind of place you'd expect a ghost
to like to wander around in,
kind of a haunted castle.
Castle Haloran is haunted.
By your mother?
By Kathleen.
I know very little about her.
In fact, I didn't even know you had
a sister until we arrived here.
There's not that much
to know about her, really.
My mother was about 40
when she gave birth to Kathleen.
It was like a gift, she used to say.
"An apple for the starving
and Kathleen for me."
She even had a poem.
"Three sons, each who would
marry and go away,
but little Kathleen would always stay."
It's engraven on her little tombstone now.
How did she die?
She drowned in the pond.
Passengers arriving from London and Cork,
Aer Lingus Irish International Airlines
wish you...
Your baggage will be delivered shortly
on the conveyor bell.
Passengers traveling onwards by air today
should check
at the passenger service desk.
Excuse me, miss.
Are-- Are you Kane?
- Yes. Hello.
- Well, I'm Billy, Richard's brother.
I came to get you.
- Oh, hi. I'm so happy to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Richard's sorry
he couldn't come to get you, but he's--
Well, he's up to his elbows in statues,
so I said I wouldn't mind picking you up.
Thanks. That's awfully nice of you, Billy.
Aer Lingus Irish International Airlines
wish you...
Your baggage will be delivered
shortly on the conveyor belt.
My oldest brother, John,
had to leave early this morning,
but his wife, Louise, is still here.
She's from America,
So you won't get homesick.
That's my bag.
- Is it cold?
- Freezing.
But all old castles are like that.
To tell you the truth, Castle Haloran
gives me nightmares.
There it is.
Unbelievable.
We'll leave the luggage for a minute.
Come on, I'll take you to him.
This is where he works.
What is it?
I'm sorry, Richard.
Kane!
- Oh, I missed you.
- I missed you, too.
Well, I'm sorry I didn't pick you up
myself, honey,
but I wanted to finish this statue.
You look wonderful.
Well, I find
a statue reminds me of death.
How very unusual, Lady Haloran,
for a woman to have been married
to such a famous sculptor
and yet feel that way.
Did John mention
when he was going to return?
He wasn't sure.
We thought I'd stay on for a while
to get to know the family,
and then if he couldn't make it back,
I'd just return to New York.
How long is a little while?
As long as you like, Mother.
Well, you're very welcome here, Louise,
as long as you understand
the privacy of our personal duties.
I speak of the ceremony tomorrow.
I'm sure John explained it to you.
I'm afraid John was usually too busy
to talk much about the family.
That's why I'm so happy
to be here, finally.
You'll have a pleasant stay.
And I'm sure you can find something
to occupy your time during the ceremony.
It won't take very long.
Perhaps I am superstitious,
but I think it's important that only
the immediate members of the family
should give their thoughts to... Kathleen.
Excuse me.
Mother, I don't care what tragedy
hangs over this family.
I wanna get married.
I'm engaged to be married.
And I'm going to get married.
Moreover, I'm going to marry Kane.
Oh, Mother, Kathleen's dead.
She's been dead for seven years.
You never talked so much
when you were a child.
Well, I cried a lot, didn't I?
Afraid I might be doing that again
if you frighten her away from me.
You want me to include her,
to talk to her?
Yes.
Yes, I do.
Very well. I will.
I'll tell her I don't care for her.
Mother!
You hurt her and I promise you
I'll never forget it.
Thought you said
you didn't ride very much.
I don't. I'm just showing off,
'cause I finally got you to myself.
Good morning.
Oh, good morning, Louise.
It's nice to see her
enjoying herself for a change.
The mood around this place
isn't good for her.
Ah, she may be right.
Especially an American girl.
You can tell she's been
raised on promises.
What are you gonna do about that?
What are you going to do about that?
I don't understand.
I saw you squirming
when Mother read the will.
You gave John enough dirty looks
to give him a heart attack.
Don't joke about that.
You know he has a bad heart.
But I know you didn't mean anything by it.
You know, I think you ought to spend
more time with your wife-to-be.
You're an intelligent woman, Louise.
You notice things, size people up.
You know when they're happy
and know when something's bothering them.
- Want you to do me a little favor.
- Of course.
Keep that microscope you've got
built into your eye off of me.
I'll see you.
This will take you in, all right.
Oh, there's plenty of view from up there.
Must be very interesting to know
about all the secret passageways.
Oh, I know them all.
I've been here 20 years.
Twenty years? How wonderful.
Ah, well, you know how it is.
You get used to a family
and you get to like your room
and you get to know the run of the house.
And before you know it,
there you are, 20 years.
You must have been here, then,
when the little girl...
Ah, yes. That was a sad thing, that was.
Lord Haloran was a much-loved man,
and he invited one of the country fellows
up here for his wedding.
Oh, a big wedding that was,
a big banquet, and everyone invited.
She was all dressed up
as the bridesmaid,
running about to her heart's content
all over the place.
There's never been a wedding here since.
- What about Kane and Richard?
- Well, it's not my business,
but I wouldn't be betting
you'd see another wedding here.
Well, I must go back to work.
Billy? Billy? Billy, are you all right?
Oh, hello, Kane.
Oh, sure, sure, I'm fine.
I was just remembering about Kathleen.
Kathleen?
Oh, yes, the little girl.
Richard told me all about her.
We used to play together right here.
Sometimes I think I can still hear
her laughing, just like then.
- Is... Is this the pond where...
- Yes.
She was missing all night.
Mother was frantic, almost uncontrollable.
The next morning, we found Kathleen
floating in the water right over there.
I'm sorry, Billy.
No, Kane, I'm sorry.
I'm not always so morbid.
It's just that the funeral ceremony
is today.
It's a very beautiful pond.
You know, this is all just exactly
like I imagined Ireland would be.
It rained the day of the funeral.
We stood around her grave
under black umbrellas.
And then we threw flowers
under her little headstone.
Mother looked at the flowers...
and then she collapsed.
Every year it's been the same.
The umbrellas, flowers...
and mother's collapse.
But that was years ago.
Why do you keep having the same ceremony
over and over again?
There's some things
you don't understand, not yet.
Please, let me help.
Have Lillian prepare her room.
I'll take care of her.
What happened?
One of the flowers died
when it touched her grave.
Shh.
Rest.
There's something in this house...
like music in the hallways...
like a child's music,
asking me something...
but more like begging me.
Begging for what?
Begging for her mother to listen to her.
You know?
I've heard her.
She asks for you.
Poor tiny thing.
She wants you to listen to her.
- To watch for her signs.
- Oh, I do try.
Do you know what she wants?
She'll tell me. I promise you.
She'll tell me.
Now, rest. She'll give us a sign.
I promise you. Shh.
Are you lost?
No. Are you?
I think you'll find that you're in quite
the wrong part of Castle Haloran
to find your room.
Good night, Louise.
Good night.
Consider your mind as a bird in your hand.
When it's relaxed, it lies quiet and easy.
But when it's tense and frightened,
it strains to leave you.
Quite a simple principle, isn't it?
You're engaged to treat my body,
not my mind.
Now, don't you try to separate
that which nature has joined.
What I'm trying to say is this,
that every year at this time,
you work yourself
toward a point of hysteria.
You remember, you worry, you imagine,
and then you collapse.
I just can't believe that such a punctual
cycle is physiological.
And aside from all this, am I well?
Aside from all this?
Oh, yes.
What I want you to do is to rest
and to relax your mind.
Remember the bird in your hand.
Come in.
Will you bring a summer dress for madam,
something youthful and cheerful,
so that we can have lunch
on the terrace?
And my daughter-in-law, Louise?
She isn't in her room.
I don't think she slept there last night,
if you were to ask me.
Yeah, but nobody's asking you,
little girl.
Now, hurry up with the lunch, or I'll wish
five years of spinsterhood on you.
I must know where Louise is.
I've never noticed this interest
in your daughter-in-law before.
Will you please find her, Lillian?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Her ladyship's summer dress.
Anything will do.
Tell her I must see her.
Do you understand?
Excuse me, Mr. Haloran.
The mistress sent me to find
your sister-in-law, Louise.
Have you seen her, sir?
I'm sorry, Lillian. We left
pretty early this morning.
- She's not in her room?
- No, sir. Her room wasn't even slept in.
- Try asking my brother.
- Yes, sir.
Luncheon is served on the terrace.
- Thank you.
- I wonder where she is.
I don't know.
Ask me what I did today.
Right, what did you do today?
- Nothing. Ask me why.
- Why?
Because you weren't there.
I thought you were going to work.
If you're going to be my wife,
you'll have to be
of the trusting, silent variety.
- Hey, Richard, you seen Louise?
- No, I haven't. Why?
I don't know. Mother's looking for her.
- Oh, is that Caleb?
- He's back.
Good afternoon, Mother.
Good morning, Caleb.
- How are you, Richard?
- I'm fine, Caleb.
And no more headaches, I trust?
Unpleasant things, headaches,
gnawing away at a man's
most valuable possession.
And congratulations
on your charming fiancée.
- Lillian.
- Patrick hasn't seen her, ma'am,
and Arthur says that none of the cars
except Master Billy's has been used.
Have you counted the silver?
Probably the most astute diagnose
you've ever made, Caleb.
You're all being ridiculous.
Kathleen?
The tiara. She wants the tiara.
Dolls?
Now, this is ridiculous.
Put it away. Probably belongs
to the gardener's child.
Now, this is very bad for your mother.
They're Kathleen's dolls.
I saw them float up
from the bottom of the pond.
One of you has a brilliantly imaginative
and sadistically effective mind.
I wish I could keep up with it.
Dr. Caleb, take this home and study it!
Fish the rest of them out. Burn them.
Are you gonna pound it all out
on that one little piece of metal?
I don't know.
You know, sometimes I get the feeling
you think I'm some sort
of a Christmas tree decoration.
Hang me up and look at me
on all the happy days,
and tie me up in a box and put me
in a closet when it gets gloomy.
You knew what I was like.
Oh, yes, I knew you were quiet,
but when we first met, I could sit
next to you in that little apartment,
watching you working
and thinking for hours.
It's this place. You know it is.
What do you want me to say?
- Nothing.
- Kane.
Believe me, I am sorry.
I don't care whether you're sorry or not.
Oh, Richard! Richard, I know
there are a lot of things
running around
in that beautiful head of yours.
I know that one of them is you love me.
Of course I love you.
But you must understand.
Ever since Kathleen died,
my mother's been running around
with some sort of crazy guilt,
looking to every one of us,
trying to put it on one of our heads.
Billy was only 13
two months after it happened.
He used to wake up
in the middle of the night
and come screaming into my room
because he had nightmares about her.
My own father died with his wife
refusing to see him.
Now I feel it's been passed on to me.
I've got to wait, and I've got to watch,
till I can make some sense
out of all this.
That leaves it up to you to decide
whether you want to sit and wait with me.
What do you think of the pond, Arthur?
- I don't understand, sir.
- Of course not.
How long would it take you to drain it?
Well, I don't know, sir.
I've never drained it before
and I don't know
that I'd drain it properly.
There are three gear channel doors
on the pond.
Open them.
If I was you, I'd save that up
for a visit to my office.
You're losing weight. Skin's pale.
She always loved the tiara.
I wanted to put it in her coffin,
but they wouldn't let me.
I'll bring it to her playhouse
and put it with her other things.
The tiara.
You want the tiara.
Richard! Richard, please come!
Somebody, please come!
Lillian, call the doctor.
- Will it be Dr. Caleb?
- Anybody.
And get Richard here.
Richard!
Hurry.
Still breathing.
Let's get her into the house.
Why don't you go to bed, Billy?
I will in a minute.
You're gonna get all depressed
sitting here by yourself.
Did you ever see where my room is?
You have to go down a corridor where
nobody's lived for the past 50 years,
then up a flight of stairs
where my great grand uncle or somebody
tripped and broke his neck.
And then past the spot where
my grandfather died of a heart attack.
I'd rather be depressed here than there.
Poor Billy. No wonder you used
to get all those nightmares.
Used to? I still get them.
What are they like? Are they terrible?
I don't know.
They're more strange than terrible.
I'm always a little boy,
and I'm in my room. It's late.
I hear somebody outside making
a kind of a scraping sound.
I get out of bed, look out of the window,
and there's a man climbing up the wall,
coming closer toward my window.
I yell for my mother,
and she comes into the room,
just as the man
is coming in through the window.
I hold on to her legs, crying.
I'm so small I only come up to her waist.
The man is in the shadows.
You can almost recognize him,
but not really.
He says that he's insane
and that someone else
in the room is insane also
and that he's going to nod his head,
and when he does,
that other insane person
will nod their head.
He nods...
and I look up at my mother...
and she's nodding her head.
And then...
she starts laughing at me.
And she picks me up in her arms,
and runs outside and...
throws me into the pond.
Oh, Billy, we've all got
to get out of here.
Come on. Go to bed.
I'll walk you past
all those spooky corridors.
Hurry and get there before Richard
throws us both in the pond.
- What's wrong?
- Oh, nothing.
You just made me realize.
The man in my dream
who climbs up my wall is Richard.
I'm sorry. I just never
thought of it before.
Just a dream.
- What is it, Arthur?
- Is Dr. Caleb in?
He's at breakfast. Is it important?
- Yes.
- All right, then.
Come on in.
Excuse me, but Arthur's here.
He says he has something
important to tell you.
Excuse me.
- Hello, Arthur.
- I drained the pond, like you told me to.
And there's something there
I think you'd want to see.
Show me.
Richard?
A shrine, beautifully done.
I never saw that before.
Why, it's skillfully carved,
I must say.
I work in iron, remember?
Six years ago, you worked in stone.
I never did that.
Every one of us worked in stone.
My father loved teaching us.
Someone else did that. I didn't.
No one else pursued
this inherited talent. Nobody.
Leave him alone. He told you before
he's never seen it, and he meant it.
Come on, Richard, let's go.
No.
He's trying to play a game
with me, don't you see?
Your mother lies in bed in a state
of shock caused by something or somebody.
I don't call that a game, Richard.
Has the all-seeing doctor noticed
that a certain money-hungry,
conniving little woman has left our midst?
That my mother, in her struggle,
clung on desperately
to a very valuable diamond tiara?
But I think that shrine has been
in that pond for five or six years.
I don't think that five or six years ago
Louise had even heard
of Castle Haloran. Do you?
- What do you want out of this, Doctor?
- Oh, I don't know,
just a solution to the nightmare that has
disturbed this family for six years.
After all, I am
the family doctor, you know.
I didn't mean to annoy your brother,
'cause I think he's right.
I think Louise did try to steal
your mother's tiara,
and I think she'll come back.
I think she's hiding somewhere in town.
Will you help me look for her?
- Sure, if you want me to.
- I do,
because your brother's upset,
and the young girl, too.
That leaves the two of us.
What do you think?
- Sure, I guess you're right.
- We'll look for her tonight.
- No!
- I told you not to follow me.
Look at you. You're frightened to death.
- Now, settle down.
- What are you doing here?
It's he studio where my father worked.
He kept his stone-cutting tools here.
I was trying to find out
who made that monument.
Oh, Richard. Richard, I'm sorry.
I'll never doubt you again. I promise.
We can get married now.
Your mother's still sick
and she won't be able to stop us.
No one will be able to stop us.
Well, this is the devil's own climate.
Good for the grass
and the country doctors.
If I had to survive
by treating the common cold,
I might as well retire.
Two large Irish for Master Haloran.
Oh, no, no, I don't care for any.
Oh, just to take the chill
from your bones.
Drink's the only road
to survival in this climate.
Despite your useless American education,
you're still Irish, you know.
Drink up.
Do you know his sister-in-law,
John's wife, an American girl?
Fair hair, fair complexion?
You'd know her.
No, I have never seen her.
I've seen her at the chemist's, Doc,
about two or three days ago.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Over here, Billy, nearer the heat.
Drink up.
What do you think, Billy?
Where did she go?
I don't know. Come on. Let's go.
Oh, there.
You wouldn't begrudge an aging man
his moment's rest, would you?
You know, I think you know the answer
to all the problems
your family's been having,
because, Billy, you saw your little sister
drown all those years ago.
- No, I didn't.
- Oh, yes, you did.
You know how I know you did?
- No.
- 'Cause you told me.
I did not.
Oh, Billy. Come on. Drink up.
Do you remember all those years ago,
when you couldn't sleep?
Do you remember who it was gave you
the little pill that made you sleep?
Remember the dreams,
faces in the shadows,
the man climbing up your wall?
I haven't forgotten.
Who was that man?
No. I don't know.
Who was it that tried
to throw you in the pond?
Richard.
Tell me what happened.
What happened to Louise?
Fishy, fishy in the brook
Daddy caught you on a hook
Come on. Let's go.
- Has anyone here seen Richard?
- No, I haven't seen him.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
You know, the one thing in the world
that really chills my bones to the marrow
is when a pretty girl
in a wedding dress looks at me
- and finds me repulsive.
- Oh, don't be silly, Doctor.
Oh, I'm often silly,
one of my major vices.
Another one is the desire
on my part to help others,
however rancid that may sound.
Then you can help me
by telling me where Richard is.
I'm not sure where Richard is
or, indeed what he is.
Oh, and you wonder why young girls
in wedding dresses give you dirty looks.
No, no, no. I'm quite serious.
I've known this family
for a very long time.
I've been aware
of the atmosphere of depression
and the slightly demented quality
that hangs over it.
But these are subtle matters,
so I never spoke.
I will tell you, young lady,
that I know that Louise did not leave,
but was... taken away from Castle Haloran.
Perhaps even her husband, John,
didn't actually go on that business trip.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Because you don't know what I'm talking
about, you think I'm some kind of villain.
Can you imagine what it's like
to try to help others
and to be mistrusted every time?
My lip twists.
This doesn't mean that
every word I say is sinister.
I don't know what you're trying to say.
What I'm trying
to say to you is that I've...
discovered things in this house
that make me uneasy,
and that you are probably
in a position of some danger.
- From Richard?
- Primarily from Richard.
But I'm not sure. It could be anyone.
Well, maybe you have forgotten,
but I certainly haven't. I'm his wife now.
And there was a sister and a sister-in-law
and his mother...
and perhaps his eldest brother.
I swear to you, Dr. Caleb,
you are a very sick man.
Kane.
- What's the matter, honey?
- Where have you been?
I was just outside having a smoke.
Well, let's get out of here.
I don't want anyone to see me crying.
Come out, come out wherever you are
These little nursery rhymes
are notoriously expressive.
Come on. I don't care
what anyone says about you.
Who said anything about me?
No one! Everyone! I don't care!
Little fishy in the brook...
Papa's hanged you on a hook.
Papa's caught you on the hook?
What is it?
Don't touch her!
Forgive me, Kathleen.
You children played with stone
the way other children played
with building bricks.
They all forgot what a talented
little boy Billy was.
What about Kathleen?
He made a wax doll,
something he could protect,
to relieve his guilt.