[Music]
so
well here we are i
turn down here at the
next clock
thanks mister i'll get off there
[Music]
want anything else no hey you
me yeah you where you're headed
peace
all of you was
headed north i might be
able to help you
out pushing the salt
lake and i don't
like to ride it alone
at night
i'm one of those
guys who got a talk or
i fall asleep
[Music]
but i ain't got nobody
at all where are
you coming from
of course yeah sure
i know but where are
they
maybe got a cousin
how can you lay you
don't say yeah he's been out
you're not much
of a talker right my
mother taught me
never to speak to
strangers
oh wise guys so what
okay okay don't get
sore
trying to be sociable that's all
hey glamorous you
change for a dime will
you
let's have something
quieter this time
joe my head's
splitting is that what's
wrong with it
done with your coffee
no and don't rush
me will you
hey turn that off
will you turn that
thing off yeah
what's eating you that
music it stinks oh
you don't like it huh
no turn off oh wait a minute pal
that was my
nickname this is a free
country
and i play whatever i wanted
[Music]
sure if you don't
like it you don't have
to listen to it and
you can leave here
anytime you want it
okay okay i'm
sorry i am first good
piece play tonight
you don't like it
some people just
ain't got any good
taste
[Music]
that tune why was
there always that
rotten tune
following me around
beating in my head
never letting up
[Music]
did you ever want
to forget anything did
you ever want to
cut away a piece of
your memory or bladder out
you can't you know
no matter how hard
you try
you can change the
scenery but sooner or
later you'll get a
whiff of perfume
where somebody will
say a certain phrase
or maybe hum something
then you're licked again
[Music]
i can't believe that
you're in love with
me i used to love that song once
so did the customers
back in the old
break at dawn club in new york
i can't remember
a night when i didn't
get at least three
requests for it
sue she was
always selling it too
those were the days
[Music]
so
i can't believe that
you're in love with
me
you're telling everyone
that i'm on your mind
each place you go
they can't believe
that you're in love
with me
[Music]
to think that i'm the lucky one
i can't believe that
you're in love with
[Music]
me
it wasn't much of a
club really you know
the kind
a joint where you
could have a sandwich
and a few drinks
and run interference
for your girl on the dance floor
i founded the piano
in there every night
from eight until
a place closed up
which usually meant
four in the morning
a good job as jobs
went in those days
then two there was sue
who made working
there a little like
working in heaven
but how we felt
about each other well
there was nothing
very unusual in that
i was an ordinary
healthy guy and she
was an ordinary
healthy girl and when
you add those two
together you get an
ordinary healthy
romance which is the
old story
sure but somehow
the most wonderful
thing in the world
[Music]
all in all i was a
pretty lucky guy
mr patarovsky i
presume it's beautiful
you're going to
make carnegie hall yet
al yeah
as a janitor i'll
make my debut in the
basement
i'll blame you for
being bitter darling
but you mustn't give up hope
by someday yeah
someday i don't get
arthritis first
in the meantime
let's blow this trap
[Music]
like to get something
hon oh i don't
think so al i lose
my appetite working
in this flea bag
let's go home okay
i can't stand much
more of that dump
did you see that
drunk tonight trying to
paw me no what drunk
does it matter what drunk
so what's the matter
with you tonight
darling that's
the third time you
started to tell me
something then stop
we shouldn't have
any secrets from each
other soon next week
we're going to make
with the ring and the
license you and me
will be a team
yes that's right
in the bush league
i don't get you
we've been struck out
it's a funny way
to talk darling don't
you want to marry me
oh look i love you
you know i do and i
want to marry you
but but not now
only after we've made
good sunday i'm going away
i know you'll
think it's silly that's
why i hesitated to train
but i'm going to
california i want to
try my luck in hollywood
that's the most
stupid thing i ever
heard of don't you
know millions of
people go out there
every year and wind
up polishing cuspadores
i thought you had
better sense you sound
as if you don't think
i have any talent
that has nothing to do with it
i'll make out all
right maybe but what
about me doesn't
mean anything to you
that you're busting
up all our plans
we may not see
each other for years it
won't be that long
i thought you love
me i do you know i do
well here we are
now as i can't you
see my side of it
i'm young we both
aren't and we've got
all the time in the
world to settle down
really darling what
i'm doing is the
only sane thing to do
i i hate the thought
of being so far
away from you but
but we'll be together
again someday
maybe you'll decide
to come out too
later on so long
al aren't you going
to kiss me good
night
sure why not
tonight
[Music]
so
do
[Music]
okay roberts you
hit the jackpot this
time
10 bucks thanks
so when this drunk
handed me a 10 spot
after a request i
couldn't get very
excited
what was it i asked
my piece of paper
crawling with germs
couldn't buy
anything i wanted it
couldn't
then i thought of something
[Music]
long distance i'd
like to put a call
through to los angeles
miss harvey sue
harvey h-a-r-v-e-y
the number is
crestview 6-5-7-2-3
[Music]
hello sue this is
al oh baby it's great
to hear from you too
what's that you do
oh me too darling
i thought i'd go
batty without you i
just had to huh
you're working as a
hashlinger gee honey
that's
tough those guys
out in hollywood don't
know the real thing
when it's right in
front of them
i'm sure you'll
click look i'll tell you
what you stay put
out there i'll come to
you
no don't try to stop
me just expect me
train
who knows train
plane bus magic carpet
i'll be there if i have to crawl
have to travel by
pogo stick and then
let's get married right away huh
that's the stuff
that's what i've been
wanting to hear you say
well goodbye for now
i'll be seeing you soon
yeah bye
the only way i could
cross country was
to thumb rides
or even after hawking
everything i only
had enough money to eat
money you know what that is
it's the stuff you
never have enough of
little green things with george
washington's picture
that men slave for
commit crimes for die for
it's the stuff that
has caused more
trouble in the world
than anything else
we ever invented
simply because
there's too little of it
at least i had too little of it
so it was me for the thumb
ever done any
hitchhiking it's not much
fun believe me
oh yeah i know all
about how it's an
education how you
get to meet a lot of
people and all that
but me from now on i'll take my
education in college
or in ps62 where
i'll send a dollar 98
and stamps for 10 easy lessons
coming rides may
save your bus fare but
it's dangerous
you never know
what's in store for you
hear the squealer breaks
if only i had known
what i was getting
into that day in arizona
throw that in the back seat
okay let's go make
sure that door is
[Music]
closed
you know emily
post ought to write a
book of rules for
guys thumbing rides
because as it is
now you never know
what's right and what's wrong
you rode along
for a little while
neither one of us
saying anything i'm
just glad of that
i never know what
to say to strange
people driving cars
until you can never
tell if a guy wants
to talk
a lot of rides have
been cut short
because of a big mouth
so i kept my mouth
shut until he started
opening up
have me that little
box that can pop up
with a pal
all the way over
how far are you
going la well you're
really traveling aren't you
yeah but i don't
expect to make it for a
couple of years at
the rate i've been
promoting rides
not much luck huh sure all bad
not many people
stop for a guy these
days afraid of a stick up maybe
oh they can't blame
them where you
coming from
new york well new york
you're in luck this
time i'm going all
the way
right through to los
angeles you drive a
car
sure whenever you're
tired let me know
i'll holla
i guess at least an
hour passed before i
noticed those deep
scratches in his
right hand
they were wicked
three puffy red lines
about a quarter of an inch apart
you must have seen
me looking at them
because he said
beauties aren't they
they're going to be
scars someday
[Music]
what an animal
whatever it was it must
have been pretty big
and vicious to have
done that
i don't both counts
new york i was
tussling with the
most dangerous animal
in the world
a woman she must
have been tarzan's mate
looks like you
lost about certainly
wasn't a draw
you know there ought
to be a law against
danes with claws
yeah i tossed her
out of the car in her
ear
was that wrong
give a lift to a tomato
you expect it to be
nice don't you yeah
after all what kind
of dame some rides
sunday school teachers yeah
a little witch he must
have thought she
was riding with some fall guy
me who's been booking
horses around race
track since i was 20.
not a million things
like her 2 million
yeah stop the car
open the door
take it on the other
duffy's sister i told her
cause that was done huh
if you want to see
a real scar brother
get a load of this
i got that one jordan julie
yeah we're just kidding
of course my dad
owned a couple of
franco prussian savers
kept him on the wall
for decorations uh
one day another kid
and i took him down
the old man wasn't
around had a jewel
he got me in the
arm here pretty mean
cut
infection set in
lady yeah i can see
that
i'll give me that box
again really yeah
pain made me lose
my head i guess i
began slashing
before i knew it i'd
put the other kid's
eye out that was tough
well it's just an
accident of course do
you know how kids are
i got scared decided
i was gonna run
away from home old
man almost caught me
when i was packing my ducks
the bloody rag i had
wrapped around my
wrist hadn't
caught his attention
just seemed to
bundle for sure but i
beat it when he was
phoning for a doctor
i was 15 16 years
ago i haven't been
home since
pulling that for a
bite or something huh
a bite
brother was i
hungry i hadn't had
anything in my stomach for hours
yet even with that
gnawing in the foot
of my belly i didn't
want to be in too
big a rush to put
on the feed bag
first i had to make
sure this guy knew
the score if i got
him down on me
it was goodbye
ticket to hollywood i'll
wait out here for you mister
if it's the money
don't worry about
paying for it this
time it's on me well
that's right of you
mr haskell think
nothing of it you
make your first
millionaire you can
do the same for me
come on new york i
gotta make the west
coast by wednesday
the horse running
in santa need a name
powered bicycle
means daughter of my
money
we'll make it all
right he did most of
the talking during
the half hour we were
in the place
i ate he rambled
on about his old man
whom he hadn't
heard from since he ran
away as a kid
now he happened to
become a bookie and
then all about how
he got rooked in
miami
one race 38 grand
they cleaned out my
book how do you like that
that was tough luck yeah and i'm
supposed to be the
smart guy will you
just wait i'm going
back to florida next
season with all kinds of jack
and you'll watch
those stinkers run for
cover
anything else no
thanks i've had plenty
let's check that assistant
oh just a miniature
change sir okay but
sister oh
thank you sir call
again you're waiting
outside for when you finish work
[Music]
i drove all that
night while haskell
slept like a log
after a while i
began to get sleepy
myself
i was happy though
soon i'd be with sue
again
the long trip was
practically over and
it'd be no more
hoofing it down the
concrete
i began to think
of the future which
couldn't have
been brighter if i'd
embroidered it with neon lights
it was nice to think
of sue shooting to
the top
it's amazing what
a full belly can do to
your imagination
i never knew what they could do
[Music]
i can't believe that
you were in love
with me
mr haskell mr haskell
mr haskell wake
up it's raining don't
you think we ought
to stop and put up
the top
[Music]
mr haskell i'm
gonna put up the top
[Music]
until then i had done
things my way but
from then on something
else stepped in
and shunned me
off to a different
destination than
one i had picked for
myself
but when i pulled open that door
mr haskell what's
the matter are you
hurt
are you hurt mr
haskell start here
i'll listen to it but i
know what you're
gonna hand me even
before you open your
mouth you're gonna
tell me you don't
believe my story of
how heskel died and
give me that don't make me laugh
expression on your smug faces
[Music]
i saw it once he was
dead and i was in
for it
who would believe
he fell out of the car
why pasco came to
which of course he
couldn't even he was
where i calmed him
over the head for his dog
yes i was in for it
instinct told me to
run
but then i realized
it was hopeless
there were lots of
people back down the
road who could
identify me that gas
station guy and the weight
piece that would be
the worst spot then
trying to explain why i beat it
the next possibility
was to sit tight
and tell the truth
when the cops came
but that would be crazy
they'd laugh at the
truth i'm not having
my head in the news
[Music]
so what else was
it to do but hide the
body and get away
in the car i couldn't
leave the car
there with him in the
gully
that would be like
erecting a tombstone
[Music]
my idea was to cover
him with brush not
to rob him
but then i remember
that even if i only
drove the car for
100 miles or so i
would need money for gas
besides it was
stupid for me to leave
all that money on a dead man
not only that i'd
have to take his
driver's license in
case i was stopped
for something
i didn't like to
think about it but by
that time i'd done
just what the police
would say i did
even if i didn't my clothes
the owner of such an
expensive car would
never be wearing them
some cop might
pull me in suspicion
[Music]
hey you this your
car don't you know
better to leave a
car without wheels
halfway in the
middle of the road
that's the way
accidents happen i'm i'm
sorry officer i
was just putting
up my top i didn't
think well the next time
think i'll let you go
now but watch your
step in the future
i know that's a
lonely stretch but cars
come by here once
in a while we have
plenty of crack ups
you
[Music]
i left nothing in
the car to give me
away as roberts if
they found a dead man
in the gully now
it could be me
[Music]
i drove off it was
still raining and the
drop streak down
the windshield like
tears
[Music]
i kept imagining i
was being followed
that i could hear
sirens back in the
distance
just how long it took
me to cover the 60
odd miles to the
california state line
i don't know i lost
all track of time
but the rain had
stopped and the sun was
up when i pulled
up to the inspection
station
[Music]
hello carrying any
fruits or vegetables
no any livestock or poultry no
i'd see your
registration and driver's
license please
anything in the baggage
compartment this
baggage
charles haskell's
junior aids 30 brown
eyes dark hair
identifying mark's
nun are you charles
haskell jr
yes well remember if
you're employed and
you stay over 30
days you take out
california plates
all right officer
but i won't be in the
state a short while
right you go now
[Music]
i couldn't drive
any farther without
some sleep cops and no cops
i knew i had to hit
the hay and hit it
high
i was dead tired
[Music]
so
oh you can't mr haskell
no
[Music]
you can't die something
i think i did it i don't
know how much
to ask
[Music]
who's there it's the
maid can i come in
and clean
later in a half hour
[Music]
there was no time
to lose every minute i
had to be charles
haskell was dangerous
and i'd have to be
charles haskell until
i got to some city
where i could leave
the car and be swallowed up
[Music]
that meant driving
the car as far as san
bernardino maybe
even to los angeles
in a little town i
might be noticed but
in a city i should
be safe enough
then after i ditched
the car i could go
on to sue
but those five
minutes at the state line
made me realize it
might be a good idea
to find out a
little bit about mr
haskell
then if anybody
asked me questions i
could give the right answers
the first thing i
found out was that i
had 768
this was a lot of
jack but believe me
was the kind of
money i'd rather not
have
[Music]
and then i found
out from a letter
haskell was cutting
around in his bag
that he wasn't the open-handed
easy-going big shot
who went around
buying dinners for
strange hitchhikers
before i got done
reading it i saw him
more as a chisler
it was written to his old man in
california the one
he hadn't seen in so
many years
in it has composed
as a salesman of
hymnals
of all things it was
easy to see where
haskell expected
to raise a new stake
for his book in miami
by looking as old man
that was about all
i found out from his
effects
and it was enough i told myself
maybe old man haskell
was lucky his son
kicked off
he would never know
it but it saved him
from taking a flier
in sacred literature
preferred
[Music]
near the airport
at desert center i
pulled up for water
there was a woman
hey you come on
if you want to ride
[Music]
she was facing
straight ahead so i
couldn't see her eyes
but she was young
not more than 24.
man she looked
as if she'd just been
thrown off the
crummiest freight train
in the world
yet in spite of this i got the
impression of beauty
not the beauty of a
movie actress mind
you or the beauty
you dream about when
you're with your wife
but a natural beauty
a beauty that's
almost homely because it's so
real then suddenly
she turned to face me
[Music]
oh nothing just
thinking out loud people
get in trouble for
doing that what's
your name
can you call me
bear if you like you
live in los angeles
no where you coming from
oh back there needles no
oh sure phoenix
you look just like a
phoenix girl
are the girls in
phoenix that bad the
girl must have been pretty tired
because she fell
asleep not 20 minutes
after she stepped into the car
she lay sprawled
out with her head
resting against the far door
like haskell i didn't
like that part of
it much
but i didn't wake
her up it wasn't that
this girl still worried me
i'd gotten over that
funny feeling i had
when she looked at me
which i put down
it's just my jangled
nerves
with her eyes closed
and the test has
gone out of them
she seemed homeless
enough and instead
of disliking her i
began to feel sorry
for her the poor kid
probably had had
a rough time of it
who was she anyway
and why was she going
to los angeles
and where'd she
come from in the first
place the only thing
i knew about it was
her name
not that it made
any difference a few
hours more would be in hollywood
i'd forget where i
parked the car and
look up sue
this nightmare of
being a dead man would
be over
who this name was well it was no
business of mine
where did you leave his
body
where did you leave
the owner of this
car you're not fooling anyone
this buggy belongs
to a guy named
haskell that's not
you mister you're out
of your mind that's
my name charles
haskell i can prove it
it's my driver's
license you found the
trouble mister haven't
asked us while it
only makes it worse
it just so happens
i rode with charlie
haskell all the
way from louisiana
he picked me up
outside of shreveport
you rode you heard me
then it all came
back to me all the talk
about dueling and
scars and scratches
there was no doubt
about it must be the
woman haskell had mentioned
she must have
passed me while i slept
well
well i'm waiting my
goose was cooked
she had me that
haskell guy wasn't dead
yet
he wasn't stretched
out stiff and cold
in any arizona gully
he was sitting
right there in the car
laughing like mad
while he haunted me
[Music]
well there was
nothing i could say
was her move vera
whatever her name was
was just my luck
picking her up on the
road it couldn't have been helen
or mary or evelyn
or ruth it had to be
the very last person
i should ever have
met
that's life whichever
way you turn fade
sticks out of foot to trip
[Music]
i told her everything
but she didn't
believe my story i
should have saved my
breath
that's the greatest
cock-and-bull story
i ever heard so
he fell out of his car
say who do you
think you're talking to a
hick listen mister
i've been around and
i know a wrong guy
when i see one
what'd you do get
him with a wrench now
wait a minute what
i told you was true
you see that's why
i had to do it you
think i killed him
well the cops would
have thought so too
yeah well maybe they
still think so
what makes you
so sure i'll shut up
about this it won't
do me any good
having you pinched
the cops are no
friends of mine now if
there was a reward
but there isn't
thanks don't thank me
yet
i'm not through with
you by a long shot
let's see that role
[Music]
is that all that
isn't enough no i
thought he had
more not that i know if
you can search me
think i'm holding out
on you well maybe i will effect
he told me he was
gonna get three
thousand dollars
bicycle on wednesday at
san anita
he was stringing
along he meant 300.
maybe sure three bucks
300. he was a
piece of cheese a big
blowhard listen mister
don't try and tell
me anything about
charlie haskell
remember i knew him
better than you did
okay then you
knew he was a floor
flusher that explains
the three grand
bet i'm not so sure
he doesn't have that
three grand
why should i believe
you you got all the
earmarks of a cheap
crook now wait a
minute
you're a cheap crook
and you killed him
for two cents i'd
change my mind and
turn you in
i don't like you
all right all right
don't get sorry
i'm not getting sore
but just remember
who's boss around here
if you shut up and
don't give me any
arguments you'll
have nothing to worry
about
but if you act wise
well mister you'll
pop into jail so
fast it'll give you the
bins
i'm not arguing that
you don't you know
as quick as you look
i'd hate to see a
fella as young as you
wind up sniffing
that perfume that
arizona hands are
free to murderers i'm
not a murderer
of course you're not
asking knocked his
own head off if so
that's how happened
just like i told you
yeah and then he
made you a president
of his belongings
i explained why i
would do that doesn't
make a difference
one way or another
i'm not a mourner
i like tascor even
less than i like you
yeah i saw what you
did to him what do
you mean scratches on his wrist
sure i scratched
him i'll say you did
so your idea was
to drive the car a
little way maybe
into san bernardino
then
you weren't gonna
sell it sell it you
think i'm crazy
somebody else's car
see all i want to do is leave it
somewhere and forget
i have a sauce not
only don't you have
any scruple you
don't have any brains
i don't get you
maybe it's a good thing
you met me you'd
have got yourself
caught sure
why you dope don't you know what
deserted automobile
always rates an
investigation
huh look the cops
find a car then they
get curious
they wonder where
the owner is so all
right they don't trace haskell
they trace you i
never thought of that
the only safe way
to get rid of the car
is to sell it to a dealer get it
registered under a new name
say stop at the next
door i want to get
a bottle and do some
shopping before we
hit la
okay let me find a
place i'll drop you
off and pick you up later
not been doing you're
coming in too from
now on you and i
are like the siamese
twins
haven't your way i
don't get the point
the point is i don't
want you to get
lost
i'm not gonna
beat it if that's what
you're afraid of
i'll say you're not
well i'm gonna see
that you sell this
car so you don't get caught
thanks of course
your interest wouldn't
be financial work
you wouldn't want a
small percentage of
the profits well now
that you insist how
can i refuse
a hundred percent
will do fine i'm
relieved i thought
for a moment you're
going to take it all
i don't want to be
a hog a few hours
later we were in hollywood
i was recognizing
places sue had written
about it struck me
that far from being
at the end of the trip
there was a greater
distance between sue
and me than when i started out
pirro wasn't kidding
with that siamese
twins crack
she rented a little
apartment as mrs
charles haskell
when i objected to
this she explained
that it was an
account of the car
the dealer might
think something was
funny if he called
and finally were
using different names
home sweet home
yeah not bad either
case there's any
dot near mine i'll take
the bedroom yeah
sure it's stuffy in here
keep the wonder shut okay
the old crow
downstairs so there's a
folding bed behind this door
you know how to work it
i invented it
some joint one
can't have everything
i'm first in the
bathtub i don't know
why
but i figured you would be
boy oh boy sure
feels good to be clean
again
i must be ten pounds
lighter we must be
well hitch and
rides isn't exactly the
way you keep your
school complexion
i wish that guy with
the sex would give
up
gets on my nerves
forget it
have a drink you
afraid i might take you
up on it
i didn't want to
give you a drink it
wouldn't go with it
might be a sword roberts you got
yourself into this thing
you should be
grateful i'm not turning
you in or if i wasn't
regular you'd be
in the pen this minute being
photographed
fingerprinted and being
pushed around by the cops
so sure get rid
of that long puss
or is your conscience
bothering you
[Music]
it isn't swell that's the spirit
he's dead no moment
around to bring him
back
anyway i never
could understand this
worrying about
something that's over and
done with now
look girl for the last
time i didn't kill him
haskell was a sick
man and he was dead
before he fell out
of the car i don't
know
sure sherry died of old age
all right silver
make you sociable
you didn't kill him
[Music]
thanks
we're out of liquor roberts yeah
too bad i felt
like getting tight
tonight
well i think you
succeeded in my turn
as a prima donna's
corset that's good
i want to get tight
why what have you
got to get tight about
well i don't know a few things
you should have my
worries if i had your
troubles i'd stay sober
and i've got the
key to that door
yeah maybe you're
right i'm always right
you know i don't
like your attitude
robert well there's
a lot of things i
don't like
it lives like a ball
game you got to
take a swing at
whatever comes along
before you wake up
and find us in ninth
inning
bet you read that
somewhere that's the
trouble with you roberts
all you do is bellyache
taking it easy and
trying to make the
best of things
but maybe that's
what's wrong with the
whole world
get the professor people knock
themselves out
trying to buck faith
now take you for
instance you're lucky
to be alive
why suppose haskell
had pulled open your
door you'd be playing a harp now
think of that you think of it
i'm tired of thinking
there's plenty of
people dying this minute
i would give anything
to trade places
with you
i know what i'm
talking about i'm not so
sure
at least they know
they're done for it
they don't just sweat blood
wondering if they
are your philosophy
stinks pal
we all know we're
gonna kick off someday
it's only a question of when
but what got us on
this subject anyway
we'll be discussing
politics next yeah
where'd you hide
the butts on the table
sucker
[Music]
we bought each
other with conversation
for a couple of hours longer
every five minutes
one of us was wishing
we had another
bottle or a radio or
something to read
then finally we ran
out of chat i know
it's only 11 o'clock
but i want to get
up early and make
the rounds of the used
car lots
don't worry about
that we've got all the
time in the world
maybe you have
but if you think i want
to stay cooped
up in this place any
longer than i have
to your battery
it's not a bad
place pay penny for
diggins like this in new york
i wouldn't like it
if it was the ritz
[Music]
you got a mean cough want to do
something about
it i'll be all right
that's what camille said
nobody you know
[Music]
wasn't that the day that died of
consumption yeah
wouldn't it be a
break for you if i did
kick off you'd be free with all
haskell's stolen car
i don't want to see
anybody die not even
me
especially not you
one person died of me
if you did well
that's all i need
you don't like me do you rabbit
like you i love you
my favorite sport is
being kept prisoner
after we sell the
car you've got a
blazer for all i care
but not until then
[Music]
i'm going to bed
good night roberts
don't try and sneak
away during the night
all the doors are
locked anyway if i
find you guys in the morning
i'll notify the police
they'll pick you
up don't worry i
know what i'm in the
spot
[Music]
well good night i
hope that portable
rack isn't too
uncomfortable for you
ah
[Music]
six five
seven two
three hello
hello hello
[Music]
hello
no not yet
tomorrow maybe
[Music]
if this were fiction
i would fall in
love with vera
marry her and make
a respectable woman
of her or else she'd
make some supreme
class a sacrifice for me
and die sue and i
would bawl a little
over a grave
and make some crack
about there's good
in all of us
but vera unfortunately
was just as
rotten in the morning
as she'd been the
night before
all right all right i'm
coming look mary
it's almost noon
so what the dealers
will be there all
day i'll be there
all year too but that
doesn't mean i'm
going to wait that long
shut up you're
making noises like a
hudson
well do i rate a
whistle you sure do but
let's go
let's go let's go i
spent 85 bucks from
two hours to fair
and bait and all you
can say is let's go
come on
we passed a few
used car lots last night
down this way what
do you think we can
get for this heap
i don't know plenty
you just let me
handle everything
i think we can get
two thousand dollars
i don't know but don't worry
i'll squeeze as much
out of this guy as
i can i'll let it go
cheap without a
fighting might think
we're still in the
car
and listen don't make
any slips and call
me roberts
that'll cook us i
don't need you to tell
me that you better
just sit by and keep
your mouth closed
remember we're
both in the soup if
anything happens
forget it and drive
you're my wife vera haskell look
after the day is
closed let's go back to
that place on
hollywood boulevard
where i saw the fur
jacket i want to buy
it after the deal's
closed i'm saying
goodbye to you
that's right i
forgot i guess i'm
getting kind of used to you
well that's a
habit you can start
breaking let's try
this place in the
middle of block
good afternoon
what can i do for you
we're interested
in selling a car
if the price is right
[Music]
well if it's in good mechanical
condition it should
blue book for about
1600. tony take a
look at this motor
sixteen hundred are you kidding
[Music]
well maybe 18.50
before i let it go for
18.50 i'll wreck
it and collect the
insurance first
[Music]
maybe this motor's
seen a lot of driving
while the mechanic
inspected the car we
haggled
at last when we were
all worn out we hit
a compromise
his price
okay it's the deal
all right come on
we'll sign the papers i have the
ownership papers
right here with me
look vera in the
meantime will you clean
out the dash
compartment there may be
some stuff in it
all right darling
hundred and fifty
bucks that dirty crap
there you are huh
yeah but you bought
the car in miami
yeah now let's see
about the insurance
we can either have
it transferred or
canceled
uh what kind of
insurance do you have mr
hassell
we'll uh hand all
the papers there
i don't see any
surely you know what
type of insurance
you carry in the car
the name of the company yeah but
uh well if you'll just
tell me the name
of the company i'd
be very glad to take
care of all the details
well did you sign
the papers yet not yet
well don't
we're not selling a
car wait a minute mr
pascal come on
darling what's the matter
you changed your mind
yes i'm sorry i
guess i have but very
high
you got me out of
a tight spot vera but
i still don't
understand all this
you're well in a
minute i almost threw
away a gold mine
1850 isn't to be
sneezed at the car
doesn't look for as
much as i thought
we're not selling
the car you want to
keep it now wait a minute
you said yourself
i wouldn't be safe
until the car was in
someone else's name
i like to be free of
this mess when i go
that's just it roberts
you're not going
there's a driver in
the next corner pull
in there we'll get
a bite to eat and
i'll explain
what is this another one of your
brilliant ideas
[Music]
hello i think you
ordered make mine a
ham sandwich and
coffee and do you think
oh i don't care the same
thank you
get this pharah i've
been pretty patient
so far
i've done everything
you asked me to do
but no more shut up you've taken
haskell's money
you can have the
door we get from
selling the car but
you're not going to
keep me a prisoner
the good thing i
bought the paper take a
look at that sure i'm a nominee
[Music]
no yes no i won't
do it yes you will
you think i'm crazy
it's impossible i
tell you excuse me
[Music]
blow the horn
when you're through
no one could possibly
get away with an
act like that be wise
to me in a minute
don't be yellow
you look enough
like him the same
coloring in the same
build see how his
clothes fit you
i'm kidding you almost
had me fooled for
a while oh grow up vera
don't you think a
father knows his own
son and there must
be other relatives
the father won't
have to know you but
whaley gives it the
ghost he's an old
geezer and he won't pull through
and as far as
other relatives are
concerned they
haven't seen you in 15 or
20 years
eat i'm not hungry
and i won't do it
it's not as tough as
it sounds remember
you've got all kinds
of identification
his car
letters like i could
never get away with
it it's the stupidest
thing i've ever
heard
the old boy has
scans of dough look in
the paper there personal fortune
assassin over 15 million
he'll leave plenty i
tell you maybe cut
off his son how do we know
it's out there i won't
have anything to
do with it
i think you will
look vera i'll do
anything within reason
but not that so
forget it i'll find
yourself another stooge
you you'll set
fixed for the rest of
your life is charlie haskell
you can take your
inheritance and go
away no more worrying
about the rent no
sweating scheme and
wondering where your
next meal's coming
from think about that
robert
vera please you're
talking too loud
unless i'm splitting
30 50 with you sure
why not we're both
alike both more in
the same gutter
take it easy vera
there's people around
here you don't know
what you're talking
well where do we
read that old man has
goes dead and you show up
like you read in
new york that he was
sick no
suppose he doesn't
die he will i know he
will something tells me
but as much as i
insisted i would have
no part of her scheme
her was taking it
for granted i would
neither of us had
our mind on the cards
as we played that night
i knew we were
just trying to kill time
between newspaper editions
this was a death
watch for vera maybe it
was for me too
don't you realize
if i'm caught i want
to know where i
got the car and stuff
and they'll have me
on a murder charge
yeah smart you won't get caught
why not for sale
and if i'm caught don't
you realize you'll be up to
18 points it gives me 30.
how will i be out
you'll be out 850 we
would have gotten on the car
really very awful
chunky through we all
let doe on a dizzy long shot
let me sell a bus
tomorrow with the
money it'll bring
and what you've
already got a clever
kid like you can
run it up in no time
then we'd both be
in the clear i'll be
in the clear anyway maybe
maybe but if i got caught
i'd get couldn't swatch
you you know you
mean you'd squeal
well no not squealing
never mind what
you meant even if you
did tell the cops i
was in honor with
you
what could they do
to me they might give
me the same
medicine they gave you
yeah a rope
but i'm on my way anyhow
all they'll be doing
will be rushing it
all right
but like the 1850
you'd lose you'd kick
yourself along the
block if you ever get
away from you
i'll take the chance
want another drink
you're being a goon
that's the way people
wind up behind the
eight ball once they
get a few dollars
to become greedy and want more
my my caesar huh
you know that roman
general
he got his for being
greedy he wasn't
satisfied so the
final wind-up was he
took the count
a couple of days
ago you didn't have a
dime while you were so broke you
couldn't pay cash
for a postage stamp
now you've got almost
700 with 18.50 in
the offing take my
advice don't try for
more
i'm tired of this
game let's have some
blackjack play
starts here okay i will
if that's the way
you feel about that's
the way i feel about
it getting sore and
thrown things won't
help much roberts
i'm really doing you
a favor i help you
out of the jam by
keeping my mouth shut
i show you how to
make some soft money
and what thanks do i get
thanks sure i would
rather call the cops
and tell him you
killed the man and
stole it
yes you did no i
didn't you know i
didn't all right then
suppose i call the
cops pier anderson
what do you got to be scared of
okay calling me mud
go ahead and call
them see if i care
at least they'll give
me a square deal
you want me to call
you heard me but
i'm warning you if i'm
pinched i'll swear
you were in on it
i'll say that you
help me if i cry i'll
get even with you
you wouldn't dare you can yeah
and try to see call
him yeah okay i will
the donation i want
the number at the
hollywood police station
okay i got it thanks
wait a minute you
wouldn't do that
wouldn't i give me
that and i'll show
you if i would take
it easy now let's
talk this over
this was early in
the evening and the
conversation while hectic
was at least pitched
low but as the
minutes passed
and more obstacles
to her plan popped
into my head the air got blue
each word coming
from our lips cracked
like a whip
i reminded her that
as charles haskell i
didn't even know
my mother's name
where i'd gone to
school the name of my
best friend
whether i had an
aunt emma or not my
religion
and if i had ever
owned a dog i didn't
even know what my
middle initial stood
for
i also pointed out
that the real haskell
had a scar on his forearm
his people never
saw that scar he told
me he ran away
right after putting out
the kid's eye
yeah but his father
knew he was cut
it'll be some kind
of a mark so what
the old man's dead
or will be i hope by
tomorrow morning's papers
anyway you can
cut yourself a little
couldn't you
boy for that kind
of dough i'd let you
cut my leg off
you're drunk and
you're crazy mad girl
turn me if you want
to but i won't get
mixed up in this
besides how do we
know haskell was such
a phony it wasn't
the man center at all
maybe just dreamed it up
well dreaming or
not you won't be
dreaming when the
law attacks you on the
shoulder
there's a cute
little gas chamber
waiting for you robin
and i hear expeditions arizona's
ascension
where's that boat
[Music]
me what do you promise all right
you hurt me i'm sorry but
it's hot in here open
up a window it's
not hot don't tell
me now do you do it
or do i do it
you're no german see yeah
all right i'll open
up that window
you're gonna open
the door please open
the door here open
the door don't use
the phone listen to me
i don't like you robert you know
gentlemen see
you hurt my hand
and i'm gonna get even
with you
you don't open the
door i'm gonna kick
it down vera
don't call the cops
listen to me i'll do
anything you say
vera let me in
i'll break the phone
[Music]
the world is full
of skeptics i know
i'm one myself in
the haskell business
how many of you
would believe you fell
out of the car
and now after
killing vero without
really meaning to
do it how many of you
would believe it
wasn't premeditated
in a jury room
every last man of you
would go down
shouting and she had me
over a barrel and
my only out was force
the room was still
so quiet that for a
while i wanted to
fight suddenly gone
death
it was pure fear of
course and that was
hysterical
but without making a sound
girl was dead and
i was her murderer
murderer what an
awful word that is
but i'd become
one i better not get
caught
what evidence there
was around the place
had to be destroyed
and from the looks
of things there was plenty
looking around the
room with things we
brought was like
looking into the faces
of a hundred people
had seen us together
and who remembered me
this was the kind of testimony i
couldn't rub out
no i could burn
clothes and hide bottles
for the next five years
there'd always be
witnesses the landlady
for one she could
identify me the car
dealer the waitress
and the driver the
girl in the dress
shop and that guy in
the liquor store
he could all identify
me
i was cooked done
for i had to get out
of there
while once i'd
remained beside a dead
body planning
carefully how to avoid
being accused of killing him
this time i couldn't
this time i was
guilty
i knew it felt it
i was like a guy
suffering from shock
things were rolling
around in my head
i couldn't make
myself think right all i
could think of was the
guy with a saxophone
and what he was
playing
it wasn't a love song
anymore it was a
[Music]
dirge
foreign
[Music]
but my problems
weren't solved i had to
stay away from new york
for all time because
roberts was listed
as dead and had to stay dead
but i could never
go back to hollywood
someone might
recognize me as haskell
then two there was sue
[Music]
i could never go
to her with a thing
like this hanging over my head
all i could do was
pray she'd be happy
[Music]
i was in bakersfield
before i read that
vera's body was discovered
that the police
were looking for a
haskell in connection
with his wife's
murder
isn't that a laugh
haskell got me into
this mess
and haskell was
getting me out of it the
police were searching
for a dead man
i keep trying to
forget what happened
and wonder what my
life might have been
if that car of pasco's hadn't
but one thing i
don't have to wonder
about
[Music]
i know someday a
car will stop to pick
me up that i never thumbs
yes fate
or some mysterious
force can put the
finger on you or me
for no good reason at all
[Music]
you