Tanaka.
Ho!
Fugimoto.
Yo!
Iuanaga.
Here.
Mosashi.
Okamoto.
Here.
Kanakas.
The ones from Hawaii.
You know what they call
us mainlanders?
Kotonks.
The way they tell it,
if you rap on our heads,
it's like
hitting a coconut.
Hollow heads,
you know.
Kotonk, kotonk, kotonk.
Look where you're
going, will ya?
Ninety-day wonder.
Still got the original shine
on those bars.
Lieutenant Grayson
to see the adjutant.
He's not in, sir.
The colonel said
he'd see you himself.
Thank you.
You can go
right in, sir.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Grayson
reports for duty, sir.
At ease, lieutenant.
Welcome to Camp Shelby.
Thank you, sir.
This your first assignment since
receiving your commission?
Yes, sir.
Well, lieutenant,
it's a rough one.
The platoon you're taking over
is just ready to start training,
and, as you may have noticed,
our facilities are not
all that they might be.
We're short of officers,
short of equipment,
short of everything
except trainees,
and they're coming in
by the carload.
This is a brand-new outfit.
A new kind of outfit.
No precedent for it
except one battalion
that was activated in Hawaii
and they haven't been
tested yet.
What do you think
of the idea, lieutenant?
Well, sir, I'd like
to make a request.
What is it?
I'd like your permission, sir,
to put in for a transfer
to the 36th Division.
You see, sir,
I'm from Texas--
What has that
got to do with it?
Nothing, sir,
except that the 36th
is an old Texas
National Guard outfit,
and I've been in it
ever since I got in the Army.
That is,
until they sent me to OCS.
I never would have gone
if I'd thought--
Sir, I just took it for granted
that I'd go back to the 36th.
You're sure that's
the only reason you have
for wanting a transfer?
Yes, sir.
No objection to working
with the kind of troops
we have here?
Because they're Japs?
Oh, no, sir.
Nothing like that at all.
Now, let's get a couple
of things straight, lieutenant.
First, there's not
gonna be any transfer.
You're staying here.
Have you got that?
Yes, sir.
Second, they're not Japs.
They're Japanese Americans.
Nisei or, as they call
themselves, buddhaheads.
All kinds of buddhaheads,
lieutenant.
From Hawaii, Alaska, California,
New York, Colorado.
Yes, and even some
from Texas.
They're all American citizens,
and they're all volunteers.
Remember that.
And another thing.
We officers are referred to
as haoles not white men.
Any questions?
No, sir.
Report to your
company commander.
The sergeant major will
show you to his orderly room.
That'll be all, lieutenant.
Sorry to keep you waiting,
lieutenant.
Oh, Captain Solari.
That's right.
That's our regimental slogan.
"Go for broke"?
It's Pidgin English
for shoot the works.
Pull up a chair, lieutenant.
Thanks.
I'll be with you
in a minute.
Tell me, sir,
do you use live ammunition
in the rifle range?
A Jap's a Jap, eh?
All I know is they were
put under armed guard
in relocation centers last year.
Maybe the Army just had
some surplus barbed wire
they wanted to use up,
was that it?
The Army was facing an emergency
at the start of the war.
A possible invasion
by Japanese troops.
So all Japanese Americans
were evacuated
from the West Coast.
There was no loyalty check,
no screening, nothing.
If there were
any spies among them,
I can assure you they're
not in the 442.
Every man in this outfit
has been investigated,
reinvestigated
and re-reinvestigated.
Now, I suggest you start
getting acquainted.
Your platoon sergeant's
over in the supply room.
Ohhara.
O'Hara!
That's right. Takashi Ohhara.
Hey, wait a minute.
Come back here.
How long you been
in the Army, soldier?
Let me see now.
Maybe I-- I been inside, uh,
two, three months.
How long you been
inside, lieutenant?
Don't you know you're
supposed to hold your salute
till an officer returns it?
Oh, sure. Sometime forget.
"Sometime forget"
to say sir, too, don't ya?
Sometime.
Well, don't forget it anymore.
No, sir.
That's your own uniform?
Sir, that's the smallest size
he got, the supply sergeant.
Sir.
Well, roll those sleeves down.
I hold salute, sir.
Why are you wearing leggings
with a class A uniform?
To keep my pants up, sir.
Long like that.
Well, get 'em cut down.
Oh, yes, sir.
Payday I'll go see
the tailor, sir.
You'd better see somebody today
before I see you again.
All right, men.
All I wanna see
is backbones and elbows.
Come on.
And he made it.
Little Phoebe.
Pretty little Phoebe.
Watch that stuff,
huh?
Get your money
down, suckers.
It all rides.
Go for broke.
Gee, break 'em up.
Break 'em up.
New lieutenant outside.
Must be the one for us.
Oh, boy.
Eight feet tall
and mean like anything.
Number-one manini kind.
Chicken.
Well, the honeymoon's over.
Mix me up. All Nisei outfit.
How come haole officers?
That's just to make us
a little more miserable.
First, they pick out
the crummiest camp
in the United States.
Why'd you ever enlist?
That's what I wanna know.
Why? Because a wise guy
college man like you
snowed me under
with a lot of fancy talk.
You guys
from relocation centers.
Okay, you probably
got it better here.
But me, I was
on the outside. Iowa.
A free man. Knocking off
500 bucks a month.
Five hundred buck?
No.
Five hundred buck,
yeah.
Chick sexing.
I can look
at a day-old chick
and tell you if
it's a he or a she.
Ha, ha. Now, who'd want to know
that except another chick?
You pay for the poultry feed
and you'd wanna know.
A he ain't no good at all
when it grows up.
Only the shes.
How come chicken farmers
no can find out themselves?
Too bashful?
You funny man.
Chick sexing is a science.
It was developed in Japan,
and it's one field
where buddhahead gets a break.
Mean to say
ya never heard of it?
I just got as far
as the birds and the bees.
These college guys are sharp,
you know that?
Four years at USC
and he's a bona fide,
recognized fruit peddler.
Yes, sir.
A fruit peddler with
an architect's degree.
I could have got a job as
an architect if I kept trying.
Well, why didn't you?
It's just my eyes.
Couldn't handle
all that close work.
Yeah, eye trouble,
that's what it was.
All you need
is corrective glasses
to take the slant
out of your eyes.
Hey, kotonk.
Take it easy, huh?
Huh, Chick?
Come on, get it down.
Buck and a half.
One more, one more.
Boy, oh, boy.
You one lucky kotonk.
Wish I got
packages like that.
You and me both.
You send package?
Yeah. Hand me those cans,
will you?
Where you gonna send?
Brother in the Army
in Pacific?
Uh-uh.
Family in a relocation
camp in Arizona.
Arizona, U.S.A.
You think that chow
here is bad... Brother.
You can even get soap?
Oh, sure.
They've got a canteen
loaded with stuff.
Anything you want,
if you can get there
before they're sold out.
Yes, sir,
all the comforts of home.
And only one block
from the barracks
to the toilets and showers.
Barracks?
Everybody
all thrown together?
Got partitions.
Separate room
for each family.
My folks are lucky.
Only five of them
since I left.
Treat you like that,
hard to figure why a guy
volunteer for the Army.
We have to do something,
so we never get
a deal like that again.
We show 'em.
We show 'em us buddhaheads
good soldiers, good Americans.
That's the idea.
I hope it works.
Sure it works.
Already a lot of stuff
in newspapers about the 442.
Yeah, all we need now
is casualty lists.
Gee, that's a pretty girl.
What her name?
Terry.
Nice name.
Your wife?
Not yet.
Why you wait?
This is a great time to be
starting a family, isn't it?
You kotonks, funny guys.
Boy, if I had a girl like that,
they gotta draft me.
No volunteer.
No, sir, draft me
and drag me away.
Once more, once more.
Go for broke!
Once more, that's all I ask.
That's all!
Seven!
Let me see those dice.
Attention!
At ease.
Men, this is Lieutenant
Grayson, our platoon leader.
Pick up that money.
Pick it up.
Yes, sir.
Donation for the company fund,
sergeant.
Give it to Sergeant Ohhara.
Can he do that?
It's my money.
I want that man's name,
sergeant.
There's no talking
after the command at ease.
Yes, sir.
This man, no dog tags,
needs haircut, window unwashed,
uniforms hanging wrong way.
Haircut, shave,
bunk out of line, dog tags,
window, beer can on shelf,
dirty floor, dirty boots,
haircut, window,
bowl of milk on floor.
Bowl stolen from mess hall.
Brought cat into barracks.
Floor, boots, dog tag, haircut.
Dust on rafters, window,
haircut, dog tags, boots,
bunk out of line,
litter on floor, boots.
Forget the book, sergeant.
They're all on the list.
You men will fall out
for a speed hike
at 8:00 tonight.
Before that
I want this hutment GI'd.
Get them started
on it right away, sergeant.
Floors scrubbed, rafters dusted,
windows washed,
boots shined, bunks made.
I want those blankets
stretched so tight
that when you drop a quarter
on them it'll bounce.
I'll be back twice a day
from now on
with a pair of white gloves
and a quarter.
You're a chicken expert.
What do you make of him?
Bakatare!
What did he say?
I didn't hear anything, sir.
Bakatare.
What does that mean?
Sorry, sir.
I don't speak Japanese.
Boots, dog tag, window,
dust on rafters, floor, boots.
Boots, floor, boots.
Blankets not tight enough.
Shirt unbuttoned,
boots, window, floor.
All right.
Up and over.
Go back and try it again.
I'm gonna wait right here
till everybody makes it.
Hey, you guys, beat it, quick.
In combat, anything goes.
That's why we teach you
dirty tactics.
I will now demonstrate
a grip against which
there is absolutely no defense.
The sergeant will now
try to get free.
Well, sergeant?
You want me to try, sir?
Of course I want you to try.
Very well, sir.
Eyes right!
Eyes front!
That was the kiss of death,
brother,
the kiss of death.
Yeah, the big brass figures
were ripe.
I can smell
that salt air already.
Take another sniff, will ya,
and see if it's the Pacific.
Yeah, that's what I'm
sweating out.
You and me both.
Nobody wanna go Pacific but me.
Well, I keep trying.
Every time they ask
for volunteers--
Tommy, you have to speak
perfect Japanese.
It's for combat intelligence,
interpreters.
They don't want buddhahead
riflemen in the Pacific.
Why?
Look, Tommy,
a million guys fighting an enemy
that looks like us.
What if a GI sniper
spots you or me?
He see uniform.
Yeah, and probably figure
we're spies.
Sam, I tell you something.
I don't like talk about it,
but I'm gonna tell you.
Pearl Harbor day
the planes they come.
You can only read it.
I can see it.
Pretty soon, I go volunteer
for the 100th Battalion.
Too young.
By the 442 come up,
I volunteer again.
Too small.
Next time, I stand on my toes
a little bit.
Okay, I'm in.
They send us Europe.
Sure, I go and fight.
More better do I fight
the ones who bomb the islands.
It's the same enemy, Tommy.
Maybe for you.
Pearl Harbor day, two people
visit friends near Honolulu.
They both been killed.
My mother, Sam. My father.
Mail call.
Guchizaki.
Here.
Hey, this is from my brother
in the 100th Battalion.
Nawaguchi.
Mail call, Tommy.
You go.
No mail for Tommy.
Come on, close it up,
close it up.
Here's the list,
lieutenant.
Thanks, captain.
Nagashook-- Shooki.
William J.
Nishigoka.
Leonard S.
Uchigakiuchi.
Harry.
Ikagani.
Joseph T.
Kamakura.
Sam W.
Toyotomi.
Tomatsu.
Guchizaki.
Satoshi.
Shimabukarotenshugi.
Shima--
George W.
Thanks.
Fugimoto.
Thomas H.
Any scuttlebutt on where
this scow is taking us?
I was just gonna ask you,
lieutenant.
Hey, Sam, how you know so sure
we're going to England?
Because that's where
the line forms
for the invasion
of France.
And it's coming off
any day now.
That's us. Shock troops.
Just in time.
They used up
the 100th Battalion at Cassino.
But anyway,
it won't be the Pacific.
How do you know?
You ever hear
of the Panama Canal?
Hey, Sam, what you think?
Maybe so, huh?
Well, if it's the Pacific,
we've been sailing three days
in the wrong direction.
The navigator don't know.
Nobody knows.
Drives you nuts.
Oh, I'll get it.
Thank you, lieutenant.
For 20 years the Italian
people have been fed on bunk.
Their propagandists declared
that all of our people
look upon Italians
with contempt,
regarding them as a race
of hand organ men
and banana peddlers.
We know that such statements
are lies.
Racial prejudice is abhorrent
to our American concept
of democracy.
Naples with its old world
history, majestic Vesuvius,
the Castle of St. Elmo,
the famous churches,
the magnificent harbor,
second to none
in all the world.
These and many other
historic sights are of interest
to the soldier.
Take advantage
of this opportunity.
See as much as you can.
You've got a great chance
to do now,
major expenses paid,
what would cost you
a lot of your own money
after the war.
You'll want to poke around
in quaint,
out-of-the way places
and the only way to do that
is to walk.
Be sure to allow plenty
of time in Naples
so you can take it all in
at a nice leisurely pace.
Start your promenade
at the harbor.
The Italian practice
is to have a siesta hour
sometime between 1 and 4:00
in the afternoon.
If this custom remains in vogue
during occupational period,
you'll save time and patience
by confining your shopping
to other hours.
Mama, Mama.
Come on, come on.
Don't hog it all.
Let's go.
Off your seat
and on your feet.
Continuing our
tour of picturesque Italy,
we come to the Via Casilina,
which leads directly to Rome.
The districts around Rome
are full of places
of historical interest,
and transportation
is excellent.
Take a break.
Take 10.
Everybody rides
but the buddhaheads.
That's the 100th Battalion.
Masami.
Hey, Masami.
Hi, you paisan.
My brother. Him okay?
Not even a scratch.
He's a few trucks back.
Hey, haven't got
an extra top string, have you?
I don't think so.
Where you going?
Same place as you, paisan.
Haven't you heard?
We been attached
to the 442.
One big, happy family.
No kidding.
Ride on, boy. Here.
Top string.
Bakatare!
What was that?
I said very sorry.
Sorry, sir.
Within easy reach of Rome,
are the medieval towns
of Tuscany,
sleepy little villages,
scarcely touched
by the march of civilization.
Take 10.
Hello, Joe.
Oh, buon giorno, signorina.
...Americana...
No capisce.
Ooh. No capisce Italiana?
No, but I'd like to learn.
The door open?
The door. The door.
It's open, lieutenant.
Grazie, signorina.
The lady is gonna
mend this for me.
Call me when the word
comes down to move out.
Yes, sir.
You know, I got a hunch we're
coming into a bottle of vino.
Maybe.
Yeah, I just got a feeling
the lieutenant's
gonna take care of us.
Grazie.
Break's over.
Let's go.
All right. On your feet.
Lieutenant Grayson.
I forgot to tell him
we're moving out.
Holy mackerel.
What'll I do?
Close it up.
Si, signorina.
Per--
Per favore?
Bravo.
Grazie, signorina.
Salute.
Come again, per favore.
Amico. Friend.
No, I don't know him.
Your friend, huh?
Sì, Smith.
John Smith.
Capitano, John Smith.
Glad to meet ya, sir.
John Smith.
Don't tell me where you got
that good-conduct ribbon.
Let me guess.
How about some more vino, huh?
Darling.
That's my old outfit.
Where did you get this?
Who gave it to you?
John Smith.
John Smith, huh?
Is he still around here?
When did you see him last?
Oh, cosa dice.
I gotta find somebody
who can talk English.
I'll be right back.
Joe.
Grayson.
Your platoon's dug in
over there.
Come here a minute,
will ya?
I've got a message for ya
from the colonel.
He was up here inspecting
our positions.
The colonel?
That's right.
He said to tell you he was
particularly pleased
with the way your platoon
was deployed.
Thanks for covering up.
And now I'm supposed to say
"you're welcome"
and that's that
until the next time, eh?
There won't be
any next time.
Don't worry about that.
I'll tell ya when to leave.
You're such a stickler on
military courtesy for your men.
From now on, you and I are going
by the book, understand?
Yes, sir.
I don't mind telling you,
Grayson, if there was any chance
of getting a replacement
for you,
I'd have had you
court-martialed for this.
Ever since you joined
the outfit,
you've been the one man in this
company who's been out of step.
You'd better pick it up,
lieutenant, and pick it up fast,
or you're gonna find yourself
volunteering
for every dirty detail that
comes up. Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
That'll be all.
Did you do a good job,
lieutenant?
Where's Kamakura?
Sam?
Out looking for water,
lieutenant.
How do you like that?
Dying of thirst
in the middle of a river.
I wanna see him
the minute he gets back.
Yes, sir.
Hiya, paisan.
Masami.
Eddie.
Vino.
Fresh off the vine.
Salute.
Good, eh, paisan?
Free sample.
Thanks.
Eddie.
Eddie!
You stay here, Tommy.
Watch us. Come on.
Keep close to the wall.
Stay here.
One at a time.
Anybody home?
Keep me covered.
You okay, Masami?
Just a scratch.
Jerry intelligence officer.
They're great at disguises.
Hiya, paisan.
Shells would be
coming in a lot closer
if those Jerries were still
in that observation post.
One of them
was an officer you say?
Oh, yes, colonel, sir.
Well, you certainly earned that.
Take this over to S2, sergeant.
Yes, sir.
Too bad about that
100th Battalion man.
What'd they say
at the aid station
about the other one
who was wounded?
Million-dollar wound, sir.
They're sending him
back to Rome.
Good. Well, anytime you're
in the neighborhood, drop in.
Thank you, sir.
I mean that.
I wanna keep in close touch
with you men on the line.
They been treatin' you
all right?
Yes, sir.
You're sure now,
no complaints?
No, sir.
Well, good luck to you.
Sir, could I have
a word with you?
Well, of course.
At ease, lieutenant.
You remember, sir,
that I told you I came
from the 36th Division?
I remember it very well.
Well, sir, I just happened
to hear that the 36th
is somewhere in this area.
Was, lieutenant, they're way
up ahead of us now.
Oh. Oh, well,
in that case, sir--
Still like to get back
in the Texas Army, eh?
Oh, no, sir, I was just, uh,
hoping I'd get a chance
to visit them.
Well, I'll do better than that.
If we ever meet up
with the 36th,
I'll try and work out
a transfer.
Oh, thank you
very much, sir.
Not at all.
It'll be a pleasure.
That'll be all, lieutenant.
It's all right, paisan.
Maybe he know
we scared too, huh?
Gives a man a nice feeling
knowing you can always
go to the old man
if you're not gettin'
a fair shake, huh, lieutenant?
Sir, I feel bad
about forgettin' to call you
when we moved out of that town
this afternoon.
Look, you see the way
it happened--
Forget it. Forget it.
I can't.
It was all my fault.
And they might have had you
up for desertion.
But, it'll never get out.
The men'll keep it quiet.
I'll see to that, sir.
Thanks, thanks.
Squad leaders, up front.
Are you
from the 100th Battalion?
Yeah.
What happens when a man
gets hit?
Sometimes they yell.
Sometimes they don't.
Squad leaders don't last long.
I mean the medics.
How do they get to you?
Medics! Medics!
Get on the other side
of the road.
Hit it.
Let's go, boy.
Squad leaders,
up front.
Squad leaders, up front.
What are you waiting for,
sergeant?
I forgot.
Bakatare!
Hey, you'd better move,
Sam.
Maybe he gonna shake.
Have a good time, Frank.
How can I miss? Rome...
The greatest architecture
in the world.
Twenty-four-hour
passes.
Big-hearted,
ain't they?
I'm gonna see a lot of things
in the next 24 hours
I've dreamed about
all my life.
The Forum, Saint Peter's,
the Pantheon...
Any other outfit,
I bet they get three-day passes.
Yeah, and not just one man
at a time, either.
Ah, chick, chick, chick,
chick, chick, chick, chick.
Relax.
That reminds me, Tommy,
I hear we having
chicken for dinner.
No joke?
Yeah, I was talking
to one of the cooks.
Fried chicken.
Good, boy.
That's what I like best.
Not me.
You know
what I like best?
Barbecued pork, yes, sir.
There's nothing
like barbecued pork.
Especially the way I make it.
Mail call.
Jingu.
Hitrai.
Gutsizaki.
Mishima.
Here! Here!
Kawaquichi.
Signore, signorina,
l'amore, l'amore.
You like-a vino, Joe?
Ah, no,
he no for sale.
Tre litre.
Three bottles, Joe.
Not for nothin'.
Quattro, cinque,
sei, sette, otto, Joe.
Waste time.
Come on, paisan.
Fame.
Hungry. Hungry.
Okay, plenty meat on her.
No eat. No eat.
Oh, no, no.
Signore, signorina.
Papa. Mama.
Bambino.
Uno, due, tre, quattro.
Ohh.
Paisan, him kind of young
for papa, no?
Sì, sì, sì.
We wait.
Tre mesi.
Three months.
Arrivederci.
Nine bottles, ten.
No!
No, Papa.
Hey, Tommy.
Look what I got.
Lookie.
Here, help yourself.
Paisan too.
He no like cookies.
Maybe bambinos, eh?
Sure, go ahead.
Who that from, Sam?
Your mother?
Terry. Hey, remember
that town we took?
Suvereto? It was on a news
broadcast, coast to coast,
and they mentioned the 442.
No kidding?
I'm tellin' you.
And there've been newspaper
stories, lots of 'em.
The 100th is getting
the Presidential Citation
from General Mark Clark,
Sassetta, Hill 140.
Hey. Let me see that.
How you like that?
They gonna let your kid brother
leave relocation camp
and work on a farm.
Next month he gonna pick
sugar beets in Idaho.
Well, what do ya know.
He's been trying to swing
that deal for months.
Good boy.
All okay, nobody sick.
Oh, oh, excuse, Sam.
That's okay.
I'll read the rest to you.
"Honestly, Sam, you'd hardly
recognize the old homestead.
"Maybe it looks the same,
the barracks, the barbed wire,
"the MPs, but it isn't
the same anymore.
"Nothing's the same.
"Because everybody knows
what the 442 is doing.
"And what means most to me
is the change
in the kids in my class."
She teaches in camp school.
I know, I know. First grade.
"They were such sad
little people, never laughed,
"never made a sound.
"Today, I'm happy to say,
I have as noisy a classroom
as you'll find in America."
More better now,
eh, kotonk?
Looks that way, Kanaka.
Plenty better now.
"I miss you so very much,
my darling.
I can't find words to tell you
how dear you are to me. How..."
Arrivederci!
How was it?
How was Rome?
I'll see you tomorrow.
I gotta go to the C.P.
and pick up my pass.
End of the line. Everybody out.
So long, Bob, see ya later.
Take it easy now.
Just wanted to let you know
we're back, sir.
Oh, good.
You're just in time.
Oh, thanks.
Sergeant, have the driver report
to the motor pool, will ya?
Yes, sir.
He's got a full tank, sir.
All set to go
with the next batch.
I was all set to go too.
Change of orders.
We're going back on the line.
That's kind of rough.
Somebody was telling me
your folks came from Rome.
A little town near there.
Oh, well, I'll get
to see it someday.
Sure you will.
Hey, we met up with some of your
folks while you were gone.
Your old outfit.
The 36th!
They passed us
on their way back.
The Texas wonders
had all they could take
so they called in the 442.
Where'd they go?
The word is
they're being moved
to another theatre
of operations.
Is that straight?
Looks like you're stuck with us
for the rest of the war.
Guy gets in to fight the Japs
and winds up fightin' with 'em.
It's hot one
when you come to think of it.
Oh, I don't know.
A lot of us have parents who
were born in enemy countries.
Italian Americans,
German Americans--
That's different, sir,
and you know it.
Why?
Well, it's just--
The shape of their eyes?
Or is it the color
of their skin?
Tell the truth, sir,
wouldn't you rather be
with some other outfit?
If I knew of a better outfit,
but I don't.
Will that be all, sir?
You don't have to be
so formal.
It was your idea
to go by the book.
That was a long time ago.
I'll see ya later.
How was it, lieutenant?
Great.
I hope the supply sergeant
takes good care of your pig.
Yep. I sure hope
he feeds him good
so he'll be nice and fat
when we get back off the line.
Hey, Frank, look.
Look at that.
Must be
an old Roman villa.
Yeah, you can tell it's Roman
by those columns.
Rubble
from another war, huh?
It's hard to believe.
Over 2000 years old.
The battles that must
have been fought around here.
Napoleon, Charlemagne, Caesar,
Alexander the Great,
all the way back
to biblical times.
More better we fight
like biblical times.
I read in the Bible.
Your army pick number one man,
enemy pick number one man,
and by big fight, two men,
one killed, war over.
I nominate Lieutenant Grayson
for our side.
No. I wouldn't know
who to root for.
It's some kind of headquarters
all right,
and it looks like they're
gettin' ready to pull out.
Yeah, with all their maps
and records.
And one machine gun's
holding us back.
A little more to the right.
Thirty yards.
Got any more?
Be right back.
Thirty yards to the right.
Can you hear me?
Yeah, officer.
Come on.
Let's take a walk.
Hey, you over there.
Not you.
You take over,
Ohhara.
Keep firing that mortar.
Keep it going.
Where's that mortar?
I don't think these columns'll
be here for the next war.
How about that mortar?
Right away.
I gotta move it.
Hurry up with that mortar.
Okay. Okay.
They moved the gun.
Right. Fifty yards right.
Short. Short.
Give it another 50 yards.
Now over to the left,
just a little.
That's it! Pour it on!
Hold it! Hold it!
Cease-fire!
Let's go!
What kind of troops
are these? Chinese?
Japanese.
Didn't Hitler tell ya?
Japan surrendered and they're
fighting on our side now.
Well,
it beats walking.
Maybe walking through Italy
wasn't so bad.
Didn't you get
the latest latrinogram?
We're shipping out.
Shipping out?
And so we take leave
of sunny Italy
and sail the seven seas to--
To where?
My guess is the Pacific.
You really think so,
lieutenant?
Yeah, but don't worry
about it.
I haven't guessed right once
since I've been in the Army.
Watch that stuff.
Sorry.
Tommy.
Oh, hello, lieutenant.
I told you to go easy
on that leg.
Plenty okay now,
lieutenant.
Well, what did you leave
the hospital for?
I've been still, lieutenant.
Three weeks. Long time, sir.
Don't you realize
officially you're AWOL?
I don't know whether
to put you in for a Silver Star
or have you court-martialed.
Gotta leave hospital, sir.
Big rumor, 442 going Pacific.
Me plenty sad sack
get left behind, huh?
Sir, maybe we still
gonna fight Japan.
You think so, maybe?
No, Tommy.
It's definitely France.
Bad cough.
I catch him in a hospital.
More better now. Sea air good.
Well, goodbye, lieutenant.
Goodbye, Tommy.
You are about to play
a personal part
in pushing the Germans
out of France.
Just west of the Riviera
district in southern France
lies the port of Marseilles.
You will be fortunate indeed
if you are stationed
in this fascinating city.
However, the chances are
you will be located
in the provinces.
Rooms with private bath
are still de luxe
in provincial towns, and you
won't always have steam heat,
but there are
many compensations.
For instance, your breakfast
will be brought to your bedroom
without extra charge.
First class on French trains
ranks with our extra-fare
trains,
second ranks
with our parlor car
and third class is like
our ordinary-day coach.
If French coaches are less
comfortable than ours,
remember that they are also
less expensive.
It all evens up.
Who's got
the time?
Two-twenty, sir.
Thanks.
Who do you think that I oughta
see about it, sir?
S1 personnel.
They assign
the new replacements,
but they're not gonna put two
brothers in the same platoon.
My kid brother's got a way
with him, sir,
and he's just liable
to talk them into it.
Bad enough being
in the same regiment,
but the same platoon...
Yeah, I'd hate for my folks
to get two telegrams
from the War Department
on the same day.
Where are
you going?
Think I'll ride
with my platoon, sir.
You're overdoing the "sir"
business, lieutenant.
I keep forgetting.
And here I've been an officer
for two hours and 20 minutes.
How are you doing, Grayson?
Hey, Sam,
you think Terry okay?
Sure. It was just
a little cold.
I feel more better
when the mail catch up.
Long time he no get mail.
I wonder how my brother's
making out.
Me too.
I guess he work
on the sugar-beet farm
already two, three weeks.
Hey, Ohhara,
we want the mail.
Write your congressman.
Ten-hut.
As you were.
Carry on, men.
How do you like that?
Do they give a commission
to one of us buddhaheads?
No, they give it
to the mick.
Ohhara,
the fighting Irishman.
Faith, and you can
say that again.
Now, get along
with your blarney.
I've got something
to tell you.
At ease.
Let's be having
a little military courtesy.
Yes, sir.
I, uh, haven't
been assigned yet,
but it looks like I'll be
taking over another platoon.
I probably won't be seeing
much of you guys.
I just wanted to say, well,
so long.
He gonna make
good platoon leader.
Yeah, while he lasts.
He's welcome to them bars.
Sam, look at those buildings.
Seventeenth century.
I'm looking
at that bakery.
Go ahead, Tommy.
I'll keep an eye on the pig.
Stick close to the train,
you guys.
I'm tired of rounding up
stragglers.
Bakatare.
What'd he say?
Oh, that's Japanese
for-- For "thank you."
They're very polite.
Pardon me. Pardon me.
Pardon me!
Hello, baby.
When did you learn that song?
When?
That's right.
When did you learn it?
Learn what?
The-- The song. Song.
No, no, no.
When you learn song?
Ah, last week.
Soldiers.
Thirty-sixth Division?
I think so.
Big T.
Are they still here?
No. Parti. Yesterday.
Au revoir.
Well, well.
The ambassador from Texas.
Good afternoon, sir.
You know, lieutenant, I had you
down as a determined man,
but I didn't think you had
enough drag
to get the whole darned outfit
transferred to the 36th.
Transferred?
That's right, lieutenant.
We've been attached
to the 36th Division.
I guess that makes us
honorary Texans.
Well, fan my brow.
Keep an eye out
for cattle-rustlers, partner.
Well, what do you know
about that?
I thought you'd be pleased,
lieutenant.
This is the man we've been
looking for, major.
One of the new combat
commissions to replace him.
Well, there's one
in his platoon, sir. Ohhara.
Good. He can take over.
Take over
my platoon, sir?
We've had a request
for a liaison officer
to work out of
36th headquarters.
Someone who can get along
with them
and knows the 442 thoroughly.
But, sir, I've always been
on the line.
Do you think I have
the qualifications
for a headquarter's job?
I think you'll make good.
When a man wants anything
as badly as you've wanted this.
But sir, I don't want this.
Remember, I told you
I just wanted to visit them.
I've got a lot of friends
in the 36th.
None of them at headquarters,
I take it.
I couldn't arrange to have you
sent back to your platoon.
Colonel Pence--
Your orders will be issued
immediately.
All aboard!
Texas special!
Dallas, Forth Worth, Galveston,
Houston and all points south.
Yeah, man!
Ya-hoo!
Arrivederci.
Oh, no, old boy.
So long.
So long, Mademoiselle.
Don't forget to write.
How do you like
that Texas artillery, strangers?
Stranger?
Man, I'm from Texas myself.
Well, pull up a chair
and have a mint julep.
That's mighty neighborly,
friend,
but we're heading back
towards town.
Another posse's
gonna spell us for a bit.
Tommy's sure anxious
to get back to that town
where he left Paisan.
Ain't love wonderful?
Howdy, stranger.
Aloha.
There's only one thing I don't
like about these buddhaheads.
They don't dig 'em long enough.
Hello, my friend.
He's here, the little Paisan.
He's here.
Paisan.
Hello, Paisan.
You looking good, boy.
You're looking wonderful,
Paisan.
Come on, Paisan.
You're beautiful, Paisan.
Nice pig.
He miss you much.
I miss him too.
Oh, thanks for taking care
of him.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you.
Y-you are very kind.
What's the matter?
You don't smoke?
Yes, I smoke.
I was hoping maybe something
to eat for the children.
Chocolate, crackers, anything.
They have so little,
so little to eat.
I don't have anything to eat.
Trade the cigarettes.
Two packs.
You can get a couple of chickens
for that.
Not here.
No chickens left. Nothing.
All right.
I'll come back later.
I hate to ask.
It won't be much.
All we get is K rations.
It will be a feast
for them.
I wish I could get
something better.
Well, uh,
see you later.
Goodbye, my friend.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
How wonderful for the children.
Kanakas.
The ones from Hawaii.
Let's stop a minute, huh?
I won't be long.
Throw those bums out.
Yeah!
Go on, get up there.
No, they're doing fine.
Come on.
Hula-hula, Kaz.
Kaz.
Hey.
Whoa!
Would you like some wine?
Ah, merci. Merci.
These men, the little ones,
they are really Japanese?
Hey, shorty, she wants to know
if you're Japanese.
I guess we can
let her in on it, huh?
They're our new
secret weapon.
Twilight fighters.
Twilight fighters?
Yeah. The Army gives them shots
to make them turn yellow, see.
They send them out
in the evening,
just as the sun's going down.
The enemy can't see 'em
in that light. Get the idea?
That guy's been looking
for trouble all night.
If he makes one more crack,
I'll--
Tommy! How are you?
Lieutenant Grayson!
How's the leg?
Fit like a fiddle.
Hiya, fellas.
Howdy, Grayson.
Who's your friend,
the one with all the stripes?
They don't care who they make
platoon sergeant anymore.
How about having a refill?
Thanks, Frank.
I wanna say hello
to my old platoon sergeant.
I trained under him.
Be right back.
Culley!
Grayson!
How are you?
Lieutenant Grayson.
Yeah, how about that?
How about a drink?
Great. Great.
Come on,
there's room down here.
That guy would be a buddy
of Grayson's.
Five to one he don't come back
for that drink.
Get it up.
They tell me you really
got it made.
What is this liaison racket?
Oh, it varies, from a soft snap
to an extra soft snap.
Thank you.
Tomorrow I'm moving out
with you.
How do you like that?
Back with the old platoon.
You mean, I gotta take orders
from you?
No. I don't mess around
with you dogfaces.
I'll be with
the artillery observer.
You're getting your artillery
from the 442,
and he's never worked
with them before.
They're sending us up
without our own artillery?
Just the Japs?
They're a good outfit, Culley.
Plenty good.
Practically winning the war
single-handed from what I hear.
Japs.
Let's get outta here,
huh?
Yeah, I could use
a little fresh air.
You win, Chick.
Japs in a Texas division.
Man, oh, man.
Come here a minute.
Culley, they're not Japs.
Huh?
They're Japanese Americans.
Nisei, or, if you prefer,
buddhaheads.
But not Japs.
They don't like it
and neither do I.
What are you,
a Jap-lover or something?
I said they're not Japs.
I'm warning ya, Culley.
You're what?
Warning ya.
Lieutenant, that gold bar
looks real sweet on you,
but I do believe you're getting
a little big for your britches.
I can always
take the bar off.
Any time you say.
"Okara."
Yo!
"Misoka."
Here! Here!
"Nishigoka."
Hey!
No letters?
Keep your pants on.
Come on, snap it up.
"Kiri."
Yo-ho!
"Kamakura."
Oh, here, here.
I take it.
Cookies.
Ho-ho!
"Ikagani."
Here!
One cookie.
Hey, look.
How you like that.
Two sets.
I go see Masami.
Woo-hoo!
Two sets.
Sam, Sam.
Wiki-wiki.
I'm wiki-wikiing
as fast as I can.
Anything from my brother?
No, all from relocation center.
Sugar report from Terry.
"Dear Sam, I hate to start out
a letter this way,
but I think it best to get
the bad news over with first."
Her cold,
she no get better, huh?
No. Terry's okay.
Your mother been get sick?
Your father?
It's my brother.
He been lose his job
on the farm?
Yeah, him and a couple
of his buddies.
A gang beat them to a pulp
and said they'd lynch them
if they ever came back.
Why they do that? Why?
Why? Because they've got
slant eyes.
That's a crime in some places,
didn't you know that?
How do ya like that?
We're good enough
to carry rifles,
but we're not good enough
to pick sugar beets.
Take it easy, Sam.
Sure, sure,
take it easy.
Take it lying down.
Go on, beat it.
Blow.
Ain't I been telling you?
Suckers, that's what we are.
Chick, chick, chick,
chick, chick, chick.
How would you like
a dental appointment?
Let's go, boy.
Katonk.
Break it up.
If you're looking
for a scrap,
you won't have long
to wait.
We've been alerted.
Pull your tents down
and move out.
Pull 'em down?
We just put 'em up.
The men Lt. Grayson moved out
with have been surrounded.
The whole battalion?
What's left of 'em.
Grayson's okay so far.
Artillery observer got hit
and he took over.
Just so the lieutenant
is safe.
Him
and his buddy,
his dear old
platoon sergeant.
What's up with Sam?
He just got
some bad news.
He's not the only one.
They're gonna send
the new replacements up on line
as soon as they arrive,
the batch my kid brother's in.
Eighteen years old.
Hey, Grayson!
Medic!
Where's the medic?
There he is!
Over here, Joe!
I found a full one.
Thanks, pal.
Give me a slug of that,
will ya?
Hey, Grayson!
Look out!
You okay, Culley?
Where's that
Jap artillery?!
Where is it?!
Wildcat six.
This is Wildcat two.
Fire mission. Over.
Fire mission point.
Fire mission point, Fox-Able-
Easy-Baker-Mike-Charlie,
and point, King-Sugar-Charlie-
Love-Able-How.
Wildcat two.
This is Wildcat six.
Stand by.
One round smoke on way.
Can't get a thing
outta this one, sir.
We got enough
from the others.
Send him over
to division headquarters.
Get anything?
Yes, sir.
Added to what we already know,
I can give ya
a pretty clear picture.
Good.
It's all dense woods.
Those roads on the map
are just forest trails,
and Jerry has roadblocks
on all of 'em.
The men are surrounded
on three sides
by elements of the, uh,
338th Infantry Division,
the 198th Fusilier Battalion
and the 202nd
Mountain Battalion.
To the northeast--
Well, let me see it
on the map, captain.
Well, starting here,
the Germans are dug in
on a continuous line
all the way around to here.
There's a gap here...
and one here that I know of,
but they're covered by machine
guns with interlocking fire.
There's a steep ridge here
that dominates this sector.
It's almost straight up
on both sides,
and they have a strong force
sitting up on top.
How far away from
here is the lost battalion?
Well, I'd say
a thousand yards.
They're just about here.
We'll have troops within
striking distance tonight.
All right, Ohhara,
this is your spot.
Good luck.
Come on, shake a leg,
will ya?
This don't make sense.
Sticking our necks out for guys
like that buddy of Grayson's.
That sergeant, that's the kind
who ganged up on your brother.
We get to the lost battalion,
that sergeant gonna change
his mind about us buddhaheads.
Plenty people already we change,
eh, Sam?
Keeps up like Terry
been writing letters,
by and by
we gonna have it good.
You bet. Yes, sir.
Good thing
you read me letters,
or maybe I go get
like Chick.
It's rough.
It's plenty rough.
But we know
what's it all about.
You bet.
More better we
go for broke, yes, Sam?
That's about it,
Tommy.
"More better we
go for broke."
Ohhara. Ohhara!
Is it bad?
Million-dollar wound.
Luck of the Irish.
Medics.
Medics!
Let's go.
I'm glad you have someone
to lean on.
I don't seem
to recognize you.
Have you been back
to any of the services?
No, Father.
I'm not Catholic.
You're not?
Different kind of rosary.
I'm Buddhist, Father.
I'll be here
if you want me.
We're gonna try
to make contact.
The Piper Cub's calling
the shots for artillery.
They're trying
to shoot us in some rations.
That'll be
a big help.
Sukiyaki and rice.
I could use
another man.
Well, the Piper Cub pilot
says there's at least a hundred
of 'em on this ridge.
And they'll be shooting
right down our throats
if we try to come up
from either side.
Our engineers have been cutting
through a road
on top of the ridge
so we can bring up a tank.
They're about here now.
Once that tank
gets within range--
When will that be?
Hard to say, sir.
It's slow going.
Minefields all over the place.
Tell division headquarters
I'm on my way back, will you?
The Jerries have been
tapping the wires, sir.
Some of them
speak perfect English.
Wildcat three.
Sergeant Yasugomoto
speaking.
Wildcat three,
this is Wildcat four.
Come in,
Wildcat three.
Sergeant Yasugomoto
speaking.
Wildcat three.
Sergeant Yasugomoto
speaking.
Good idea, sergeant.
Thank you, sir.
It's just that good old
Yankee know-how.
Watch out!
If I was a Jerry
on the end of this ridge
and a tank got close enough
to fire point-blank,
I'd take off
like a ruptured duck.
Yeah.
Right over the side
of the ridge.
There oughta be somebody
down there to meet 'em.
That's what I was thinking.
Let's go.
Hey, sergeant.
Sergeant.
Where's Lieutenant Ohhara's platoon?
This is it.
We're your
new replacements.
Ohhara's the name.
Another suntanned Irishman.
Come on.
Ohhara.
They're Japs.
Hey, knock it off,
will ya?
What's
the password?
Dipsy doodle,
that's it.
That was it,
a week ago.
Let's have
that password.
One. Two.
Bakatare.
Come on out.
Make 'em give you
the right password.
You ever hear a Jerry try
to pronounce a Japanese word?
If that's not
a buddhahead, I'll...
You'll what?
Sam, Chick, Tommy.
A whole battalion's lost,
and we gotta find them.
Man, I never thought I'd be
so happy to see a bunch of Japs.
Pardon me. Japanese.
I mean, Nisei.
No, that ain't it.
What is it, Grayson?
Buddhaheads.
Okay. Okay.
Buddhaheads, huh?
That's right.
He sure is touchy
about that.
One time,
he even slugged me.
Slugged you, huh?
Did you hear that,
Chick?
Where's the rest
of your outfit, lieutenant?
Back there about a mile.
But it took us hours
to get here.
On our bellies,
most of the way.
When do we start?
Not enough of us would make it
to do 'em any good.
What do we do,
lieutenant?
That's up to you, Sam.
I'm strictly
a liaison officer.
Skirmish line
up the hill.
Skirmish
line up the hill.
Tell me something, Sam.
What does bakatare mean?
Well, freely translated:
You're a heel.
A stupid jerk and a heel.
That was putting it mildly.
Go for broke!
Grenade!
Aah!
Look out, Tommy!
Is that all there were?
They went thataway,
partner.
Go for broke!
Yahoo!
Any of you guys
want a cigarette?
Bye, you buddhaheads.
So long.
Ride 'em, cowboy.
Bye! Thanks a lot, Jack.
See you in Berlin.
Look out for that mademoiselle.
Take it easy.
So long.
Thanks.
Au revoir.
Goodbye, you all.
So long.
I'll be seein' ya.
Aloha, partner!
So long.
Attaboy.
See you in Paris.
Battle honors.
By order
of the secretary of war,
in the name of the president
of the United States,
as public evidence of
deserved honor and distinction,
the 442nd Regimental
Combat Team
is cited for outstanding
accomplishment in combat.
The gallantry
and esprit de corps
displayed
by their officers and men
in bitter action
against a formidable enemy
exemplify the finest traditions
of the Armed Forces
of the United States.