This subtitle is free.
OK to Translate.
Subtitles By:
MightyMike77020
All's well!
ᴬˡˡ'ˢ ʷᵉˡˡ!
♪ All's well! What's
a rainy day? ♪
♪ Never mind that cloud. ♪
♪ Behind that cloud
you'll find a golden ray. ♪
♪ All's well! Laugh
your fears away. ♪
♪ See the light
ahead. Right ahead. ♪
♪ There's a moonlit
night ahead. ♪
♪ Everyone, come on
have fun. All's well! ♪
Why do they make
me sing that song?
The poet who wrote
it was certainly wrong.
It's bright ahead.
The go right ahead.
I'd rather go home
and go right to bed.
All's well!
My feet are wet and
my bunions ache,
and yet I've to keep wide awake,
all night!
ᵃˡˡ ⁿⁱᵍʰᵗ!
♪ I wake folks up to tell
them things are all right! ♪
♪ And, all's well!
What's a rainy day? ♪
♪ Never mind that cloud. ♪
♪ Behind that cloud
you'll find a golden ray. ♪
♪ All's well! Laugh
your fears away. ♪
♪ See the light
ahead. Right ahead. ♪
♪ There's a moonlit
night ahead. ♪
♪ Everyone, come
on have fun. All... ♪
A-a-a-a-all's w-w-w-well!
What's a rainy...
Day?
Awww-ohhhh!
The king has visitors.
Do you know they're
signing a wedding contract?
There's a giant on the beach!
There, there's
a giant out there!
Your Majesty.
Thank you, your Majesty.
Marriage contract.
King Little `ahem` of Lilliput.
Does this 5th day of November
1699 give the hand of his daughter.
Princess Glory
to Prince David
son of Bombo.
King of Blefuscu!
Quite in order, fine.
King...
Bom-bo!
Well we did it, you little
rascal, you. We did it.
Yes we, we certainly
did, didn't we?
Just a couple of old
dag cupids, I think!
Your Majesty, the wedding things
arrrrre here.
There's a giant on
the beach! There's a gi...
Let me go! Let me go! There's a
giant on the beach! There's a gi...
Exquisite taste, exquisite!
Rrroses, frrreesia, rrrrhododendrons,
rrrranunculus, snapa' drrragons, und' daisies.
Ahh!
They're pretty
posies, aren't they?
Beautiful blooms, beautiful!
Oh!
May I?
Oh, but please do!
Magnificent!
Oh! A masterpiece!
Vanilla. Wow!
♪ Faithful remember,
that whatever I do, ♪
♪ I'm always faithful, my love. ♪
♪ Faithful, with all my
soul and thankful for you, ♪
♪ who came from heaven above. ♪
♪ We'll dance tonight together, ♪
♪ on a world with me we'll find. ♪
My only little daughter.
I dread losing her.
Huh, buck up there old boy.
You're not losing a daughter.
♪ So I'll be faithful and faithful as I ♪
You're gaining a son.
My son!
David.
♪ Promise to be, ♪
♪ and you'll be mine, ♪
♪ all mine. ♪
Hmm. Lovely melody.
Yes, we like it.
That is Faithful.
The song of Lilliput.
It will be played at
the wedding tomorrow.
Of course. Of course.
Oh! What's that, Faithful?
Oh, no, no! Forever!
The song of Blefuscu must
be played at the wedding.
But Bombo, Faithful is
always played at our weddings.
It, it's tradition, sir.
And it's very pretty.
Yes, yes, I know.
Pleasant little ditty.
Oh but hardly appropriate
for this great occasion.
But Forever! There's
a song for you! Ho, ho!
Uh-uh, Faithful will be played.
Bah! Twaddle. Absolute
twaddle. It must be Forever!
Faithful.
Forever!
Fᵃⁱᵗʰᶠᵘˡ.
It will be Forever, or
there will be no wedding!
No wedding? But the cake
and the pretty flowers and..
Oh Bombo, you'll love Faithful.
♪ Di di the de dum. ♪
♪ Tthe de di doe doe. ♪
Ahh!
♪ Di doe the dee...
Oh whas som matter!
teach you!
Why this is an outrage!
That it!
IT'S WAR!
There's a giant on the beach!
Oh whas som matter!
IT'S WAR!
War. tsk-tsk-tsk Woe
is me. Woe is me.
I found a mountain, your Majesty. I
found it! It was man, a man mountain!
War isn't nice.
It was, was this big!
No, no. It was this big!
People are hurt in wars.
He's as big, as big
as, as,.. Big as, as, as..
Wait your Majesty!
Bombo can't frighten me. No sir.
Speak up. Don't stand
there like a nincompoop!
I'm trying to tell you
that there's a giant!
When I get my dandruff up,
then look out.
But Glory, poor little Glory.
Don't look now
gentleman, but it's war.
War? Whoopee!
♪ Forever, forever, ♪
♪ there won't be
anyone but you. ♪
♪ Remember I'm true, my sweet. ♪
♪ Forever, forever, ♪
♪ you'll share in
everything I do, ♪
♪ and keep smiling
through, my sweet. ♪
♪ I'll have just you
here in my heart, ♪
♪ and I'll trust you
though we're apart. ♪
♪ So, forever, forever, ♪
♪ my guiding
angel you will be. ♪
♪ So always have faith in me. ♪
Shh!
- Shh!
War. Ha. Ha. Rolls
off my back like a duck.
- But, but I’m, but I'm trying to tell ya!
- Speak up.
I'm telling ya
there's, there's a...
What's on your mind?
- I said..
- Speak up, man.
There's a giant on the beach!
For heaven's sake,
Gabby. Button your mouth.
Can't you see I have
a war on my hands?
Be off with you. Shoo!
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
A war?
Do you suppose he
could be a, a spy?
Or they outta be with
patient I should think.
Who's a spy? Who's a spy?
The giant on the beach!
A giant? Giant? Why
don't you tell me things?
Do something. Don't stand
there. Go. Sic the dogs on him.
Fetch him to me at once!
Wake up! Wake up!
There's a giant on the
beach! A giant on the beach!
Wake up, I tell ya! Wake up!
There's a giant on the beach!
Giant on the beach! Giant on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up!
Giant on the beach!
There's a giant on the beach!
A giant on the beach!
Wake up, I tell ya! Wake up!
There's a giant on the beach!
Wake up on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up!
Giant on the beach!
There's a giant on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up!
A giant, on the beach?
A giant?
On the beach?
T-T-There's a, there's
a, there's, there's a...
Giant on the beach!
Giant! Ohhh!
It's open!
A giant?
A giant on the beach!
Giant!
Giant! On the
giant! On the beach!
I said, "there's a GIANT
ON THE BEACH!"
Bring cables and tools.
Bring horses and mules.
Bring snipers and clippers,
ladders and spools.
Bring derricks and rigs,
and bring pulleys a jig.
Bring whatchamacallit. Little and
big. A thingamathud. A thingamajig.
And all kinds of things
and stuff like that there.
Follow me!
Shh!
Hmm!
Shh! Quiet.
We're almost there.
Whoa!
Wh, where, where is it?
I don't know,
but it was right here.
Here?
Oh yeah? Well where is it now?
Well ah, ah, I
can't understand it.
It was right here.
Honest.
Giant, huh!
Dragging us out into
the dead of the night.
Yeah, chasing wild geese.
Gabby must have
been seeing things.
Maybe it just got
up and flew away.
Yeah, and breathing fire.
Look out Gabby. Your
giant's gonna bite ya!
Hey, hey fellas, maybe
it was me he saw.
Look. I'm a giant! I'm a giant!
Psst!
Psst! Psst! Psst!
Eh, listen.
Oh!
I-I... t-t-told ya
that there was
a-a-a-a gi, a-a giant
on the b-b-b-b-beach.
- And well, there he is.
- Eh?
He said,"THAT'S THE THE
GIANT ON THE BEACH!"
Shh!
There isn't a moment to waste.
Every last man must
do all that he can.
Work with the greatest of haste.
So bind up its hands, its
arms, its chest, its neck, its feet!
And I'll do the rest.
Let's go!
Quiet.
- Quiet.
Eh?
Oh!..
Shh!
Careful!
Up!
Put him there! No! No!
Here! Don't be afraid man!
Aw! Aw! He got me! He got
me! Aw! Aw! Help! He's killing me!
I don't want to die! Help!
Help! He's killing me! Help!
Hey!
Well, what are you rubes
waiting for? Tie him up!
Get the wheel. Come
on, roll in the plate.
Bring pegs to hold him. Bring
jacks, tacks, cleats, an axe.
All kinds of things
and stuff like that there!
Hip!
Hiccup!
Come on now! Let's go!
Heave, ho!
Up! Up men! Up! Up!
Back up Billy! Come on, Nicky.
Steady there, Bessie!
Back up, Billy!
Hip! Hip!
Ho!
Five, and six, and seven,
and eight, and nine, and...
Oh!
Ready there below?
Let's go!
Giddy up, Susie! Giddy up!
Lower away men!
Careful! Careful!
All set below!
Okay, let's go!
Giddy up! Tally ho!
Giddy up!
Come on Henry. Giddy up!
Come on!
Oh-ah! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Tighten the ropes there!
Not so fast! Not so fast!
Hurry up, there!
Slow down!
Get the wheels past!
Phew! I don't know what they
would do around here without me!
Oh! Ahh!
Heave! Heave!
Zzz.
Faithful was always
played at our weddings...
Zzz.
Faithful.
Your, your, your Majesty.
Huh?
I've got the giant.
The giant. Oh,
yes, yes, the gi...
Well bring him in. Bring him in.
Okay. Okay.
Your Majesty, I don't
think he'd fit in here.
Oh you don't, huh? So it's
not good enough for him, hmm?
Well where is he?
Out there, your Majesty.
Now, then.
Humph! Not good enough for him!
Well, where is he?
From here, on!
Call out the guards,
the Army, the Navy,
women and children
first, I'll see you later.
Search him men.
He may be armed.
Ow.
Yow!
Ohhhh!
Ugh! Oh!
I don't like it out!.. Help!
Your Majesty! Let me in!
Your Majesty!
Let me in!
Let me in! Let me in!
Let me in! Let me in! Help! I
don't like this! Wah-haa-haa!
Ohhhh!
Get back there.
Ooh! Let me go! Help! Help!
Let me go! I don't wanna die!
- Well, well. What have we got here?
- Help! Put me down! Help!
Help! Help! Don't
eat me! Don't eat me!
Help! I won't taste good.
I'll give you indigestion.
- A man. A tiny man.
- Let me go! Help! Help!
You can't do this to me.
I've got a wife and kids.
Millions of kids.
Hold on there, mate.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Help! Put me down! Help! Help!
Drop that! Drop that!
Well, another one. Who are you?
Who me? What?
I'm king around here.
Guards! Guards! To the turrets!
Archers! Surround the giant!
Surround the giant! Guards!
Well.
Oof!
Huh! You'll pay for this.
Ready!
Aim, fire. Aim, fire.
Aim!
Fire, fire, fire.
How do you like that?
Want some more?
All right, let her go!
It's Bom
bo!
Close the gates! Man the
battlements! Defend the city!
We're attacked! We're attacked!
Stop! Stop you swine!
Get back to your posts!
Get back there and fight!
We of Blefuscu are not...
Afraid of anything.
Well, where's everyone gone?
This is no way to
treat a harmless visitor.
Look Gabby, we've
won! Gabby? Gabby?!
See Gabby? They've
gone. Yes, sir. Scared stiff.
Hello there.
Come now, don't let
my size frighten you.
You, your Majesty. Surely
you're not afraid of me?
Uh-uh.
Well, good. Then let
me present myself.
My name is Gulliver, your
Majesty. Lemuel Gulliver,
a shipwrecked sailor.
At your service.
Well, welcome to
Lilliput, Mr., Mr. Gulliver.
Er,.. Mr. Gulliver, can you fight?
Well your Majesty, I
can lick anybody my size.
Ah, splendid, splendid!
I don't think Bombo will give us any
further trouble while you're around here.
No sir!
He's on our side, Gabby.
He's on our side!
There's nothing to fear!
The man mountain's on our side!
♫ All's well! ♫
♫ What's a rainy day? ♫
♫ Never mind that cloud. ♫
♫ Behind that cloud ♫
♫ you'll find a golden ray. ♫
♫ All's well! ♫
♫ Laugh your fears away. ♫
♫ See the light ahead. ♫
♫ Right ahead. ♫
♫ There's a moonlit night ahead. ♫
♫ Everyone, come on have fun. ♫
♫ All's well! ♫
♫ All's well! All's well! All's well! ♫
♫ It's a hap-hap-happy day. ♫
♫ Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay. ♫
♫ For you and me for us and we. ♫
♫ All the clouds have rolled away. ♫
♫ It's a hap-hap-happy day. ♫
♫ Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay. ♫
♫ The sun shines bright
and the world's all right ♫
♫ it's a hap-hap-happy day ♫
♪ it's a hap-hap-happy day. ♪
♪ Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay. ♪
♪ For you and me...
♫ for us and we ♫
ᵃˡˡ⁻ᵗʰᵉ⁻ᶜˡᵒᵘᵈˢ⁻ʰᵃᵛᵉ⁻ʳᵒˡˡᵉᵈ⁻ᵃʷᵃʸ.
♫ All the clouds have rolled away. ♫
♫ It's a hap-hap-happy day. ♫
♫ Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay. ♫
♫ The sun shines bright
and the world's all right ♫
♫ it's a hap-hap-happy day. ♫
♫ Four and twenty sunbeams ♫
♫ are dancing round my face. ♫
♫ Four score and twenty more ♫
Come on, where are those buttons?
♫ Are dancing every place. ♫
♪ It's a hap-hap-happy day. ♪
♪ Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay. ♪
♪ You can't go wrong
if you sing that song. ♪
♪ It's a hap-hap-happy day. ♪
♫ Four and twenty sunbeams ♫
♫ are dancing round my face. ♫
♫ Four score and twenty more ♫
♫ are dancing every place. ♫
♫ You can't go wrong
if you sing that song. ♫
♫ It's a hap-hap-happy day! ♫
Out of soap! Push him up!
Hotta' towel! Shesa' coming up!
Hey look out! Grab
it! Pull those! Nab it!
Take it off! Get it off.
Ow! it's burning me.
You understand that not
until that giant is removed
can our forces taste
the sweet fruits of victory!
Now then, it is up to you to carry
this message to my spies in Lilliput.
Be off! And may luck be with you!
Too-da-loo.
Get going!
Your Majesty,
I'm sorry the little
Princess isn't with us.
Yes, too bad. Too much
excitement for one day.
♪
Dear spies:
Get rid of that giant or else...
cordially yours king Bombo
♫ There are bluebirds
in the moonlight. ♫
♪ Silly idea, bluebirds
in the moonlight. ♪
♫ But that's how I feel
when I'm with you. ♫
♫ There are night
owls in the daylight. ♫
♪ Silly idea, night
owls in the daylight. ♪
♫ Or maybe my heart is saying,
whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo! ♫
♪ Who is the one for us? ♪
♪ You. It's what
you've done for us. ♪
♫ There are bluebirds
in the moonlight. ♫
♫ Silly idea, bluebirds
♫ But that's how I feel
when I'm with you. ♫
♫ There are bluebirds
in the moonlight. ♫
♫ Silly idea, bluebirds
♫ But that's how I feel
when I'm with you. ♫
♫ There are night
owls in the daylight. ♫
♫ Silly idea, night
♫ Or maybe my heart is
saying, whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo! ♫
♫ Who is the one for us? ♫
♫ You, that's what
you've done for us. ♫
Woops!
♫ There are bluebirds
in the moonlight. ♫
Wow.
♫ Silly idea, bluebirds
in the moonlight. ♫
♫ But that's how I feel
when I'm with you. ♫
♫ I'm that way about you! ♫
Gulliver's Thunder Machine.
Zzz, burr, beep, squeak.
Zzz, burr, beep, squeak...
Gulliver's thunder machine
♫ Come home again, come home. ♫
♫ Wherever you may be. ♫
♫ Come home again you sailor man, ♫
♫ sailor man. ♫
♫ Home again to the sea. ♫
♪ I hear a dream all day. ♪
♪ A dream that calls to me. ♪
♪ Come home again you sailor man, ♪
♪ sailor man. ♪
♪ Home again to the sea. ♪
Ahoy, mate! Ahoy, m...
Ahoy, mate! Ahoy! Ahoy! I
see that you're a sailor boy.
I owned a boat. A beauty, too.
Fifty times as big as your... um,..
As big as your uh,..
As big as your shoe.
My, my.
Hoy, hoy.
Lost her though
in a glorious gale,
but I came home on
the back of a whale.
But tell me though how
you caught the whale.
Simply grabbed
a hold of his tail.
My, my.
Aye, aye.
I climbed a mountain
peak so high.
I bumped my head
against the sky.
And there I was, where was I?
On the Island Of Alibi.
Aye, aye.
My, my.
But now my life is very dull.
They ought to
make me an admiral.
Now that's the
job that I'd enjoy.
I must be going. Ahoy! Ahoy!
My, my, my.
Ya' put that ball in there.
And then it goes
down and around.
Pull that thing.
And it comes out here.
Hey!
♪
The g-g-g-g-giant!
Wow!
The light. The light.
Douse the light!
He's gone.
Phew!
Hello! Anybody in there?
Nobody here but just us spi...
Chickens!
My, my.
♪ Forever, forever, ♪
♪ there won't be
anyone but you. ♪
♪ Remember I'm true, my sweet. ♪
- ♪ Forever, forever, ♪
- ♪ La, la, la, la-la-la-la, la. ♪
- ♪ You'll share in everything I do, ♪
- ♪ Forever, forever, ♪
- ♪ And keep smiling through, ♪
Forever! Forever!
♪  my sweet. ♪
That's the song of Blefuscu!
A spy!
Guards!
A spy! A spy!
Where is he? Where did he go?
Concealing a spy.
And at a time of war,
too. That makes it worse!
Carry on the search men!
Mind you, your
father will hear of this.
♪
♫
Ahem.
King Bombo, say the word
and the giant is a dead duck.
"Is a dead duck."
P.S. What do we
do with the body?
Two hearts and a wedding
broken by a melody?
Incredible!
Wait a minute.
I have an idea that might
turn this malice to a melody!
Sing Faithful and Forever
together, as one song.
The giant will be a dead duck.
Ha! Now we are
getting at somewhere!
Dear spies, destroy,
crush, obliterate, annihilate!
Kill him!
I vill' attack at dawn!
Affectionately yours, Bombo.
Whatcha got there?
Attack at dawn. Attack..
Bombo's attack.., Bom..., Bom...
Guards! Guards! Guards!
Bombo's attacking! Bombo's attacking!
Bombo's attacking at dawn!
Bombo's attacking! It's war!
Bombo's attacking!
To arms! It's war!
The enemies outside!
To the beach! To the beach!
Bombo's Attacking!
What?
Bombo attacking!
It's war! It's war!
To the beach!
To the beach! The enemy attacks!
To defend Lilliput.
-TO DEFEND LILLIPUT!-
Yes, forward march.
♫ We're all together
now. All together now. ♫
Gulliver! Gulliver!
Where are you?
Bombo's attacking.
Where are you Gulliver?
We'll be wiped out!
Gulliver where are you?
Gulliver! Gulliver!
Bombo is attacking!
It's war! Gulliver!
It's war!
Gulliver! Where are you?
Huh?
Gulliver! Gulliver!
It's the war!
Gulliver! Bombo's attacking!
Bombo's attacking! It's war!
Put me down.
Hah! Well, where you been you
lazy, long legged, overgrown lummox?
Now, get down there to that
beach and wipe out that Bombo
and that bunch of Blefuscuians.
And tear em to pieces
and don't leave a man
alive to tell the tale.
Forward march! Get going!
Aye, aye, sir!
My, my.
Hey! Wait for me.
♫ We're all together ♫
Gulliver, wait for me!
Wait for me, Gulliver!
♫ What'll we get? ♫
♫ We're all together now. ♫
♫ All together now. ♫
♫ Ready to do, ready to dare, what'll we, what'll we, what'll we care?, ♫
♫ We're all together now.  All together now. ♫
♫ All for one, one for all.
All for one, one for all. ♫
♫ We're all together now. ♫
♫ All together now. ♫
♫ There's a war that must be won. ♫
♫ There's a job that must be done. ♫
No note.
♫ There's a war that must be won. ♫
♫ There's a job that must be done. ♫
Where is it?
What did you done with it?
Where did you lose it?
Who's got it now?
Gulliver! Gulliver! Wait for me!
Gulliver! Gulliver!
♫ Ready to do, ready to
dare, ready to, ready to, die. ♫
♫ all together now. All together now. ♫
♫ Ready to do, ready to
dare, ready to ready to, die. ♫
Let me go! Let me go!
Let's go!
♫ Ready to do, ready to
dare, ready to ready to, die. ♫
♫ We're all together now.  All together now. ♫
♫ Ready to do, ready to
dare, ready to ready to, die. ♫
♫ What do we care. ♫
Hold on there!
We can settle this peacefully.
Listen!
Hold you fire!
Hear what I have to say.
Bombo, order your men
to lay down their arms.
Must I make you listen?
David, look! Gulliver's
thunder machine.
Wait here, Glory.
David!
The powder!
Pull!
Come on! Pull!
David!
Poor, poor,
foolish little people.
Look what you've done.
Now go ahead! Break your
nutshell heads over your songs!
But did you have to break
Glory's heart, King Little,
because your
thoughtless and selfish?
And you Bombo, O mighty
warrior, what have you won?
You were too stubborn to think,
too busy quarreling to lend ear to the
harmony that might have been yours.
But now in your
sorrow and despair,
perhaps you will listen to your
songs as they might be sung.
♪ Faithful. ♪
♪ Forever. ♪
♪ Whatever I do. ♪
♪ Remember I'm true. ♪
♪ Remember that. ♪
♪ Faithful. ♪
♪ Forever. ♪
♪ And thankful for you. ♪
♪ I'll keep smiling through, ♪
♫ remember that. ♫
♫ We may be apart now and then ♫
♫ but I'll hold you in my heart ♫
♫ till you're in my arms again. ♫
♫ Faithful forever I promise to be. ♫
Get out of this?
♫ So always have faith ♫
♫ in me. ♫
In behalf of the peoples
of Blefuscu and Lilliput,
with eternal gratitude and love in
our hearts, we christen thee, Gulliver!
♫ Come back again, come back ♫
♫ wherever you may be ♫
♫ come back again you
sailor man, sailor man. ♫
♫ Back again from the sea. ♫
♫ Come back again you
sailor man, sailor man. ♫
♫ Back again from the sea. ♫
The end...
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}Subtitles By:
MightyMike77020