MAN 1: I owe everything
to George Bailey.
Help him, dear Father.
MAN 2: Joseph, Jesus and Mary,
help my friend Mr. Bailey.
WOMAN 1:
Help my son George tonight.
MAN 3: He never thinks
about himself, God.
That's why he's in trouble.
MAN 4: George is a good guy.
Give him a break, God.
WOMAN 2: I love him,
dear Lord.
Watch over him tonight.
GIRL: Please, God.
Something's
the matter with Daddy.
GIRL 2: Please
bring Daddy back.
(PEOPLE PRAYING)
Please
bring Daddy home.
WOMAN 1:
Watch over him tonight.
GIRL 2: Please
bring Daddy back.
FRANKLIN:
Hello, Joseph. Trouble?
JOSEPH: Looks like
we'll have to
send someone down.
A lot of people
asking for help
for a man named
George Bailey.
George Bailey?
Yes. Tonight's
his crucial night.
You're right.
We'll have to send
someone down immediately.
Whose turn is it?
That's why I came
to see you, sir.
It's that clockmaker's
turn again.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, Clarence.
Hasn't got his
wings yet, has he?
We've passed him
up right along.
Because, you know, sir,
he's got the IQ of a rabbit.
Yes,
but he's got the faith
of a child. Simple.
Joseph,
send for Clarence.
CLARENCE:
You sent for me, sir?
Yes, Clarence.
A man down on Earth
needs our help.
Splendid. Is he sick?
No, worse.
He's discouraged.
At exactly 10:45 p.m.
Earth time,
that man will be
thinking seriously
of throwing away
God's greatest gift.
Oh, dear, dear,
his life?
Then I've only
an hour to dress.
What are they
wearing now?
You will spend that hour
getting acquainted
with George Bailey.
Sir, if I should
accomplish this mission,
I mean, uh,
might I perhaps
win my wings?
I've been waiting
for over 200 years
now, sir,
and people are
beginning to talk.
What's that book
you've got there?
Oh, The Adventures
of Tom Sawyer.
Clarence, you do a good job
with George Bailey
and you'll get
your wings.
Oh, thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Poor George.
Sit down.
Sit down?
What are we...
If you're going
to help a man,
you want to know
something about him,
don't you?
Well, naturally,
of course. I...
Now, keep
your eyes open.
See the town?
CLARENCE: Where?
I--I don't see a thing.
Oh, I forgot.
You haven't got
your wings yet.
Now, look,
I'll help you out.
Concentrate.
Begin to see something?
Why, yes.
This is amazing.
If you ever get
your wings, you'll
see all by yourself.
Oh, wonderful.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yay! Yippee!
Okay, boys, let's go.
CLARENCE:
Hey, who's that?
JOSEPH: That's your
problem. George Bailey.
A boy?
That's him
when he was 12
back in 1919.
Something happens here
you'll have to
remember later on.
BOY: Come on, Marty.
Let's go, Marty!
Attaboy, Marty.
Hee-haw!
(BOYS CHEERING)
Let's go, Sam. Hee-haw, Sammy!
Here comes the scare-baby,
my kid brother Harry Bailey.
I'm not scared.
BOY: Come on, Harry.
GEORGE: Let's go, Harry!
Come on, Harry!
GEORGE: Come on, Harry!
BOY: Come on, Harry!
Help, George, help!
Help!
Don't worry, Harry.
I'm coming!
HARRY: Help!
Hang on, Harry!
Help.
Make a chain--chain, gang.
JOSEPH: George
saved his brother's
life that day,
but he caught
a bad cold which
infected his left ear.
Cost him his hearing
in that ear.
It was weeks
before he was
able to go back
to his after-school
job at old man Gower's
drugstore.
Mr. Potter.
CLARENCE:
Who's that, a king?
FRANKLIN:
That's Henry F. Potter,
the richest
and meanest man
in the county.
(BOYS WHISTLING)
BOYS: Hee-haw! Hee-haw!
BOY: Go to work, slave.
Don't worry,
we'll take care of it.
Wish I had a million dollars.
Hot dog!
(WHISTLING)
It's me, Mr. Gower.
George Bailey.
You're late.
Yes, sir.
Hello, George.
Hello, Mary.
Hello, Violet.
Two cents'
worth of shoelaces?
She was here first.
I'm still thinking.
Shoelaces?
Please, Georgie.
I like him.
You like every boy.
What's wrong with that?
Here you are.
Help me down?
Help you down?
(CASH REGISTER DINGING)
Made up your mind yet?
I'll take chocolate.
With coconuts?
I don't like coconuts.
You don't like coconuts?
Say, brainless,
don't you know where
coconuts come from?
Lookit here.
From Tahiti,
the Fiji islands,
the Coral Sea.
A new magazine.
I never saw it before.
Of course you never.
Only us explorers can get it.
I've been nominated
for membership
in the National
Geographic Society.
Is this the ear
you can't hear on?
George Bailey, I'll love you
till the day I die.
I'm going out
exploring someday. You watch.
And I'm gonna have
a couple of harems
and maybe three
or four wives.
Wait and see.
(WHISTLING)
GOWER: George. George!
Yes, sir?
(SLURRING) You're not paid
to be a canary.
No, sir.
Mr. Gower, do you want
something? Anything?
No.
Anything I can do
back here?
No.
I'll get them, sir.
Quick, take those capsules
over to Mrs. Blaine.
She's waiting for them.
Yes, sir.
They have
the diphtheria there,
haven't they, sir?
Yeah.
Is it a charge, sir?
Yes, George.
Mr. Gower, I...
Oh, get going.
Yes, sir.
(BILLY EXCLAIMING)
Avast there, Captain Cook.
Where you heading?
I've got to see Pop,
Uncle Billy.
Some other time, George.
It's important.
There's a squall in there.
It's shaping up into a storm.
TILLY: Uncle Billy, telephone.
Who is it?
Bank examiner.
Bank examiner?
I should have
called him yesterday.
Switch it inside.
BAILEY: I'm not crying,
Mr. Potter.
Well, you're begging.
That's a whole lot worse.
All I'm asking
for is 30 days more.
Pop.
Just a minute, Son.
Just 30 short days.
I'll dig up that
$5,000 somehow.
Shove me up,
shove me up.
Pop.
Just a minute.
Have you put
any real pressure
on these people of yours
to pay those mortgages?
Times are bad,
Mr. Potter.
A lot of these people
are out of work.
Well, then, foreclose.
I can't do that.
These families
have children.
GEORGE: Pop.
They're not my children.
But they're
somebody's children,
Mr. Potter.
Are you running a business
or a charity ward?
Well, all right...
Not with my money.
Mr. Potter,
what makes you such
a hard-skulled character?
You have no family,
no children.
You can't begin
to spend all the
money you've got.
Oh, I suppose
I should give it
to miserable failures
like you and that
idiot brother of yours
to spend for me.
He's not a failure!
You can't say
that about my father.
George, George.
Quiet, George.
You're not.
You're the biggest
man in town...
Run along, run along.
...bigger than him,
bigger than everybody.
Gives you an idea
of the Baileys.
Don't let him say
that about you, Pop.
All right, Son.
All right. Thanks.
I'll talk to you tonight.
(MEN CHATTERING)
GOWER: What?
(SLURRING)
Why, that medicine should have
been there an hour ago.
It will be over
in five minutes, Mrs. Blaine.
Where's Mrs. Blaine's
box of capsules?
I... You...
Didn't you hear
what I said?
Yes, sir. I...
What kind of tricks
are you playing anyway?
(SLAPPING)
Why--Why didn't you
deliver them right away?
Don't you know
that boy's very sick?
(SOBBING) You're hurting
my sore ear.
You lazy loafer.
Mr. Gower,
you don't know
what you're doing.
You put something wrong
in those capsules.
I know you're unhappy.
You got the telegram,
and you're upset.
You put something bad
in those capsules.
It wasn't
your fault, Mr. Gower.
Just look and see
what you did.
The bottle you took
the powder from,
it's poison.
I tell you, it's poison.
I know you feel bad.
(GEORGE SNIFFLING)
Oh!
Don't hurt
my sore ear again!
Oh, no, no.
Don't hurt
my sore ear again.
(SOBBING)
Oh, George, George.
Oh, Mr. Gower,
I won't ever tell anyone.
I know how you're feeling.
I won't ever tell a soul.
Hope to die, I won't.
Oh, George. George.
An overnight bag.
Genuine English cowhide.
Combination lock.
Fitted up with brushes,
combs...
Nope, nope, nope, nope.
Now, look, Joe. Now, look.
I--I--I want a big one.
CLARENCE:
What did you stop it for?
FRANKLIN: I want you
to take a good look
at that face.
Who is it?
George Bailey.
Oh, you mean
the kid that had his ears
slapped back by the druggist?
That's the kid.
Ah.
It's a good face.
I like it.
I like George Bailey.
Tell me,
did he ever tell
anyone about the pills?
Not a soul.
Did he ever
marry the girl?
Did he ever go exploring?
Well, wait and see.
Big, see? I--I don't want
one for one night.
I want something
for 1,001 nights
with plenty of room here
for labels
from Italy and Baghdad,
Samarkand.
Great big thing, about...
I see. A flying carpet,
huh?
Yeah.
I don't suppose you'd like
this old secondhand job,
would you?
Now you're talking.
Gee whiz,
I could use that as a raft
in case the boat sunk.
How much this cost?
No charge.
That's my trick ear, Joe.
It sounded like
you said "no charge."
That's right.
Well, what's my name
doing on it?
A little present
from old man Gower.
Came down
and picked it out himself.
He did?
What do you know about that?
My old boss.
Isn't that nice?
What boat are you
sailing on?
I'm working across
on a cattle boat.
A cattle boat?
Okay, I like cows.
(CHILDREN CLAMORING)
Hello, Mr. Gower.
How are you?
Thanks ever so much
for the baggage.
It's just exactly
what I wanted.
Oh, forget it.
Oh, it's wonderful
of you to think of me.
Hope you enjoy it.
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
I wish I had
a million dollars.
Hot dog!
Avast there, Captain Cook!
You got your sea legs yet?
(LAUGHING)
Parlez-vous
francais, mister?
Hey, send us some
of those picture postcards,
will you, George?
Hey, George,
don't take
any plug nickels.
Hey, George,
your suitcase is leaking.
GEORGE: Hey, Ernie!
Hi, Ernie. Hi, Bert.
Hiya, George.
George.
Hey, hey, hey,
I'm a rich tourist today.
How about driving
me home in style?
Hop in,
Your Highness. Hop in.
Yes, sir.
And for the carriage trade,
I put on my hat.
Good afternoon,
Mr. Bailey.
Hello, Violet.
Hey, you look good.
That's some dress
you got on there.
This old thing?
Why, I only wear it
when I don't care how I look.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
How would you
like to take...
Yes.
Want to come along, Bert?
We'll show you the town.
No, thanks.
I think
I'll go home and see
what the wife's doing.
Family man.
(GEORGE AND HARRY DANCING)
George, Harry,
you're shaking
the house down. Stop it.
Oh, let them alone.
I wish I was up
there with them.
But Harry will tear
his dinner suit.
George!
That's why all children
should be girls.
Well, if they were all girls
there wouldn't be any...
Oh, never mind.
George, Harry,
come down to dinner
this minute.
Everything's
getting cold, and you know
how long we've been
waiting for you.
GEORGE: Okay, Ma.
HARRY: Okay, Ma.
(GEORGE AND HARRY SINGING)
Ta-da!
(DOG BARKING)
We got a present
for you, Pop.
There you are.
Whoa.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, you two idiots.
George, sit down
and have dinner.
I've eaten.
Fine.
Well, aren't you
gonna finish dressing
for your graduating party?
Look at you!
I don't care.
It's George's tux.
Annie, my sweet,
have you got those pies?
If you lay a hand on me,
I'll hit you with this broom!
Annie, I'm in love with you.
There's a moon out tonight.
(ANNIE SCREAMS)
Boy, oh boy, oh boy!
My last meal
in the old Bailey
boarding house.
Oh, my lands,
my blood pressure.
Pop, can I have the car?
I gotta take over a lot
of plates and things.
What plates?
Mom, I'm chairman
of the Eats Committee.
We only need
a couple of dozen.
Oh, no, you don't, Harry.
Now, not my best
Haviland, no.
Oh, let him have
the plates, Mother.
Hope you have
a good trip, George.
Uncle Billy and I
are gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you, too, Pop.
What's the matter?
You look tired.
Oh, I had another
tussle with
Potter today.
I thought when we put him
on the board of directors,
he'd ease up
on us a little bit.
Oh, what's eating
that old money-grubbing
buzzard anyway?
Oh, he's a sick man,
frustrated,
sick in his mind.
Sick in his soul,
if he has one.
He hates everybody
that has anything
that he can't have.
He hates us
mostly, I guess.
Gangway. Gangway.
So long, Pop.
So long.
You got a match?
Very funny, very funny.
Put those things
in the car,
and I'll get your tie
and studs ready for you.
Now, hurry up.
Okay, Mom.
Now, don't drop
one of those.
You coming later, George?
What do you mean,
and be bored to death?
Couldn't want a better death.
Lots of pretty girls,
and we're gonna use
that new floor tonight, too.
I hope it works.
No gin tonight, Son.
HARRY:
Oh, Pop, just a little?
No, Son. Not one drop.
Oh!
Boys and girls and music.
Why do they need gin?
Did I act like that
when I graduated
from high school?
Pretty much.
You know, George, I wish
we could send Harry
to college with you.
Your mother and I
talked it over
half the night.
Mmm. We have that all
figured out.
You see,
Harry will take my job
at the Building and Loan,
work there for four years,
then he'll go.
Pretty young
for that job.
Well, no younger than I was.
Well, you were
born older, George.
How's that?
I said you were
born older.
I suppose you've decided
what you want to do
when you get out of college.
Oh, well, you know
what I've always
talked about,
build things,
design new buildings,
plan modern cities.
All that stuff
I've been talking about.
Still after
that first million
before you're 30?
I'll settle
for half that in cash.
(CHUCKLING)
Of course,
it's just a hope.
But, uh, you wouldn't
consider coming back
to the Building
and Loan, would you?
Well, I... I...
Annie, why--why--why don't
you draw up a chair?
Then you'd be
more comfortable,
and you could hear
everything
that's going on.
I would if I thought
I'd hear anything
worth listening to.
You would, eh?
I know it's soon
to talk about it.
No, now, Pop, I--I couldn't.
I--I couldn't face
being cooped up
for the rest of my life
in a shabby little office.
Oh, I'm sorry, Pop.
I didn't mean that, but I...
I-It's this business
of nickels and dimes
and spending all your life
trying to figure out
how to save three cents
on a length of pipe.
I'd go crazy.
I--I want to do
something big
and something important.
You know, George,
I feel that,
in a small way,
we're doing
something important,
satisfying
a fundamental urge.
It's deep in the race
for a man to want his own roof
and walls and fireplace.
And we're helping him
get those things
in our shabby little office.
I know, Pop.
I--I know that.
I--I wish I felt that, uh...
I--I've been hoarding pennies
like a miser here
in order to...
Most of my friends
have already
finished college.
I--I just feel like if
I didn't get away, I'd bust.
Mmm-hmm.
Yes, yes,
you're right, Son.
You see what I mean,
don't you, Pop?
This town is no place
for any man
unless he's willing
to crawl to Potter.
Now, you've got talent, Son.
I've seen it.
You get yourself
an education and
get out of here.
Pop, you want a shock?
I think you're a great guy.
Why, did you
hear that, Annie?
I heard it.
It's about time
one of you lunkheads said it.
I'm gonna miss old Annie.
Pop, I think I'll
get dressed and go over
to Harry's party.
Have a good time, Son.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING MUSIC)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Excuse me.
There you are.
MAN: George, hello.
You know
my kid brother George.
I'm gonna put him
through college.
MAN 2: Hello, George.
Hee-haw!
Oh-oh, Sam Wainwright.
How are you?
When did you get here?
Oh, this afternoon.
I thought I'd give
the kids a treat.
Old college graduate now.
Yeah,
old "Joe College" Wainwright
they call me.
Well, freshman, looks like
you're gonna make
it after all, huh?
Harry, you're the guy
I want to see.
Hello, Sam.
Coach has heard
all about you.
He has?
Yeah,
he's followed every game,
and his mouth's watering.
He wants me to find out
if you're gonna
come along with us.
Well, I, uh, I got to
make some dough first.
Well, you better
make it fast.
We need great ends
like you.
Not broken-down
old guys like this one.
Hee-haw!
George, welcome back.
Hello, Mr. Partridge,
how are you?
Putting a pool
under this floor
was a great idea.
Saved us another building.
Now, Harry, Sam,
have a lot of fun.
There's lots of stuff here
to eat and drink.
Lots of pretty girls around.
A third dance... A third...
Hello, Violet.
Hello. What am I bid?
George.
Marty! Well,
it's old home week.
Marty!
Sam, Harry,
how are you?
Do me a favor,
will you, George?
What's that?
You remember
my kid sister Mary.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
(MIMICKING MARY)
"Mama wants you, Marty.
Mama wants you." Remember?
Dance with her,
will you?
Oh, me?
Well, I feel funny enough
already with all these kids.
Oh, come on, be a sport.
Just dance with her
one time,
and you'll give her
the thrill of her life.
Hey, Sis!
Don't be long, Marty.
I'm not being
a wet nurse to a...
TEEN: The next thing
I knew, some guy
came up and tripped me.
That's the reason
why I came in fourth.
If it hadn't been
for that, that race'd
have been a cinch.
I tried to find out
who it was later,
but I couldn't find out.
Nobody'd ever tell
you whoever it was,
because they'd be scared.
'Cause they know
what kind of a guy I am.
You remember George.
This is Mary.
Well, I'll be seeing you.
Well, well, well.
Now to get back
to my story, see?
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING MUSIC)
Hey, this is my dance.
Oh, why don't you
stop annoying people?
Well, I'm sorry. Hey!
Well, hello.
Hello.
You look at me as if
you didn't know me.
Well, I don't.
You've passed me
on the street
almost every day.
Me?
Mmm-hmm.
No. That was a little girl
named Mary Hatch.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
That wasn't you.
Oh, yes! Oh, yes! Oh, yes!
The big Charleston contest!
(ALL CHEERING)
The prize,
a genuine loving cup.
Those not tapped by the judges
will remain on the floor.
Let's go!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm not very good at this.
Neither am I.
Okay. What can we lose?
Hey, you're wonderful.
What's the matter,
Othello? Jealous?
Did you know
there's a swimming pool
under this floor?
And did you know that
button behind you causes
this floor to open up?
And did you further know
that George Bailey
is dancing
right over that crack?
And I've got the key.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Stand back, everybody!
Stand back!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING LOUDER)
They're cheering us.
We must be good.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Get out of there!
What... Oh, well.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
BOTH: * Buffalo gals
can't you come out tonight?
* Can't you come out tonight?
* Buffalo gals,
can't you come out tonight
(BOTH SINGING OFF-KEY)
* And dance
* By the light
* Of the moon?
Oh, hot dog.
Just like an organ.
Beautiful.
I told Harry I thought
I'd be bored to death.
You should have seen
the commotion
in that locker room.
I had to knock down
three people
to get this stuff
we're wearing here.
Let me-- let me
hold that old wet dress
of yours.
Do I look as funny
as you do?
I guess I'm not
quite the football type.
You--you look wonderful!
You know,
if it wasn't me talking,
I'd say you were
the prettiest girl in town.
Well, why don't you say it?
I don't know.
Maybe I will say it.
How old are you anyway?
Eighteen.
Eighteen?
Why, it was only last year
you were seventeen.
Too young or too old?
Oh, no, no. Just right.
Your age fits you.
Yes, sir,
you look a little older
without your clothes on.
(STAMMERING)
I mean, without
a dress you look older.
(STUTTERING)
I mean younger.
You look... You just...
BOTH: Oh-oh.
Oh, I'm on
the thing here.
Sir, my train, please.
A pox upon me
for a clumsy lout.
Your, uh...
Your caboose, milady.
You may kiss my hand.
Mmm.
Hey.
Hey, Mary.
* As I was
lumberin' down the street
* Down the street,
down the street
Okay, then. I'll
throw a rock at the
old Granville house.
Oh, no, don't.
I--I love that old house.
No, you see,
you make a wish and then try
and break some glass.
And you got to be
a pretty good shot
nowadays, too.
Oh, no, George, don't.
It's full of romance,
that old place.
MARY: I'd like to live in it.
GEORGE: In that place?
Uh-huh.
I wouldn't live
in it as a ghost.
Now, watch.
Right in the second floor,
there. See?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
What did you wish, George?
Well, not just one wish,
a whole hatful.
Mary, I know what
I'm gonna do tomorrow
and the next day
and next year
and the year after that.
I'm shaking the dust
of this crummy
little town off my feet,
and I'm gonna see
the world!
Italy, Greece,
the Parthenon, the Coliseum.
Then I'm coming back here
and go to college
to see what they know.
And then I'm
gonna build things.
I'm gonna build airfields.
I'm gonna build skyscrapers
100 stories high.
I'm gonna build
bridges a mile long.
What, are you gonna
throw a rock?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Hey, that's pretty good.
What did you wish, Mary?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
* Buffalo gals
can't you come out tonight?
BOTH: * Can't you
come out tonight?
* Can't you
* Buffalo gals,
can't you come out tonight
(BOTH SINGING OFF-KEY)
* And
* Dance by
the light of the moon? *
* What did you wish
when you threw that rock? *
Oh, no.
Come on, tell me.
If I told you,
it might not come true.
What is it you want, Mary?
What do you want?
You--You want the moon?
Just say the word,
and I'll throw a lasso
around it and pull it down.
Hey, that's
a pretty good idea.
I'll give you the moon, Mary.
I'll take it.
Then what?
Well, then you could
swallow it,
and it would
all dissolve, see?
And the moonbeams
would shoot out of
your fingers and your toes
and the ends of your hair.
Am I talking too much?
Yes!
Why don't you kiss her
instead of talking her
to death?
How's that?
Why don't you kiss her
instead of talking her
to death?
You want me
to kiss her, huh?
Oh, youth is wasted
on the wrong people.
Hey. Hey, hold on,
hey, mister.
Come on back out here!
I'll show you some kissing
that'll put hair
back on your head.
What are you...
Mary?
(WHISTLES)
Okay, I give up.
Where are you?
Over here
in the hydrangea bushes.
(CHUCKLING)
Here you are. Catch.
Wait a minute.
What am I doing?
This is a very
interesting situation.
Please give me my robe.
Hmm.
A man doesn't
get in a situation
like this every day.
I'd like to have my robe.
Not in Bedford Falls,
anyway.
Ouch! Oh!
Gesundheit.
George Bailey!
This requires
a little thought here.
Give me my robe.
I've read about
things like this,
but I've never...
Shame on you!
I'm gonna tell
your mother on you.
My mother's way up
on the corner there.
I'll call the police.
They're way downtown.
They'd be on my side, too.
Th-Then--Then I'm going
to scream!
Maybe I could
sell tickets.
Let's see.
No, the point is
in order to get this robe...
I've got it.
(CAR APPROACHING)
I'll make a deal
with you, Mary.
George! George!
George, come on home!
Quick!
Your father's had a stroke.
What?
Mary, Mary, I'm sorry.
I've got to go.
Come on, George,
let's hurry.
GEORGE: Did you
get a doctor?
Yes.
Campbell's there now.
I think that's all
we'll need you for, George.
I know you're anxious
to make a train.
I have a taxi
waiting downstairs.
I want the board to know
that George gave up
his trip to Europe
to help
straighten things out here
these past few months.
Good luck to you
at school, George.
Good luck, George.
Goodbye, George.
And now we come
to the real purpose
of this meeting,
to appoint a successor
to our dear friend
Peter Bailey.
Mr. Chairman,
I'd like to get
to my real purpose.
Wait just a minute now.
Wait for what?
I claim this institution
is not necessary
to this town.
Therefore, Mr. Chairman,
I make a motion
to dissolve this institution
and turn its assets
and liabilities
over to the receiver.
Potter, you dirty,
contemptible...
I'll wring his neck.
George, did you hear
what that buzzard...
Mr. Chairman.
It's too soon after
Peter Bailey's death
to talk about chloroforming
the Building and Loan.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Peter Bailey died
three months ago.
I second
Mr. Potter's motion.
Very well.
In that case,
I'll ask the two
executive officers
to withdraw.
But before you go,
I'm sure
the whole board wishes
to express its deep sorrow
at the passing
of Peter Bailey.
Thank you very much.
It was his faith
and devotion
that are responsible
for this organization.
I'll go further
than that.
I'll say that
to the public Peter Bailey
was the Building and Loan.
That's fine, Potter,
coming from you,
considering
that you probably
drove him to his grave.
Peter Bailey
was not a businessman.
That's what killed him.
Oh, I don't mean
any disrespect to him.
God rest his soul.
He was a man
of high ideals, so-called.
But ideals
without common sense
can ruin this town.
Now, you take this loan here
to Ernie Bishop,
you know, that fellow
that sits around all day
on his brains
in his taxi, you know.
I happen to know
the bank turned down
this loan.
But he comes here,
and we're building him
a house worth $5,000.
Why?
Well, I handled
that, Mr. Potter.
You have all
the papers there.
His salary, insurance.
I can personally
vouch for his character.
A friend of yours?
Yes, sir.
Uh-huh.
You see, if you shoot pool
with some employee here,
you can come
and borrow money.
What does that get us?
A discontented, lazy rabble
instead of
a thrifty working class.
And all because
a few starry-eyed dreamers
like Peter Bailey
stir 'em up
and fill their heads
with a lot
of impossible ideas.
Now, I say...
Just a minute.
Just--Just a minute.
Now, hold on, Mr. Potter.
Now, you're right when you say
my father was no businessman.
I know that.
Why he ever started this cheap
penny-ante Building and Loan
I'll never know.
But neither you
nor anybody else
can say anything
against his character,
because his whole life was...
Why, in the 25 years since
he and Uncle Billy
started this thing,
he never once
thought of himself.
Isn't that right,
Uncle Billy?
He didn't save enough money
to send Harry to school,
let alone me.
But he did help a few people
get out of your slums,
Mr. Potter.
And what's wrong
with that?
Why, here,
you're all businessmen here.
Don't it make them
better citizens,
and doesn't it make them
better customers?
You--You said that they...
What'd you say
just a minute ago?
They--They had to wait
and save their money
before they even thought
of a decent home.
Wait? Wait for what?
Until their children
grow up and leave them?
Until they're so old
and broken-down that they...
Do you know how long it takes
a working man to save $5,000?
Just remember
this, Mr. Potter,
that this rabble
you're talking about,
they do most
of the working and paying
and living and dying
in this community.
Well, is it too much
to have them work and pay
and live and die
in a couple of
decent rooms and a bath?
Anyway, my father
didn't think so.
People were human beings
to him, but to you,
a warped, frustrated old man,
they're cattle.
Well, in my book, he died
a much richer man
than you'll ever be.
I'm not interested
in your book.
I'm talking about
the Building and Loan.
I know very well
what you're talking about.
You're talking about something
you can't get your fingers on,
and it's galling you.
That's what you're
talking about, I know.
Well, I--I--I've said
too much. I...
You're-- You're
the Board here.
You do what you want
with this thing.
There's just
one thing more, though.
This town needs
this measly
one-horse institution
if only to have someplace
where people can come
without crawling to Potter.
Come on, Uncle Billy.
Sentimental hogwash.
I want my motion.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Boy, oh boy,
that was telling him,
George, old boy.
You shut his big mouth.
You should have heard him.
What happened?
We heard
a lot of yelling.
Well, we're being
voted out of business
after 25 years.
Easy come, easy go.
TILLY: Here it is.
"Help wanted. Female."
You still want me
to hang around, George?
Yeah, I'll be right down.
Yeah, hey,
you'll miss your train.
You're a week late
for school already. Go on.
What's going on
in there?
Oh, never mind.
Don't worry about that.
They're putting us
out of business.
So what?
I can get another job.
I'm only 55.
56.
Go on, go on. Hey, look,
you gave up your boat trip,
now you don't want to
miss college, too, do you?
George! George!
They voted Potter down.
They want to
keep it going.
(ALL CHEERING)
You did it, George.
You did it.
They got one condition,
only one condition.
What's that?
And that's
the best part of it.
They've appointed George here
as Executive Secretary
to take his father's place.
Oh, no! But, Uncle Billy...
You can keep him on.
That's all right.
As Secretary,
you can hire anyone you like.
Dr. Campbell, now
let's get this thing
straight. I'm leaving.
I'm leaving right now.
I'm going to school.
This is my last chance.
Uncle Billy here,
he's your man.
But, George, they'll vote
with Potter otherwise.
CLARENCE: I know, I know,
he didn't go.
JOSEPH: That's right.
Not only that, but he
gave his school money
to his brother, Harry,
and sent him
to college.
Harry became
a football star.
Made second team
all-American.
Yeah, but what
happened to George?
JOSEPH: George got
four years older, waiting
for Harry to come back
and take over
the Building and Loans.
There are
plenty of jobs around
for somebody that
likes to travel.
Look at this. Here.
Venezuela oil fields.
"Wanted, man
with construction
experience."
Here's the Yukon,
right here.
"Wanted, man
with engineering
experience."
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
There she blows.
You know what
the three most exciting
sounds in the world are?
Uh-huh. Breakfast
is served. Lunch
is served. Dinner...
No, no, no, no!
Anchor chains,
plane motors
and train whistles.
Peanut?
There's the
professor now.
Old Professor
Phi Beta Kappa
all-American Baily.
Why, old George
"Geographic Explorer" Bailey.
What? No husky dogs?
No sled?
Uncle Billy,
you haven't changed a bit.
Nobody ever changes here,
you know that.
Oh, am I glad
to see you.
Say, where's Mother?
She's home, cooking
the fatted calf.
Come on, let's go.
Oh, wait!
Wait, wait a minute.
George, Uncle Billy,
I want you to meet Ruth.
Hello.
How do you do?
Ruth Dakin.
Ruth Dakin Bailey,
if you don't mind.
Huh?
Well, I wired you
I had a surprise.
Here she is.
Meet the wife.
Well, what do
you know? A wife.
Well, how do you do?
Congratulations.
How do you do?
What am I doing?
Congratulations!
Doggone it,
Harry, you...
They're married!
Why don't you
tell somebody?
Come on, Mrs. Bailey,
I can't wait
to see everybody's reaction.
You're really married?
Why, yes.
What's a pretty girl
like you doing
marrying this
two-headed brother of mine?
Well, I'll tell you.
It's purely mercenary.
My father
offered him a job.
Oh, he got you
and the job?
Well, Harry's cup
runneth over.
Uh, George, about that job.
Ruth spoke out of turn.
I never said
I'd take it.
You've been
holding the bag here
for four years,
and, well, I won't let
you down, George.
I would like to...
Oh, wait a minute.
I forgot the bags.
I'll be right back.
BILLY: It was
a surprise to me.
This is the
new Mrs. Bailey,
my nephew's wife.
MAN: How are you?
BILLY: Old, old friend
of the Baileys.
RUTH: Oh, really?
What are their names?
Let's see...
Oh, of course,
I've heard him
speak of you.
BILLY: And I want to tell
you, we're gonna
give the biggest party
(RUTH EXCLAIMING)
this town ever saw.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Here, have some popcorn.
George, George, George.
That's all Harry
ever talks about.
Uh, uh, uh, Ruth,
this, uh...
What about this job?
Oh, well, my father
owns a glass factory
in Buffalo.
He wants to get
Harry started in
the research business.
Well, is it a good job?
Oh, yes, very.
Not much money,
but, uh, good future,
you know.
Yeah.
Harry's a genius at research.
My father just fell
in love with him.
And you did, too.
Uh-huh.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Hey, Joe.
Oh boy, oh boy,
oh boy, oh boy.
I feel so good.
I could spit
in Potter's eye.
I think I will.
What did you say? Huh?
Maybe I'd better go home.
Where's my hat? Where's my...
Oh, thank you, George.
Which is mine?
The middle one.
Oh, thank you, George.
Oh boy, oh boy. Now, look,
if you'll point me
in the right direction...
Would you do that, George?
Right down here.
(SLURRING) Old Building
and Loan pal, huh?
Now you just turn this way
and then right
straight down there.
Oh, that way, huh?
* My wild Irish rose
(CRASHING)
I'm all right.
(BILLY CONTINUES SINGING)
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Hello, Ma.
That's for nothing.
How do you like her?
She's swell, isn't she?
Looks like she can keep
Harry on his toes.
Keep him out
of Bedford Falls, anyway.
Did you know that
Mary Hatch is back
from school?
Mmm-hmm.
Came back three days ago.
Mmm.
Nice girl, Mary.
Mmm-hmm.
Kind that'll help you
find the answers, George.
Mmm-hmm.
Stop that grunting.
Mmm?
Can you give me
one good reason
why you shouldn't
call on Mary?
Sure. Sam Wainwright.
Hee-haw?
Yes, Sam's crazy
about Mary.
Well, she's not crazy
about him.
Well, how do you know?
W-What, did she
discuss it with you?
No.
Well, then how
do you know?
Well, I've got eyes,
haven't I?
Why, she lights up
like a firefly
whenever you're around.
Oh!
Besides, Sam Wainwright's
away in New York,
and you're here
in Bedford Falls.
And all's fair
in love and war.
I don't know about war.
Mother of mine,
I can see
right through you
right to your
back-collar button.
Trying to get
rid of me, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, here's your hat.
What's your hurry?
All right, Mother,
old Building and Loan pal,
I think I'll go out
and find a girl
and do a little
passionate necking.
Oh, George.
Now, if you'll
just point me in
the right direction...
This direction.
Good night, Mrs. Bailey.
Excuse me.
Now, wait a minute.
I think I got a date.
But, uh,
stick around, fellows,
just in case, huh?
We'll wait for you, baby.
Hello, Georgie Porgie!
Hello Vi.
What gives?
Nothing.
Where are you going?
Oh, I'll probably end up
down at the library.
Georgie, don't you
ever get tired of just
reading about things?
Yes.
What are you
doing tonight?
Not a thing.
Are you game, Vi?
Let's make a night of it.
I'd love it, Georgie.
What'll we do?
Let's go out in the fields
and take off our shoes
and walk through the grass.
Huh?
Then we can go
up to the falls.
It's beautiful up there
in the moonlight,
and there's a green pool
up there, and we--we can, uh,
swim in it.
Then we can
climb Mount Bedford
and smell the pines
and watch the sunrise
against the peaks,
and we'll stay up there
the whole night,
and everybody'll be
talking. There'll be
a terrific scandal.
Georgie, have you
gone crazy?
Why, walk in the grass
in my bare feet?
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(GEORGE SHUSHING)
Why it's 10 miles
up to Mount Bedford.
If you think...
O-O-O-Okay,
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
just forget
about the whole thing.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
What are you doing,
picketing?
Hello, Mary.
I just happened to
be passing by here.
Yes, so I noticed.
Have you made up
your mind?
How's that?
Have you made up
your mind?
About what?
About coming in.
Your mother just phoned
and said you were on your way
over to pay me a visit.
My mother
just called you?
Well, how did she know?
Didn't you tell her?
I didn't tell anybody.
I just went for a walk
and happened to
be passing by here.
What--What do you...
Went for a walk. That's all.
I'll be downstairs, Mother.
MRS. HATCH: All right, dear.
(BUFFALO GALS PLAYING
ON GRAMOPHONE)
Well, are you coming in
or aren't you?
Well, I'll come in
for a minute.
But I--I...
I didn't tell anybody
I was coming
over here, you know.
When did you get back?
Tuesday.
Where did you get
that dress?
Do you like it?
It's all right.
* As I was lumbering
down the street *
I thought you would go back
to New York,
like Sam and Angie
and the rest of them.
Oh, oh, I worked there
a couple of vacations,
but I don't know.
I guess I was homesick.
Homesick?
For Bedford Falls?
Yes, and my family and...
Oh, everything.
Would you like to sit down?
(SIGHING)
All right, for a minute.
I--I still can't
understand it, though.
You know,
I didn't tell anybody
I was coming here.
Would you rather leave?
No. I don't want
to be rude.
Well, then, sit down.
What's that?
Mmm.
Some joke, huh?
Well...
I see it still smells
like pine needles
around here.
Thank you.
(BUFFALO GALS CONTINUES)
* And dance by the
What's the matter?
Oh. Oh, yeah, yeah.
Well...
Nice about
your brother Harry
and Ruth, isn't it?
Oh, yeah, yeah,
that's all right.
Don't you
like her?
Well, of course
I like her.
She's a peach.
Oh, just marriage
in general you're not
enthusiastic about, huh?
No. Marriage is all right
for Harry and Marty
and Sam and you.
Mary! Mary!
Who's down there
with you?
It's George Bailey,
Mother.
George Bailey?
What's he want?
I don't know.
What do you want?
Me? Not a thing.
I--I just came in
to get warm.
He's making violent
love to me, Mother.
MRS. HATCH: You tell him
to go right back home,
and don't you
leave the house, either!
Sam Wainwright
promised to call you
from New York tonight.
What's your mother mean?
You know,
I--I didn't come here to...
What did you
come here for, then?
I don't know. You tell me.
You're supposed to be
the one that has all
the answers. You tell me.
Why don't you go home?
That's where I'm going.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
I don't know why I came here
in the first place.
Good night.
Good night!
Mary! Mary!
The telephone. It's Sam.
I'll get it.
MRS. HATCH:
Whatever were you doing
that you couldn't hear?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Mary, he's waiting.
Hello?
(DOOR OPENING)
Forgot my hat.
Hee-haw! Hello, Sam,
how are you?
SAM: I'm great.
Gee, it's good
to hear your voice again.
Well, that's awfully
sweet of you, Sam.
There's an old friend
of yours here.
George Bailey.
You mean
old mossback George?
Yes, old mossback George.
Hee-haw! Put him on.
Wait just a minute.
I'll call him. George!
He doesn't want
to speak to George,
you idiot.
He does so.
He asked for him.
George, Sam wants
to speak to you.
Hi, Sam.
Well, George Bailyoffski!
Hey, a fine pal you are.
What're you trying
to do, steal my girl?
W-W-What do you mean?
Nobody's trying to
steal anybody's girl.
Here... Here--Here's Mary.
No, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
I want to talk
to both of you.
Tell Mary to get
on the extension.
Mother's
on the extension. We...
I am not!
We can both hear. Come here.
We're listening, Sam.
Well, look,
I have a big deal
coming up
that's gonna
make us all rich.
George, do you
remember that night
in Martini's bar
when you told me
you'd read someplace
about making
plastics out of soybeans?
MAN: Chili beans.
Shut up, will you?
You remember,
out of chili...
Out of soybeans.
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Soybeans, yeah.
Well, listen,
Dad snapped up
the idea,
and he's gonna
build a factory
outside of Rochester.
How do you
like that?
Rochester?
Well, why Rochester?
Well, why not?
Can you think
of anything better?
Well, I don't know.
Just why not right here?
You remember that, uh,
that old tool
and machinery works?
You tell your father
he can get that
for a song.
And all the labor
he wants, too.
Half the town
was thrown out of work
when they closed down.
That so?
Well, I'll tell him.
Hey, that sounds great.
Oh, baby,
I knew you'd
come through.
Now here's
the point, Mary.
Mary, you're in
on this, too.
Now listen.
Have you got
any money?
Money? Yeah...
Well, a little.
Well, now, listen.
I want you to put
every cent you've got
into our stock, do you hear?
And, George,
I may have
a job for you,
that is unless
you're still married
to that broken-down
Building and Loan.
(LAUGHING)
Well,
this is the biggest
thing since radio,
and I'm letting you in
on the ground floor.
Oh, Mary. Mary?
Well, I...
I'm here.
Uh, would you
tell that guy
I'm giving him
the chance of a lifetime,
do you hear?
The chance
of a lifetime!
He says it's the chance
of a lifetime.
Now you listen to me.
I don't want any plastics,
and I don't want
any ground floors.
And I don't want
to get married,
ever, to anyone.
You understand that?
I want to do
what I want to do.
And you're...
Oh, Mary, Mary.
George, George, George.
Oh, Mary.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
Oh, dear.
Mary...
Here they come!
(WEDDING MARCH PLAYING)
(ALL CHEERING)
WOMAN: Goodbye, George!
WOMAN: Goodbye!
First Harry, now George.
Annie, we're just
two old maids now.
You speak for
yourself, Miss B.
If either of you two
see a stranger
around here, it's me.
Hey, look. There's somebody
driving this cab.
Bert the cop
sent this over.
He said to float away
to Happyland on the bubbles.
Oh, look at this.
Old Bert. Champagne!
By the way,
where are you two going
on this here now honeymoon?
Where are we going?
Look at this.
There's the kitty, Ernie.
Here, come on, count it, Mary.
I feel like
a bootlegger's wife. Look.
You know what we're gonna do?
We're gonna shoot the works.
A whole week in New York.
A whole week in Bermuda.
The highest hotels,
the oldest champagne,
the richest caviar,
the hottest music
and the prettiest wife.
(BARKS)That does it!
Then what?
Then what, honey?
After that, who cares?
(BARKS)
That does it, come here.
Come here.
Don't look now,
but there's something funny
going on over there
at the bank, George.
Hmm?
I've never really
seen one,
but that's got all
the earmarks of being a run.
Hey, Ernie, if you got
any money in the bank,
you better hurry.
MARY: George, let's not stop.
Let's go!
Just a minute, dear.
Oh-oh.
Please,
let's not stop, George.
I'll be back
in a minute, Mary.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Well, hello, everybody.
Mrs. Thompson, how are you?
Charlie?
What's the matter here,
can't you get in?
(CAWING)
What is this, Uncle Billy?
A holiday?
George.
Come on in, everybody.
That's right.
Just come on in.
Look out, you.
Now, look,
why don't you all sit down?
There are a lot
of seats over there.
Just make
yourselves at home.
George,
can I see you a minute?
Why didn't you
call me?
I just did,
but they said you left.
This is a pickle, George.
This is a pickle.
All right,
now, what happened?
How did it start?
How does a thing
like this ever start?
All I know is
the bank called our loan.
When?
About an hour ago.
I handed over all our cash.
All of it?
Every cent of it,
and still it was less
than we owe them.
Holy mackerel!
And then I got
scared, George, and
closed the doors.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
I... I...
The whole town's
gone crazy.
BILLY: (STAMMERING)
Yeah, hello?
George, it's Potter.
Hello?
George, there is a rumor
around town
that you've
closed your doors.
Is that true?
Oh, well,
I'm very glad to hear that.
George, are you all right?
Do you need any police?
Police? What for?
Well, mobs get pretty ugly
sometimes, you know.
George, I'm going all out
to help in this crisis.
I've just guaranteed the bank
sufficient funds
to meet their needs.
They'll close up for a week
and then reopen.
He just took over the bank.
I may lose a fortune,
but I'm willing
to guarantee
your people, too.
Just tell them to bring
their shares over here,
and I will pay
50 cents on the dollar.
Oh, you never miss a trick,
do you, Potter?
Well, you're gonna
miss this one.
If you close
your doors before 6:00 p.m.,
you will never reopen.
(PHONE HANGING UP)
George,
was it a nice wedding?
Gosh, I wanted to be there.
Yeah.
You can take
this one off now.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Now, just remember
that this thing
isn't as black
as it appeared.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
I have some news
for you, folks.
I was just talking
to old man Potter,
and he's guaranteed
cash payments at the bank.
The bank's gonna
reopen next week.
But, George,
I got my money here.
Did he guarantee
this place?
Well, no, Charlie.
I didn't even ask him.
We don't need
Potter over here.
MAN: Then,
I'll take mine now.
No, but you're...
You're-- You're thinking
of this place all wrong,
as if I had
the money back in a safe.
The money's not here.
Well, your money's
in Joe's house.
That's right next to yours.
And in the Kennedy house
and Mrs. Macklin's house
and 100 others.
Why, you're lending them
the money to build,
and then,
they're gonna pay it back
to you as best they can.
Now, what are you gonna do,
foreclose on them?
I got $242 in here,
and $242 isn't going
to break anybody.
Okay, Tom. All right.
Here you are.
You sign this. You'll get
your money in 60 days.
Sixty days?
Now, that's what you
agreed to when you
bought your shares.
Tom! Tom, did you
get your money?
No.
Well, I did.
Old man Potter'll pay
50 cents on the dollar
for every share you've got.
ALL: 50 cents on the dollar!
Yes, cash!
Well, what do
you say?
Now, Tom, you have to stick
to your original agreement.
Now, give us 60 days on this.
Okay, Randall.
Are you going to
go to Potter's?
Better to get
half than nothing.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Tom! Tom!
Randall!
Now, Randall, wait! Wait.
Now, listen.
Now, listen to me.
I--I beg of you
not to do this thing.
If Potter gets a hold
of this Building and Loan,
there'll never be
another decent house
built in this town.
He's already got
charge of the bank.
He's got the bus line.
He got the department stores.
And now he's after us. Why?
Well, it's very simple.
Because we're cutting in
on his business, that's why.
And because
he wants to keep you
living in his slums
and paying the kind
of rent he decides.
Joe, you had one
of those Potter houses,
didn't you?
Well, have you forgotten?
Have you forgotten
what he charged you
for that broken-down shack?
Here, Ed, you know.
You remember last year
when things
weren't going so well
and you couldn't
make your payments.
Well, you didn't lose
your house, did you?
You think Potter
would've let you keep it?
Can't-- Can't you understand
what's happening here?
Don't you see
what's happening?
Potter isn't selling.
Potter's buying, and why?
Because we're panicky
and he's not. That's why.
He's picking up
some bargain.
Now we--we can get through
this thing all right.
We've-- We've got to
stick together, though.
We've got to have
faith in each other.
But my husband hasn't worked
in over a year,
and I need money.
How am going to live
until the bank opens?
I got doctor bills to pay.
I need cash.
MAN: I can't feed
my kids on faith.
How much do you need?
Hey! I got $2,000.
Here's $2,000.
This'll tide us over
till the bank reopens.
All right, Tom,
how much do you need?
$242.
Oh, Tom,
just enough to tide you over
until the bank reopens.
I'll take $242.
(ALL CHATTERING)
There you are.
That'll close my account.
Your account's still here.
That's a loan.
Okay. All right, Ed?
I got $300 here, George.
Now, Ed, w-w-what'll it take
till the bank opens?
What do you need?
Well, I suppose $20.
$20. Now you're talking.
Thanks, Ed. That's fine.
All right,
now, Mrs. Thompson,
how much do you want?
MRS. THOMPSON: But it's
your own money, George.
Never mind about that.
How much do you want?
I can get along
with $20, all right.
$20, fine.
And I'll sign the paper.
You don't have
to sign anything.
I know you.
You pay it when you can.
That's okay.
All right, Mrs. Davis?
Could I have $17.50?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Bless your heart.
Of course you can have it.
You got 50 cents?
Seven...
We're gonna make it, George.
...six...
They'll never
close us up today!
...five, four, three, two,
one, bingo!
We made it!
Close the door, Eustace!
We made it.
Look, look,
we're still in business.
We've still got
two bucks left.
Look, let's have
some of that.
Let's celebrate!
Get--get
some glasses, Tilly.
Well, a couple of
financial wizards.
Call us Rockefellers.
Get a tray
for these two great big
important simoleons here.
We'll save them
for seed. A toast.
A toast.
A toast to Mama Dollar
and to Papa Dollar,
and if you want to keep
this old Building and Loan
in business,
you better have
a family real quick.
I wish they were rabbits.
I wish they were, too.
Okay, let's put them
in the safe and
see what happens.
(ALL SINGING)
Close the door.
Folks, folks,
wedding cigars.
Oh-oh, wedding.
Holy mackerel, I'm married.
Where's Mary? Mary! Poor...
Look, I got a
train to catch.
Well, the train's gone.
I wonder
if Ernie's still here
with his taxicab.
George, there's
a call for you.
Look, will you get my wife
on the phone?
She's probably
over at her mother's.
Mrs. Bailey is
on the phone.
I don't want Mrs. Bailey.
I want my wife.
Mrs. Bailey!
Oh, that's my wife.
Here, I'll take it
in here.
Mary. Hello.
Listen, dear, I'm sorry.
Huh? Come home?
What home?
320 Sycamore?
Well, what...
Whose home is that?
The Waldorf Hotel, huh?
Hey, this is
the company's posters,
and the company
won't like this.
How would you like
to get a ticket next week?
You got
any romance in you?
Sure, I had it,
but I got rid of it.
Liver pills.
Who wants to see liver pills
on their honeymoon?
What we want is
romantic places,
beautiful places,
places George
wants to go.
(MAN WHISTLES)
Hey, Bert. Here he comes.
Come on,
we got to get this up.
He's coming.
Who?
The groom, idiot.
This is their honeymoon.
Come on. Get that ladder.
What are they, ducks?
Get that ladder up here.
All right, all right.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Hurry up.
I'm hurrying.
Hiya... Good evening, sir.
(GREETING IN FRENCH)
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
Welcome home, Mr. Bailey.
Well, I'll be...
Mary. Mary,
where did you...
* I love you truly
* Truly, dear
* Life with its shadows
Oh, Mary.
* Life with its tears
Remember the night we broke
some windows in this old
house?
This is what I wished for.
You're wonderful.
(WHISPERING)
* Truly, dear
Martini,
you rented a new house?
Rent?
(LAUGHING)
You hear
what he say, Mr. Bailey?
What's that?
I own the house.
Me, Giuseppe Martini,
I own my own house.
No more we live like a pigs
in this Potter's Field.
Mary, Mary!
Mary, come on,
bring the baby.
(ALL CHATTERING)
I feel like a queen.
I'll take
the kids in the car.
Oh, thank you,
Mr. Bailey. Thank you.
All right, kids, here.
Here, get in here.
Now, one at a time.
Get right up
on the seat there.
Sit down, there.
Here, now, get the dog, now.
That's it.
Goat, too.
Everybody!
All in!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
MARTINI: Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
All in?
(O SOLE MIO PLAYING)
(GOAT BLEATING)
Mr. and Mrs. Martini,
welcome home.
Good old George,
he's always making a speech.
Hee-haw!
Sam Wainwright.
Oh, who cares.
Bread. That this house
may never know hunger.
Salt. That life
may always have flavor.
And wine.
That joy and prosperity
may reign forever.
Enter the Martini castle.
(ALL CHEERING)
Look, Mr. Potter,
it's no skin off my nose.
I'm just your little
rent collector.
But you can't laugh off
this Bailey Park anymore.
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
Look at it.
WOMAN ON INTERCOM:
Congressman Black is here
to see you, sir.
Oh, tell the Congressman
to wait. Go on.
Fifteen years ago,
a half a dozen houses
stuck here and there.
There's the old cemetery,
squirrels, buttercups,
daisies.
I used to hunt
rabbits there myself.
Look at it today.
Dozens of the prettiest
little homes you ever saw,
90 per cent owned by suckers
who used to pay rent to you.
Your Potter's Field,
my dear Mr. Employer,
is becoming just that.
And are the local yokels
making with those
David and Goliath wisecracks.
Oh, they are, are they?
Even though they know
the Baileys never
made a dime out of it.
You know very well why.
The Baileys were all chumps.
Every one of these homes
is worth twice
what it cost the Building
and Loan to build.
If I were you,
Mr. Potter...
You are not me.
As I say,
it's no skin off my nose,
but one of these days
this bright young man
is gonna be asking
George Bailey for a job.
The Bailey family has been
a boil on my neck long enough.
WOMAN ON INTERCOM: Yes, sir?
Come in here.
We just stopped in town
to take a look
at the new factory,
and then we're gonna
drive on down to Florida.
Oh.
Why don't you
have your friends join us?
Why, sure.
Hey, why don't you kids
drive down with us, huh?
Oh, I'm afraid
I couldn't get away, Sam.
Still got the nose
to the old grindstone, eh?
Jane, I offered
to let George in
on the ground floor
in plastics,
and he turned me
down cold.
Oh, now, don't rub it in.
I'm not rubbing it in.
Well, I guess we better
run along.
Awfully happy
to have met you, Mary.
Nice meeting you, too.
Goodbye. Glad to see you.
Goodbye, George.
So long, George.
See you in the funny papers.
So long, Mary.
Bye, Sam. Have fun.
Thanks for
dropping around.
Florida!
Hee-haw!
BOTH: Hee-haw.
Thank you, sir.
That's quite
a cigar, Mr. Potter.
You like it?
I'll send you a box.
Well, I, uh...
I suppose I'll find out
sooner or later,
but just what
exactly did you want
to see me about?
(LAUGHING)
George, now that's
just what I like
so much about you.
George, I am an old man,
and most people hate me.
But I don't like them, either,
so that makes it all even.
You know
just as well as I do
that I run
practically everything
in this town
but the Bailey
Building and Loan.
You know, also,
that for a number of years
I've been trying
to get control of it.
Or kill it.
But I haven't
been able to do it.
You have been stopping me.
In fact,
you have beaten me, George,
and as anyone in this county
can tell you,
that takes some doing.
Take during the Depression,
for instance.
You and I were the only ones
that kept our heads.
You saved
the Building and Loan.
I saved all the rest.
Yes. Well, most people say
you stole all the rest.
The envious ones say that,
George, the suckers.
Now, I have stated
my side very frankly.
Now let's look at your side.
Young man, 27-28,
married,
making, say, $40 a week.
$45.
Out of which,
after supporting
your mother
and paying your bills,
you're able to keep,
say, $10, if you skimp.
A child or two comes along,
and you won't even be able
to save the $10.
Now, if this young man of 28
was a common, ordinary yokel,
I'd say he was doing fine.
But George Bailey
is not a common,
ordinary yokel.
He is an intelligent, smart,
ambitious young man,
who hates his job,
who hates
the Building and Loan
almost as much as I do.
A young man who's been dying
to get out on his own
ever since he was born.
A young man...
The smartest one
of the crowd, mind you.
A young man
who has to sit by
and watch
his friends go places
because he's trapped.
Yes, sir, trapped
into frittering his life away,
playing nursemaid
to a lot of garlic eaters.
Do I paint a correct picture,
or do I exaggerate?
Now, what's
your point, Mr. Potter?
My point?
My point is I want
to hire you.
Hire me?
Yeah, I want you
to manage my affairs,
run my properties.
George, I'll start you out
at $20,000 a year.
$20,000 a year?
You wouldn't mind living
in the nicest house in town,
buying your wife
a lot of fine clothes,
a couple of business trips
to New York a year,
maybe once in a while Europe.
You wouldn't mind that,
would you, George?
Would I?
Y-You're not
talking to somebody else
around here, are you?
You know, this--this is me.
You remember me?
George Bailey.
Yeah, George Bailey,
whose ship has just come in.
Provided he has enough brains
to climb aboard.
Holy mackerel.
Well, how about
the Building and Loan?
Oh, confound it, man,
are you afraid of success?
I'm offering you
a three-years contract
at $20,000 a year,
starting today.
Is it a deal, or isn't it?
Well, Mr. Potter, I...
I--I know I ought to
jump at the chance
but I... I just, uh...
I--I wonder if it would
be possible for you
to give me 24 hours
to think it over?
Sure, sure, sure.
You go on home
and talk about it
to your wife.
I'd like to do that.
Yeah.
In the meantime,
I'll draw up the papers.
All right, sir.
Okay, George?
Okay, Mr. Potter.
No. No. No, no,
now wait a minute, here.
Wait a...
I don't need 24 hours.
I--I don't have
to talk to anybody.
I know right now,
and the answer is no.
No, doggone it!
You sit around here,
and you spin
your little webs,
and you think the whole world
revolves around you
and your money.
Well, it doesn't,
Mr. Potter.
In the-- In the whole vast
configuration of things,
I'd say you were nothing
but a scurvy little spider.
You...
And that goes
for you, too!
And it goes for you, too!
POTTER:
You wouldn't mind living
in the nicest house in town,
buying your wife
a lot of fine clothes,
going to New York
on a business trip
a couple of times a year,
maybe Europe
once in a while.
GEORGE: I know what
I'm gonna do tomorrow
and the next
day and next year
and the year after that.
I'm shaking the dust
of this crummy
little town off my feet,
and I'm gonna
see the world.
And then I'm
gonna build things.
I'm gonna build airfields.
I'm gonna build skyscrapers
100 stories high.
I'm gonna build
a bridge a mile long.
What is it you want, Mary?
What, you--you want the moon?
If you do, just say the word,
I'll throw a lasso around it
and pull her down for you.
MARY: * Buffalo gal
Won't you come out tonight?
* Won't you come out
tonight? *
tonight?
* Buffalo gal
Won't you come out tonight
* And
Hi.
Mary Hatch,
why in the world
did you ever marry
a guy like me?
To keep from
being an old maid.
You could have married
Sam Wainwright
and anybody else
in town.
I didn't want to marry
anybody else in town.
I want my baby
to look like you.
You didn't even
have a honeymoon.
I promised you...
Your what?
My baby.
(STAMMERING) Your...
Mary, you--you
on the nest?
George Bailey
lassoes stork.
Lassoes a stork!
Well, you...
You mean you...
What is it,
a boy or a girl?
Mmm-hmm.
JOSEPH: Now, you've
probably already guessed
that George never
leaves Bedford Falls.
CLARENCE: No!
Mary had her baby,
a boy.
Then she had
another one, a girl.
Day after day
she worked away,
remaking the old
Granville house
into a home.
Night after night,
George came back
late from the office.
Potter was bearing
down hard.
Then came a war.
Ma Bailey and Mrs. Hatch
joined the Red Cross
and sewed.
Mary had two more babies
but still found time
to run the USO.
Sam Wainwright made
a fortune in plastic
hoods for planes.
Potter became head
of the draft board.
One-A.
Gower and Uncle Billy
sold war bonds.
Bert the cop was wounded
in North Africa,
got the Silver Star.
Ernie the taxi driver
parachuted into France.
Marty helped capture
the Remagen Bridge.
Harry...
Harry Bailey
topped them all.
A Navy flier,
he shot down 15 planes,
two of them as they were
about to crash
into a transport
full of soldiers.
Yes, but George.
George?
Four-F on account
of his ear,
George fought the
battle of Bedford Falls.
Now, hold on!
Hold on! Hold on now!
Don't you know
there's a war on?
Air raid warden.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Paper drives.
Scrap drives.
Rubber drives.
Like everybody else
on VE Day,
he wept and prayed.
On VJ Day,
he wept and prayed again.
FRANKLIN: Joseph,
now show him
what happened today.
Yes, sir.
This morning,
day before Christmas,
about 10:00 a.m.
Bedford Falls time...
Oh, hey, Ernie.
Look at that.
It's gonna snow again.
What do you mean,
it's gonna snow?
Look at the headlines.
The President...
I know,
I know, George.
That's marvelous.
Commander Harry Bailey!
Mr. Gower, look at this,
the second page.
Now, look,
this is for you.
This is for you.
That's for you.
Okay.
ERNIE: Right, right, thanks.
See you again.
Hey! Be sure you
spell the name right.
(CHUCKLING)
(HUMMING)
Extra! Read all about it!
EUSTACE: George, George!
It's Harry now
on long-distance
from Washington.
Harry!
What do you know
about that!
He reversed the charges.
It's okay, isn't it?
Reversed the charges?
Of course it is
for a hero.
Harry!
Ha! You old seven times
a son of a gun.
Congratulations.
Well, h-how's Mother
standing it? She did?
Well, what do you know?
Huh?
Mother had lunch with
the President's wife.
Wait till Martha
hears about this.
What did they
have to eat?
What'd they have to eat?
Uh, Harry,
you should see
what they're cooking up
in the town for you.
Oh, they are?
The Navy's gonna
fly Mother home
this afternoon.
In a plane?
What? Uncle Billy?
Has Uncle Billy
come in yet?
Oh, he stopped
at the bank first.
He's not here
right now, Harry.
But look, now, tell--
tell me about it.
George. George, George.
What?
That man is here again.
What man?
(STAMMERING)
Bank examiner.
Oh, oh.
Uh, Harry, talk to Eustace
for a minute, will you?
I'll be right back.
Well, Harry.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Oh, good morning, sir.
Carter, bank examiner.
Mr. Carter, Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
We're all excited
around here.
My brother just got
the Congressional
Medal of Honor.
The President
just decorated him.
Well, I guess they do
those things.
Well, I trust you had
a good year.
Good year?
Uh, well, between you and me,
Mr. Carter, we're broke.
Yeah, very funny.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Well, uh, well, now,
come right in here,
Mr. Carter.
Although I shouldn't
wonder when you okay
reverse charges
on personal
long-distance calls.
George, shall
we hang up?
No, no. He wants to
talk to Uncle Billy.
You just hold on, there.
Now, if you'll cooperate,
I'd like to finish
with you by tonight.
I want to spend Christmas
in Elmira with my family.
I don't blame you at all,
Mr. Carter.
Just step right in here.
We'll fix you up.
December 24.
$8,000.
ALL: Merry Christmas,
Mr. Potter.
Merry Christmas.
Well, good morning,
Mr. Potter.
What's the news?
Oh, well, well, well,
"Harry Bailey wins
Congressional Medal."
That couldn't be
one of the Bailey boys.
You just can't keep
those Baileys down,
now can you, Mr. Potter?
How does slacker George
feel about that?
Very jealous.
He only lost three
buttons off his vest.
Of course,
slacker George
would've gotten
two of these medals
if he had gone.
Bad ear.
Yes.
After all, Potter,
some people like George
had to stay at home.
Not every heel
was in Germany
and Japan.
(CHUCKLING)
Good morning,
Mr. Bailey.
Good morning, Horace.
I guess you forgot
something.
Huh?
You forgot something.
What?
Well, aren't you going
to make a deposit?
Oh, sure, sure I am.
Well, then, it's usually
customary to bring
the money with you.
Huh?
Oh, shucks,
I knew I had. I...
How about that
finger there?
Well, I...
Bailey.
Take me back there.
Hurry up.
Come on, look sharp.
Take me back.
Just make yourself
at home, Mr. Carter.
I got those books
for you here.
Oh, hello, Vi.
George,
can I see you
for a second?
Why, of course you can.
Go on in the office there.
Oh, Uncle Billy,
talk to Harry.
He's on the telephone.
TILLY: Hurry up,
Uncle Billy, hurry.
Long distance, Washington.
EUSTACE: Hey, here's Harry
on the phone.
You know, your nephew,
remember? Harry.
Here he is.
Hurry up.
(STAMMERING)
Hello? Hello. Yes, Harry,
yes, everything's fine.
I ought to have
my head examined.
$8,000.
It's got to be
somewhere.
Here you are.
Character?
If I had
any character, I'd...
It takes a lot of character
to leave your hometown
and start all over again.
No, George, don't.
Here now, you're broke,
aren't you?
I know, but...
What do you want to do,
hock your furs
and that hat?
You want to walk
to New York?
You know, they charge
for meals and rent up there,
just the same as they do
in Bedford Falls.
Yeah, sure.
No, that's a loan, now.
That's my business,
Building and Loan.
Besides, you'll get a job.
Good luck to you.
I'm glad I know you,
George Bailey.
Say hello to New York
for me.
Yeah, yeah, sure, I will.
Now, let's hear from you
once in a while.
Merry Christmas, Vi.
Merry Christmas, George.
Mr. Bailey.
Oh, Mr. Carter, I'm sorry.
I'll be right with you.
Uncle Billy in there?
TILLY: Yeah,
he's in his office.
Unc...
What's going on?
The bank
examiner's here.
He's here?
Oh, yeah, yeah. He wants
the accounts payable...
What's the matter
with you?
Come here.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Eustace.
Yeah?
Come here a minute.
Did you see Uncle Billy
with any cash last night?
He had it on his desk
counting it
before he closed up.
Now, look,
did you buy anything?
Nothing. Not even
a stick of gum.
All right, all right.
Now, we'll go over
every step you took
since you left
the house.
Right. This way.
Come on.
(HORN HONKING)
And did you put the envelope
in your pocket?
Yeah, maybe, maybe.
Maybe! Maybe!
I don't want any maybe.
We've got to find
that money!
I'm no good to you, George.
Uncle Billy, look,
do you realize
what's going to happen
if we don't find it?
Listen to me.
Do you have any
secret hiding place
here in the house?
Someplace
you would have...
Someplace you hide
the money?
I've gone over
the whole house,
even in rooms
that have been locked
since I lost Laura.
Listen to me, listen to me!
Think, think!
I can't think anymore,
George.
I can't think anymore.
It hurts.
Where's that money,
you silly, stupid old fool?
Where's that money?
Do you realize
what this means?
It means bankruptcy
and scandal and prison!
That's what it means.
One of us is going to jail.
Well, it's not going
to be me.
(SOBBING)
(PLAYING HARK!
THE HERALD ANGELS SING)
Hello, darling.
Hello, Daddy.
(SNEEZING)
How do you like it?
Bless you!
Did you bring
the wreath?
PETE: Yes, Daddy,
did you bring
the Christmas wreath?
What wreath?
Th-The Merry Christmas wreath
for the window.
No. I left it
at the office.
Is it snowing?
Yeah, it just started.
Where's your coat
and hat?
Left them at the office.
What's the matter?
Nothing's the matter.
Everything's all right.
(GROWLING)
Come on, Pete,
you're a big boy.
You can help me
get this star up.
Way up at the top.
There. That's it.
All right,
fill in that little bare spot
right there. Right there.
(GRUNTING)
MARY: Isn't it
wonderful about Harry?
We're famous, George.
Bet I had 50 calls today
about the parade,
the banquet.
Your mother's so excited.
She...
(JANIE CONTINUES
PLAYING PIANO)
Must she keep
playing that?
I have to practice it
for the party tonight,
Daddy.
Mama said we could
stay up till midnight
and sing Christmas carols.
Can you sing, Daddy?
MARY: Better hurry
and shave.
The families
will be here soon.
Families.
I--I don't want
the families over here.
Come on out
in the kitchen with me
while I finish dinner.
Excuse me.
Have a hectic day?
Oh, yeah.
Another
big red-letter day
for the Baileys.
Daddy, the Browns next door
have a new car.
You should see it.
Well, what's the
matter with our car?
Isn't it good enough
for you?
Yes, Daddy.
Excuse me.
Excuse you for what?
I burped.
(SIGHING)
All right, darling,
you're excused.
Now, go on upstairs
and see if little Zuzu
wants anything.
Zuzu? W-W-What's
the matter with Zuzu?
Oh, she's just got a cold.
She's in bed.
Caught it coming
home from school.
They gave her a flower
for a prize, and she didn't
want to crush it,
so she didn't
button up her coat.
What is it,
a sore throat or what?
It's just a cold.
The doctor says
it's nothing serious.
The doctor?
Was the doctor here?
Yes, I called him right away.
He says it's nothing
to worry about.
Is she running
a temperature?
What is it?
Just a teensy one, 99.6.
She'll be all right.
Of course,
it's this old house.
I don't know why
we don't all
have pneumonia.
Drafty old barn.
Might as well be living
in a refrigerator.
Why did we have
to live here
in the first place
and stay around this
measly, crummy old town?
George, what's wrong?
Wrong! Everything's wrong.
You call this
a happy family?
Why do we have to have
all these kids?
PETE: Dad, how do you
spell "frankincense"?
I don't know.
Ask your mother.
Where're you going?
I'm going up to see Zuzu.
He told me to write
a play for tomorrow.
(PIANO PLAYING CONTINUES)
F-r-a-n-k-i-n...
Hi, Daddy!
Well, what happened
to you?
I won a flower.
Wait now.
Where do you think
you're going?
I want to give
my flower a drink.
All right, all right.
Now, give Daddy the flower.
I'll give it a drink.
Now, here.
Look, Daddy!
Paste it!
Yeah, all right, all right.
Give it here.
Now, we'll paste
this together here.
There. There it is.
Good as new.
Now, give the flower
a drink.
Now, will you do
something for me?
(WHISPERING) What?
(WHISPERING) Will you try
and get some sleep?
I'm not sleepy.
I want to look
at my flower.
I know, I know,
but you just go to sleep
and then you can
dream about it,
and it'll be
a whole garden.
It will?
Uh-huh.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
KIDS: Telephone!
I'll get it.
Hello?
Yes, this is Mrs. Bailey.
MARY: Oh, thank you,
Mrs. Welch.
I'm sure
she'll be all right.
The doctor said
that she ought to be
out of bed
in time to have
her Christmas dinner.
Is that Zuzu's teacher?
Yes.
Let me speak to her.
Hello. Hello, Mrs. Welch?
This is George Bailey.
I'm Zuzu's father.
Say, what kind of
a teacher are you,
anyway?
What do you mean
sending her home
like that, half naked?
Do you realize
she'll probably
end up
with pneumonia
on account of you?
George!
Is this the sort of thing
we pay taxes for
to have teachers...
to have teachers like you?
Stupid, silly,
careless people
who send our kids home
without any clothes on?
You know,
maybe my kids aren't
the best-dressed kids.
And maybe they don't have
any decent clothes...
That stupid...
H-H-Hello, Mrs. Welch.
I want to apologize...
Hello? Hello.
She's hung up!
I'll hang her up!
MAN ON PHONE: Hey, you!
I'll knock your block off!
What is that?
Hello! Who's this?
Oh, Mr. Welch?
Okay, that's fine,
Mr. Welch.
Give me a chance
to tell you what I really
think of your wife.
George, stop it.
Will you get out
and let me handle this?
Hello? Hello? What?
Oh, you will, huh?
Okay, Mr. Welch.
Any time you think
you're man enough, you...
Hello! Any...
Dad, how do you spell
"hallelujah"?
How should I know?
What do you think I am,
a dictionary?
Tommy, stop that!
Stop it!
Janie,
haven't you learned
that silly tune yet?
You play it over
and over again.
Now stop it! Stop it!
I'm sorry, Mary.
Janie, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that. I...
You go on and practice.
Pete, I owe you
an apology, too.
I'm sorry.
What do you want to know?
Nothing, Daddy.
What's the matter
with everybody?
Janie, go on.
I told you to practice.
Now, go on, play!
Oh, Daddy!
(JANIE CRYING)
George, why must you
torture the children?
Why don't you...
Mary...
(DOOR CLOSING)
Bedford 247, please.
Is Daddy in trouble?
Yes, Pete.
Shall I pray for him?
Yes, Janie,
pray very hard.
Me, too?
You, too, Tommy.
Hello? Uncle Billy?
I'm in trouble, Mr. Potter.
I need help.
Through some
sort of an accident,
my company's short
in their accounts.
The bank examiner
got there today.
I've got to raise
$8,000 immediately.
Oh, that's what
the reporters wanted
to talk to you about?
The reporters?
Yes.
They called me up
from your Building and Loan.
Oh, there's a man over there
from the D.A.'s office, too.
He's looking for you.
Please help me,
Mr. Potter.
Help me,
won't you, please?
Can't you see
what it means
to my family?
I'll pay any sort of
a bonus on the loan,
any interest,
if you still want
the Building and Loan...
George,
could it possibly be
there's
a slight discrepancy
in the books?
No, sir. There's nothing
wrong with the books.
I've just misplaced $8,000.
I can't find it anywhere.
You misplaced $8,000?
Yes, sir.
Have you notified
the police?
No, sir.
I didn't want
the publicity.
Harry's
homecoming tomorrow...
(CHUCKLING)
They're going to
believe that one.
What've you been
doing, George?
Um, playing the market
with the company's money?
No, sir. No, sir,
I haven't.
Oh, is it a woman,
then?
You know,
it's all over town
that you've been giving
money to Violet Bick.
What?
Not that it makes
any difference to me,
but why did you
come to me?
Why don't you go
to Sam Wainwright
and ask him for the money?
I can't get a hold of him.
He's in Europe.
Well, what about all
your other friends?
They don't have that
kind of money, Mr. Potter.
You know that.
You're the only one
in town that can help me.
(CHUCKLING)
I've suddenly become
quite important.
What--what kind of security
would I have, George?
Have you got any stocks?
No, sir.
Bonds? Real estate?
Collateral of any kind?
I have some life insurance,
a $15,000 policy.
Yes. How much
is your equity in it?
Five hundred dollars.
Five hundred dollars?
And you ask me
to lend you $8,000?
Look at you.
You used to be so cocky.
You were going to go out
and conquer the world.
You once called me a warped,
frustrated old man.
What are you but a warped,
frustrated young man?
A miserable little clerk,
crawling in here
on your hands and knees
and begging for help.
No securities,
no stocks, no bonds.
Nothing but a miserable
little $500 equity
in a life insurance policy.
(CHUCKLING)
You're worth more
dead than alive.
Why don't you go
to the riffraff
you love so much
and ask them
to let you have $8,000?
You know why?
Because they'd run you
out of town on a rail.
But I tell you
what I'm going to do
for you, George.
Since the state examiner
is still here,
as a stockholder
of the Building and Loan,
I'm going to swear out
a warrant for your arrest.
Misappropriation of funds,
manipulation, malfeasance.
All right, George,
go ahead.
You can't hide
in a little town
like this.
Yeah, Bill?
This is Potter.
MARTINI: Ah! Merry Christmas!
Glad you come!
MAN: How about some of
that good spaghetti?
We got everything.
(ITALIAN MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, God.
Dear Father in Heaven,
I'm not a praying man,
but if you're up there
and you can hear me,
show me the way.
I'm at the end
of my rope. I...
Show me the way, O God.
Are you all right, George?
Want somebody
to take you home, huh?
Why you drink so much,
my friend?
Please go home, Mr. Bailey.
This is Christmas Eve.
Bailey?
Which Bailey?
This is
Mr. George Bailey.
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
MR. WELCH: The next time
you talk to my wife
like that, you'll get worse!
She cried for an hour!
It isn't enough
she slaves teaching
your stupid kids
how to read and write,
and you have
to bawl her out.
You get out of here,
Mr. Welch!
Now, wait,
I want to pay
for my drink.
Never mind the money!
You get out of here quick!
All right!
You hit my best friend!
Get out!
You all right, George?
Who was that?
He gone. No worry.
He name is Welch.
He no come into
my place no more.
Oh, Welch.
That's what I get
for praying.
The last time
he come in here.
You hear that, Nick?
Yes, you bet.
Where's my insurance policy?
Oh, here it is.
Oh, no, please,
don't go this way,
Mr. Bailey.
I'm all right.
No, no, you no feel
so good.
Sit down and rest.
I'm all right.
Please no go away,
please!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
What do you think
you're doing?
Now look what you did.
My great-grandfather
planted this tree!
Hey, you! Hey, you!
Come back here,
you drunken fool!
Get this car out of here!
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(HORN HONKING)
MAN: Hey,
what's the matter
with you?
Look where you're going.
CLARENCE: Help!
Help! Help!
(CLARENCE SCREAMING)
Help!
Help! Help! Help! Help!
(CLARENCE SCREAMING)
Help! Help!
I didn't have time
to get some
stylish underwear.
Wife gave me this
on my last birthday.
I passed away in it.
Oh, Tom Sawyer's
drying out, too.
You should read the new book
Mark Twain's writing now.
How did you
happen to fall in?
I didn't fall in.
I jumped in
to save George.
You what? To save me?
Well, I did,
didn't I?
You didn't go
through with it,
did you?
Go through with what?
Suicide.
It's against the law to
commit suicide around here.
Yeah, it's against the law
where I come from, too.
Where do you come from?
Heaven.
I had to act quickly.
That's why I jumped in.
I knew if I were drowning,
you'd try to save me.
You see, you did,
and that's how I saved you.
Very funny.
Your lip's bleeding,
George.
Yeah, I got a bust
in the jaw
in answer to a prayer
a little bit ago.
Oh, no, no, no,
George,
I'm the answer
to your prayer.
That's why I was sent
down here.
How'd you know
my name?
Oh, I know
all about you.
I've watched you grow up
from a little boy.
What are you,
a mind reader
or something?
(CHUCKLING) No.
Well, who are you then?
Clarence Oddbody, AS2.
Oddbody?
(STAMMERING)
AS2? What's that, AS2?
Angel Second Class.
Cheerio, my good man.
Oh, brother.
Gee whiz.
I wonder what Martini
put in those drinks.
Hey, what's with you?
W-W-What did you say
just a minute ago?
Why'd you want
to save me?
That's what
I was sent down for.
I'm your guardian angel.
I wouldn't be
a bit surprised.
Ridiculous of you
to think of killing yourself
for money, $8,000.
Yeah, now,
just things like that...
How do you know that?
I told you.
I'm your guardian angel.
I know everything
about you.
Well, you look
about like the kind
of an angel I'd get.
Sort of a fallen angel,
aren't you?
What happened
to your wings?
I haven't won my wings yet.
That's why I'm
an Angel Second Class.
I don't know whether
I'd like it very much
being seen around
with an angel
without any wings.
Oh, I've got to earn them,
and you'll help me,
won't you?
Sure, sure.
How?
By letting me help you.
Yes. Only one way
you can help me.
You--you don't happen
to have 8,000 bucks
on you, do you?
Oh, no. No.
We don't use money
in heaven.
Oh, yeah, that's right,
I keep forgetting.
Comes in pretty handy
down here, bub.
Oh, tut, tut, tut.
I found it out
a little late.
I'm worth more
dead than alive.
Now, look, you mustn't
talk like that.
I won't get my wings
with that attitude.
You just don't know
all that you've done.
If it hadn't been
for you...
Yeah, if it hadn't
been for me,
everybody'd be
a lot better off.
My wife and my kids
and my friends.
I mean, look,
little fellow,
go off and haunt
somebody else, will you?
No, now,
you don't understand.
I've got my job...
Oh, shut up, will you?
Oh, this isn't gonna
be so easy.
Yeah, so you still think
killing yourself
would make everyone
feel happier, eh?
Well, I don't know.
I guess you're right.
I suppose it would
have been better
if I'd never been
born at all.
What'd you say?
I said I wish
I'd never been born.
Oh, you mustn't say
things like that.
You...
Wait a minute.
That's an idea.
What do you think?
Yeah, that'll do it.
All right.
You've got your wish.
You've never been born.
(WIND BLOWING)
You don't have
to make all that fuss
about it!
What did you say?
You've never been born.
You don't exist.
You haven't a care
in the world.
No worries, no obligations,
no $8,000 to get,
no Potter looking for you
with the Sheriff.
Say something else
in that ear.
Sure, you can hear
out of it.
Well, that's
the doggonedest thing.
I haven't heard anything
out of that ear
since I was a kid.
Must have been that jump
in that cold water.
Your lip stopped bleeding,
too, George.
What do you know
about that?
What's happening?
It stopped snowing
out here, didn't it?
Well, I...
What's happened here?
What I need is a couple
of good stiff drinks.
How about you, Angel?
You want a drink?
(LAUGHING)
Come on, soon as these
clothes of ours are dry...
The clothes are dry.
What do you know
about that?
Stove's hotter
than I thought.
Now, come on,
get your clothes on.
We'll stroll up
to my car and get...
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll stroll. You fly.
I can't fly.
I haven't got
my wings.
You haven't got your wings.
Yeah, that's right.
(WIND WHISTLING)
What's the matter?
Well, this is where
I left my car,
and it isn't here.
You have no car.
Well, I had a car,
and it was right here.
I guess somebody
moved it.
Good evening.
Oh, say, hey,
w-where's my car?
I beg your pardon?
My car, my car.
GEORGE: I'm the fellow
that owns the car
that ran into your tree.
MAN: What tree?
What do you mean,
what tree?
This tree.
Here, I ran into it.
Cut a big gash
in the side of it there.
You must mean
two other trees.
You had me worried.
One of the oldest
trees in Pottersville.
Pottersville?
Why, you mean Bedford Falls.
I mean Pottersville.
Don't you think
I know where I live?
What's the matter
with you?
What's the matter with me?
Well, I guess I just...
Oh, I don't know.
Either I'm off my nut
or he is or you are.
It isn't me.
Well, maybe I left the car
up at Martini's.
Well, come on, Gabriel.
Clarence.
Clarence. Clarence.
That's all right.
Go on in.
Martini is
a friend of mine.
There's a place
to sit down. Sit down.
Oh, hello, Nick.
Hey, where's Martini?
Want a martini?
No, no, Martini.
Your boss.
Where is he?
Hey, look,
I'm the boss.
You want a drink
or don't you?
Okay, all right.
Double bourbon,
will you, and quick, huh?
Okay.
What's yours?
I was just thinking.
(CHUCKLING)
It's been so long
since I...
Look, mister,
I'm standing here
waiting for you
to make up your mind.
That's a good man.
I was just thinking
of a flaming rum punch.
No, it's not cold
enough for that,
not nearly cold enough.
Wait a minute.
I got it.
Mulled wine,
heavy on the cinnamon
and light on the cloves.
Off with you, me lad,
and be lively!
Hey, look, mister,
we serve hard drinks
in here
for men who want
to get drunk fast.
And we don't need
any characters around
to give the joint
atmosphere.
NICK: Is that clear,
or do I have to slip you
my left for a convincer?
What's he talking about?
Nick, Nick,
just give him
the same as mine.
He's okay.
Okay.
What's the matter
with him?
I never saw Nick
act like that before.
You'll see
a lot of strange things
from now on.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, little fellow,
you worry me, you know.
You--you got someplace
to sleep?
No.
You don't, huh?
Well, you--you got
any money?
No.
No wonder you jumped
in the river.
I jumped in the river
to save you
so I could get my wings.
(CASH REGISTER RINGS)
Oh-oh.
Somebody's just made it.
Made what?
Every time you hear
a bell ring, it means
that some angel's
just got his wings.
Look, uh,
I think maybe
you better not mention
getting your wings
around here.
Why? Don't they believe
in angels?
I...
Yeah, they believe
in them.
Oh, why should
they be surprised
when they see one?
Oh, he never
grew up. He's...
How old are you
anyway, Clarence?
Two hundred
and ninety-three, uh,
next May.
That does it.
Out, you two pixies!
Go through the door
or out the window.
Look, Nick,
what's wrong?
Now, that's another thing.
Where do you come off
calling me Nick?
GEORGE: Well, Nick,
that's your name.
NICK: What's that
got to do with it?
I don't know you
from Adam's off ox.
Hey. Hey, you rummy, there.
Come here, come here.
Didn't I tell you
never to come panhandling
around here, huh?
(ALL LAUGH)
Mr. Gower.
What... What did...
Mr. Gower, look,
this is George Bailey.
Don't you know me?
No.
NICK: Throw him out.
Throw him out.
Mr. Gower! Hey, what is...
Hey, Nick. Nick.
Isn't that Mr. Gower,
the druggist?
You know,
that's another reason
for me not to like you.
That rum head
spent 20 years in jail
for poisoning a kid.
If you know him,
you must be
a jailbird yourself.
Uh, would you show
these gentlemen
to the door?
Sure. This way,
gentlemen.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
Stay out.
Get me! I'm giving out wings!
(ALL LAUGHING)
You see, George,
you were not there
to stop Gower
from putting that poison
into the capsules.
What do you mean,
I wasn't there?
I remember distinctly...
Hey, what's going on
around here?
What... What...
Why, this ought to
be Martini's place.
Look, who are you?
I told you, George.
I'm your guardian angel.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
You told me that.
What else are you?
What, are you--you
a hypnotist?
No. Of course not.
Well, then,
why am I seeing all these
strange things here?
Don't you understand,
George?
It's because
you were not born.
Well, if I wasn't born,
who am I?
You're nobody.
You have no identity.
What do you mean,
no identity?
My name's George Bailey.
There is no George Bailey.
You have no papers, no cards,
no driver's license,
no 4-F card,
no insurance policy.
They're not there, either.
What?
Zuzu's petals.
You've been given
a great gift, George,
a chance to see
what the world
would be like without you.
Now, wait a minute here.
Wait a minute here.
This is some sort of
a funny dream I'm having.
So long, mister.
I--I'm going home.
Home? What home?
Oh, shut up! Cut it out!
(STUTTERING) You're crazy!
That's what I think.
You're-- you're screwy.
You're driving me
crazy, too.
I'm seeing things here.
I'm going home
and see my wife
and family.
You understand that?
And I'm going home
alone.
How am I doing,
Joseph?
Thanks.
No, I didn't have a drink.
(JAZZ PLAYING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(CROWDS CHEERING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Hey, hey,
where did the Building
and Loan move to?
Building and what?
The Bailey
Building and Loan.
It was up there.
They went out of
business years ago.
That sailor's a liar!
I know every big
shot in this town!
I know Potter,
and I'll have
you kicked off the beat.
Hey, Violet!
Hey, hey! Listen.
That's Violet Bick.
I know.
I know that girl!
Take a walk. Beat it.
GEORGE: Hey, Ernie!
Ernie.
Ernie, take me home.
I'm going off my nut.
Where do you live?
Now, doggone it, Ernie,
don't you start
pulling that stuff.
You know where I live.
320 Sycamore.
Now hurry up.
All right. 320 Sycamore?
Yeah, yeah, hurry up.
Zuzu's sick.
Come on.
All right. All right.
Come on, Ernie,
now straighten me
out here.
Look,
I've got some bad liquor
or something. Listen to me.
Now, you are Ernie Bishop,
and you live in Bailey Park
with your wife and kid?
That's right, isn't it?
You seen my wife?
Seen your wife?
I've been to your house
100 times.
Look, bud, what's the idea?
I live in a shack
in Potter's Field,
my wife ran away
three years ago
and took the kid,
and I ain't never seen you
before in my life, see?
Okay, well, just step on it.
Just get me home!
Is this the place?
Of course it's the place.
Well, this house
ain't been lived in
for 20 years.
What's up, Ernie?
I don't know.
But we better keep
our eye on this guy.
He's bats.
Mary. Mary!
Tommy! Pete! Janie! Zuzu!
Where are you?
They're not here, George.
You have no children.
Where are they?
What have you done
with them?
BERT: All right,
put up your hands.
No fast moves.
Come on out here,
both of you.
Bert! Thank heaven
you're here.
Back this.
Bert, what's happened
to this house?
Where--where's Mary?
Where's my kids?
Watch him, Bert.
Come on, come on.
GEORGE: Bert, Ernie.
What's the matter
with you two guys?
You--you--you were here
on my wedding night.
You, both of you,
stood out there
on the porch
and sung to us,
don't you remember?
Think I'd better be going.
Look, now, why don't you
be a good kid,
and we'll take you in
to a doctor?
Everything's gonna
be all right.
Bert, no, listen to me.
Ernie,
will you take me over
to my mother's house?
Bert, listen.
It's that fellow here.
He says he's an angel.
He's trying
to hypnotize me.
I hate to do
this to you, bud, but...
(SCREAMING)
CLARENCE: Run, George!
Run, George! Run!
BERT: Ow!
Joseph! Help!
Oh, shut up.
Help!
Oh, Joseph! Joseph!
Where'd he go?
I had him right here.
I need a drink.
Well, which way did he go?
Help me find him.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Well?
Mother.
Mother? What do you want?
Mother, this is George.
I thought sure
you'd remember me.
George who?
If you're looking
for a room,
there's no vacancy.
Mother, listen.
Please help me.
Something terrible's
happened to me.
I don't know what it is.
Something's
happened to everybody.
Please let me come in,
and keep me here
until I get over it.
Get over what?
I don't take in
strangers
unless they're sent here
by somebody I know.
W-Well, I know everybody
you know.
Your brother-in-law,
Uncle Billy.
You know him?
Well, sure I do.
When did you see him last?
Today over at his house.
It's a lie. He's been
in the insane asylum
ever since he lost
his business.
And if you ask me,
that's where
you belong.
Strange, isn't it?
Each man's life
touches so many
other lives.
CLARENCE:
And when he isn't around,
he leaves an awful hole,
doesn't he?
I've heard of
things like this.
You got me in
some kind of
a spell or something.
Well, I'm gonna
get out of it.
I'll get out of it.
I know how, too. I...
The last man I talked to,
before all this stuff
started happening
to me, was Martini.
You know where he lives?
Well, sure,
I know where he lives.
He lives in Bailey Park.
Are you sure
this is Bailey Park?
No, I'm not sure
of anything anymore.
All I know is
this should be
Bailey Park.
But where are
the houses?
You weren't here
to build them.
Your brother Harry Bailey
broke through the ice
and was drowned
at the age of nine.
That's a lie.
Harry Bailey
went to war.
He got the Congressional
Medal of Honor.
He saved
the lives of every man
on that transport.
Every man
on that transport died.
Harry wasn't there
to save them,
because you weren't there
to save Harry.
You see, George?
You really had
a wonderful life.
Don't you see
what a mistake it would be
to throw it away?
Clarence.
Yes, George?
Where's Mary?
(STAMMERING)
Oh, well, I can't...
I don't know
how you know these things,
but tell me, where is she?
If you know where she is,
tell me where my wife is.
I'm not supposed to tell.
Please, Clarence,
tell me where she is.
You're not gonna
like it, George.
Where is she?
She's an old maid.
She never married.
Where is Mary?
Where is she?
She's just about to
close up the library!
(GROANING) There must be
some easier way for me
to get my wings.
GEORGE: Mary!
Mary!
Mary! Mary!
Mary, it's George.
Don't you know me?
What's happened to us?
I don't know you.
Let me go!
Mary, please!
Oh, don't do this to me.
Please, Mary, help me.
Where's our kids?
I need you, Mary.
(SCREAMING)
Help me, Mary!
Mary! Let me go!
MARY: Help!
It's a wild man!
The wild man is chasing me.
Somebody stop him!
Tom! Ed! Charlie!
That's my wife!
(SCREAMING)
Mary!
MAN 1: No, you don't.
MAN 2: Somebody
call the police.
MAN 3: Somebody hit him
on the head with a bottle.
You need
a straightjacket.
(SIREN WAILING)
Clarence!
MAN: Get out of here!
GEORGE: Clarence!
Right, that's you!
Stand back!
(GUN FIRING)
Clarence!
(SIREN WAILING)
Clarence! Clarence!
Help me, Clarence!
Get me back!
Get me back. I don't care
what happens to me.
Get me back
to my wife and kids.
Help me, Clarence,
please.
Please. I want to live again.
I want to live again.
(WIND STOPS HOWLING)
Please, God,
let me live again.
(SOBBING)
Hey, George!
George!
You all right.
Hey, what's the matter?
Now get out of here, Bert,
or I'll hit you again!
Get out of here!
What the sam hill
are you yelling for,
George?
You...
Bert, do you know me?
Know you? You kidding?
I've been
looking all over town
trying to find you.
I saw your car
piled into that tree
down there,
and I thought maybe you...
Hey, your mouth's bleeding.
Are you sure
you're all right?
What did...
(LAUGHS)
My mouth's bleeding, Bert!
My mouth's...
Zuzu's petals. Zuzu...
There they are!
(SHOUTING) Bert! What
do you know about that?
Merry Christmas!
Well, Merry Christmas.
Mary! Mary!
(CHEERING)
Hello, Bedford Falls!
Merry Christmas!
MAN: Merry Christmas,
George!
WOMAN: Merry Christmas!
MAN 2: Merry Christmas,
George.
GEORGE: Merry Christmas,
movie house!
Merry Christmas,
emporium!
you wonderful
old Building and Loan!
Hey, Merry Christmas,
Mr. Potter!
Happy New Year
to you in jail!
Go on home.
They're waiting for you.
GEORGE: Mary! Mary!
Mary!
Well, hello,
Mr. Bank Examiner!
How are you?
Mr. Bailey,
there's a deficit.
I know, $8,000.
George, I've got
a little paper here.
I'll bet it's a warrant
for my arrest.
Isn't it wonderful?
I'm going to jail!
Merry Christmas!
Reporters?
Where's Mary?
Mary!
Oh, look at this wonderful,
old drafty house.
Mary! Mary!
Mary.
Have you seen my wife?
CHILDREN:
Merry Christmas, Daddy.
Kids! Pete!
(LAUGHING)
Kids! Janie!
Janie! Tommy!
Let me look at you.
Oh, I could eat you up.
GEORGE:
Where's your mother?
PETE: She went looking
for you.
JANIE: With Uncle Billy.
Daddy!
Zuzu!
Zuzu, my little gingersnap.
How do you feel?
Fine!
Not a smidge
of temperature.
(LAUGHS) Not a smidge of...
GEORGE: Hallelujah!
Hello.
MARY: George!
George, darling!
Mary! Mary!
George, darling.
Where have you been?
Oh, George, George, George.
Mary.
Oh, let me touch you.
Let me touch you.
Are you real?
George, George.
You have no idea
what's happened to me.
You've no idea
what happened...
Well, come on, George.
Come on downstairs, quick.
They're on their way.
All right.
Come on.
(LAUGHS)
Come on
in here now.
Now, you stand
right over here
by the tree.
Right there,
and don't move.
Don't move.
What's happening?
Who's gonna come?
Oh, I hear them
coming now.
George, it's a miracle.
It's a miracle.
JANIE: What's happening?
What's happening?
PETE: Who's gonna
come, Daddy?
ZUZU: Who, Daddy?
GEORGE: I don't know.
Come in, Uncle Billy.
Everybody, in here.
George. George.
Here's everything
right here.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Isn't it wonderful?
So many friends.
Mary did it, George!
Mary did it!
She told some people
you were in trouble,
and they
scattered all over town
collecting money.
Didn't ask any questions.
Just said,
"George in trouble?
Then count me in."
What is this...
You never saw
anything like it.
...another run
on the bank?
Here you are, George.
Merry Christmas.
ERNIE: Now, don't crowd.
Don't push.
There we are.
The line forms
on the right.
MAN: More coming, George.
Merry Christmas,
and God bless you.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, Mr. Martini!
ERNIE: Martini!
Step right up here.
I busted the jukebox, too.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, Mr. Gower!
I made the rounds
of my charge accounts.
I'm not gonna go, George.
I changed my mind.
Violet Bick.
Oh, Annie! Annie!
I've been saving
this money
for a divorce,
if ever I get a husband.
ANNIE: Merry Christmas.
There you are, George.
I got the faculty
all up and out of bed.
Here's something
for you to play with.
I wouldn't have
a roof over my head
if it wasn't
for you, George.
ERNIE: Just a minute.
Just a minute.
Quiet, everybody.
Quiet, quiet.
Now, get this,
it's from London.
Oh!
"Mr. Gower cabled
you need cash. Stop.
"My office instructed
to advance you
up to $25,000. Stop.
"Hee-haw and Merry Christmas.
Sam Wainwright."
(ALL CHEERING)
And Mr. Martini.
How about some wine?
(JANIE PLAYING PIANO)
ALL: * Hark the herald
angels sing
* Glory to the newborn king
* Peace on earth
and mercy mild
* God and sinners reconciled
* Joyful, all ye nations rise
* Join the triumph
of the skies
* With angelic host proclaim
* Christ is born
in Bethlehem *
ERNIE: Harry Bailey!
George, you old son of a gun.
Harry. Harry.
Looks like I got here
too late.
Mary, I got him here
from the airport
just as quick as I could.
The fool flew
all the way up here
in a blizzard.
Harry,
how about your banquet
in New York?
Oh, I left right
in the middle of it
as soon as I got
Mary's telegram.
Good idea, Ernie.
A toast
to my big brother, George,
the richest man in town!
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL: * Should auld
acquaintance be forgot
* And never brought to mind?
* Should auld acquaintance
be forgot
* And days of auld lang syne
Who's that?
That's a Christmas
present from a very
dear friend of mine.
(BELL RINGING)
Look, Daddy!
Teacher says
every time a bell rings,
an angel gets his wings.
That's right.
Attaboy, Clarence.
* Auld lang syne
* For auld lang syne,
my dear
* For auld lang syne
* We'll drink
a cup of kindness yet
* For auld lang syne
* We'll drink
a cup of kindness yet
* For auld lang syne