[Music]
so
hello you got a wrong number
don't hang up on me again pete
if i was a cop or
one of the boys i
wouldn't buy the
calling i just walk in
on you
i'm trying to tell
you you got it i'm
doing the telling pete
i didn't crack to the
clerk your name's
not johnson
listen whoever
you are i'm your one
chance to get out from under
300 grand a clean
getaway out of the
country
who is this if you're
interested come to
room 302
baker hotel 10 o'clock tonight
hey wait a minute
[Music]
come in
no change that
pete still jumping
that was a sucker
move burning down your
boss
you had him all wrong
he never crossed
you
but you're a guy
who shoots first and
thinks afterward
in your spot i'd almost
choose the cops
even if it is a
first-degree murder rap
it's lucky i spotted you
what's so lucky
about being dead i'm
gonna take care
of a guy just a little
too smart take off the mask
come on take it off
i don't like games
what makes a two-bit
heel like you think
a heater would give
an edge over me
i ought to ram it
down your throat
what's waiting for
you harris the chair
the gas chamber or
just a rope how do i
know that line you
handed me on the
phones on the level
your voice don't
even sound the same
neither will yours
when you put on a
mask
who else figures into
besides me you ask
too many questions
and i'm not getting
any answers i'd like
to know who i work with
when we make a
split and who i take my
orders from
get out of here
all right i'll get out
that choice you're
giving me you know
the bind i'm in
take it or leave it
you said 300 grand
for my end at least
free and clear only
you do it my way
nobody sees the
others without a mask
even when we make
a split and i decide
where and when that takes place
that makes it all foolproof
okay you got yourself a boy
now i stay in your
room keep out of
sight like call you
[Music]
do a little thinking
next time before
you use it
okay don't get any
wrong ideas about me
i don't shove around
this easy i'll give
you a chance to show
me how hot you are
on the job
[Music]
you're a three-time loser tony
not yet i ain't the
police know you
drove the getaway car
this time it's life
and no chance of
parole
this time tony you
go up for life under
the habitual criminal act
with no chance of
parole you don't have
to tell me the score
and it's a deal okay
but no dames understand no dames
look friend if you don't like it
don't knock it
[Music]
what makes you
think i can't go on doing
all right
if i can spot your
back of those trick
cheaters soaking the cops
this job you're
talking about i said i'd
listen
you're a cop killer
you killed one on
that last deal
i don't like heroes
you can tell that to
the warden when they burn you
so i'm still listening
[Music]
so
why don't you watch
where you're going
i'm sorry lady i didn't see you
[Music]
go
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
here's the description
mike all units
stand by
a 117 attention all units a 117
here's a description
of the suspects
involved in the
armed robbery of the
southwest bank
three men masked
wearing identical
coveralls they
are driving a light
delivery car belonging
to the western
wholesale florists
use extreme
caution all are armed
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
80k to control 2 on
that 117 we have the
suspect flores struck
20th in jackson
hey what is this put
your hands in the
back of your neck and
come on out come
on come on get out
you guys nuts
shout out you in there
come on out one
at a time with your
hands in the air
all right you your
pals have any ideas
you better start talking
you're gonna open
it open what you're
crazy there's
nothing in there but
flowers
why'd you drop them off come on
we must roll 300
miles plenty drop this
ball now they'll never get us
why do we make
the split this blitz what
i'm gonna talk about
four kings a pet
hand that's just what
we're holding
hang on to those cards i've got
everything
covered but in case
something does go
wrong and i can't
make the payoff myself
the cards will identify
you to whoever i
send with the money
say that again we'll
cut up the money
when i think it's
had time enough to
cool off
right now it's good
enough for me let's
cut this horsing around
how far do you think
you'd get with hot
money every cop
in the state's out
looking for us i'll
take my i told you
the mass stays on
sure you told us
it's a pat hand only
because nobody can
ride on you
you can't even rat on
each other because
you've never seen
each other without
those masks
i made you cut proof
and stool pigeon
proof and it's
gonna stay that way
money all right
i got one of these
for each of you with
enough money to
keep you comfortable
while you're waiting
but not enough to
get you into trouble
300 jesus coming
to me i can stand a
little trouble make
up your mind which
way is it going to be
you'll find tickets
for where you're
going you're each
going to a different
foreign country
stay there till i
wire you where and
when to come
and keep those
masks you'll be wearing
them at the payoff
this is where
you get off hit that
buzzer
[Music]
open the door
jump
[Music]
what about me i'll tell you when
it's odd that you'd
stop at that florist
next to the bank
twice in the same
morning
once that's all i
was there then the
woman who
identified you as a liar
now she's telling
the truth i did bump
in and the other
witnesses who swear
your truck was the
getaway car they're
telling the truth too
they're wrong if they
say i had anything
to do with a robbery
you want me to
believe there was
a duplicate truck
i wouldn't know i
wasn't there you were
framed then is that it
yeah and that year
you spent in the pen
did anyone frame you on that rap
asked the captain
here he was the
arresting officer a
real model citizen
look just because i
got in a jam over a
gambling bet doesn't
make me a bank
robber
well the boy wants
pity what about the
truck
if i knew the answer
to that i wouldn't
be here now how's
this for an answer
there was no
other truck listen i
mr andrews here
with the insurance
company he's willing
to give you a break
aren't you scott
he knows we are
same questions same
answers you can save your breath
it's my job joe
after all we've got to
make good the loss
in fact we're willing
to pay out as much
as 25 percent of the
money is a reward
that's 300 000 for a lead joe
you're an industrial
engineer aren't you
i never graduated
that's right left
school to enlist with
the engineers
pretty good soldier
too bronze star
purple heart
try and buy a cup
of coffee with them
came back
to resume his
studies at night why
why i ask myself
would a man with such
training want to
take a job outside his
line
set up a touch
for over a million
dollars that's why
i got the job
through the probation
officer you're gonna ask him
mr collins do i
ever give you any
trouble when i
work for you no joe
not at all but i'm
afraid i've got to
let you go now
nothing personally
you understand it's
just that well
we sell to a lot of
very conservative
people
you know how it is
yeah i know how it is
ah sergeant
see that mr collins
gets back uh i'll go
along with him some
questions i want to
ask
all right ralph you
want it the hard way
i can fix that too
you've got 20 years
staring you right in the face
what do you want
me to say that i did it
why don't you go
ahead mr martin you got
a big day tomorrow
the boys will help me
keep ralph company
what do you think
mcbride i think you
left them to me and
the boys that have
his confession on
your desk the first
thing in the morning
we'll be back after
first thing in the
[Music]
morning
[Applause]
millionaire
[Music]
okay we'll take him once more
you got visitors again real
[Music]
come on mcbride
we've got to turn
him loose the upstate
police found the
duplicate flyer struck
half an hour ago
it was inside an
abandoned moving van
still doesn't clear
off in my book
this part of the job
could have been to
use his truck as a
blind to draw us away
from the real getaway car
it could have been
anything just give me
a little more time
i'll sweat it out of
him forget it mcbride
i've checked every
move he's made he's clean
all right ralph you
can go sorry we had
to detain you
you are sorry
these things happen
thanks for nothing
go on beat it
maybe you didn't
hear what i said i
said for nothing
expert extra what
do you read all about
the big bang stick up
extra get the latest
spoons and the big
banks stick off
ex-con drill down
the million-dollar
grab get the latest
snooze on the bed
hey that's him
[Music]
you gotta do it rick you don't
understand rick
i i know this spot
you're in rick but
you gotta help joe
rick rick
hi joe hi eddie
get you something
yeah two things
cup of coffee and that
information you promised me
it's like i told you
the first one is
easy
listen eddie i gotta
know who set me
into this little deal
did you ask him
you're leaning with your
chin joe
so i'm leading with
my chin what have i
got to lose look
at he's been three
weeks no job no angle
nothing okay okay
take it easy on your
side
i'll get you another
cup of coffee
you come back
tonight around closing
time
so
okay brother says
you're in trouble jim
i gotta find a way
to clear myself
sometimes that's tough joe
sometimes it's too
tough look i want to
know who framed me
wasn't anyone local
that's for sure any
ideas
maybe might be
why pete harris beat it
to mexico
pete harris where in mexico
tijuana look from
where that dice road
is a real
sucker for a crap game
anything else
kind of dog got real
weird eyes you
won't have any trouble
finding with the
cigarettes he smokes
just follow the chain
watch you blind good luck joel
take it easy joe
thanks kid
that's the guy that
saved your life on
iwo jima huh
i'd buy em
[Music]
i have the name of dear senor
if you are looking
for a good time i
know all the best
places in tijuana
long as there's a
dice table there oh
but gambling is illegal but uh
like in these stages
in your there are
some things the
law does not know
i will show you
where it's a nice game
of chance okay
[Music]
boys
[Applause]
is
[Music]
you any other
check the card game
okay hands off the
table come on back
[Music]
all right let the
dice go and he's
coming out come on dice get her
anyone away with
a poor tray it's not
your night bud
next shooter come on now give me
something on the
field you can't go
wrong with the big
six of the big gate
and don't overlook
that ever loving any
traps it's over two men
20 you don't hit
you got a bet mister
coming out ah earn the big miss
box cars all right
take the inside and
pay the outside
to double up after
craftsmen
one good one makes
up for all the bad
ones
you might as well be
broke does not have
enough all right here we go
let the piece ride
i'm still saying you
can't do it
make em eat those
words mister and
another 20.
there they go and he's got
nine for a number
he makes nine for all
the money
three to two you
can't do it i'll take
50 to 25 i make it
no bad it's a three to two wager
i'll cover that
all right boys come
on now give me
something on the field
and the shooter's
coming out on a gravy
train oh oh
the devil jumped up
he went away with
seven
hank the inside pay the outside
you wanted me to
tell you when it was 10
30 fella
all right let the dice
go no more good
hot oh when he went away with
a poor truck and
we're coming out with a
brand new shooter brand new
overlooked field man
can't go wrong with
the big six in the beginning
get somebody give
me something for that
ever level no crap
since over new men
okay let him go
i don't know it gives
me the willies you
just don't smell right to me
so long dears
a guy who did all
right you seem to be
in too much of a hurry
is there a log against it maybe
who sent you here
fella dale's the cab
driver
okay fellaini
you found me now what
what's eating you
you've been giving me
the fish eye all night
you better see a
doctor mac you're in
bad shape
i ain't that sick
then stop imagining
things
get some rest
[Music]
who is it man
downstairs to see you
yeah look you tell that guys
now you and i are
gonna have a little
talk you a cop
that's to teach you
manners i'm the guy
that drove the florist truck
i don't know what
you're talking about
take a good luck
pete you're looking at
the patsy with this
frame for the kill
you got the wrong guy
pay off will you
when you're ready to
talk you got me wrong
what'd you do with
your cut pete i don't
follow you
you will there's
no money in there
you were one of
them weren't you i don't
know what you're talking about
listen this ain't my
bag i copped it out
of a car
you're lying give me that
what's this plane
ticket that's why
what's so
interesting in barratas
so we start all over again
go ahead go ahead
but i still don't know
what you're talking
about i can't open
you up maybe the cops can
wait no cops
so you were one
of the gang i i had
other reasons
i'm interested in this one
your plane leaves
in 50 minutes pete
you're not gonna be on it
look i gotta get the burrados
that wire means 300
grand to me you're
cut
who set it up i don't know
look we didn't have
nothing against you
we didn't even
know you just fell that
way
lucky me who else
was in on it i don't
know that either
we all four of us
wore masks i thought
they're only three
three in the big guy
look look i'm giving
it to you straight
that's the way it was
planned we all did
business with a mask
he could know us
but none of us could
know him get it
none of us could
squeal that way if one
of us didn't get away
that explains
everything but this
i i won't know what
that means like it
there
all right partner we'll find out
together
pardner the big
man set me in on this
so we split five
ways you're kidding
if i don't split five
ways there's gonna
be no split at all
okay go ahead hang yourself
it'll be a pleasure
all right so i'm
moving blind but
i got you for a bird
dog
to point away as we
go along you forget
even i don't know
the big guy so i'm
taking a chance
but remember i'm
taking no chances with
you between here and burrato's
partner
now get ready we
don't want to miss our
plane
yes sir you just
have time you make
connections for
barras in mexico city 10
30 am
round trip one way it'll be 92
please
hey buddy look who's here
over by the cigarette
machine vermillion
that's pete what harris
go ahead race them
don't worry about
this boy
you stay here
cops
i don't get it this
man reached for a
gun and he's clean
don't worry senior
this man's wanted for
murder
this will happen
what's that he's
trying to say about
dough
what do pete you
haven't got a chance
pete but you can go
out clean he's right
pete tell us about the doll
who's down here
with you what are you
doing in mexico
where were you going
got anything you
want to tell us you
haven't got a chance
sounds like it
maybe there is the
ambulance will be here at once
what do pete
that's cool pete
come on pete time's
running out tell us who
peter
[Music]
senor
you forgot your claim
checks and yours
your packages aboard the plane
thanks
gracias attention
with mr pete harris
please
board the plane
flight 589 now leaving
buenos dias ah good
morning my customers
good morning it
looks like maybe today
is going to rain finally
i hope so at least
it'll cool off then
everyone can go outside and play
when the senior came
well nasty romano i
see you have found
something you want
perhaps you would
like this one yeah
don't you want to
buy it it's not bad
for a bottle
how much only
11 american dollars
11 bucks but of
course in your if you're
looking for something cheap
i get nothing but the best
then shall i wrap it
into a nice package
for you
don't bother i
bought it for a nice
package
[Music]
you're too generous
that will be 11
american dollars
[Music]
gracias
that there is a she is a jewel
the smartest girl
that ever worked for
me
that's the 12th time
she has sold that
same bottle of perfume
and that kind of
business i can afford
to give her 50 commission
who is that person
came here yesterday
you mean to tell me
you've been here two
hours and not met tony romano
come on introduce
you don't bother say
tomas
why doesn't it
rain if it's gonna the
one thing i have no control over
the rain yeah the
minute i get outside
though it'll start
coming down like
cats and dogs ah
senor foster good
morning to my zone
what's everybody
so gloomy about the
weather senor
she's so uncertain
up in the states
they're having blizzards
ah if something
like that would only
happen here
but no nothing but sunshine
and people catching
fish if just once
a fish would catch
a man that's possible
tomasso
all depends on
the bait senor foster
senor kane how do
you do mr kane you
look right at home here
should be been
coming down here every
season for a good many years
senior foster i have
your tobacco for
you oh good teresa
i was almost out good fishing
thank you um when
are you going to try
your hand at some
of this fishing mr
romano
in this heat i got better sport
how about some
cards again tonight i'll
give you a chance to get even
come early and
bring a lot of money
hiya tim
glad to see you
scott well you're
certainly looking in the pink
that little girl yours
how is she oh
she's a big girl now
she's home preparing
for a bar exams be
a lawyer any day
it's been years since
anyone's seen you
around the old haunts
yeah two years one
month and eight days
since i got my walking papers
still bitter tim you
spent 20 years of
your life being a
cop and then get
thrown out what
am i supposed to do
stand up and cheer
well maybe it was
time to get out it was
beginning to affect your health
uh call it forced
retirement all right
scott forced retirement
you backed the
wrong party captain
foster so now we've
got ourselves a new
boy
i call it a frame
well whatever it was
you've been
through it it'll only stir
up old memories
how about that urgent
telegram to meet
you here
how far did you ever get on that
southwest bank
job likely nowhere
you must be hearing
plenty from the
front office on that one
you don't know the
half of it every bank
in the country is
on the alert to spot
the serial number of those bills
and up to now not
one of them has turned
up
how'd you like to crack that gun
how would i like
to find oil in my
backyard i don't
know but i might be
able to deliver that gang to you
you wouldn't fool
an old friend tim
might not be anything
and then again it
could be just what
you're looking for
i've been watching
a couple of strange
characters drift in
here one at a time
named boyd kane
mean anything to you
kane
yeah i want him for
a jewelry store hold
up
i knew that when i
sent you the wire who
else a prize package
by the name of tony
romano
should fit into a
touch like that bank
job
they're playing it
like they don't know
each other but it's
an old act any cop
could spot so i listen
yeah but they're
supposed to be three of
them that's where
it begins to make
sense
third one's due to
arrive that ties in
anything else
the talk is about
a money split big
money
the kind that could
have come out of
that southwest bank job what a
sweet break they
get together for a
split
and put their necks
right into a noose
how do we handle it tim
keep out of sight
until i call you you
better line up the police
where can i reach
you ill national
thanks tim
good you uh any
idea how much reward
this will bring in
well it should be plenty 25
of what the insurance
companies stand to
lose and that's
over a quarter of a
million
that's a lot of money
and you're the cop
they said was played out
[Music]
gracias
do you like it nice
[Music]
ah senorita
but of course if
the senior wants to
sign the register right
come with me senor
i will show you which
bungalow is yours
follow me i'll see
you later thanks for
the company
my pleasure
[Music]
not bad at all i
am teresa i sell
souvenirs
you are here for
fishing i'm here for a
vacation
that is good then
you have come to the
right place
tell me i develop playing pool
who's he wouldn't
you like to buy
something you know
presents souvenirs
things to send back
home
maybe very special
ladies perfume
how about the fell
at the pool table ah
that is senor kane
he arrived this
morning but he's not
very sociable all
the time he's chewing
bubblegum
and the other poem
ah you mean romano
now that one he is very social
thanks
you won't forget
about the souvenirs
what's a vacation
without souvenirs
hi fisherman what luck
helen
for a minute i thought
you weren't glad
to see me glad to
see you you know i'm
always glad to see
you pumpkin but you
come barging in here
what are you doing
here you i thought
you had a lot of studying to do
i've got news dad
important news there's
nothing more
important than your law
exams
sure there is you
are that's why i'm
here
you know being a
law student has its
advantages
i set up a brief
and brought it to the
mayor myself
sounds just like a
lawyer let's have the
facts
all right that facts i got the
commissioner to reopen your case
well don't you
understand that it's a
chance for you to
get back on the force
forget it it's too
late i don't want to
get back on the force
oh now look dad
this is your daughter
helen don't fool
me i know what it's
meant to you being
forced into retirement
through politics
this is your chance to come back
you're not gonna
let pride get in the
way
all right pumpkin
thanks now you're
gonna turn right
around and go home to
those law books
i'm taking a week's
vacation with study
besides i kind of
like a young man who
just checked in
his name is pete harris
our husbands fishing all day and
sleeping all night
this is supposed to
be our vacation they
only stay awake
i wouldn't even mind
if they play poker
remember olson
biggest sailfish i
ever latched on to
must have weighed
140 if you ate a pound
up ten just when i
had him softened up
ready to land
the lever breaks
allah right now we're
playing stud
remember the man
just boosted a tent
oh sorry beats me
go ahead deal oh
try not draw man maybe
you're a high bet
you're queens check to
you
check
just see jack and
jill three-fourths
how do y'all like
that guy souvenir
senor
oh senor harris catal
come on over and
take a hand
sit down i'll give
you a stack of chests
shall i deal you in
looks like you're
doing all right
without me senor eres
meet your foster
he wins all the time
and you're romano
you lose all the time
senor morelli what
is more about fishing
glad to know you
gentlemen the morning
you don't let that
boy scout look at
fosters fool you
he's had me on the
hook ever since i've
been here he's dynamite
his daughter
warned me about it i
promise to be careful
he hasn't learned
a man should never
press bad luck yeah
expect to be around
this tank a while i
don't know well maybe
where you from kansas city
originally used
to know girl then
swell cook you gonna bet that ac
is oh yeah
five skins just to
bring in the suckers
i'm in
buy me make a 10 to keep him out
see what i mean i'll call
looks like you've
got yourself a pigeon
always room for one more tony
well you can catch me in
i think i owe you
about ten dollars
you're not quitting so early
sure i thought i'd
take a walk through
the village before i turn in
don't walk too fast
you'd be out of town
without even seeing
it then there are
his rights in your arrest
come back some more
we need loser player
oh my good luck
piece souvenir the
biggest pot ever sat in on
[Music]
don't let me break
up the game see you
later
[Music]
so
my
[Music]
what's the idea
of tossing my joint
i didn't mean
nothing i figured you
meant to give me
the office when you
dropped that card on the table
what's with you
chum look i had to be
sure before i cracked
go on don't take
no big thinking to
figure a couple of guys like
us ain't in this
bananaville on a
vacation
yeah i'm just
going for my wallet
by calling god
you must been one
of the guys in the van
yeah you were
outside doing the driving
i'm uh sorry i had to rough you
up
no hard feelings
i'd have done the
same in your spot
one will get you ten
i got the other guy
uncovered too who
came
could be
two more days and
we'll be living it up
just think over 300 000
smackers if we get
it what do you mean
if
kid i said we don't
even know who he is
who wouldn't know
where to find him if
he didn't show up
but why would he bring
us here if he ain't leveling
search me but i
don't like working for
someone i don't know
especially if he can
recognize me and i
can't recognize him
neither do i
how about this guy
kane could he be mr
big
are you kidding that gum chewing
character
could be an act yeah
could be
you know
i think i'll get myself some gum
yeah gotcha
[Music]
see
so
[Music]
hi
hi how'd you make
up a few more hands
and your father would break me
well don't say i
didn't warn you it's
all right
i'll get even tomorrow
night now that's
one thing i don't
understand about men
what's that well you
work hard all year
and do nothing
but talk about your
vacation
and when it comes
you sit indoors and
play cards
doesn't figure
does it a lot of things
don't figure
like for instance
well for instance
what you do all year
i save up to play cards
i guess i should
have brought along a
deck of cards instead
of a swimming suit
oh i'd say you
did the right thing
you can swim too
like you play cards
tell you what i'll
meet you at the pool
tomorrow morning
you teach me and i'll
teach you
that's a deal
thanks banana
[Music]
good morning good morning
do you always bring
a book along when
you have a date
no it depends on the
date
let's see civil
code of the state of
missouri rules and procedure
translation i'm
cramming for the bar
exams
no cracks please
don't tell me you're
opposed to the
higher education of the female
no it's just that
you don't look like a
lawyer to me
well i found that
people rarely look
like what they are
now take yourself
for instance to look
at you i'd say
you're probably um
a fisherman instead
salesman would
you like it if i were a
salesman
oh look i'm the one
that's supposed to
get the answers by
cross-examination
i've always heard
that the best witness
is the ones who
who want to answer
thanks for the advice
i got some more for
you and for free too
always arrange to
have your cases tried
in front of all male juries
you can't lose kid
hey you're beginning
to sound promising again
i left my cigarettes
up the cabin i'll
be right back
oh mr harris milkman
iceman
[Music]
so
morning mr foster oh hello
how about some
cards tonight i can't i
got a dinner date
with a lawyer she
may never get to be
one if she's kept
from her studies
she has to eat
sometime why don't you
join us i'd like to
good i'll see you then
[Music]
so
what's up
hmm
get up you hear
what he said palsy
smart boy didn't hear you
what's the matter
palsy ears stuff
i think he hears you now
see
he's cooperating ain't you
palsy what is this
smart boy here
wants to know what is
this what's your line mister
he knows read me
for a sucker palsy
i don't like that
you're crazy
i'll pinpoint it for
you chum pete
harrison we did a
deuce together juliet
that makes you a
phony now we're gonna
take a nice quiet walk
when we get to the
right place you're
gonna tell us the
story of your life
i don't move yeah make a noise
bring the cops in on
you smart boy wants
it done quiet
come in
oh pardon me i
didn't know you had
visitors
that's all right come on in
miss foster no mr romano
mr kane i've seen
mr romano around
how do you do mr king hello
they were trying to
talk me into taking
a walk with him
i explained we
had a date oh i don't
mind i told him you wouldn't
just a couple of
nature lovers we were
chatting about it
when you knocked
well it must have
been a very warm
discussion
oh uh i just dropped
in to return this
to you
thanks i hardly missed it
i only carry it in
case of snakes
you'll be seeing your hairs yeah
hey tony i know
a sure cure for a
nosebleed
a cold knife in the
middle of the back
nice guys playful
don't bother making
up any stories for
me
i thought the law said a man was
innocent until proven guilty
that's right considering the
circumstantial evidence
if you were my
attorney how would you
advise me to answer
i tell you not to
answer at all unless
you could answer honestly
it might incriminate you
now you're giving
me some good advice
thanks
and for free
[Music]
um
so
[Music]
i have a letter for
you she smells like
a business one
a letter for you
this one she also
smells like a business one
a letter for you
senoras oh thanks
you're very welcome excuse me
[Music]
mail from home it'll wait
i expect you to get
in some solid study
tonight
well isn't that nice
of you how's that
mr foster
thanks for that
and the dinner don't
forget
i may ask questions
tomorrow well i'll
look forward to it
good night
tony you're not
even looking at how
pretty they are
and only 11 american dollars
everything around
here is 11 bucks tony
you lie charge it with the rest
tony see you later
i see you got
your invitation tony
yeah how about
your friend out there
you get his two let's go ask
pumpkin it isn't
often i butt into your
affairs but
i'm gonna make like
a father you sound
serious
or you're concerned
i'm always serious i
want you to forget that fellow
but you don't know
anything about him
dad neither do you
[Music]
right in there
drop the gun in the
well kane what's he
tell you
get you know well
do it the gun
drop it drop it
don't shoot stop it in the well
do what he tells you don't
shoot
all right you two
knuckleheads now
you're gonna listen to me
i wish you want to
join the guns in the
well
i got my invitation
to the party i take
pete harris here
you gave harris the
double shuffle you
got it wrong pal
the cops paid
him off in full like
gambling
a man puts up his
bet he's entitled to
be paid off if he wins
harris lost what did you put up
a possible 20 years in stir
you're looking at
the guy who's framed
for the job that's
why i'm cutting
myself in whether
you like it or not
you're smart you'll
play along with me
you're not it goes
rough on everybody
you talk awfully
green for a smart guy
what happens when
mr big sees you
let's wait till we
get to that huh now
you two boys make
like friends go to
sleep
go on
in case you get any
ideas about visiting
me later
forget it i sleep light
[Music]
um
what are you doing
here simple i came
looking for you
it's a matter of
principle mr harris i
just don't like
anybody running out on
me twice in the same day i see
what you see
after i got the letter i
told you you didn't
have to make up any
stories for me
that's right you did
look pete i know i
may be butting into
something i shouldn't but
that's the way i am
even when i was a
kid i was always the one asking
questions
bet you even
cross-examined your nurse
you know if i was
smart i'd find myself
another date and
forget all about you
only i can't help
feeling you're in
trouble
i liked it better
this afternoon when
you stopped asking questions
i'm no fool pete i've
been around cops
long enough to pick
up a few tricks of
the trade
those playmates
of yours are pretty
obvious
what do they got on
you one question at
a time
especially in cops
would you pick that
up well my father's
a retired captain of
police
oh i see that
explains your being a
lawyer
papa nails him and
you free him is that
him what's that
guy look at you're a
nice girl but in case
you're thinking of
mothering me forget it
i'm no straight dog
he can pick up and i
like my neck without
a collar now get
lost
now i'm supposed
to be hurt maybe even
cry
but i won't i think
you're in trouble
and i'm going to help you
listen sister forget
it mind your own
business
[Music]
then you move in
you got it now scott
yeah let me check
back they meet out on
the boat tomorrow
at dawn for the split
i wait out on the
police boat for your
light signal then i move in
and you answer
my signal first right
[Music]
don't miss don't worry i
won't good luck
[Music]
well pumpkin but
you'd be asleep by this
time
i've been waiting for you dad
a little problem yeah
used to happen
pretty often when you
were younger i always knew when
something was troubling you
matter of fact kind
of miss it were they
very tough problems
i used to bring to
your dad oh very
tough some new trinkets
you wanted money
for the movies
that time you got
into your first form
when your boat came
down with the mises
that was a tough
one finally had to take
you out myself that night
once you even wanted
to know when we'd
get your new mod
to look after you oh
that was a real tough
one most of them
know we were able to work out
you were right about
harris dad he's in
a jam
oh i forgot to tell you
you used to take my
advice in those days
you wouldn't have
gone running after him
if i'd ask you not to
i want you to help
him dad that way
you'll be helping me
why professional interest
i don't really know
dad something's
happened
well i know it sounds crazy and
illogical but
that's the way it is
he's out of bounds
for you helen way out
of bounds
you said that before
why isn't it enough
that i tell you not this time
all right he's an ex-con
i just didn't want
to hit you over the
head with it
what else do you
know about him isn't
that enough no
it's not there's more
there's got to be more
you wouldn't be
so positive if there
weren't something
what else have
you got against him
you're going home
tonight young lady
is that the way you
solved my problems
when i was a kid
this is for your own
good
is it believe me
believe me punkin go
home and forget him
you can start the
ball rolling on that
re-hearing and i'll be
helen
[Music]
so
good morning palsies hold it
you'll never learn
[Music]
good morning don't
tell me you boys are
going fishing too
yeah we see you
get such a kick out of
it we decided to give it a try
great sport i'm on
my way to the pier
can i give you a lift
you got yourself a passenger
[Music]
might as well take
us all seeing as the
three of us are going fishing
oh did you run a boat yeah
we got us about
to call the manana
[Music]
i understand you're
an ex-captain of
police mr poster oh
that was a long
time ago they will be
able to match
these stories
tonight huh sure i'll
bring pictures
[Music]
[Applause]
quite a boat
any kind of luck
we all ought to do
pretty good gummy hairs
good luck
[Music]
thanks
so
[Music]
hold it
freeze
[Music]
i'll go see if he's still there
what's the matter
palsy run out of talk
not quite i got a proposition
i know where the
money is right here on
the boat
i'll show you all right
look for yourself
right in the cupboard
there go ahead look
[Music]
million two hundred
thousand dollars
tony
think about a million
two for you and me
i got to take four
ways when we only
have to cut two
it's over half a
million a piece over
half a million
why split with cane
[Music]
okay
why a two-way split
a guy living big
all the time like me
needs though
right in front of you
kick it over here
move back back up
i don't get it you
will let's just take
it easy till the police get here
a little falling out
over the split you
get around a lot for a fisherman
part of my job thanks cop
making out like he
knows from nothing
all depends on what
the assignment calls
for
you never had a
chance we had the big
guy from the beginning
don't let that bother
you tony it was
all marked anyway
we should have
figured that that's right
joe
the name is pete
uh like in pete harris
who was shot
and killed in tijuana
something bothering you joe yeah
the only person
who would know pete
harris was in tijuana
would be the one
who sent him there to hide out
wait for a wire
you're a boy with
a lot of ideas sure
like only a cop would
know you couldn't
use a million two
in hot cash but you
could trade it in for a nice
clean reward get
it all figured out
huh three little
patsies one down
two to go you're
being there to give us
a lift the money on a platter
honey for the bees
uh captain foster
stay where you are
sure sure when
will the cops arrive
try my story on
for size if i'm wrong
i'll apologize
[Music]
uh
forget it my luck
had to give out some
time
i wouldn't mind
so much joel helen
didn't have to find out
you're not part of
this you gotta break
them
[Music]
tim what's happened
are you hurt what's
rolfe doing here
i've been saving
surprise for you
was his lead turn the trick
only it didn't come
off the way we
planned it
did it joe
[Music]
no no it didn't
third guy was pete
harris burning down a
two on him
scott anybody
deserves a reward it's him
let's get him to a doctor well
give her my mom joe thanks
i know it's just
talk now helen but
i feel the loss of
your father as keenly
as you do
i owe him a lot
for what he did if
there's anything
that you ever need
will you call on me
thanks mr andrews
one other thing about joe rolfe
he's a fine boy that
scrape he got into
a long time ago
he's more than
made up for it and the
way i feel
my company will
underwrite him anytime
i tried so hard to
make dad understand
you did alan the
last thing he said was
for joe
to give you his love
how is she taking
it mr anders pretty
good joe
she's had time to
get over the shock but
hero's medal isn't
enough when you're
alone
she and dead were
pretty close i told
her about you
what'd you say why
don't you ask her
[Music]
[Applause]
you