Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes
I've never seen anything like it.
Talk about your heroism?
He went down in that blazing pit
not once, mind you, but three times...
...and carried them all out,
one after another.
- Not really.
- Why, he doesn't know what fear is.
Probably too dumb to know what it is.
Well, where there's no sense,
there's no feeling.
There's nothing dumb about him.
I wish I had more men like him.
I hope you rewarded him, Arthur.
Say, you wouldn't believe this.
I presented him with a check for a thousand
dollars and he wouldn't take it.
What?
Must be interesting to meet
a man like that.
You're going to.
I've asked him over.
- Here?
- Yes, tonight.
For heaven's sake.
But we're going to the opera
right after dinner.
That's alright, he's only coming
for dinner.
- A workman?
- For dinner?
Yes. Why not?
Arthur, what ghastly joke is this?
But Henrietta, he's a hero.
- In overalls.
- What will our guests say?
Call him up at once and tell him
he's not to come over.
He isn't a common worker.
He's a steel boss.
See, Mother, it's perfectly alright.
- He's a steel boss.
- His name is Dick Brunton.
I don't care what his name is.
Brunton? Brunton?
That name sounds familiar.
He's a fine chap. I've had my eye
on him for a long while.
Don't talk to me.
Overalls!
Well, it'll be a thrill having
a working man for dinner.
Yeah? Well, you've had one
for a good many years.
Me!
That's all I was when I started.
But this invitation, it's downright cruelty.
Dinner with all our flunkies around
might prove very embarrassing...
...to Slim Jim, the railbender.
Gosh, I never thought of that.
It'll be lots of fun watching him scoop
mashed potatoes on his knife.
Oh, it won't be as bad as that.
I know those strong silent men.
Well, I'll put the radio on while
he's inhaling his soup.
Longview 5855.
Now what are you going to do?
Break the big news to Charlie Bates.
Well, I guess I'll go up and change
for dinner.
Yes, by all means.
And Finnie's laid a nice new pair
of overalls for you.
Oh, hello, Charlie.
Listen, you're going to have
the laugh of your life tonight.
Father's invited a big he-man from
the mill for dinner.
Alright, Dot, I'll come over
and bring my dinner pail.
Now don't fail to get over here
on time, will you, Charlie?
You bet, Dot. As soon as the
whistle blows...
...I'll throw down my tools and rush
right over.
Alright, Charlie, goodbye.
What's the opera tonight?
Well, I think they're singing
Il Trovatore.
- Il Trovatore, good.
- I'm glad I ducked it.
I hear enough anvil chorusus
out at the foundry.
Dot, I know you'll enjoy
the opera tonight.
- Why, she's not going.
- Pass the olives.
Dorothy, would you mind passing
the olives?
Do the doctors think they
can cure it?
- Cure what?
- Your hearing.
I've asked you eighteen times
to pass the olives.
Pardon me.
I said the olives.
Excuse me.
Say, Dot.
Get a load of that.
The big barrel looking for
a toothpick.
What a nice charm.
May I see it, please?
- Oh, it's nothing really.
- Oh, pulease!
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen.
A grievous social error has been
made here tonight.
Dorothy!
A guest has been brought here
under false pretenses.
Let me introduce to you
the real Dick Brunton.
All-American halfback.
The man who beat Yale.
Why, Brunton!
Say, I had no idea!
Halfback? I thought you said
he was a steel boss.
Boy, I'll never forget that forward
pass as long as I live.
Well, I'll be a something or other.
You certainly will.
Well, I'm glad that's out.
You've had me guessing all night.
Serve coffee in the drawing room.
Dick Brunton, this is a surprise.
- One or two lumps, Mrs. Parker?
- One, please.
Well, Brunton, have you changed
your mind about that check?
No, sir. Thanks just the same.
- Have you talked it over with your mother?
- Yes, sir, and she agrees with me.
You see, Mr. Parker, I didn't do
that for money.
I did it because... well, anybody'd do it.
You understand, don't you?
Yes, I think I do.
A thousand dollars is a lot
of money, Mr. Brunton.
- Yes, but...
- Oh, don't be silly. Go ahead and take it.
Why? Do you want me to?
Would you, if I wanted you to?
- No.
- Uh-oh.
Fourth down, nine yards to go.
Well, at the very least, I'll see
that you get the Carnegie medal.
Oh, no, please don't do anything
like that.
How does it feel to be a hero?
You'll never know.
Dorothea!
Now please leave Mr. Brunton alone.
I want to talk to him.
Why didn't you tell us you were Dick
Brunton, the all-American halfback?
Why should I? Right now I'm simply
your father's steel boss.
Well, I can't understand why
you kept it out.
The all-American, I mean.
Makes things easier for you.
I know. But easy things aren't
much good.
But aside from that, it would get you
in with the right crowd.
You can't run around with the right
crowd on forty-five a week
Mr. and Mrs. Post.
Good evening, everybody!
- Hello, there.
- Hello.
- Hello, Henrietta.
- How are you?
Say good evening everybody,
Pansy, darling.
Are you ready to go, Henrietta?
- Yes, dear. Good evening, Llewellyn.
- How do you do?
Shall we go upstairs while
we get our wraps?
Naturally!
- Say, Llewellyn, will you have a...
- Oh, you'd better go sit in the car.
- Yes, dear.
- And bundle Pansy up good.
Because I don't want my little bitsy
baby to catch cold.
Yes, dear.
Yes dear, yes dear, yes dear,
what a spectacle!
Why, he's no more than a
kept husband.
It's a tragedy. Llewellyn Post should have
been the greatest architect in America.
But he married Lucille.
She wouldn't let him work.
She killed all his ambition.
It's her fault, not his.
Oh, you don't have to go yet.
Dad and I aren't going out.
I know, but it's late for me.
I have to get home and go to bed.
You see, I have to be at the
plant at six.
Six, eh? I never go to bed until six.
I'll have Hopkins take you home
in the car.
I haven't seen a first act in years.
- Well, all set?
- Yep.
- Good night, Mr. Brunton.
- Good night, Mrs. Parker.
I've had a wonderful time.
- Have a good time.
- We will.
You've been mighty kind,
Miss Parker.
I'll remember this evening for
a long time.
So will I.
I hope you'll forgive me for
exposing your, er... past.
- That's all right.
- I wish you'd think it over.
You know, about getting in
with the right crowd.
- Honestly, I can't afford to.
- That wouldn't make any difference.
Anyhow, I spend my spare
time studying.
See, I want to get somewhere.
There's more to life than just
gold footballs.
Really? And there's more to life than
grinding away at books every night.
I don't like to. I'm human.
You don't mean it. I wouldn't have
suspected that.
I enjoy a good time as much
as anyone.
But I'm working now so I can have
fun when I get older.
- And can't enjoy it.
- Well, maybe you're right.
- Well, Brunton, if you're ready, we'll...
- Yes, sir.
- Good night, Miss Parker, thank you.
- Good night.
Thank you too, you've been
very kind.
Not at all.
Well, good night, Mr. Parker.
Good night, my boy.
Well?
Did you notice how he balanced
those peas on his knife?
Oh, don't rub it in.
How about your thousand dollar check?
Oh, that boy has something.
He's one man in a thousand.
Thousand? He's one in a million.
And as far as your daughter's concerned,
he's the one man in the world.
- What do you mean?
- I mean I'm going to marry him.
- What? Are you crazy?
- You just bet I am.
Look here, Dot, you're not serious.
Dad, I was never more serious
in my life.
The minute I saw him...
I didn't give two hoots if he gargled
his soup in the key of A minor.
All I knew was that boy was
made for me.
And what's more, I'm gonna have him.
Now look here, Dot, aren't you
just a little bit hasty?
I can't get him too quick
to suit me.
See here, Dot, and listen.
Don't you fool yourself.
Now, I'm a pretty good judge
of men. I tell you...
...this boy has real character and he'll
never propose to you.
Now see here, Dad, listen.
There isn't a man in this world
a woman can't win,
if she really wants to land him.
- I don't believe that.
- All right.
- All I ask is four weeks.
- Four weeks.
Four weeks.
When do you think your wayward
son will stagger in?
Can't tell you.
Well, it's getting late.
Oh, rich folks like the Parkers
have supper till all hours.
Yeah, what's caviar to the few
is apple sauce to the gander.
You should have told him to take
that thousand bucks.
Oh, no, Hughie, why should I?
Why, I wouldn't want Dick to take
anything he didn't earn.
A penny saved is a dollar earned.
If you had all that sugar, maybe
you could ease up on my board bill.
I'm in no hurry for
the money, Hughie.
Well, that's just as well,
cause I ain't got any.
Say, would you mind honking the horn
a couple of times?
Sure.
Well, Mother, I told you we'd be riding
around in a Rolls-Royce one day.
- Did you have a nice time, Dick?
- I certainly did.
Hey, highpockets, did you bring
home the bacon?
No, I told him he could keep
his check.
I figured that all in.
- Did you give Miss Parker my love?
- Sure.
- What'd she say?
- I'll take vanilla.
Well, now that that's all settled,
maybe you'd better hit the hay.
I claim early to rise and early
to bed and you'll live all your life.
Until you're dead.
Tell me, Dick, what kind
of people are they?
Oh, you'd get a great kick
out of them Mother.
The father's a pretty good scout.
Don't do that, Mother!
- You're going to ruin your teeth.
- Oh, they were ruined long a ago.
How about Mrs. Parker?
She's got one of those trick
English accents.
The only trouble is it slips out
of gear all the time...
...and she gets all balled up between
her ballses and her bases.
Well, that's no crime.
Is she nice?
She almost froze me when I first
came in.
Looked at me as though she expected
I'd be wearing overalls.
Oh, you only imagine that.
How about the daughter?
Not for mine.
Just plain spoiled.
Oh, now, maybe that isn't her fault.
Too much money isn't good
for anybody.
Still, some of them make very
good wives.
Well, I can never imagine her
as a wife.
Imagine Dot Parker bending
over a washtub.
Maybe she wouldn't be afraid
to bend over one if she had too.
Oh, don't be silly.
She's about as useful as a little
silky kitten.
That's what they should have
called her, kitten.
Kitten.
- Hello, Mr. Barber.
- Hello, Dick.
- Look all of these.
- What are they?
The Mississippi Bridge plans. Something
that will revolutionize the industry.
- That is, if we can sell the idea.
- You don't seem very confident.
I know it's the greatest engineering
achievement in years.
Parker's willing to bet his roll on it.
But it'll take a real salesman
to make others see it as we do.
- Well, let's get started.
- Alright.
Can you get them finished
by one o'clock?
- Yes, sir.
- Fine, we're awfully busy.
I know I can depend on you.
Hey, how long have you
been working here?
Well, there she is again.
Couldn't be more regular if she
punched the clock.
Ain't that old man Parker's daughter?
- Sure.
- What's she here for?
Well, if you don't know, you're
the only one that don't.
She's here to grab Dick Brunton.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Pretty soft for Brunton.
That girl's independently rich.
She's got nothing on him.
He's independently poor.
Gee! I wish some doll with all her
dough was nuts about me.
Sorry, busy.
Why, Dick, too busy for me?
- Oh, Dot. How are you.
- Fine, how are you?
Well, I'm kind of tide up.
Mr. Barber gave me a rush job.
- Oh, that can wait.
- No, it's very important.
But I've got something even
more important.
Honestly, Dot, I can't.
- It's your lunch hour, isn't it?
- But I promised Mr. Barber.
- Oh, he can spare you for an hour.
- No.
- Hello, Mr. Barber.
- Hello, Miss Parker.
Do you mind if I take Dick away
for an hour?
Why, no, not at all.
- Those plans can wait, can't they?
- Yes, certainly.
- But Mr. Barber...
- That's alright, my boy, that's all right.
Thank you, Mr. Barber.
Oh.
Oh, no.
Oh, but this is my treat.
You can't sign here.
You're not a member.
- That's yours, Paul.
- Thank you.
They always work.
Gee, that's a keen trick.
You gotta show me how to do that.
Dick, know what day it is today?
Yeah, Wednesday... December 20th.
It was exactly for weeks ago
today I met you.
That's right, four weeks.
What are you smiling at?
Just thought of something.
Just think, four weeks.
- And it seems as if I'd known you ages.
- That's just the way it seems to me too.
But I have known you a long time.
I've seen many games you've played.
Why, when you beat Yale,
I even cut your picture out of the paper
and put it over my dresser.
Oh, you're kidding.
Am I?
- There.
- Well...
Gee, that... that was published about
five years ago.
I guess you believe me now.
December 20th.
Five more days till Christmas.
I'd better get busy.
I suppose you did your Christmas
shopping early.
I've only got one more thing to get.
Been expecting to get it for
four weeks.
You'd better not put it off
any longer.
- That depends on you.
- On me?
Hm-hmm.
Well, if there's anything I can do.
What is it?
A proposal.
- A what?
- May I have it?
- You mean you want me...
- I want you.
You're only kidding.
Alright, just propose to me and see
whether I am or not.
Dot, I can't do anything like that.
- You mean...
- I'm nothing but a...
You mean you won't propose to me?
- I'd propose if I could, but...
- Very well, I'll propose to you, Dick.
Will you marry me?
No, Dot, I can't. I haven't anything
to offer a girl like you.
You're all I want.
I know what you're thinking.
But don't let that stand
in your way.
Don't you love me enough to forget it?
Oh, I wish I could forget.
Oh, if you really love me,
you'll try.
Won't you please try?
Come on, Dick, say yes.
No.
Dick!
Do you mean that?
Yes.
Oh, gee, I'm so happy.
- Put that on.
- No, I can't do that.
Oh, but look, some day you'll
afford to buy me one.
Go on, Dickie.
Please.
Mrs. Borham, crystal champagne set.
Miss Prag, you're impossible.
Send her a Christmas card.
And her husband is a victim
of the stock market.
Spare me your sarcasm, Arthur.
- That completes the list, doesn't it?
- Yes, ma'am.
Mother, you've forgotten
all about aunt Julia.
Thanks for reminding me, Dorothea.
Now, let's see, what is useful
in a boarding house?
A long reach.
Money's useful in a boarding
house, Mother.
If I send Julia money, she'll only
spend it.
Send aunt Julia a nice warm shawl,
Miss Prag.
- That will be all?
- Yes, Prag.
Christmas gets more appalling
every year.
Prag's so stupid, I'm sure she's
omitted someone.
She has.
Now, what do you want
for Christmas?
- Oh, I've selected my Christmas present.
- Oh, you have, have you?
Well, what is it?
Not what, who.
Stop your foolishness, Dorothea.
What do you want for Christmas?
A husband!
I'm afraid I have no sense of humor.
- Wait a minute, so it's happened, has it?
- Hm-hmm.
- Give a woman for weeks.
- What are you talking about?
Mother, I'm going to marry
Dick Brunton.
- Dick Brunton? The working man?
- Yes.
But he's a steel boss.
Ohhh!
Arthur, are you going to do nothing
if your daughter's gone crazy?
Oh, it's all your fault,
inviting him here to dinner.
Dot, I can hardly believe it.
I never thought he'd propose to you.
He didn't.
I proposed to him.
Well, I'll be...
Oh, Dad, it's alright with you,
isn't it?
Can't I have him?
But just think, Dot, he couldn't
keep you in shoes.
You're accustomed to all this.
You'd never be able to give it up.
- Well, I don't intend to.
- You'll have to.
- He only earns 45 dollars a week.
- But you're going to raise his salary.
- What?
- Dad,
I want him more than anything
in the world.
Won't you please let me have him?
Oh, you know that I'd do anything
to make you happy.
Gee, you're a peach, Dad.
He's a good man.
And you'll promote him, won't you?
I'll have to, if you're going
to marry him.
And don't forget, I can't get along on
a cent less than 50 thousand a year.
- Fifty thousand?
- Hm-hmm.
Why, I couldn't possibly pay him that.
It would disrupt all my organization.
- Aw, Dad.
- Now, don't worry.
I'll give him a little raise in salary
...and I'll make up the difference
out of my own pocket.
- Aw, thanks, Dad.
- But look here, Dot, now you be careful.
A man has to be made of strong stuff,
not to let money spoil him.
- Don't let it spoil Dick.
- Money spoil Dick?
Oh, don't be silly.
It could never spoil Dick.
- Well, I have to be going.
- Now, where are you going?
I promised Dick that I'd go right over
and tell him what you said.
Bye, I'm in an awful hurry.
Oh, that's you, Hughie?
- I guess so.
- Didn't Dick come home with you?
Two's company, three's a crowd.
What are you talking about?
It won't be long now. Coming events
cast their shadows behind.
Oh, go up and get ready for dinner.
I guess if you knew what I know,
you'd believe in Santy Claus.
Mother, I've got a surprise for you.
A surprise?
What is it?
I'm going to be married.
Dick...
Oh, that's wonderful.
Who is she?
You just wait. She'll be here
in a minute and you'll see her.
I just knew something like this
was going to happen.
I know you're going to love her, Mother.
Oh, I'll fix up the spare bedroom.
- Spare bedroom?
- Yes.
You can have it until you move into
a home of your own.
Oh, Dick, this is lovely.
Imagine getting a daughter for
a Christmas present.
- I wonder who that is.
- Must be Santa Claus.
A Christmas present for you, Mother.
Mother, this is Dorothy,
Dorothy Parker.
You dear, dear child.
Isn't she sweet?
- She certainly is.
I don't know what I've done to deserve
the two best women in the world.
Who told him he deserves us?
Oh... let me go.
You hug like a bear.
Will you excuse me a moment,
please?
Oh, Dick, I'm terribly happy.
Everything's alright.
And you don't know how glad
I am, kitten.
- Kitten?
- Yeah, that's my pet name for you.
Well, isn't that funny.
You know, Dad used to call me
that when I was a kid.
Let's sit down.
Want to take your coat off?
Oh, no, Dick, I think we'd better
be going.
Alright.
Dear, I want you to have this.
I wore it when I was young,
and my mother before me.
It's supposed to bring good
fortune for the bride.
Why, what a lovely old ring.
I'll wear it all the time.
Mrs. Brunton, I can't tell you
how much I appreciate this.
I hope it brings you all the
happiness in the world.
I don't want to rush, Mother,
but we've got a million things to do.
Oh, that's alright, I understand.
Dick's a wonderful boy.
But all men are peculiar.
You just handle him right
and you'll be very happy.
Oh, I understand.
I'll be home early, Mother.
Good night, Mrs. Brunton.
Good night.
- Goodbye.
- Bye, Mother.
- Bye.
Isn't that a beautiful car?
I don't give it much.
It's last year's model.
Well, Hughie, what do you think?
I think he's a sap if he marries
a dame like her.
You'd never catch me doing that.
Doggone if I'd slave for
a million bucks a week...
...just to have some canary spend
it on brassieres.
She's a nice girl.
What's one man's meat
is another guy's poison.
I've heard of marriages made in heaven,
but not in the Parker Steel plant.
Well, they're so devoted.
- I think it'll work out all right.
- Don't kid yourself.
I claim oil and water don't mix.
East is west and west is east
when Greek meets Greek.
You were the loveliest bride.
When you came down that aisle,
it just took my breath away.
Will you forgive me for kidnapping
your son?
Of course, I know he's in good hands.
Dick, you have the most wonderful
girl in the world.
- See that you take good care of her.
- I will, Mother.
And don't you go shutting yourself in your
room every night like you did with me.
You know, Dick was always
terribly ambitious.
Yes, I know.
Oh, I won't let him work too hard.
Oh well, I...
Guess I'd better run along. You're in
a hurry to get down to the boat and...
I'll say good... goodbye.
I'm going out to the car.
Will you come along with me?
- Come on, Mother, dear.
- Goodbye, Dick.
God bless you both.
Goodbye, Mother.
Say, Dick.
- Well, are you happy?
- Yes, sir.
Well, I hope you're a good sailor,
...because my yacht isn't quite as large
as the Leviathan.
Now, have a good time.
Lots of work for you when you come back.
Oh, I'll be ready.
One thing more, Dick. You know,
girls are peculiar...
...and you have to handle them
very carefully.
Well, Dorothy and I, I think we
understand each other, Mr. Parker.
Yes, I know, but when little things crop up
as they will in best of families, well...
you give in a bit and the woman
will give in a whole lot.
I see.
Er... just some spending money
for your honeymoon.
What?
- Well, haven't you made some mistake?
- That's all right.
I want you both to remember your
honeymoon as long as you live.
- But I can't...
- Now, you've turned down my check...
...once for saving some lives.
I want this one to remind you...
...that I'm entrusting you with
the most precious life in the world.
Well... thank you, Mr. Parker.
Come in.
Hello, Dick.
Isn't it funny?
That door connects both our rooms.
Oh, please come in,
so I can really believe it.
It still seems like a dream.
- Oh, you're nothing but a kid.
- And you're nothing but a kitten.
It's been a strenuous day, getting
married and running off to the yacht.
So I think I'll retire.
Good night.
Husband.
See you in the morning?
Good night.
Kitten.
- You're asleep?
- Hm-hmm.
Oh, c'est charmant!
C'est charmant, madame.
You look marvelous in it!
And this, Mme. Brunton, I have
shown to no one else.
For no one else could wear it
as you can.
Is that the kind of a woman
you think I am?
Oh, not that you are, but that
you should look on occasion.
Oh...
What's that, Prinz?
But I didn't order a coat.
But I knew you will after
you saw this.
- Oh, it's magnificent.
- It was smuggled out of Russia...
...a few skins at a time.
Don't tempt me, Prinz, we're
almost broke.
But when your husband
sees you in this...
oh-ha-ha-ha, he will not think
of the expense.
Oh-ha-ha-ha, I'll try it on,
but I won't take it.
Oh, it's beautiful, Dorothea.
- It is...
- C'est magnifique, magnifique!
What's the bad news, Prinz?
Oh... only 200.000 francs.
Good heavens, I can't afford that.
Afford? Ten thousand dollars
for a coat like this?
Madame!
Really, you frighten me when
you say it in francs.
But put that way, it does
seem sort of, er...
- There you are.
- Merci bien, madame.
- Merci beaucoup. Au revoir, madame.
- Au revoir.
- Au revoir, madame.
Au revoir, mesdames.
Au revoir, monsieur.
- Do you really like it?
- I think it's perfectly stunning.
I do.
Oh, Dick, come here. I want
to show you something.
- Dick, where's Llewellyn?
- Why...
Why, he's downstairs, I think he'll
be up in a moment.
Entrez.
Oh! Oh, my Pansy is dying!
Oh... oh, my baby!
What happened to my beautiful baby?
Oh, my darling baby.
- Oh...
- Listen, darling, I can explain...
Oh, I thought at least you could take
care of my dog to earn your living.
- I know, pet...
- Don't talk to me!
You're not fit for anything!
You're not a man!
- You're just what everybody calls you.
- Now, pet, please let me explain...
Get out of my sight, you...
You worm!
Alright, pet.
Oh!
Aren't you a little rough
on him, Lucille?
What do you think I give him
his allowance for?
Look at my darling, just look at him.
Can't the poor sap do anything
to earn his money?
Just look at my darling!
Just look at her!
Oh, you don't understand
what I've been through.
Just wait until I get him alone.
I'm awfully sorry this had
to happen, Dick.
I'll see you again later.
Good night.
Where's mother's little baby girl?
Getting hurt by that nasty, mean old man.
Just wait till Mother gets home
to that man.
- Dick, how did you like the coat?
- Don't try and change the subject.
Disgusting, wasn't it?
I'm through with her.
That's all right.
You know what I mean.
Kept husband there.
If you apply that to yourself,
it's an insult to me.
Well, that's what I am,
until we get home.
You're making me angry!
Oh, please don't be angry
with me, Dot.
Well, if you promise not to say
things like that anymore, I...
I've got to get back to work.
But look, we haven't been to Deauville,
Nice, Monte Carlo or Biarritz.
Why, that's the best part of
our honeymoon.
- Road work can keep.
- How about keeping my self-respect?
Oh, why can't we stay over
here longer?
Why, a few more months won't
do any harm.
Well...
- What are you whistling about?
- Well, this coat.
Two hundred thousand dollars,
that's ten thousand dollars.
- Well, it's worth it?
- Well, where's the money coming from?
Oh, don't be so dense. All you have
to do is cable Father.
- I've cabled him three times already.
- And he hasn't turned us down once.
Well, I'm not going to keep on
hitting him for more.
- Not if I ask you?
- Aw, please don't ask me.
You know I've got to get back to work.
I've got to start earning a living.
But there's no rush.
Now, your father's been wonderful, but I'm
not going to impose on him any longer.
But we've got to go back.
Oh, Dot, what's the matter?
You know very well your old
work can wait.
But it isn't right.
We've got to go back.
First we're going to Deauville, Nice,
Monte Carlo and Biarritz.
No, we're not going to Deauville,
Nice, Monte Carlo and Biarritz.
We're going home!
Well, how do you like it?
- Well, it's fine, but...
- But what, sweet?
It's alright for people who like this sort
of thing, but we won't stay here long.
Why, what do you mean?
Tomorrow you and I will go looking
for a little apartment.
Say, that's right. I'd forgotten
all about that.
We do need a little place in town.
- Say, what are we driving at?
- Don't you know where we are?
We're home!
- Home? Our home?
- Yes, I've been saving it for a surprise.
Surprise!
A little cheer for the homecoming.
To the homecoming!
Jolly times and happy moments.
Hooray!
They're both too happy
for words, Hughie.
Isn't it wonderful to think they've
been in every spot in Europe?
England, France, Germany,
Italy, Switzerland.
Everywhere.
Yeah. Well, I don't want
to discourage you.
But a rolling stone gathers
no moss.
Dick has a wonderful wife.
I'm so glad.
Didn't they ask you over
to the house?
This is their first night in their
new home...
...and they want to be alone,
and quiet.
Well, Mr. Parker, I'm ready
to go back on the job.
That's great. I'm glad to hear it.
We've got a fine office for you, son,
and we're going to keep you mighty busy.
Well that's great.
Well, we've got to be going.
I'm going to say good night, Dick.
You see, I think you and Dot
ought to be alone.
Oh, by the way, where is Dot?
I want to say good night.
Well, I don't know.
Well, never mind, I'll see her
again later.
Alright.
Come, Llewellyn, we must go.
Good night.
Well, Dick, we'll have to go too.
Tell me, how did the boyfriend
behave?
Did he sleep in his overalls?
What do you care what he slept in?
Can't you do anything besides
knock people?
Now, listen, Dot, you think
you're kidding me.
But you're only kidding yourself.
About Dick?
Oh, you're crazy.
Oh, this marriage can't last.
I've never seen one that could,
and you know it's true.
- But Dick and I are different.
- I know.
But he just doesn't belong
with this crowd.
Don't worry about him. He will before
I get through with him.
Oh, you're going to have a tough
time making a tea hound out of that, er...
What do you call him...
Oh, yes, steel boss.
What's the matter?
- If you don't stop riding Dick...
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Won't you forgive me?
- Yes. But it won't happen again.
- It won't. I promise.
Cross my heart, right?
Now listen, just to prove
that we're still good friends,
how about a little kiss?
Just one, Charlie.
Uh-oh!
Aren't you forgetting your friends?
They're all going home.
Well, if that's the case, I guess
I'd better go along.
- Good night, Dot.
- Good night, Charlie.
Good night, Dick.
Sorry, Dick. I'll bid them
good night.
- Good night, Dot.
- Good night. Good night.
- Good night, Llewellyn.
- Good night.
- Good night, Dick.
- Good night, Dot.
- Good night.
- We had a lovely time.
- That's good. Come again, will you?
Well? What have you got
to say for yourself?
- Wasn't it a swell party?
- You know what I mean.
- No. What?
- Your necking with Bates.
Oh, Dick, don't be silly.
I've known Charlie all my life.
That doesn't make any difference.
You don't mean to tell me
you're jealous.
You just bet I am. I don't care
very much for Mr. Bates.
Now look, Charlie's alright.
Now don't go worrying about that.
Listen, Dot, don't let it ever
happen again.
Of course I won't, if you feel
that way about it.
Come on, now. Let's go and
inspect the house, huh?
Now wait a minute.
We can't stay here.
- Why not?
- It isn't right.
It's too much. Your father's been
too kind to us.
Besides, I could never support
this place on my salary.
- Is that all that's bothering you?
- Yes.
And that's why we're going
into a smaller place.
Oh, Dick.
Oh, I'd be so disappointed.
- Why, I planned everything.
- I know, dear, but...
Now look, Dick. What would everybody
say if we left this house?
Aw, Dick, you'll do this for your
little kitten, won't you?
Oh, I'd do anything in the world
for you.
Oh...
Hello, Hughie. How's everything
at the factory?
Sufficient unto the day is
the evil thereafter.
Why, what do you mean?
That son of yours is getting
pretty high-hat.
Well, a friend in need is
a friend indeed.
Why? What has Dick done?
It ain't what he's done, it's what
he ain't done.
He won't even get me that job
as boss puddler.
Well, I do more work around there
now than he does.
He don't do nothing.
- He's the joke of the joint.
- Oh, now, Hughie, I'm sure...
Well, he won't high-hat this baby
any longer. I'm through with him.
We are known by the company
we do not keep.
- Good morning.
- Any calls?
Yes, Mr. Parker's been trying
to get you all morning.
Said he'd call after lunch.
And Mrs. Brunton called.
Said she'd call back.
Hm, fine.
Hello?
Oh, yes, just a moment, please.
- Mrs. Brunton on the wire, Mr. Brunton.
- Thank you.
Hello, kitten.
I just wanted to remind you, dear,
I'll meet you at the recital at 2:30.
And don't forget we're due
at the Ritz at five.
Oh, yes, and Rose Clayton is giving us that
big dinner party at the club tonight.
All right.
Goodbye, sweetheart.
Any orders, Mr. Brunton?
Due at the recital at 2:30,
the Ritz at five and...
Never mind about that.
Well, Dick.
Well, I've got big news for you.
- Is that so?
- Been looking for you all morning.
- I'm sorry, I didn't feel very well.
- Oh, that's all right.
You still think Barber's idea about
that bridge is practical?
I know it is.
And you know it's against all
theories of engineering.
Yes, but this bridge won't be built
on theories.
It'll be built on brains, and imagination,
and concrete and steel.
Why, look at this.
Now, when Barber planned to put
those steel girdles...
That's all right, that's far enough.
I just wanted to know if you were
still sold on the idea.
- More than ever.
- Fine, that's just the way I feel.
Now, what I want to tell you is this.
I've made up my mind to take
the biggest gamble of my life.
I am going to win this contract
with that bridge.
You'll never make it. You know
what you're up against, don't you?
A bunch of old fogies who can't
see anything new or original.
Yes... The thing I need most is a man
who knows this idea from every angle.
A man who will set them afire
with his own enthusiasm.
A man who gets whatever he goes after
no matter how tough the opposition.
You mean Barber?
- No, he's an inventor, I want a salesman.
The man I've picked up
to put this thing over is...
- You.
- Me?
Yes, if you can sell a hard-boiled
egg like me,
...you can certainly sell those
St. Louis folks.
- You bet I can.
- Of course you can!
All you need to do is put that old fighting
football spirit into it and you can't fail.
Don't you worry, I won't fail you.
- Why, son, it's the chance of a lifetime.
- I know it is. I'll catch the next train.
Oh, now, take it easy.
Time enough for that tonight.
What we'll do, we'll spend this afternoon
going over this thing from A to Z...
...so there won't be any chance
of a slip up.
Oh, boy, just wait till I tell Dot.
Won't she be proud to know
that you gave me this big job?
- How long will I be away?
- About two weeks.
- Great, I'll take her with me.
- Fine.
Now come on. We'll go over to the office
and go through this thing thoroughly.
Alright.
That's fine, Mary.
By the way, did Mr. Brunton call
and say he'd be detained?
No. No, madame.
Dot!
- Oh, Dot, I've got the grandest news.
- Good heavens, where've you been?
- Oh, my gosh, I forgot to call you.
- Yes.
You didn't come to the recital.
You didn't show up at the Ritz.
And here it is, nearly 8 o'clock, and you
know very well we're due at that party.
Oh, but wait.
Gee, your father's a grand old scout.
He's given me the biggest job
in the history of the company.
- You can tell me all about it later.
- No, I can't.
We're leaving for St. Louis tonight.
- What?
- Sure, you and I.
Have you gone out of your head?
Of course I have. Now come on
and get your things packed.
Have you forgotten the Claytons are giving
a dinner in our honor at the club tonight?
Oh, dickens with the dinner.
We're shoving off for St. Louis.
Aw, kitten.
What's the matter?
Matter? Well, of all the crazy stunts.
Going to St. Louis.
I'll give father a piece of my mind.
But, kitten, it's a chance of a lifetime.
It'll be a good trip for you and
a nice change for two weeks.
Two weeks? At the top of the season?
What a chance.
Aw, it'll be like a second honeymoon.
Well, I've decided you're not to go.
That's all there is to it.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- I'll tell Dad a thing or two.
Riverside 6826.
- Oh, give me that!
- Oh, no.
I'm going to St. Louis and you're
going with me.
With a book full of engagements?
I guess not.
Well, then it looks like I'll have
to go alone.
Oh... and you'd leave me all alone
for two weeks?
I can't help it.
Business is business.
And you think more of business
than you do about me?
Now, you know it isn't that at all.
- Oh, don't let's quarrel about it.
- I don't want to quarrel either, dear.
You do love your little kittens,
don't you?
And you won't go away and leave
your little kittens...
...all alone for two weeks,
will you?
Oh, I do love you, Dot.
But I've got to go.
- Well, go, if you want to.
- Oh, now, be reasonable.
Be reasonable, huh? Go to St. Louis.
Don't let me keep you.
I'll find someone who'll be glad
to take me out.
- Oh, now, listen.
- No.
Aren't you going to say
goodbye, Dot?
Goodbye.
Then go to St. Louis!
Dick.
You don't mean to tell me
you left her crying.
Think I'm ashamed of you.
- Can't you see it wasn't my fault?
- Oh, wasn't it?
She made her plans and you rushed in
without warning and upset them.
- But mine were more important.
- Oh, yes, to you.
But her plans might have been
just as important to her.
Oh... I never thought of that.
Now you go on right home and
smooth it over.
But I can't, I haven't time.
You've got to find time.
You can't leave her like this.
Why, there's no telling what
might happen.
A high-spirited girl like her.
Well, what could I do?
Take her in your arms and ask
her to forgive you.
- And give up the trip?
- You won't have to give up anything.
But be fair to her. Don't ask her
to give up anything either.
But what if she insists?
Just take her in your arms
the right way and she won't insist.
I'll bet you'll find her all packed up
and waiting for you to ask her.
Oh, you look lovely in
that gown, madam.
I've been saving it for a
special occasion.
Hello?
It's Mr. Bates, madam.
- Oh, let me talk to him.
Hello, Charlie?
I'll phone Dorothy right away,
Mother.
Carlton 8831.
Now you be nice to her.
Well, when am I going to see you?
I'll see you over at the party tonight.
- What's the matter?
- The line's busy.
I know what I'll do.
I'll run home and catch her
before she leaves.
Now don't you worry.
- Is Mrs. Brunton upstairs?
- No, sir, she just left.
Hello? Give me Lakewood 6522...
please.
Hello, ready to go in?
Hello?
Is this the Lakewiew Country Club?
Mrs. Brunton will be there shortly
with the Clayton party.
I wonder if you'd have
her call her home.
- Yes, Mr. Brunton, as soon as she comes in.
- Thank you.
- Say when.
- All right.
When!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Give us a little toast, Dot.
- Know any new ones?
- No, I don't.
Pardon me a moment.
Uh... I didn't want any intruders
coming in.
Well, well, the old ten-twenty-thirty
stuff, eh?
Surely, why not?
Well, here's to you.
Here's to both of us.
Let it go.
- How about some more?
- Fine.
Give me Lakewood 6522.
Yes.
- Hello?
- Is this the Lakeview Country Club?
Well, this is Mr. Brunton speaking.
Mrs. Brunton is there with the
Clayton party,
I wonder if you'd call her
to the phone.
I'm sorry, sir, the Clayton party
has been called off.
Called off?
Well, is Mrs. Brunton there?
No, sir. She just left with
Mr. Bates.
The sound of the gong denoted
exactly 2 a.m., Eastern Standard Time...
...and marks the conclusion of
our program.
Good night, pleasant dreams.
Is that right, 2 o'clock?
Oh, the evening is still early.
Really, Charlie, I'd better be
trotting along.
You know, I'm terribly disappointed
in you.
- Yes?
- Hm-hmm.
Well, we'll certainly have
to fix that.
I thought you had lots more finesse.
I suppose your big he-man taught you
all the fine points of the game.
Oh, never mind about him.
Get my things.
I'm bored stiff.
I thought sure you'd give
me a thrill.
Don't worry, darling, you're going
to get your thrill.
Don't play so rough, Charlie.
You're a cute little kitten.
Kitten?
Kitten? Why, you're a little hellcat.
Ah, the perils of the big city.
Isn't any working girl safe?
Not with this fiend in human form.
Unhand me, Jack Dalton.
Think of my reputation, pulease.
Just think of mine.
Why, if I let you go it would be
fatal to my reputation.
Wait, wait!
If you come one step nearer,
I'll plunge this dagger in my heart.
Alright, clown if you want to,
but don't forget.
The villain still pursues her.
- Ah-ha!
- No, honestly, Charlie, you slay me.
- Your technique is rotten.
- Yes?
Well, you ain't seen nothing yet.
Wait, what am I supposed to do now?
Scream, I know.
How loud can you scream?
Not loud enough.
Will the marines never come?
Halt! Halt! What's that?
It's the United States Cavalry, boys!
We are ashamed!
There you are, Dot.
You win.
But stay awhile, don't rush off.
I'd love to, Charlie. But I've got to be up
first thing in the morning.
Yes? What's the big idea?
I'm going to grab the first
train for St. Louis.
I'll get your wraps for you.
- Good night, Charlie.
- Good night, Dot.
- Good night.
Why, Dick!
I thought you'd gone to St. Louis.
Where have you been?
- You know, Rose and Bob Clayton.
- Yeah?
- At the party, remember?
- Must have been some party.
Oh, it was. It was an awful brawl.
- Lots to drink?
- Barrels. Why?
Because those parties usually
don't break up...
...until they've cleaned out the last
bottle of booze.
And it's pretty late.
Yes, I know, but you see, uh...
Oh, Rose passed out, and Bob asked
me to take care of her.
- Anything serious?
- Oh, no!
Just a bad head.
Oh, but she's alright now.
That's good.
Oh, Dick.
- Dick, let me explain?
- You don't have to!
You were with Bates,
and I can guess the rest.
- But, Dick, I want to tell you the truth.
- Don't bother!
Don't you love me anymore?
Why don't you ask yourself
the same question?
- But you know I do.
- I don't know anything of the kind.
- But I just told you.
- Yeah, you told me a lot of things,
but I don't believe you.
- Oh, Dick.
- Expect me to believe a liar and a cheat?
- You dare say that to me?
- Well, that's what you are.
You didn't give me the chance
to tell you.
You've had your chance,
you told me enough.
- I can account for everything!
- Oh, I don't doubt that.
All your friends weren't drunk
and put in jail.
Oh, I know all about you and
Charlie Bates.
That's just it, you don't know
a thing about it.
Well, I can guess.
I'm well acquainted with the rotten habits
of that crowd you trot around with.
The rotten crowd, eh? Well, I notice you
don't mind trotting around with them.
Oh, don't I? Well, I only did it
to please you.
Hm, you accept their friendship
and hospitality,
then you turn around and call them...
A rotten bunch of pasty-faced,
loose-lipped wasters.
Parasites!
Parasites?
Well, that's good!
That sounds fine coming from you.
Why, you're in the same class as
Llewellyn Post, only you won't admit it.
Oh, I'll admit it.
I'm nothing but a kept husband.
Since you put it that way,
that's just what you are.
- That's just what I was.
- Was?
- What are you going to do?
- Quit.
I'm through with you and I'm
through with all this.
Through chiselling your father out of
all that money I don't earn...
...just to be your lap dog.
Oh, is that so?
Well, you can keep all that stuff.
There's only one thing I'll keep.
- That's my self-respect.
- All right!
I won't give you back this engagement ring
because I paid for it myself.
But you can give this back
to your mother.
Here.
Goodbye, Mr. Brunton.
My lawyers will call you up
in a few days.
Don't hold me up for too
much alimony.
You don't look so snappy this
morning, Mrs. Brunton.
I didn't sleep a wink all night,
worried about Dick.
Oh, he's all right.
He takes after you.
Great oaks from little acorns grow.
I know everything's alright, but...
Still I...
Say, you ain't going to raise my room rent
just because I'm a boss puddler, are you?
No, Hughie.
- You'd better hurry.
- I never hurry.
I claim haste makes waste.
Holy Moses.
- Good morning, Mr. Parker.
- Morning.
Is Mrs. Brunton downstairs?
- No, sir.
She hasn't come down yet today.
- Is my daughter in?
- Yes, sir, but you can't see her.
- Why can't I?
- She's been ill.
- She hasn't slept.
- Well, that's just too bad.
Here, read that.
Oh, Dad, I'm terribly sorry.
You ought to be.
Though little good it'll do you.
What do you mean?
You almost ruined the biggest deal
the Parker Steel Corporation ever had.
Yes, and you ruined one of the
finest boys I ever saw.
- I did not.
- I tell you you did.
You rotted his soul, you killed
his manhood and ambition.
Why, when he walked into the office with
this I thought I was looking at a ghost.
- Why, what has he...
- I don't know what he's done,
...and I hate to think what
he might do.
I tried to pep him up and make
him take that St. Louis job.
- But I'm afraid.
- Oh, I'm afraid too.
You had an infernal nerve letting your
pink teas interfere with that boy's career?
What right have you to say that
to me when it's all your fault?
- My fault?
- Yes!
Oh, it's no use arguing with you.
You men always stick together.
Well you can get rid of this house.
I never want to live in it again.
You'd better get rid of some
of your foolishness...
...and you've got to find that boy
and find him quick.
And what's more, you're going
back to him.
I won't go back!
I won't, I won't, I won't,
I won't, I won't go back!
Well... he said goodbye.
But he said he couldn't go to St. Louis and
put that deal over the way he was feeling.
Mother, I'd give anything to see him
just for a minute.
I'm afraid, dear, from what
you've told me...
...it's too late.
There, there, there now, dear.
I didn't mean that.
No, it's just that you said...
...it's too late.
- Oh, Mother, I've been just rotten.
- No you haven't, dear.
You've just been human.
But why did I say...
Oh, why didn't I cut my tongue off?
Oh, well, you didn't mean it.
Dick should have known you didn't mean it.
Oh, can you blame him?
Who'd stand for being called a...
Listen, Dorothy.
All husbands are kept.
Some of them are kept with money.
But most of them with love, devotion,
and sacrifice.
Why, it's every woman's mission in life.
Keeping her husband.
Mother.
- Couldn't you find him, Mr. Hanready?
- No, didn't he phone in?
No.
What can't be cured must be endured.
- Any luck, Hanready?
- No, couldn't find him anywhere.
- Been in every speakeasy in town.
- By George.
I wonder...
Say, I think I know where
I can find him.
Call my chauffeur and tell him
to bring my car at once.
Yes, sir.
Connecticut wrapper with
ACID fedity filler.
Beggars can't be chosers.
My boy, I'm glad you didn't
change your mind.
- Mr. Parker.
- I knew you wouldn't fail me.
All aboard!
Don't you worry a minute.
I'll put this deal over.
But that resignation goes
the minute I get it over.
We'll talk about that when
you get back.
- Goodbye.
- Good luck.
And boy, bring in a table.
Yes, sir. Coming right up, boss.
Oh, Dick!
What are you doing here?
Aren't you glad to see me?
I can't say that, I'm no liar.
Oh, I don't blame you. I did lie to you.
But I'm no cheat.
I couldn't let you go away
without explaining it to you.
Oh, Dick, you must believe me.
Oh, I do believe you.
Oh, thanks.
Oh, listen, Dick.
- I'm going to get rid of the house.
- That's not enough.
We're not going to be kept by
your father's money any longer.
Oh, no, never.
Dick, we're going to live on your salary.
But wait a minute.
Will you do me a favor?
- What is it?
- Let's start all over again.
You propose to me.
Will you be my wife, Dot?
Yes. But this time I'm going to keep
you in a different way.
Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes.