Well, these are certainly
the cleanest steps
on Madison Avenue.
That's how Mr. Day wants them kept.
- Good morning.
- You're new here, aren't you?
- Just this mornin'.
This is the way Mr. Day
gets his milk.
Giddap.
Annie, be careful of this dish.
You could burn your hands.
And keep the cover on
till you're ready to serve them.
- Mr. Day likes his muffins hot.
- I'll do that.
Annie, is the table set
for breakfast?
'Yes, ma'am.'
Good mornin', ma'am.
Good morning, Annie.
How are you getting along?
Alright, ma'am, I hope.
Now don't be nervous just
because this is your first day.
Everything's
going to be alright.
But I do hope
nothing goes wrong.
Oh, no, Annie. The cream
and sugar go down at this end.
Oh, I thought
in the center, ma'am
everyone could reach them easy.
- Mr. Day sits here.
- Oh, excuse me.
I didn't know where to place
the napkins, ma'am.
You can tell by the rings.
The boys have their initials.
C for Clarence. He sits here.
J for John, here.
W for Whitney. He sits
over there next to his father.
And the one
with a little dog on it
is Harlan's, of course.
He's the baby.
This narrow plain one is mine
and this is Mr. Day's.
It's just like mine except that
it got bent...one morning.
That reminds me, Annie.
Always have Mr. Day's coffee
piping hot.
And whenever Mr. Day speaks
to you, just say yes sir.
Don't be nervous.
You'll get used to him.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, that beautiful rubber plant.
I'm so glad it came.
You mustn't water it every day.
Too much moisture
makes it very unhappy.
Oh, good morning, mother.
I thought
you were still upstairs.
'Good morning, Clarence.'
Father must be talking
to himself.
A redhead.
- Did you sleep well, mother?
- Yes, thank you, dear.
Golly, I'm hungry.
Oh, and, Annie, we always start
with fruit in the morning.
Except the two younger boys who
have their porridge and milk.
'Jiminy, another wreck
on the New Haven.'
That always disturbs
the stock market.
Father won't like that.
I do wish the New Haven
would stop having wrecks.
If they knew
how it upsets your father.
My soul and body! Clarence,
what's happened to your coat?
Oh, it ripped open again.
Margaret mended it for me
but it wouldn't stay mended.
Oh, dear,
I'll just have to speak
to your father
about a new suit of clothes.
Clarence, why did you take
my H2SO4
out of our clothes closet?
'I've told you a hundred times'
'that closet's
not to make experiments in.'
Two?
Good morning, mother.
John, have you been making
those chemical smells again?
No, mother,
I'm making an electric battery.
It will ring a bell
and everything.
You know your father
doesn't like electricity.
But, mother, everything's
going to be electricity.
- Not in this house.
- 'Oh, God!'
What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
- 'Where's my necktie?'
- Which necktie?
'The one I gave you yesterday.'
It isn't pressed yet.
I forgot to give it to Margaret.
'I told you distinctly I wanted
to wear that necktie today.'
You've got plenty of neckties.
Put on another one right away
and come down to breakfast.
'I don't know
what this world's coming to.'
Mother,
may I have my breakfast early?
I'm going to play baseball.
Three?
Whitney,
before you leave the house
you have to study
your catechism.
But, mother, they're going
to let me pitch today.
Good morning.
- Who won?
- The Giants, 7 to 3.
- Buck Ewing hit a home run.
- Let me see.
Boys, don't wrinkle the paper
before your father sees it.
Mother, could you ask me
my catechism now?
- I think I know it.
- Well, let's see.
- Ah, what is your name?
- Whitney Benjamin.
- Who gave you your--
- 'Here I come!'
Come and help me down, mother.
There are steps to come down on.
- Good morning, darling.
- Good morning, mother.
- How's your finger?
- It itches.
Good. That's a sign
it's getting better.
Come along.
Four!
Let's see. What was I doing?
Oh, yes, the catechism.
Who gave you your name?
My sponsors at baptism
wherein I was made a member
of Christ
the child of God
and an inheritor
of the kingdom of heaven.
Mother,
if I hadn't been baptized
wouldn't I have any name?
Not in the sight of the church.
What did your sponsors
then for you?
They did promise and vow
three things in my name.
First, that I should renounce
the devil and all of his..
'And secondly..'
'...secondly, that I believe'
'all the articles
of the Christian faith.'
And thirdly, that I should keep
God's holy will and commandments
'and walk in the same
all the days of my--'
Morning, boys. Morning.
- Good morning, father.
Morning, Vinnie.
Had a good night?
- Yes, thank you, Clare.
- Good.
Sit down, boys.
What's that thing doing in here?
Clare,
that's our new rubber plant.
Place for rubber plants
is on the equator.
Uh, take that object out,
Catherine.
- You're not Catherine.
- No, sir.
Good.
Never liked Catherine, anyway.
Put it somewhere else, Annie,
but not too near a window.
Yes, ma'am.
Sit down, Harlan.
Thank you, dear.
Where did that dog come from?
She'll leave, mother.
I'll talk to her.
What did you say?
Oh, Clare,
that new suit looks very nice.
You've put on a little weight,
dear.
I weigh just the same
as I always have.
Well, Clarence has just
managed to ruin
the only decent suit he has.
I'm sorry, but I'm afraid he'll
need a new suit of clothes.
Vinnie, Clarence has to learn
not to be so hard
on his clothes.
But, father, I thought--
You're starting Yale
in the fall.
You'll be completely outfitted.
But nothing this summer.
Can I have one of your old suits
cut down for me?
Every suit I own
still has plenty of wear in it.
I wear my clothes
until they're worn out.
Well, if you want
your clothes worn out
Clarence can wear them out
much faster than you can.
Yes, and, father, you never get
a chance to wear yours out.
Every time
you get a new batch of clothes
mother sends the old ones
to the missionary barrel.
I guess I'm just as good
as any old missionary.
Clarence, before you compare
yourself to a missionary
'remember the sacrifices
they make.'
Oh, I don't know, Vinnie.
I think my clothes
would look better on Clarence
than on some Hottentot.
Have that, uh, dark suit of mine
cut down to fit you.
Well, thank you, father.
One of father's suits.
Thank you, sir.
In return for that, Clarence
I want you to practice
more often on your violin.
Whitney, don't eat so fast.
Well, father,
I'm going to pitch today.
But before I go,
I have to study my catechism.
What do you bother
with that for?
Because if he doesn't know
his catechism
he can't be confirmed.
But, Vinnie,
Whitney's going to pitch today.
He can be confirmed
any old time.
Clare, sometimes
it seems to me you don't care
whether your children
get to heaven or not.
Oh, Whitney will get to heaven
alright.
I'll be there before you are,
Whitney.
I'll see that you get in.
And, Whitney,
when we get to heaven
we'll organize a baseball team
of our own.
- Good.
- Hmm.
Be just like you to try
and run things up there.
Well, from all I've heard
about heaven
it seems to be a pretty
unbusiness-like place.
They could probably use
a good man like me.
What makes you so sure
they'll let you in to heaven?
Well, if they don't,
I'll certainly raise
a devil of a row.
Clare, I do hope you'll behave
when you get to heaven.
Now, Vinnie, what..
Vinnie, how many times have I
asked you not to engage a maid
who doesn't know
how to serve properly?
Clare, can't you see
she's new and doing her best?
How can I serve myself
when she's holding that platter
over my head?
- Hold it lower, Annie.
- Yes, ma'am.
What became of the one
we had yesterday?
I don't know
why you can't keep a maid.
Oh, you don't!
Why on earth
can't you run your house
the way I run my office?
All I want is service.
What the devil's that noise?
- It's Annie.
- Annie? Who's Annie?
The maid.
I'll take it, Annie.
Clare,
aren't you ashamed of yourself?
What have I done now?
You made her cry,
speaking to her the way you did.
I never said a word to her.
I was addressing myself to you.
I do wish you'd be more careful.
It's hard enough to keep a maid
and the uniform
just fit this one.
'What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?'
What in the name of..
Well, where did you come from?
- Who do you belong to?
- She's mine, father.
Her name is Princess.
Hmm, looks more
like a prince to me.
- Margaret, this bacon's good.
- Oh.
- Well, it's good.
- Yes, sir.
Harlan, how's that finger?
'Come here, let me see it.'
Yes, father.
Ah, yes,
that's healing nicely.
I guess you'll know
the next time
that cats don't like
to be hugged.
It's alright to stroke them,
but don't squeeze them.
Now go back
and finish your oatmeal.
I don't like oatmeal.
Go on and finish it.
It's good for you.
But I don't like it.
I'll tell you what you like
and what you don't like.
You're not old enough
to know about such things.
You've no business
not to like oatmeal.
- It's good.
- I hate it!
That's enough!
We won't discuss it.
Eat that oatmeal at once!
Ugh.
John, that letter's
for your mother.
I finished my oatmeal, father.
May I be excused?
Yes, Whitney, you may go.
Pitch a good game.
I will.
Whitney.
Yes, mother, my catechism.
Never mind this morning,
darling. Run along.
Thank you, mother.
Margaret, what is this?
- Coffee, sir.
- It is not coffee.
You couldn't possibly take
water and coffee beans
and arrive at that.
It's slops. That's what it is.
Slops! Take it away.
I come down to this table
every morning hungry--
'Well, if you're hungry, Clare'
'why aren't you eating
your breakfast?'
I am.
Aunt Judith wants me
to come up and visit her.
Now, Vinnie, I want no more
relatives in this house.
We're going to live here
by ourselves
in peace and comfort.
Clare, I was saying Aunt Judith
wants me to visit her.
- Oh.
- Eat your oatmeal, dear.
What on earth is this?
"Dear friend Day,
we are assigning you
"the exclusive rights
to Staten Island
for selling
the Gem Home Popover Popcorn."
I think that's for me, father.
But then why isn't it
addressed to Clarence Day, Jr.?
Oh, it is.
I wouldn't get mixed up
in popcorn, Clarence.
It's too indigestible.
Confound it!
Another wreck on the New Haven.
If you please, ma'am,
there's a dollar due
on a package.
It's from Lewis & Congers.
'Oh, yes, those kitchen knives
I ordered.'
Ah, make a memorandum of that,
Vinnie.
One dollar
and whatever it was for.
Of course, Clare.
I must have a record
of what is spent
running this house.
I've never understood
what good a record is
after the money's gone.
There's just a dollar, Margaret.
Vinnie, this house must be run
on a business basis.
That's what
the household accounts are for.
Oh, Clare, it's half past 8:00.
'You don't wanna be late
at the office.'
Plenty of time.
- Annie, clear the table now.
- Yes, ma'am, I'll do that.
- Clarence, John.
- Yes, mother?
You boys go up
and move the small bureau
from my room into yours.
- Who's coming?
- Cousin Cora.
And she's bringing a friend
with her.
- A young girl.
- A girl!
You'll have to help
entertain her, Clarence.
Oh, mother, do I have to?
Wait till father finds out
we've got
visitors. There'll be a rumpus.
John, don't criticize
your father.
He's very hospitable
after he gets used to the idea.
- I like coffee. I like tea.
- Tsk, tsk.
I like the girls
and the girls like me.
Well, I don't like girls
and they don't like me.
- 'Oh, God!'
- Go on, boys. Go on.
What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
How did that get in this room?
Now, Clare,
how was the new maid to know?
Keep that abomination
out of here.
Alright, I'll take it.
Oh, Clare dear, I'm afraid
I'm going to need
some more money.
You were complaining
about the coffee this morning.
Well, that nice French drip
coffee pot is broken
and you know how it got broken.
Never mind that, Vinnie.
As I remember that coffee pot
cost $5 and, uh, something.
I'll give you $6.
Uh, when you get it, Vinnie
enter the exact amount
in the ledger.
Of course, Clare.
We can't go on month after month
having the household accounts
in such a mess.
No, and I thought of a system
that will make my bookkeeping
perfect.
Well, I'm certainly relieved
to hear that.
All we have to do is open
charge accounts everywhere
and the stores will do
my bookkeeping for me.
Now wait a minute, Vinnie--
Then when the bills come in
you'd know exactly
where your money had gone.
Yes, I certainly would.
Vinnie,
we get enough bills as it is.
Clare dear, don't you hate
those arguments
we have every month?
I certainly do.
Not to have those,
I should think would be worth
something to you.
Well, I'll open an account
at Lewis & Congers
and, uh, one at McCreery's
to start with.
- Thank you, Clare.
- We'll see how it works out.
Thank you.
Oh, the rector's
coming to tea today.
The rector.
Well, I'm glad you warned me.
I'll go to the club.
Don't expect me home
until dinnertime.
Clare dear,
I do wish you'd take
a little more interest
in the church.
Getting me into heaven
is your business, Vinnie.
If there's anything wrong
with my ticket when I get there
you can fix it up.
Everybody loves you so much.
I'm sure God must too.
I'll do my best, Clare.
It wouldn't be heaven
without you.
If you're there, Vinnie,
I'll manage to get in some way
even if I have to climb
the fence.
Margaret. Margaret.
'Oh, God!'
What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
Why did God make so many
dumb fools and Democrats?
Ah, politics.
Yes, but it's taking the bread
out of our mouths!
Honest Hugh Grant.
Honest, bah!
Fine mayor
you've turned out to be.
If you can't run this city
without raising taxes
every five minutes,
you'd better get out.
Let someone who can.
Richard Cook
is running in this town
and you're just his cat's paw!
Tell me this,
are these increased taxes
going into public improvements
or are they going into graft?
Answer me that honestly
if you can
Mr. Honest Hugh Grant.
You can't? I thought so.
Bah!
- Don't order dinner..
- 'You were elected to office..'
'...on the promise
that you would put an end'
'to all this thievery
and corruption.'
'Have you put an end to it?
No. You've encouraged it.'
'Every day there's some new raid
on the public treasury.'
- If you don't stop..
- Father, if you don't mind..
...of New York,
we're going to throw you
and your boodle board
of aldermen out of office.
I'm warning you
for the last time.
Robbery. That's what it is.
Highway robbery!
- Annie. Annie.
- What is it?
Take this fresh cup of coffee
in to Mr. Day.
But Mr. Day's got a visitor.
'...are not going to tolerate
these..'
Nonsense. Run along in there.
We pay you a good round sum
to watch after our interests
and all we get is inefficiency.
I know you're a nincompoop
and I strongly suspect you
of being a scalawag.
You're not going to escape
your legal responsibilities.
Legal responsibilities?
By God, I mean
criminal responsibilities!
Don't think for one minute
we're going to let you escape.
We're going to throw you
into jail!
- Annie, are you hurt?
- He can't throw me into jail!
Vinnie?
Vinnie, why can't I have
quiet here in the morning?
Clare, what happened?
Uh, sounded to me
as though that maid
dropped a whole tray of dishes.
Yes,
but what did you say to her?
Say to her? I haven't seen her
since breakfast.
- I better get to the office.
- Oh, yes, Clare.
You don't want to be late.
I'll be home in plenty of time
for dinner.
Why don't we have
chicken fricassee tonight?
Well, Clare, chicken's gone up.
It's 8 cents a pound.
Where the devil's she going
dressed up like that?
Clare, you've done it again.
How could you?
- How could I what?
- Can't you see she's leaving?
Oh, dear. I have no time
to engage a new maid.
- We'll have to have dinner out.
- Dinner out. Nonsense.
- I'll engage a new maid myself.
- Clare, you can't.
- She has to fit the uniform.
- I'll have one here in an hour.
- 'Goodbye, dear.'
- 'Goodbye, Clare.'
Good morning, Mr. Day.
On your way to the office?
- Yes.. Good morning.
- Mrs. Day.
- Good morning, Mr. Day.
- Morning, Jim.
Giddap!
Giddap.
Cora, it's wonderful to see you.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, Vinnie,
I declare you're getting
younger and prettier every year.
- Oh, this is Mary Skinner.
- Ed Skinner's daughter.
My goodness,
I never would have known you.
Just leave your things out here
and come right on in.
I heard my father talk so much
about you, Mrs. Day.
Oh, did he tell you
how he used to dip my pigtails
in the inkwell at school?
What's the news
in Pleasantville, Cora?
Oh, Vinnie,
I have so much to tell you.
We wrote you
that Aunt Carrie broke her hip.
That was the night
that Robert Ingersoll lectured.
Of course, she couldn't get
there, but it was a good thing
for Mr. Ingersoll she didn't.
'How do you do, Cousin Cora?'
Oh, Clarence, my, my.
No, no, Cora, this is John.
John! Why, how you've grown.
You'll be a man
before your mother.
'John, this is Mary Skinner.'
- How do you do?
Vinnie, everybody in
Pleasantville sends their love.
Grandpa Evans, Cousin Edith,
Aunt Hattie, the Taylors.
- Oh, just everybody.
- Cora, how is Grandpa Evans?
Oh, he hasn't been at all well.
You know, he only has one kidney
and that's bloating.
How do you do, Cousin Cora?
I'm glad to see you.
This can't be Clarence.
- Yes, it is.
- My, my.
My goodness,
every time I see you boys
you've grown another foot.
Let's see, you're going
to St. Paul's now, aren't you?
St. Paul's? I was through
with St. Paul's long ago.
I'm starting in Yale this fall.
Yale!
Oh, uh, oh, Mary,
this is Clarence.
- Mary Skinner.
- How do you do?
Oh, this is Mary's
first trip to New York.
Yes, it is.
It's her first trip.
We'll have to show Mary around.
Oh, I'll tell you,
I'll ask Mr. Day
to take us all to Delmonico's
for dinner tonight.
- Delmonico's!
- Think of that, Mary.
Delmonico's!
And Cousin Clare's
such a wonderful host.
Well, I know you girls want
to freshen up, so come upstairs.
Clarence, get their bags.
I've given you girls
Clarence's room
but he didn't know about it
until this morning.
- I don't want you to give..
- He hasn't moved his things..
John, get their old bags.
Oh, you play the violin.
Well, I, I fool with it
a little.
You're just being modest.
No, really, I..
I play the piano.
Not awfully well, but..
Now you're being modest.
Do you ever play duets?
Well, I haven't up to now.
Neither have I...up to now.
Cora didn't tell me about you.
I never met a Yale man before.
What's happened to you?
Nothing. I feel fine.
Where do you keep 'em?
Do you wish a domestic servant?
Where do you keep them?
I will take your name
and address.
Confound it.
I'm late at the office now.
If you will give me the details
as to what kind of person
you require.
I'm asking you
where you keep them?
Why, the girls are in there
but clients are not allowed
in that room.
If you will tell me
the kind of a position you wish
to have held,
I'll be very glad to..
You stand up, please.
Sir, this is quite
against the rules.
I must know
what you want the girl for.
I'll take that one.
What's your name?
Hilda, sir.
Hilda, you go right over
to 420 Madison Avenue.
- I will, sir.
- That's all. Thank you.
Sir, before I can let any girl
go from this establishment
I must know the character
of the home
in which she will be employed.
Madam,
I am the character of my home.
Oh.
My duty toward my neighbor
is to love him as myself
and to do unto all men as, as..
As they should do unto me.
As they should do unto me
to, to..
He really knows it.
Well, he's done very well
for so young a boy.
- May I go now?
- Yes, darling.
- Thank you, Dr. Lloyd.
- Not at all.
Come on, Harlan.
Wait for me.
Ah, you and Mr. Day must be
very proud of your children.
I was hoping I'd find Mr. Day
at home this afternoon.
Well, he-he's usually home
from the office by this time.
Hmm. Perhaps he's gone
for a gallop in the park.
It's such a fine day.
He's very fond
of horseback riding, I believe.
Oh, yes.
Tell me, has he ever been
thrown from a horse?
Oh, no,
no horse would throw Mr. Day.
I just thought he might
have had some accident.
I notice
he never kneels in church.
Oh, that's no accident.
Uh, but I don't want you
to think he doesn't pray.
He does.
Why, sometimes you can hear him
all over the house.
But he never kneels.
Ah, perhaps that's Mr. Day now.
Oh, I hardly think so.
Oh, the devil. I forgot.
Clare,
you're just in time for tea.
- I'll send for some hot water.
- How are you, Dr. Lloyd?
'It's a great pleasure to have
a visit with you, Mr. Day.'
- Mother, are they back yet?
- No, Clarence, no.
'Except for a brief glimpse
on the Sabbath'
I don't see much of you.
Well, Clare, did you have
a busy day at the office?
- Devilishly busy.
- Clare.
Uh, a very busy day. Tired out.
How a man can get tired
just sitting at a desk all day,
I don't know.
I suppose Wall Street
is just as much a mystery to you
as it is to me, Dr. Lloyd.
No, no.
It's all very clear to me.
My mind often goes
to the businessman.
The picture I'm most fond on
is when I envision him
at the close of the day's work.
I see him pausing in his toil
and it comes over him
that all those figures
of profit and loss
are without importance
or consequence.
Vanity and dust.
- Well, I'll be--
- Clare.
- Yes, ma'am?
- 'Delia, some more hot water.'
- Yes, ma'am.
- Who's that?
The new maid.
Where's the one I sent
this morning?
The uniform didn't fit.
Hmm. I like the one
I picked out better.
Uh, Clare,
Dr. Lloyd wants to tell us
about the plans
for the new edifice.
- The new what?
- The new church.
You knew we were planning
to build a new church.
Of course, we're going to have
to raise a large sum of money.
Hmm. Well, personally,
I am against the church
hop, skipping and jumping
all over the town.
So any contribution I make
will have to be a small one.
The amount
everyone is to subscribe
has already been decided.
Who decided it?
After considerable thought
we voted
that our supporting members
should each contribute a sum
equal to the cost of their pew.
I paid $5000 for my pew.
Yes, Clare. That makes
our contribution $5000.
That's robbery.
Do you know what that pew
is worth today? $3000.
That's what
the last one sold for.
I've taken a dead loss of $2000
on that pew already.
Frank Bags sold me that pew
when the market was at its peak.
He knew when to get out.
And I'm warning you, Vinnie,
if the market ever goes up
I'm going to unload that pew.
Clarence Day, how can you speak
of the temple of the Lord
as though it was something to be
bought and sold on Wall Street?
Now, Mrs. Day, your husband
is a practical man.
We've had to be practical
about the new church.
We have all the facts
and figures.
Oh. What's the property worth
where we are now?
Oh, let's see. Is it $40,000?
I know the figure
has a four in it.
What's the new piece of property
going to cost you?
I think the figure I heard
mentioned was $85,000.
Or was it 185,000?
Uh, Dr. Lloyd,
you preach that someday
we'll all have to answer to God.
We shall indeed.
Well, I hope God doesn't
ask you any questions
with figures in them.
'Mrs. Day
is in the living room.'
'Thank you.'
- I-it's Cousin Cora.
- Hmm?
- She's passing through town.
- Oh.
Well.
- Oh, hello.
- Hello.
- Thank you for helping me.
Come, Mary.
Oh, Vinnie, what a day.
We've been in every shop
in town.
- Why, Cousin Clare.
- 'Cora.'
My, my.
You're as welcome
as the flowers in May.
- This is Mary Skinner. Mr. Day.
- How do you do?
I've been telling Mary
all about you.
- She's been dying to meet you.
- Well.
Dr. Lloyd, I want you to meet
my favorite cousin,
Miss Cartwright.
- How do you do?
- And this is Mary Skinner.
Miss Skinner, Dr. Lloyd.
- How do you do?
Well, this seems to be
a family reunion.
- I'll just run along.
- Goodbye, Dr. Lloyd.
Uh, goodbye, Miss Cartwright.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, uh..
Oh, Clarence, you haven't said
how do you do to Dr. Lloyd.
Goodbye, Dr. Lloyd.
- Oh.
- Uh, goodbye, everybody.
I'll go to the door with you,
Dr. Lloyd.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for the tea.
Those muffins were delicious.
Who did you say
this pretty little girl is?
She's Ed Skinner's daughter.
This is Mary's first trip
to New York.
Oh, uh, sit down. Sit down.
- Have some tea.
- We had tea downtown.
- Oh, uh, never mind then, uh..
- Delia.
Delia.
Uh, sit down, sit down.
Even if you have had tea, you
can stay and visit for a while.
As a matter of fact, why don't
you both stay to dinner?
That's all arranged, Clare.
Cora and Mary are going
to have dinner with us.
Fine, fine.
Of course, you'll just
have to take potluck.
- Well, I'd hardly call it--
- Clare.
Did you know the girls
are going to visit Aunt Judith
in Springfield
for a whole month?
Fine.
Now how long are you going
to be in New York, Cora?
- All week.
- Splendid.
We'll hope to see
something of you.
Well, you certainly will--
Cora, d-did you find anything
you wanted in the shop?
Oh, I can't wait to show you.
Oh, but I'm afraid
some of these packages
can't be opened
in front of Cousin Clare.
Shall I leave the room?
Oh, Clarence, would you take
the package in the hall
up to our room,
or should I say your room?
Wasn't it nice of Clarence
to give up his room
to us for a whole week?
Cora, come on, I just can't wait
to see what's in those packages.
Well, we'll be back soon.
Uh, uh, Vinnie, I wish to speak
to you before you go upstairs.
I'll be down in just a minute,
Clare.
I wish to speak to you now.
I'll be up in just a minute,
Cora.
It's alright, Vinnie.
Come along, Mary.
Are those two women
encamped in our house?
- Now, Clare--
- Answer me, Vinnie.
- Now, Clare, you know--
- Answer me!
Just a minute. Clarence!
Now, Clare, you know
you've always been fond of Cora.
What has that got to do with her
packing herself down in my house
and bringing hordes of strangers
with her?
How can you call
that sweet little girl
a horde of strangers?
Why don't they go to a hotel?
New York is full of hotels
built for the express purpose
of housing such nuisances.
Clare,
two girls alone in a hotel.
Why, who knows
what might happen to them?
Alright, then put them
on the first train.
They want to roam like gypsies?
Lend them a hand.
Keep them roaming!
But, Clare, they're just
staying in that little room
of Clarence's.
The trouble is,
they don't stay there.
They stay in the bathroom.
Every time
I want to take my bath
it's full of giggling females
washing their hair!
I tell you, I won't have it.
Send them to a hotel.
I'll pay the bill gladly,
but get them out of here.
Father, I'm afraid
they can hear you upstairs.
Then keep those doors closed.
Clarence, you open those doors.
Open them all the way.
Now, Clare, you be quiet
and behave yourself.
They're here,
and they're going to stay here.
That's enough, Vinnie.
I want no more of this argument.
Hmm.
Oh, chaa!
What I don't understand is
why this swarm of locusts
always descends on us
without any warning.
Oh, thunder!
'Vinnie, dear Vinnie.'
Hmm.
Father, may I go along
with the rest of you
to Delmonico's?
What's that? Delmonico's?
You're taking mother,
Cousin Cora
and Miss Skinner to Delmonico's
for dinner tonight.
Oh, God!
I won't have it.
I will not have my life
arranged for me.
I bought this house
for my own comfort.
I will not submit myself
to this indignity.
- Now, Clare, what's the matter?
- I won't stand it.
By heaven, I won't stand it!
Clarence.
Do I understand
that I am not permitted
to have dinner in my own home?
Oh, Clare, a little change
will do you good.
I have a home to have dinner in.
And any time
I can't have dinner at home
this house is for sale.
Well, Clare, you can't
have dinner here tonight
because it isn't ordered.
And besides, Cora and Mary
want to see something
of New York.
Well, that's no affair of mine.
I am not a guide
to Chinatown and the Bowery.
Oh, Mr. Day,
I just love your house.
I could live here forever.
Cora's waiting for you,
Mrs. Day.
Oh, yes. I'll run right up.
I'm, uh, glad you like
our house, Miss Skinner.
I like it very much, Mr. Day.
Praise from a stranger
is approbation indeed.
At home,
our living room is green.
I like green.
I like green too.
Red's my favorite color.
I-it's an interesting thing
about colors.
Red's a nice color
in a house, too
but outside too much red
would be bad.
I mean, for instance,
if all the trees
and the grass were red.
Outside, green's the best color.
That's right.
I never thought of it that way.
But when you do think of it,
it's quite a thought.
I bet you'll make your mark
at Yale.
Oh.
My mother
wants me to go to college.
Do you believe
in girls going to college?
I guess it's alright if
they wanna waste that much time
before they get married,
I mean.
I'm glad you're fond of music,
Mr. Day.
Oh, hello.
Look, a new "Youth's Companion."
John enjoys
"The Youth's Companion."
- John.
- Oh.
- Won't you sit down?
Oh, thank you.
It tells all about
connecting batteries in series.
John, Miss Skinner and I
were talking.
Oh, that's alright.
You won't bother me.
Jiminy, there's where
I made my mistake.
- I didn't mix enough--
- Shh!
- Oh, don't stop.
- Can you play that?
I'm afraid not.
Can you play "Sweet Genevieve?"
- That's my favorite.
- Not without my music.
Hymns are nice, don't you think?
I like this one.
That's funny.
The words are the same,
but it's the wrong tune.
Oh, it can't be the wrong tune.
We sing it exactly that way
in church.
We don't sing it that way
in the Methodist church.
- You see, we're Methodists.
- 'Oh, that's too bad.'
Oh, I-I don't mean it's too bad
that you're a Methodist.
Anybody's got a right to be
anything they want.
But what I mean is..
...we're Episcopalians.
Yes, I know.
Anyway, the words are the same.
Shall we begin?
Now.
- Oh, dear.
- What's wrong?
Shall we try again?
- It must be my fault.
- 'Oh, no, it's my fault.'
No, you're the Episcopalian.
I just remembered something.
My father was an Episcopalian.
He was baptized an Episcopalian.
He was an Episcopalian
right up to the time
he married my mother.
- She was the Methodist.
- Oh.
Oh, well,
let's try it again then.
Well, Clarence,
if you're going to Delmonico's
with us,
you'd better get dressed.
Am I going too? Jiminy!
Thank you, father.
Be ready in just a minute,
mother.
Vinnie, that young lady looks
about the same age you were
when I came out to Pleasantville
to rescue you.
- Rescue me?
- Mmm.
You came out there
to talk me into marrying you.
Well, it worked out
just the same.
- French.
- Oui.
No cooking like the French.
Clare, it was so nice of you
to invite
Cora and Mary here
their first night.
Well, it's been a pleasure.
Mr. Day, have you always
been an Episcopalian?
I've always gone
to the Episcopal Church, yes.
But you weren't baptized
a Methodist or anything
were you?
You were baptized
an Episcopalian?
Come to think of it,
I don't believe
I was ever baptized at all.
Clare, that's not very funny
joking about a subject
like that.
I'm not joking.
I remember now.
I never was baptized.
Clare, that's ridiculous.
Everybody's baptized.
Well, I'm not.
No one would keep a little baby
from being baptized.
Well, you know
father and mother.
Free thinkers, both of them.
They thought
their children should decide
those things for themselves.
But, Clare--
I remember when I was, uh
ten or twelve years old
mother said I ought to give
some thought to it, but, uh
'I never got around
to having it done to me.'
Clare, do you know
what you're saying?
Yes, I'm saying
I've never been baptized.
Then something's got to be done
about it right away.
Now, Vinnie, don't get
excited over nothing.
Why haven't you ever told me?
Well, what difference
does it make?
I have never heard of anyone
who wasn't baptized.
Even the savages
in darkest Africa.
Well, it's alright
for savages and children.
But if an oversight
was made in my case
it's too late to correct it now.
Well, if you're not baptized,
you're not a Christian.
Why, confound it,
of course, I'm a Christian.
A mighty good Christian too.
A lot better Christian than
those psalm singers in church.
But you can't be
if you won't be baptized.
I won't be baptized
and I will be a Christian.
I'll be a Christian
in my own way.
Clare, don't you want
to meet us all in heaven?
'Of course, and I'm going to.'
'But you can't go to heaven'
'if you're not baptized.'
'Oh, that's a lot of folderol.'
Clarence Day,
don't you blaspheme like that.
You're coming to church with me
before you go to the office
in the morning
and be baptized then and there.
Vinnie, don't be ridiculous.
If you think I'm going
to stand there and let Dr. Lloyd
splash water on me at my age,
you're mistaken.
Now I'm sleepy.
Goodnight, Vinnie.
Mother, what is folderol?
Get back to sleep.
- Mother?
- Yes, Whitney.
If father hasn't been baptized
he hasn't any name.
In the sight of the church,
That's right.
Maybe we're not even married.
We, Thine unworthy servants
do give Thee
most humble and hearty thanks
for all Thy goodness
and loving kindness
to us and to all men.
We bless Thee
for our creation, preservation
and all the blessings
of this life.
'But above all,
for Thine inestimable love'
'in the redemption of the world
by our Lord Jesus Christ'
'for the means of grace,
for the hope of glory.'
'And we beseech Thee'
'give us that due sense
of all Thy mercies'
'that our hearts
may be unfeignedly..'
Harlan, tell Clarence to kneel.
Whitney, tell Clarence to kneel.
John, tell Clarence to kneel.
Mother says kneel.
He says he can't.
'...world without end.'
'Amen.'
Amen.
The grace
of our Lord Jesus Christ
and the love of God
and the Fellowship
of the Holy Ghost
be with us all evermore.
- 'Amen.'
- Amen.
And so, my friends
what comfort and security
it gives us
when we have reached
the age of understanding
'to know
that the rite of baptism'
has not been neglected
in our infancy or youth.
Can you imagine any man
who has reached maturity
with the knowledge
that he had never been baptized
failing to hasten
to the holy font
that his soul might be saved?
'As it says
in the baptismal office'
'"Except a man be born of water
and of the spirit'
'he cannot enter
into the kingdom of God."'
'"He that believeth'
"and is baptized
shall be saved
but he that believeth not
shall be damned."
What's that fellow up to?
He can't be..
'Which also showeth us
the great benefit we reap..'
Tell father shh.
Mother says shh.
'"For the promise is to you'
'"and to your children.'
'"Doubt ye not therefore'
but earnestly believe."
In the name of the father
and of the Son
and of the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Amen.
This is
William Tyler Wickersham.
And this is
Wilhelmina Eugenia Wickersham.
'What a lovely day
for them to be baptized.'
'The happiest day in my life.'
- Lovely sermon.
- Thank you, Mrs. Day.
Clare, you know I didn't ask
Dr. Lloyd to do that.
You must have said something.
Well, I had to find out from him
if we were really married.
I am married
and I'm not baptized.
And as far as I'm concerned
the whole congregation
can know it.
- They certainly know it now.
- That suits me.
I don't go to church
to be preached at
as though I were
some lost sheep.
Clare, you don't seem
to understand
what the church is for.
Vinnie, if there's one place
the church should leave alone
it's a man's soul.
Well, he's going to be baptized,
Cora, you mark my word.
I just couldn't go to heaven
without Clare.
Why, I get lonesome for him
even when I go to Ohio.
It's awfully hard on a woman to
love a man like Clare so much.
Oh, men are so aggravating.
They take everything
for granted.
They certainly do.
You know, I don't believe
Clare's come right out
and told me he loves me
since we've been married.
Of course, I know he does
because I keep reminding him
of it.
You have to keep
reminding them, Cora.
'Vinnie, the table isn't set
for dinner yet.'
I'll be back in a minute, Cora.
We're having it after Cora
and Mary go to the train.
Their cab is coming
at 1 o'clock.
'Cab? The horse cars
go right past the door.'
But, Clare,
they have those heavy bags.
Cabs are a waste of money.
Well, if dinner's going
to be delayed
I'll work on this month's bills.
Where are they?
Now, Clare, it isn't fair to go
over the household accounts
when you're hungry.
Vinnie, where are those bills?
They're in the library
on your desk.
Hmm.
I didn't know
dinner was going to be late.
No one ever tells me
anything in this house.
Back home I ride all the time.
I love horses.
The horse is my favorite animal.
Well, goodness,
where have you two been?
Clarence wanted to show me
his grandfather's house.
You will have to hurry
and finish your packing.
- It won't take me long.
- Can I help you pack?
Clarence.
Clarence..
...why didn't you kneel
in church today?
I, I just couldn't.
If it's because
your father doesn't kneel
you must remember he wasn't
brought up to kneel in church.
But you were.
Has it anything to do with Mary?
- I know she's a Methodist.
- Oh, no, mother.
Methodists kneel.
Mary told me.
They don't get up and down
so much
but they stay down longer.
Clarence, you want to kneel,
don't you?
Oh, yes.
I wanted to kneel today.
I-I tried. You saw me try.
But...I just couldn't.
Well, is that suit of your
father's too tight for you?
- No, it's not too tight.
- Well, what is it?
Mother, very peculiar things
have happened to me
since I started to wear
this suit.
I can't seem
to make these clothes
do anything father wouldn't do.
Oh, that's nonsense, Clarence.
And not to kneel in church
is a sacrilege.
Making father's trousers kneel
seemed more of a sacrilege.
Clarence.
Do you know what happened
at Dura Wakefield's party
for Mary last night?
We were playing musical chairs
and some girl sat down
suddenly right in my lap.
Well, I jumped up so fast,
she almost got hurt.
She was sitting
on father's trousers.
Well, mother, I've got
to have a suit of my own.
My soul and body.
Well, you'll just have to talk
to your father about it.
I'm sure if you approach him
the right way
you know, tactfully, he'll see.
Oh, excuse me.
Gracious.
It didn't take you very long.
Well, I'll see about
your box lunch for the train.
Remember, it's Sunday.
I, I was hoping we could have
a few minutes together
before you left.
Cora had so much to do.
I wanted to get out of her way.
Well, didn't you wanna see me?
I did want to tell you how much
I've enjoyed our...friendship.
Oh, hello.
Mother told us to sit
in the living room
till dinner's ready.
- Not on the best sofa.
- Hello.
Hello.
Have you ever been out
on our porch?
- Oh, yes.
- Well, let me show it to you.
It's awfully hard to grow up
in a family with children.
My, I've never known a week
to pass so quickly.
- Why, I..
- Yes?
You're going to write me
when you get to Springfield,
aren't you?
Of course,
if you write me first.
But you'll have something
to write about.
Your trip, and Aunt Judith
and how things are
in Springfield.
You write me
as soon as you get there.
Maybe I'll be too busy.
Maybe I won't have time.
Well, you find the time.
Let's not have any nonsense
about that.
You'll write me first,
and you'll do it right away
the first day.
How do you know
I'll take orders from you?
Well, I'll show you.
- Give me your hand.
- Why should I?
Give me your hand, confound it!
What do you want with my hand?
I just wanted it.
What are you thinking about?
I was just thinking.
About what?
I was hoping
you'd write me first
because that would mean
you liked me.
What's my writing first
got to do with liking you?
Oh, you do like me then?
Of course, I do.
I like you better
than any girl I ever met.
But you don't like me
well enough to write first?
Well, I don't see
how one thing's
got anything to do
with the other.
But a girl can't write first
because..
...because she's a girl.
Well, that's nonsense. If a girl
has something to write about
and a fellow hasn't,
there's no reason
why she shouldn't write first.
You know,
the first three days I was here
you'd do anything for me.
And then you changed.
You used to be a lot of fun.
Then all of a sudden, you turned
into an old sobersides.
Why, why, you even dress
like an old sobersides.
What's the matter?
I just happened
to remember something.
What?
Oh, I know.
It's because
this is the last time
we'll be together.
Mary, please.
But, Clarence,
we'll see each other
in a month when I come back.
Oh, Clarence,
please write me first
because that will show me
how much you like me.
Please?
I'll show you
how much I like you.
- Get up. Get up!
- Ah.
Oh. Oh!
Oh, Mary, don't do that.
Please, don't do that!
Now you'll think
I'm just a bold
and forward girl.
Oh, no. No, it's not that.
Was it because it's Sunday?
No, it'd be the same any day.
Oh! You just didn't want me
sitting on your lap.
Oh, it was nice of you to do it.
It was nice of me
so you told me to get up?
You just couldn't bear
to have me sit there.
Oh, and you needn't write me
first.
You needn't write me
any letters at all.
Because I'll tear them up
without opening them.
I never want to see you again.
Oh, Mary. Mary, listen to me,
Mary, please.
Oh, Mary.
Clarence.
Yes, father?
That young lady's crying.
She's in tears.
What's the meaning of this?
I'm sorry, father.
It's all my fault.
Nonsense. What's that girl
trying to do to you?
Oh, n-no, no, she wasn't.
It was.. I, I..
Well, whatever the quarrel
was about, Clarence
I'm glad you held your own.
Father, I have to have
a new suit of clothes!
You've got to give me
the money for it!
Young man, do you realize that
you're addressing your father?
I'm sorry, father.
I apologize.
But you don't know
how important this is to me.
A new suit of clothes
is so impor..
Oh, why should..
Clarence, has your need
for a new suit of clothes
anything to do
with that young lady?
Yes, father.
Why, Clarence.
Oh.
Why, this comes
as quite a shock to me.
What does, father?
Well,
you're being so...grownup.
Still, I might have known.
If you are going to college
this fall..
Yes, you're at the age
when you'll be meeting girls.
Clarence, there are things
about women
that I think you ought to know.
Sit down.
Yes, I think it's better for you
to hear this from me
than to have to learn it
for yourself.
Clarence..
...women aren't the angels
that you think they are.
Well, now first,
let me explain this to you.
You see, Clarence,
we men have to run this world
and it's not an easy job.
It takes work
and it takes thinking.
A man has to reason things out.
Now you take a woman.
A woman thinks..
No, I'm wrong right there.
A woman doesn't think at all.
She gets stirred up.
And she gets stirred up
over the most confounded things.
Now I love my wife
just as much as any man
but that doesn't mean
that I should stand
for a lot of folderol.
By God, I won't stand for it!
Stand for what, father?
That's the one thing
I shall not submit myself to.
Clarence, if a man thinks
a certain thing is wrong
he shouldn't do it.
If he thinks it's right,
he should do it.
Now that has nothing to do with
whether he loves his wife
or not.
- Who says it has, father?
- They do.
- Who, sir?
- Women.
They get stirred up
and then they try
to get you stirred up too.
But don't you let them do it,
Clarence.
Don't you let them do it.
Now, if you can keep reason
and logic in the argument
well, a man can hold his own,
of course.
But if they can switch you
pretty soon the argument's about
whether you love them or not.
I swear,
I don't know how they do it.
But don't you let them,
Clarence.
Don't you let them.
I see what you mean so far,
father.
If you don't watch yourself,
love can make you do
a lot of things
you don't wanna do.
'Exactly.'
But if you do watch out
and know
just how to handle women..
Then you'll be alright.
All a man has to do is be firm.
You know how sometimes I have
to be firm with your mother.
Yes, but, father,
what can you do when they cry?
Hmm.
Well, uh,
that's quite a question.
You just have to
make them understand
that what you're doing
is for their good.
I see.
Now, Clarence,
you know all about women.
- But, father.
- Yes, Clarence?
I thought you were going
to tell me about..
- About what?
- About women.
Clarence, there are some things
gentlemen don't discuss.
I've told you
all you need to know.
The thing for you to remember
is be firm.
Mary,
when you get to Springfield
the very first thing you..
Oh, God!
What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
Sit down, Vinnie.
Oh, Clare, Cora and Mary
are leaving any moment now.
Sit down.
Vinnie,
you know I like to live well
and I want my family
to live well.
But this house must be run
on a business basis.
I must know how much money
I'm spending and what for.
For instance,
if you recall, a week ago
I gave you $6
to buy a new coffee pot.
Yes,
because you broke the old one.
You threw it right on the floor.
I'm not talking about that.
Now I find here among my--
It was a pity to break
that nice coffee pot, Clare.
It was imported from France.
And that little shop
has stopped selling them.
They said the tariff
wouldn't let them.
And that's your fault
because you're always voting
to raise the tariff.
The tariff protects America
against cheap foreign labor.
Now this bill--
The tariff does nothing
but put up the prices
and that's hard on everybody
especially the farmer.
Vinnie, I wish to heaven
you wouldn't talk about matters
you don't know anything about.
I do, too, know about them.
Miss Guelig says
that every intelligent woman
should have some opinion--
Who may I ask is Miss Guelig?
She's the current events woman
I told you about.
And the tickets are a dollar
every Tuesday.
Do you mean to tell me that
a pack of idle-minded females
pay a dollar apiece
to hear another female
gabble about
the events of the day?
Listen to me
if you want to know anything
about the events of the day.
But you get so excited, Clare.
And besides, Miss Guelig says
that our President
whom you're always belittling,
prays to God for guidance.
Vinnie,
what happened to that $6?
What $6?
I gave you $6
to buy a new coffee pot.
Now I find that
you apparently got one
at Lewis & Congers
and charged it.
Here's their bill.
"One coffee pot, $5."
So you owe me a dollar,
and you can hand it right over.
I'll do nothing of the kind.
What did you do with that $6?
Well, Clare,
I can't tell you now, dear.
Why didn't you ask me
at the time?
I give up.
Oh, wait a minute.
I spent $4.50
for that new umbrella.
Now we're getting somewhere.
One umbrella, $4.50.
And that must have been the week
I paid Mrs. Tobin
for two extra days' washing.
- Mrs. Tobin.
- That's $2 more.
- Two dollars.
- That makes, that makes up..
$6.50.
And that's another 50 cents
you owe me.
I don't owe you anything.
What you owe me
is an explanation
of where my money is gone.
I do the best I can
to keep down expenses.
You know yourself, Cousin Phoebe
spends twice as much as we do.
Don't talk to me
about your cousin Phoebe.
Oh, you talk about
your own relatives enough.
That's not fair, Vinnie.
When I talk about my relatives,
I criticize them.
I can't even speak
of Cousin Phoebe.
'You can speak of her
all you want to.'
'But I won't have Cousin Phoebe
or anyone else'
'dictating to me
how to run my house.'
I didn't say a word
about her dictating.
'Clare,
you know she isn't that--'
You said, you said..
I don't know what you said now.
You never stick to the point.
Now, we're going over this
account book item by item.
I find here a bill for $38.
I don't know
what you expect of me.
I tire myself out
chasing up and down
those stairs all day long
trying to look after
your comfort
to bring up our children.
I do the mending
and the marketing.
Now you want me to be
an expert bookkeeper too.
Vinnie,
I want to be reasonable, but..
Can't you understand? I'm doing
all this for your own good.
Oh.
Well, I suppose I'll have to
go ahead just paying the bills
and hoping I've got enough money
in the bank to meet them.
But it's all very discouraging.
I'll try to do better, Clare.
Well, that's all I'm asking.
Well, I'll, uh, make out
the checks and sign them.
But, uh, ahem, maybe I haven't
any right to sign those checks
since in the sight of the Lord,
I haven't any name.
That's right.
Clare, to make those checks good
you'll have to be baptized
right away.
Vinnie, the bank doesn't care
whether I've been baptized
or not.
Well, I care.
And no matter
what Dr. Lloyd said
I'm not sure
we're really married.
Vinnie, we have four children.
If we're not married now,
we never will be.
Clare, Dr. Lloyd said
this morning--
Well, that's all, Vinnie.
Uh, I think you better go tell
Whitney to watch for the cab.
Not before you give me
that $1.50.
- What $1.50?
- That $1.50 you owe me.
I don't owe you any $1.50.
I gave you money
to buy a coffee pot for me
and somehow it turned
into an umbrella for you.
Why, Clarence Day,
what kind of man are you?
Quibbling about $1.50
when your immortal soul
is in danger.
- And what's more, if you--
- Alright.
Alright, alright.
Hmm.
Thank you, Clare.
Now the accounts
are all straight again.
What were you doing down there?
I'm setting up
this new burglar alarm.
I invented it myself.
Have you got any money
you can lend me?
No, you owe me 30 cents now.
Well, I'll give you
my stamp collection
and my piece
of John Wilkes Booth's finger.
How much?
Enough to get
a new suit of clothes.
If you can wait a month till
I hear from the patent office
in Washington, I may be rich.
- Oh, I can't wait that long.
- Maybe I could get it sooner.
I'm going to look
into something else tomorrow.
"Wanted. An energetic young man
to sell household necessity.
Liberal commission.
Apply 312.."
John, let me have this job.
Why should I give you my job?
They're hard to get.
But I've got to get
a new suit of clothes.
Maybe I could get the job
for both of us.
I'll ask the man.
- The cab's here, father.
- Oh, t-thank you, Whitney.
Uh, Vinnie, Cora,
the cab's here!
Uh, John, uh,
go up and get their bags.
Yes, sir.
Here's the lunch
for the train, sir.
Well, take it out to the cab.
- Who's that one?
- It's Ellen.
Delia left yesterday.
I don't know
where your mother finds them.
Now, Vinnie, don't you let
Clare worry about us.
We have plenty of time.
Oh, take the bags right on out,
John.
- Yes, sir.
- Well, goodbye, Clarence.
It was so nice to see you again.
Goodbye, Cousin Cora.
Goodbye, Whitney.
Now you be a good boy.
- Goodbye, Cousin Cora.
- Goodbye, Harlan.
Goodbye.
Keep out of mischief.
Come along, everybody.
Don't keep the cab waiting.
Cabs cost money.
If there's one thing
Mr. Day can't stand
it's to keep a cab waiting.
If there's any waiting to do,
there's a waiting room
at the Grand Central Depot
just for that.
Mary..
...aren't you even going
to shake hands with me?
I don't think I'd better.
You may remember that
when I get too close to you
you feel contaminated.
Mary, you're going to write
to me, aren't you?
- Are you going to write first?
- No, Mary.
There are times
when a man must be firm.
Mary, mother says
you better hurry out
before father starts yelling.
It's Sunday.
Goodbye, John.
I'm very happy
to have made your acquaintance.
Thank you.
- May I help you?
- No, thank you.
Take care of yourself.
- Goodbye, Mr. Day.
- Goodbye, Mary.
Bye, Mrs. Day.
I've had a wonderful time.
- Goodbye, Mary.
- Thank you.
- 'Bye-bye.'
- 'Goodbye.'
- 'Goodbye, Cousin Clare.'
- Goodbye, Cora.
- 'Bye.'
- Bye, Cousin Cora.
- Bye.
- Bye!
Dear Mary..
"My duty toward my neighbor
"is to love him as myself
"and to do to all men
as I would
they should do unto me."
Has father
gone to the office yet?
Come on,
let's go to the ball field.
I've got to guard this box
till John comes back.
It's his burglar alarm.
It wouldn't work so he fixed it.
We're going to put it back
in the dining room
after father goes to the office.
Are there burglars around?
- Everywhere.
- Oh.
"To love, honor, and succor
my father
and my mother--"
Why do you have to learn that?
Because if I don't,
I'll go to hell.
- Father's going to hell.
- He is not!
Yes, he is,
because he isn't baptized.
He'll go to hell and burn
for a thousand years.
He won't! He won't!
He'll be in a lake
of fire and brimstone
and a thousand devils
with pitchforks
will be poking at him.
- No! Mother, don't let--
- Shh.
- Father will hear you!
- No, I don't..
'Don't smother me!'
What's that noise?
- Just singing, father.
- 'You boys, be quiet.'
You know your mother
isn't feeling well.
'Yes, father.'
What did your mother say?
She says she doesn't want
any breakfast.
Oh, why does your mother
do that to me?
She knows it just upsets my day
when she doesn't come down
to breakfast.
- A special delivery, sir.
- Thank you.
- Where's John this morning?
Well, John had his breakfast
early, father
and went out
to see about something.
See about what?
Well, John and I thought
we'd work this summer
and earn some money.
Good. Work never hurt anyone.
It's good for them.
But if you're going to work,
work hard.
King Solomon had the right idea
about work.
"Whatever thy hand
findeth to do," Solomon said
"do thy doggonedest."
Hmm.
Well, I don't understand this
at all.
Here's a letter from some woman
I never even heard of.
- Oh, father.
- Oh, God!
What is it, father?
This woman claims
that she sat on my lap
and that I didn't like it.
Huh.
What's that word?
No, that one down there.
It looks like curiosity.
Oh.
"I only opened your letter
as a matter of curiosity."
- Hmph.
- Yes, go on.
Why, this gets worse and worse.
It just turns into a lot
of sentimental lovey-dovey mush.
Chaa! Huh.
If this is someone's idea
of a practical joke..
What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
Nothing wrong.
Just a fool letter.
- How are you feeling, Vinnie?
- I thought you needed me.
If you don't,
I'll go back to bed.
On, no, no, no.
Uh, come sit down
and, uh, get some food in you.
Do you good.
Build up your strength.
Yeah, here. Sit down. Sit down.
Here, uh..
- What's this one's name?
- Nora.
Nora, uh, get Mrs. Day
some bacon and eggs.
'No, Nora.'
'Bring me a cup of tea
up to my room.'
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, Vinnie, it's just weak
to give in to an ailment.
I notice
when you have a headache
you yell and groan
and swear enough.
Well, that's to prove
to the headache
that I am stronger than it is.
I think I've caught
some kind of germ.
Some of my friends have had
to send for the doctor.
A doctor? Oh, poppycock.
But, Clare dear,
when people are ill
you have to do something.
Certainly,
Cheer them up.
That's the way to cure them.
How would you go about
cheering them up?
I? Why, I'd tell them bah!
Well, what have I done now?
Oh.
Oh, Clare, hush up.
Vinnie,
I didn't mean to upset you.
"Dear Clarence.."
I, I-I was just
trying to help you.
You know,
w-when you take your bed
I have a confounded
lonely time around here.
So when I see you
getting it into your head
that you're not feeling well
I want to do something about it.
Just because some of your
friends have given into this
there's no reason why
you should imagine you're ill.
Oh, Clare, stop.
Get out of this house
and go to your office.
- Did you get the job?
- Yes, for both of us.
- Look, I've got it with me.
- What is it?
- Medicine.
- Medicine?
You took a job for us
to go out and sell medicine?
But it's wonderful medicine.
Look what it cures.
"A sovereign cure
for colds, coughs, catarrh
"asthma, quinsy,
and sore throat
"poor digestion,
summer complaint, colic
"dyspepsia, heartburn,
and shortness of breath
"lumbago, rheumatism,
heart disease
"giddiness,
and women's complaints
"nervous prostration,
St. Vitus' dance
"jaundice, la grippe,
proud flesh
pink eye, sea sickness,
and pimples."
It's made from a secret formula
known only to Dr. Bartlett.
We get 25 cents commission
on every bottle we sell.
And he's giving us the territory
of all Manhattan Island.
Well, lots of father's
and mother's friends
have some of those diseases.
Let's start out
by calling on them.
Yes. Oh.
What if they ask us
if we use it at our house?
Oh, yes, it would be better
if we could say we did.
Excuse me.
Oh, i-is that the tea
for Mrs. Day?
- Yes.
- Oh, I'll take it up to her.
Oh, thank you.
Right away now while it's hot.
What's the matter with mother?
I don't know.
She was just complaining.
Say, it says here it's good
for women's complaints.
Here.
'Yes, sir, Chesapeake and Ohio,
an eighth.'
'New York Central,
three quarters.'
'I'd like to see Mr. Day about'
'those Morris & Essex bonds.'
Mr. Day's very busy
this morning.
You'll have to wait.
- Where's father?
- Well, Master Whitney.
Have you come
to pay us a visit?
Where's father?
He's busy in his office
with a customer.
Master Whitney!
Mr. Day,
the president of the firm is--
Father, you have to come home
right away.
What's the meaning of this?
Who sent you down here?
- Your mother?
- No, sir. Mother's ill.
She's terribly ill.
Did the doctor send you for me?
- No, sir. It was Margaret.
- Margaret?
Margaret says
you're to come home right away
and no nonsense.
Uh, Perkins, go down and stop
the first cab you see.
A cab, sir? For you, Mr. Day?
Yes, I want a cab,
and no nonsense!
- Yes, sir.
- Uh, I'm sorry, Mr. Hopkins.
Confound you!
Can't you go any faster?
Alright, sir.
Giddap!
Giddap there, you hear me!
- Oh, doctor. How is Mrs. Day?
- She's a pretty sick woman.
Well, what's wrong with her?
Well, do you know or don't you?
What did Mrs. Day have
for breakfast this morning?
Not a thing.
I tried to get her
to eat something,
but she wouldn't.
I can't understand it.
Understand what?
These violent attacks of nausea.
It's almost as though
she were poisoned.
- Poisoned?
- Let me take your cab.
I'll try not to be gone more
than ten to fifteen minutes.
And, Mr. Day,
you are not to go into her room.
You'd better get her well.
Right away
or you'll hear from me.
- Turn west on 27th Street.
- Giddap. Giddap.
- How is mother?
- I don't know.
Well, she better be
good and sick
or father may be mad at me
for getting him up here.
Specially in a cab.
- Has your father come?
- Yes, just now.
Where are you going, Margaret?
I have to go for the minister.
I guess the minister's
coming to baptize father
so he won't have to go to hell.
You can't be baptized
in a house.
- You've got to have water.
- We have lots of water.
Not the right kind.
Is mother better, father?
How can I tell? She wouldn't
let me in the room with her.
These confounded doctors
never know
what's the matter with anybody.
Father?
Yes?
Mother's going to get well,
isn't she?
Of course,
she's going to get well.
Father, may we come in?
It's lonesome without mother.
Yes, it is, Harlan.
It's lonesome.
Come in, boys.
What have you been doing,
Harlan?
Nothing.
They won't let me upstairs.
What about you, Whitney?
I was supposed to learn
the rest of my catechism.
Will you hear me, father?
Yes, Whitney, I'll hear you.
Start here.
"How many parts are there
in a sacrament?"
Two, the outward visible sign
and the inward spiritual grace.
"What is the outward
visible sign or form
in bap, baptism?"
Water, wherein the person
is baptized in the name of..
You haven't been baptized,
have you, father?
Whitney, what is the outward
visible sign?
Water, wherein the person..
'...wherein the person..'
You don't know it well enough,
Whitney.
You'd better go and study it
some more.
Do you want me to read to you,
Harlan?
Father, are they gonna
put you into hell?
Whitney, take Harlan with you.
Oh, what's the world coming to?
Everybody's sending for doctors.
Doctors don't do you any good.
Only make you feel worse.
All poppycock.
Who's ringing that bell?
Stop that noise!
Stop it, I say!
What idiot's ringing that bell?
Mr. Day, we must all be quiet.
- Mrs. Day's very ill.
- I know she's ill.
Go up and see
if she needs anything.
And what are you doing
out of the house?
I sent for the minister.
- The minister?
- He'll be right in.
He's paying off the cab.
I was deeply shocked to learn
the serious nature
of Mrs. Day's illness.
Will you take me up to her?
She's resting now.
She can't be disturbed.
The doctor will be back
in a minute.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Mrs. Day has been
a tower of strength
in the parish.
Everyone liked her so much.
Yes, she was a fine woman.
I wish to heaven
you wouldn't talk about Mrs. Day
as if she were dead.
- Is the doctor back yet?
- No, does she need him?
Well, she's kind of restless.
She's talking in her sleep
and twisting and turning.
Well, doctor, it seems to me
that was a pretty long
ten minutes.
See here, Mr. Day.
if I'm to handle this case--
How can you handle it
if you're out of the house?
Who is this?
- It's Dr. Somers.
- How do you do?
I felt that Mrs. Day's condition
warranted my getting
Dr. Somers here
as soon as possible
for consultation.
I hope that meets
with your approval?
Why, yes, of course.
- Anything that can be done.
- Upstairs, doctor.
Pardon me.
Mrs. Day is in good hands now,
Mr. Day.
There's nothing you and I
can do at the moment to help.
- Dr. Lloyd?
- Yes?
There's something that's
troubling Mrs. Day's mind.
Oh?
I think you know
what I refer to.
Yes. You mean the fact that
you've never been baptized.
Yes, I gathered
that you knew about it
from your sermon last Sunday.
But let's not get angry.
I think something
had better be done about it.
Yes, Mr. Day?
When the doctors get through
up there
I want you to talk to Mrs. Day.
I want you to tell her
something.
Well, I'd be glad to.
You're just the man to do it.
She shouldn't be upset
about this.
I want you to tell her
that my being baptized
would just be a lot
of confounded nonsense.
But, Mr. Day--
Oh, she'll take your word
on a thing like that.
And we both must do everything
we can to help her now.
But the solution is so simple.
It would take only your consent
to be baptized.
That's out of the question.
And I'm surprised
that a grown man like you
would suggest such a thing.
Well, doctor, how is she?
What have you decided?
Is there a room we could use
for our consultation?
- Oh, yes, my library.
- Doctor.
Dr. Somers,
this isn't serious, is it?
Uh, after we've had
our consultation
we'll talk to you, Mr. Day.
But surely--
Rest assured, Dr. Somers will do
everything
that is humanly possible.
Uh, we'll try not to be long.
Tell me, this Dr., uh, Somers
he's very highly thought of,
isn't he?
Oh, yes.
If Vinnie is seriously..
If anyone could help her,
he could.
- Don't you think?
- Very fine physician.
But there is a greater help
ever-present
in the hour of need.
Let us turn to him in prayer.
Let us kneel and pray.
Oh, Lord,
look down from heaven.
Behold, visit, and relieve
this Thy servant
who is grieved with sickness.
Have mercy on her, oh, Lord.
Have mercy
on this miserable sinner.
Forgive her
and extend Thy accustomed--
She's not a miserable sinner,
and you know it!
Oh, God! You know Vinnie
is not a miserable sinner!
She's a fine woman!
'She shouldn't be
made to suffer!'
It's got to stop, I tell you!
It's got to stop!
Have mercy, I say!
Have mercy, I tell you!
What's the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
Vinnie. Vinnie, what are you
doing down here?
You shouldn't be out of bed.
You get right back upstairs.
I heard you call.
Do you need me?
Vinnie, I know now
how much I need you.
Get well, Vinnie.
I'll be baptized.
- I promise I'll be baptized.
- You will?
- I'll do anything.
- Oh, Clare.
We'll go to Europe,
just we two.
You won't have to worry
about the children
or the household accounts or..
Vinnie.
Don't worry, Mr. Day.
She'll be alright now.
Bless you
for what you have done.
- What did I do?
- You promised to be baptized.
I did? Oh, God!
- Isn't it drafty here, mother?
- Shall I get your coat, mother?
- The draft--
- No, thank you.
I'm quite comfortable,
thank you.
Come on now.
Let's stay together.
Harlan,
don't you get lost again.
Aren't the hats lovely
this year?
Ostrich feathers.
You wouldn't wear that hat,
would you, mother?
Oh, I think that's very pretty.
I think they're all pretty.
Oh, I do need
some pink silk thread.
Oh, isn't this applique
beautiful?
Just arrived from Paris, madam.
It's charming.
What are you looking for,
mother?
Oh, I'm just shopping.
I think
I'll just take a plain one.
But this is the very latest.
We've only had them in
a few days.
Remember, mother,
this is your first day out.
You mustn't get too tired.
No, I'm saving myself, dear.
I have to.
Cousin Cora's coming tomorrow.
She is?
Does father know about it?
- Not yet.
- Is Mary coming too?
Yes, dear.
Harlan, don't touch things.
- I'll bet you knew it.
- No, honest, I didn't.
- Not tomorrow.
- Yes, it is.
'Do we have any more
of this material?'
- 'Yes, we do.'
- 'Thank you.'
'This one
is genuine imitation Dresden.'
'The original design by Duriet.'
John, isn't this
the darlingest thing?
It's exactly
what I've always wanted.
How much is this lovely pug dog?
Uh, $15, ma'am.
- Fifteen dollars.
- Gee whiz, mother.
We can buy
a real live bloodhound for $5.
Oh, isn't he perfectly adorable?
Oh, I shouldn't.
- I know I shouldn't.
- 'Mrs. Day.'
Oh, Mrs. Whitehead.
How nice to see you.
Are you quite recovered?
Almost.
This is my first day out.
We've missed you at the church.
You remember Mr. Morley.
- How do you do, Mrs. Day?
- How do you do?
Mr. Morley preached the Sunday
Dr. Lloyd was ill.
Oh, yes.
I can't tell you
how much I enjoyed your sermon.
Even my husband
enjoyed your sermon.
We've just come from the board
meeting of the foreign missions.
I'm taking Mr. Morley home
to lunch.
I had to drop in here
to pick up a purchase.
I won't be a minute.
- Is your parish in the city?
- Yes, it's on the outskirts.
My church is in Audubon Park.
Oh, way up there.
Oh, are you acquainted
in Audubon Park?
No, I don't believe
we know a soul there.
Mr. Morley,
would this be possible?
Uh, my husband, Mr. Day..
If we lower the collar,
it will be a very fine fit.
You wouldn't find a better suit
of clothes in the city for $15.
Oh, it's not the price.
It's the money.
Thank you for holding it for me.
You're welcome.
Goodbye, Mrs. Day.
I hope we meet again soon.
Goodbye. It was very pleasant
meeting you again.
I think
it was divine providence.
I shall be delighted
to be of service.
- Goodbye, Mr. Morley. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- May I work it?
- Oh, no.
It's against the rules.
Hello.
Oh, what did you bring home
more medicine for?
Dr. Bartlett paid us off,
didn't he?
- Oh, yes.
- Oh, Jiminy, you scared me.
I've got to take $15
right down to McCreery's.
I bought a suit there
this morning and I said
I'd have the money
this afternoon.
- Gee, that's too bad.
- What's too bad?
- Well, well, you see, Clarence.
- What?
Dr. Bartlett
paid us off in medicine.
Oh, God!
Well, he thanked us, too
for our services to mankind.
But my suit,
I've got to have it tomorrow.
And besides,
they're making the alterations.
I've gotta have $15.
Maybe you could offer them
15 bottles of medicine.
Oh, they wouldn't take it.
McCreery's don't sell medicine.
Father!
Vinnie, I'm home!
- Good afternoon, sir.
- How's your mother, Clarence?
Oh, the ride this morning
did her a lot of good.
She'll be well enough to go
to church with us next Sunday.
Ah, fine.
Uh, father, have you noticed
I haven't been kneeling down
in church lately?
Don't let your mother
catch you at it.
Then I have to have a new suit
of clothes right away.
That doesn't make sense.
I can't do anything
in your clothes
that you wouldn't do.
Well, if my old clothes make you
behave yourself, I don't think
you ought to wear anything else.
Oh, no, you're you and I'm me.
I wanna be myself.
I mean, suppose I should wanna
kneel down in front of a girl.
Why in heaven's name should you
want to do a thing like that?
Well, I've got to propose
to a girl sometime.
- Clarence.
- Oh, not right away.
But for $15, I can get
a good suit of clothes.
Clarence, you're beginning
to talk as crazy as your..
Hello, Vinnie. You're feeling
better today, huh?
Much better.
Thank you, Clare.
You don't have to hurry home
from the office
every day like this.
Uh, with business
the way it is, there's no use
going to the office at all.
Yes, you do look better, Vinnie.
What did you do today?
Well, I got a carriage
and took the boys for a ride.
And we stopped in
at McCreery's, and..
Oh, Clare, I have the most
wonderful news for you.
Who do you think I met?
Mr. Morley.
Morley? Never heard of him?
Remember
that nice young minister
who substituted for Dr. Lloyd
one Sunday.
Oh, yes.
Bright, young fellow.
Preached a good sensible sermon.
Short one too.
Ought to be more ministers
like him.
Well, Clare, his parish
is in Audubon Park.
You know, way up above Harlem.
Nobody knows you up there.
You'll be perfectly safe.
Safe? Vinnie, what the devil
are you talking about?
I've gone all over everything
with Mr. Morley
and he's agreed
to baptize you.
Oh, he has.
The young whippersnapper.
Very nice of him.
We can go up there any morning.
We don't even have to make
an appointment.
Who said I was going
to be baptized at all?
Why, Clare, you did.
Now, Vinnie.
You gave me your promise,
your sacred promise.
You said, "I'll be baptized.
I promise I'll be baptized."
Well, what if I did?
Clare, aren't you a man
of your word?
Vinnie, we all thought
you were dying.
So naturally,
I said that to cheer you up.
As a matter of fact, the doctor
told me that's what cured you.
So it seems to me
pretty ungrateful of you
to press this matter
any further.
My being well
has nothing to do with it.
You gave me your word.
You gave the Lord your word.
And you're going to march
yourself up to Mr. Morley's
church some morning
before you go to the office
and be christened.
If you think for one minute--
What in the name of heaven
is that?
If you think I'm going
to let you add the sin
of breaking your solemn
and sacred promise--
I demand to know
what that repulsive object is?
It's perfectly plain what it is.
It's a pug dog.
What is it doing in this house?
I wanted it and I bought it.
You spent good money for that?
Clare, don't try
to change the subject.
How much did you pay
for that atrocity?
I didn't pay anything for it.
I charged it.
Charged it?
I might have known.
- How much was it?
- Fifteen dollars.
- $15 for that eyesore?
- Uh, Clare..
Don't you call this lovely
work of art an eyesore.
It will look beautiful
sitting on a red cushion
by the fireplace
in the living room.
If that sits in the living room,
I won't.
Furthermore, I don't even want
it in the same house with me.
Get it out of here!
Clare..
...you're not going
to get out of this room
until you set a date
for your baptism.
I'll tell you one thing.
I'll never be baptized
as long as that hideous
monstrosity is in this house.
Alright.
Alright!
Clarence.
That pug dog
goes back this afternoon
and he's christened
first thing in the morning.
You heard him,
didn't you, Clarence?
You heard him say
that he'd be baptized
as soon as I got this pug dog
out of the house.
You hurry right back
to McCreery's with it
and be sure
they credit us with $15.
Oh, mother,
while we were at McCreery's
I happened to see a suit
I'd like very much
and the suit was only $15.
Well, Clarence, I'm afraid
your suit will have to wait
until after
I get your father christened.
Well, no, I meant
that since the suit cost
just the same as the pug dog
If I exchanged the pug dog
for the suit..
Why, yes.
Then the suit wouldn't cost
your father anything.
Why, how bright of you,
Clarence, to think of that.
I'd better start right away
before McCreery's closes.
Yes. Now let's see.
If we're going
to take your father
all the way to Audubon Park..
Clarence, on your way back,
you stop at the livery stable
and tell them to have a cab here
at 8 o'clock tomorrow morning.
Mother, a cab?
Do you think you ought to?
We can't walk
all the way to Audubon Park.
But you know what
a cab does to father.
This is
a very important occasion.
- Alright.
- Get one of their best cabs.
The kind they use at funerals.
Those cost $2 an hour.
And if father gets mad--
Well, if your father
starts to argue
in the morning, you remember--
Oh, he agreed to it.
We both heard him.
I hope you notice Clarence
is returning the pug dog.
'Well, that's a sign you're
getting your faculties back.'
Don't dawdle, Clarence.
Vinnie, it's good
to hear you singing again.
Oh, uh, on the way uptown
I stopped in at Tiffany's
and, uh, bought you
a little something.
Thought you might like it.
Clare!
What a beautiful ring.
Well, I'm glad
if it pleases you.
Oh, Clare, how sweet of you.
I don't know how to thank you.
- Mmm.
- Ah.
Well, it's thanks enough for me
just to have you
up and around again.
You know,
when you're ill, Vinnie
this house is like a tomb.
There's no excitement.
That's the loveliest ring
you ever bought me.
Now that I have this,
you needn't buy me
any more rings.
Well,
if you don't want any more.
What I'd really like now
is a nice diamond necklace.
Vinnie, do you know how much
a diamond necklace costs?
Yes, I know, Clare.
But don't you see?
Your giving me this shows
I mean
a little something to you.
- Now a diamond necklace--
- Good heaven.
If you don't know by this time
how I feel about you.
We've been married for 20 years
and I've loved you
every minute of it.
What did you say, Clare?
I said we've been married
for 20 years
and I've loved you
every minute of it.
But if I have to buy out
jewelry stores to prove it..
If I haven't shown it to you
in my words and actions
well, I might as well..
Well, what have I done now?
It's alright, Clare.
I'm just so happy.
Happy?
You said you loved me.
And this beautiful ring
that's something else
I didn't expect.
Oh, Clare, I love surprises.
That's another thing I've never
understood about you, Vinnie.
Now I like to know
what to expect.
- Then I'm prepared to meet it.
- Yes, I know, Clare.
But life would be pretty dull
if we always knew
what was coming.
Well, it's certainly not dull
around here.
In this house, you never know
what's going to hit you
tomorrow.
Well, then, Harlan, the very..
Who are you?
What's your name?
- Margaret, sir.
- Can't be Margaret.
We've got one Margaret
in the house.
At home,
they call me Maggie, sir.
Alright, Maggie.
If her name's Margaret,
that's a good sign.
Maybe she'll stay a while.
Do you know, boys,
your mother used to be
just the same about cooks
as she is about maids?
Never could keep them
for some reason.
Well, one day about, uh,
14 years ago..
Yes, it was right after
you were born, John.
My, you were a homely baby.
Thank you, Margaret.
- Good morning, boys.
- Good morning, mother.
- Good morning, Clare.
- Morning, Vinnie.
Why, you look as though
you were dressed for a wedding.
- Do I, dear?
- 'Yes.'
- Have a good night?
- Yes, thank you, Clare.
Ah, sit down, Vinnie.
Sit down, boys.
Oh, thank you, Clarence.
Well, seems to me everyone's
all dressed up this morning.
What's on the program
for this fine day?
Well, uh, this afternoon
May Lewis' mother
is giving a party for everyone
in May's dancing class.
- Harlan's going to that.
- I don't want to go, mama.
Harlan, don't you
wanna go to a party
and get ice cream and cake?
May Lewis
always tries to kiss me!
Hmm.
When you get a little older,
you won't object
to girls wanting to kiss you.
Will he, Clarence?
This is for you, Mr. Day.
Where shall I put it?
Oh, that's for me, I think.
Take it upstairs, Maggie.
Wait a minute, Maggie.
Bring it here. Let's see it.
See, it's for me, father.
Clarence Day, Jr.
Let me look.
Well, that's from McCreery's.
It is marked charged.
What is it?
Clare, it's alright. It's
nothing for you to worry about.
Well, at least I think I should
know what's being charged to me.
- What is it?
- Clare, stop your fussing.
It's a new suit of clothes
for Clarence
and it isn't costing you
a penny.
It's marked "Charged $15."
It's costing me $15.
And I told Clarence--
'Clare, can't you take my word?
It isn't costing you a penny.'
I'd like to have you explain
why it isn't.
Because Clarence took
the pug dog back
and got the suit instead.
Of course, and they'll charge me
$15 for the suit.
Nonsense, Clare,
we gave them the pug dog
for the suit. Don't you see?
Then they'll charge me $15
for the pug dog.
But, Clare, they can't.
We haven't got the pug dog.
- We sent that back.
- Well..
Hmm?
But..
Well, now, wait a minute,
Vinnie.
The suit..
The..
Well, there's something wrong
with your reasoning.
Well, Clare,
I'm surprised at you.
And you're supposed to be
so good at figures.
Why, it's perfectly clear to me.
Vinnie, they're going to charge
me for one thing or the other.
Don't you let them!
Chaa! Well, McCreery's
aren't giving away suits
and they aren't giving away
pug dogs.
Why, it should be clear
to a child
that if Clarence sent
the pug dog back, they..
Well..
I will not have that
botanical freak in this room.
'John,
have you been going around'
'this town selling medicine?'
- Yes, mother.
- Dog medicine?
No, mother.
Not dog medicine.
This letter
from Mrs. Sprague says
you sold her
a bottle of this medicine
and that her little boy
gave some of it to their dog
and it killed him.
Now she wants $10 from us
for a new dog.
Here, let me see that letter.
Well, he shouldn't have given it
to a dog. It's for humans.
Why, it's Bartlett's
Beneficent Balm
made from a secret formula.
Have you been going around
among our friends and neighbors
selling some patent nostrum?
But it's good medicine, father.
I can prove that by mother.
Vinnie, what do you know
about this?
Well, nothing, Clare.
But I'm sure John--
- No, I mean that day mother--
- That's enough!
You're going to every house
where you sold
a bottle of that concoction
and buy it all back.
But it's a dollar a bottle.
I don't care how much it is.
Here.
I'll give you the money now.
- How many bottles did you sell?
- One hundred and twenty eight.
One hundred and twenty eight?
Clare, I always told you
John would make
a good businessman.
Young man, you'll have to
come down to my office with me.
I'll give you the money
to buy back that medicine.
$128, and $10 more
for Mrs. Sprague's dog.
That's $138.
Thank you, Vinnie.
But it's all coming
out of your allowance!
That means that
you'll not get another penny
until the whole $138 is paid up.
I'll be 21 years old!
Oh, God!
What the matter, Clare?
What's wrong?
Those gypsies are back.
Don't anyone answer the door!
They're moving in on us again,
bag and baggage.
I won't have it, I tell you.
- I won't have it!
- Now, Clare--
Don't let them in!
'Clare, hush up.
They'll hear you.'
'Tell them to get back
in that cab'
'and drive right on to Ohio.'
'As if we could turn
our own relatives away.'
They're extravagant enough
to take cabs
when horse cars run
right by our door.
Clare, now you be quiet
and behave yourself.
John,
come help with the baggage.
Why do they always
have to pounce on us
without any warning?
Shh!
Cora, Mary.
Well, it's so good
to have you back again.
How are you, Vinnie?
We've been so worried about you.
Oh, I'm fine now.
Did you have fun in Springfield?
- Oh, it was wonderful.
- Was it?
John, my, you're still growing.
- Thank you, Cousin Cora.
- John, go get their baggage.
- There's Whitney.
- Whitney.
- How are you, darling?
- Fine, thank you.
- And little Harlan.
- Hello.
- Have you been a good boy?
- No.
Clare, the girls are here.
Cousin Clare, here we are again.
My, my, it's so nice to be back.
- How do you do, Mr. Day?
- How do you do?
Come in, sit down
and have some breakfast with us.
Oh, we had breakfast
at the depot.
Well, we've practically
finished ours.
I haven't finished my breakfast.
Well, then sit down, Clare.
Come have a cup of coffee,
anyway.
Mary, sit over there. Cora.
- Maggie, clear those places.
- My, my, this seems so natural.
Clare, don't let your kippers
get cold.
- Maggie, serve some coffee.
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, where's Clarence?
Uh, he must be upstairs
moving his things
so you can have his room again.
Oh, oh, Vinnie,
we can't stay overnight.
Grandpa Evans
has been failing very fast
and that's why
I have to hurry back.
We're leaving on the 5 o'clock
train this afternoon.
Well, Cora, it certainly
is good to see you again.
Well, who can that be?
Well, this time
it can't be another
special delivery letter
for Clarence.
Uh, while you were
in Springfield
our postman
was kept pretty busy.
- It's the cab, ma'am.
- Cab? What cab?
The cab that's to take us
to Audubon Park.
Oh, who's going to Audubon Park?
We all are.
Cora, the most wonderful thing
has happened.
Clare is going to be baptized
this morning.
Vinnie, what are you saying?
'I'm saying you're going to be
baptized this morning.'
I am not going to be baptized
this morning
or any other morning!
You promised yesterday
that as soon as I sent
that pug dog
that you'd be baptized.
I never said anything
remotely like that!
Clarence was right there
and heard you.
That's why I ordered the cab.
The cab.
Vinnie,
you send that right back.
I'll do nothing of the kind.
I'm going to see
that you go to heaven.
- I can't go to heaven in a cab.
- Oh.
Oh!
Well, you can start in a cab.
I'm not sure they'll ever
let you into heaven.
But I know they won't
unless you're baptized.
They can't keep me out of heaven
on a technicality.
Clare, stop quibbling.
You may as well face it.
You've got to make
your peace with God.
Until you stirred Him up,
I had no trouble with God.
Harlan, Whitney,
come get your Sunday hats.
- Clarence, John!
- 'Yes, mother?'
Hurry, we're ready to go.
Oh, my prayer book.
Harlan, come let me fix
your tie.
Vinnie, are you mad?
Was it your plan
that my own children
should witness this indignity?
Why, Clare,
they'll be proud of you.
I suppose
Harlan is to be my godfather.
Vinnie, I won't go through
with this thing. That's final.
Well, Clare dear,
if you feel that way about it--
I do!
Well, we won't take the children
with us.
I'm not talking
about the children.
- I'm ready, mother.
- Oh, John.
Vinnie, I haven't time for
anything like that this morning.
I've got to take John
down to my office with me
and give him the money
to buy back that dog medicine.
But it wasn't dog medicine, sir.
Young man, we're starting
downtown this minute.
You'll do no such thing.
You gave me your sacred promise
that day I almost died.
Yes, and she would have died
if we hadn't given her
some of that medicine.
That proves it's good medicine.
You gave your mother
some of that dog medicine?
- John, you didn't?
- Yes, we did, mother.
We put some in your tea
that morning.
Oh, John.
Do you realize you might have
killed your mother?
You did kill Mrs. Sprague's dog.
John, I'll have to give
considerable thought
as to how you are to be punished
for this.
- But, Clare--
- No, Vinnie.
When I think of that day, what..
Why, we might have lost you.
You're alright now,
thank heaven.
But what I went through
that afternoon
the way I felt..
Well, I'll never forget it.
You've forgotten it already.
What do you mean?
That was the day you gave me
your sacred promise.
Yes, but I wouldn't have
given you my promise
if I hadn't thought
you were dying.
And you wouldn't have
almost died
if John hadn't given you
that dog medicine.
Don't you see? Well,
the whole thing is illegal.
Suppose I had died.
It wouldn't make
any difference to you.
You don't care whether
we meet in heaven or not.
You don't care whether you ever
see me and the children again.
Oh, Vinnie,
you're not being fair to me.
It's alright, Clare.
If you don't love us enough
there's nothing
we can do about it.
But that has nothing
to do with it.
I love my family
as much as any man.
All my life, I've struggled
and worked just to..
Oh, God, there's that cab.
Vinnie, y-you're not well enough
to go all the way to Audubon.
Oh, I'm well enough if we ride.
But that trip would take
all morning.
And those cabs cost
a dollar an hour.
This is one of their best cabs.
This costs $2 an hour.
Well, then why aren't you ready?
Get your hat on!
Oh, tarnation!
Hallelujah! Amen!
Young lady,
if it hadn't been for you
no one would have known
whether I was baptized or not!
Oh, God!
Good morning, Mr. Day.
Going to the office?
No! I'm going to be baptized!