We’re almost there, honey. Just a little
while longer and your vacation starts.
I’m getting cold, mother, and hungry.
We should be pretty close right now,
the agent said it was about
12 miles from highway 10,
and that was highway 10, back there.
But you know we should’ve asked for
better directions at the last gas station.
Listen, I’ve never gotten us lost before.
Mommy, I’m cold.
Okay, Debbie, I’ll put the top up.
Never mind, Mike.
Debbie can come up and sit between us.
Now, that’s better, baby.
Why don’t we sing a song
to help pass the time?
Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream
Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily,
life is but a dream
Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream
Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily,
life is but a dream
Row, row, row your boat
All right, mister.
I see you have a tail light problem.
No excuse – running late,
first vacation, kid getting tired.
It’s too bad.
Well, can’t you give us a break, officer?
Well, all right, all right.
Sure do appreciate it.
We are running kind of late.
Okay, but if you’re running late,
you should’ve started earlier.
Anyhow, no tail light.
Have it fixed.
Thank you, officer.
Ten miles up this road.
We’re almost there, Debbie.
Just a few minutes more.
- I wonder where they’re going.
- Man, like, there’s nothing up that road.
Now look, the sign pointed this way.
Mike, let’s go back to the crossroads
and ask those kids we saw.
Okay, okay,
but I know we can’t be wrong.
Look, the sign pointed this way.
How many times do we have
to chase you kids?
Oh, shit.
Holy cow, man.
You think we’re doing
something wrong.
Well, whatever it is you’re not doing,
go don’t do it somewhere else.
Why don’t you guys leave us alone?
Come on, now. No wisecracks.
Just go on home.
Okay.
- Get going, get going.
- All right already.
I could have sworn
we didn’t make a wrong turn.
You must have.
- Where did the road go?
- No need to get upset. We’ll find it.
Where did this place come from?
It wasn’t here a few minutes ago.
I don’t care. Let’s see
if we can get some directions.
Look, there’s someone at the door.
I am Torgo. I take care of the place
while the Master is away.
But the child – I’m not sure
the Master would approve, or the dog.
The Master doesn’t like children.
We only want to know
where Valley Lodge is.
Which way do we go?
There’s no place like that around here.
Mike, I’m scared.
It’s getting dark.
Well, Torgo, which way is out of here?
There is no way out of here.
It will be dark soon.
No way out?
Well, you know, we could spend
the night here, and then tomorrow...
Oh, Mike, Mike...
I-I don’t want to spend the night here,
I don’t like the looks of the place.
Well, it seems we have no alternative.
Well, how about it, Torgo,
can we spend the night here?
Well, I don’t know what else we can do.
But Mike, I don’t wanna stay here.
And the Master wouldn’t approve.
Don’t worry about it, we’re here now,
and I’m sure the Master won’t throw us out.
Well? How about it, Torgo?
I don’t wanna stay!
Let’s leave!
I don’t know about it.
I just don’t know.
Daddy, I’m cold. Let’s go in.
Well, Torgo, in or out?
Patient, dear.
Very well.
The Master will be very disturbed.
I’ll get the luggage.
Torgo, we’ll stay tonight,
and then tomorrow...
You must be...
You cannot stay.
The Master would not approve.
See? You’re feeling better already.
Look at this.
Mike, I...
He looks so sinister.
Must be the Master himself.
Oh, Mike, I’m scared.
He has the meanest look.
And that dog...
I’d hate to run up on him in the dark,
or even in the light, for that matter.
That must be your Master.
What did you say he was?
He has left this world,
but he is with us always –
no matter where we go,
he is with us.
- What?
- No matter where he goes?
What does that mean?
And that dog... is the most
vicious-looking animal I’ve ever seen.
Well, I hope he goes
where the Master goes.
There is nothing to fear, madam.
The Master likes you.
Nothing will happen to you;
he likes you.
Likes me?
I thought you said he was dead.
Dead? No, madam,
not “dead” the way you know it.
He is with us always.
Not “dead” the way you know it.
Mike, I don’t like this.
Nothing to worry about,
it’s only your imagination.
I think that it’s best
that I show you to the bedroom, now.
Oh, my God!
Mike, what was that?
Probably some animal in the desert.
Nothing to be afraid of.
I’m scared, Mike.
Michael, I don’t care what it is,
chase it away.
Okay, if it will make you relax,
I’ll go out and see what it is.
What happened? I heard...
Stay here. Get back into the house.
Get back in the house, damnit!
My God, Mike! What happened?
He’s dead. Peppie’s been killed.
Get back in the house, honey.
Mike, what kind of place is this?
My God, what kind of place is this?
I’ll take care of everything, honey.
Get back in the house.
Mike...
Oh, Mike, what could’ve done it?
Honey, it was probably
some animal from the desert.
This place must be full of them.
Peppie...
He went away, baby.
Went away while you were asleep.
Mike, I wanna leave this place.
Now.
Okay, honey. We’ll leave right away.
Where the hell is that caretaker?
Torgo!
Did you want me?
We’re leaving. Would you mind
putting the luggage back into the car?
As you wish.
Right now.
Fast, damnit! Fast!
I’ll be glad to leave,
I’ve had all this place I want.
Madam, it would be very dangerous
to leave now.
The Master wants you.
Wants me?
What kind of talk is that?
He wants you for his wife.
He loves beautiful women.
Don’t you ever try that again,
you... beast!
The Master wants you,
but he can’t have you.
I want you!
Stop that talk this instance, you hear?
He wants you,
but he can’t have you.
Mike! Mike!
Where in the world can he be?
Let me out of here.
Let me out of here, now!
Do you hear? Now!
Forgive me, madam.
I meant no harm.
Forgive you?
Just wait till I tell my husband!
I meant no harm, madam.
I’ll protect you.
I will protect you.
Very well, I won’t tell my husband.
Now let me out.
Imagine, the damned car won’t start.
Margaret?
Damned car won’t start.
Well, that really fixes things.
What are we gonna do now?
I don’t know, and I couldn’t find
anything wrong with it, either.
Hey, Torgo, where’s the phone?
Yes, Alexander Graham Bell,
you know, telephone?
There is none, sir. The Master
doesn’t approve of such devices.
Then where is the nearest phone?
The nearest phone is at the crossroads.
That’s ten miles.
Ten miles?
Might as well be 10,000 miles!
Easy, honey. It won’t help to get mad.
The Master won’t mind
you staying tonight.
He has no choice – we can’t leave,
we can’t walk out of here,
and the damned car won’t start.
I’ll just bring the bags
back to the room.
Sinister.
“Sinister” isn’t descriptive enough.
Honey, we’ll leave in the morning,
and soon this place will be forgotten.
Forgotten? I’ll never forget.
Peppie’s gone.
I just hope Debbie will understand.
She’ll understand.
She’s my baby, she’ll understand.
I hope so, darling. I sure hope so.
Say, where is she?
Oh, my God! Michael!
Don’t get wrought up,
she’s probably playing hide-and-seek.
Okay, Debbie, we see you.
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
Maybe she slipped into one of the rooms.
Debbie?
- Debbie?
Torgo, have you seen Debbie?
- No.
- She’s gone. Help us find her.
She couldn’t have gone outside;
the door is bolted.
For God’s sake, don’t panic!
She’s got to be in here.
Is there another exit to the outside?
In the kitchen.
That door is bolted, too!
Outside, Mike.
She’s got to be outside.
All right, we’ll look outside for her.
- Debbie?
Mike, I’m scared.
- The animals and Debbie...
- Cut it out!
We’ll find her. Don’t worry.
Debbie?
Daddy, is this a good puppy?
Mike, it’s the dog from the portrait.
Stand back, Debbie! Stand back!
That dog wants to play with you, daddy.
Darling, baby, you could’ve been hurt.
I saw the puppy and got close to.
But you should never run away from us.
Debbie, don’t ever run away from us.
But I wanna find my puppy.
Where did you find the new dog, baby?
In that big place.
In a big place? Where, Debbie?
There was this big dark place.
It was so dark,
but I wasn’t afraid of the dark,
there were all kinds
of funny people in it.
Where is the place, Debbie?
Follow me, daddy.
Mike, it’s horrible!
- Let’s get out of here!
- Let’s go!
Get into the bedroom
and lock yourself in.
I’m gonna find Torgo.
He’s got some explaining to do.
Hurry. Please hurry.
I want her.
She’s mine! Mine! Mine, you hear?
I want this one. You have all the wives
you need. This one is mine.
Look!
Oh, you pretty ones.
No matter how good you are,
I won’t need you anymore.
I have my own wife!
I won’t have to come in here
to dream of having one of you.
You... You are the worst!
You were his first wife.
He doesn’t want you anymore.
And now even I don’t want you.
No, I’m through with all of you.
Through!
Through, you hear me?
Again? How many times
do you have to be told?
Like, wow!
Have a heart, will you?
Go chase that other couple.
What other couple?
Those idiots that went deeper in the desert.
Find them and queue on them a while.
We know that this road goes nowhere,
so now get!
No smart stuff.
We ain’t trying to jump on you.
Just get!
O Manos...
Thou of primal darkness!
Thou, who dwelleth in the depths of the
universe, in the black chasms of night!
Thou, who bestoweth the mother darkness
upon thy faithful,
to live eternally in her keeping.
Thou dost make him most blessed forever!
And thou who dost curse
with eternal burning life
those who transgress
against thee!
Holy art thou, holy art thou,
holy art thou!
Manos will be done!
Thy priesthood remains steadfast,
thy priesthood remains constant,
thy priesthood remains righteous.
Thou hast taught us, o Manos,
and we hath listened.
Give ear to our words, o Manos,
and hear us!
Hear us!
For we are faithful
and thou art our God.
Arise, my wives.
Give ear to the words of Manos.
Arise, my wives,
and hear the will of Manos.
Why has the child been brought here?
Why?
And a female child at that!
I have never complained
about sacrificing a man,
but a child?
The woman is all we want.
The others must die.
They all must die!
We do not even want the woman.
They child is a female –
she must not be destroyed.
She will grow up to be a woman.
- She must be killed!
- No!
I’m the oldest of the wives,
and it is my privilege to say that...
Enough!
Enough of this stupid bickering!
The child must die!
If you persist in this foolishness,
your usefulness will come to an end.
Say what you will,
I will have no part of this madness.
As the oldest of the wives,
I demand that she lives.
I don’t know what they’re doing here
in the first place.
You have caused enough trouble.
I think perhaps your service to us
is at its end, now.
Silence! Silence!
And now, my wives, I shall deal with the one
who is responsible for the child being here.
Torgo, he’s the one!
Get Torgo!
You are responsible for this nonsense.
We shall dispose of you, later.
It’s a terrible mistake.
The man, yes. The child, no.
Maybe she’s right.
Maybe we should spare the child.
It is against our will that we stay here.
Do not make the child die
to satisfy him.
He does not need any more wives.
Yes, he has no more time
for us older wives, just the newest.
Jealousy is not part of us.
Why are you so jealous of me?
You are a troublemaker.
You deserve to die!
Die? I may die, but I do not care.
The child must live.
She is right.
We will not kill the child.
But Manos would not approve.
The law of Manos exits for us only.
Manos loves women.
She will grow up to be a woman.
She must die.
When the Master hears of this,
he will be furious.
You are all mad! Mad, the whole lot of you!
The man, yes. The child, no.
Master, what are you doing here?
You have failed us, Torgo.
I know of your visits to the tomb.
My visits?
The women have told me.
They may not be able to say anything,
or move when you’re there,
but they remember
everything you say to them,
and everything you do to them.
But Master, you have six wives.
Why can’t I have one for myself?
You’re not one of us,
therefore you cannot have one of them.
But I have one now.
This one is mine. You’ll never get her.
You have failed us, Torgo.
For this you must die!
Failed you? No.
You have failed yourselves.
You’ll never kill them!
I’ll help them!
You have failed...
and you must die!
Manos, God of primal darkness,
as thou has decreed, so have I done.
The hands of fate have doomed this man.
Thy will is done.
The women are fighting!
What was that?
Michael?
Michael, where are you?
Oh, please, God! Where is Mike?
Stop! What foolishness is this?
Manos must be served!
There you are!
She is the one!
She has upset all of our plans!
This foolishness must stop!
There has been enough trouble.
Our purpose must be served.
There will be no further insolence.
- But the child...
- We cannot kill a child!
Yes, we can!
You have caused enough trouble!
As soon as we have disposed of Torgo,
we shall take care of you!
Your power fails you; I have no more fear.
Seize her! And prepare her for sacrifice!
Well done, my wives.
The will of Manos shall be served!
Tis the will of Manos
that he be sacrificed.
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Manos has decreed it.
Mike, help us! Oh, my God!
Margaret, open the door!
Enough!
The ceremony is done.
Killing doesn’t help anymore!
You’re all finished!
You have said enough!
Your turn will come,
as soon as we’ve disposed of the others!
Go find the others!
Hurry, before the night slips away!
At the window, Mike.
I saw him at that window.
Okay, honey. We’ll leave. We’ll leave.
We’ve got to leave now!
I can’t stand it any longer!
Please, Mike!
We’ll hide in the desert.
Someone will help.
The gods will destroy you!
Your power fails!
You cannot endure!
Destroy?
The gods destroy me?
Destroy me?
I am permanent!
Manos has made me permanent!
Your power fails you!
You are losing your control!
Even Torgo defied you!
And he was destroyed,
even as you shall be!
Your power does not affect me anymore!
Even your other wives
do not trust you!
See? I do not fear you!
Eventhough you beat me!
Beat me again! Beat! Beat!
I do not fear you!
I can’t go on.
Take Debbie and run.
No, darling. We’ll make it.
Let’s go.
Nothing of that way.
Let’s go this way.
Mike? Mike, are you all right?
Damn...
Mike, we can’t go on this way.
We got to keep going.
They have gone!
They have left the house!
We have searched everywhere.
Find them!
They must not escape!
- Find them!
- No, leave them alone!
We cannot kill a child!
Enough talk!
Find them!
Manos will be served!
I can’t make it, Mike!
I can’t make it!
Take the baby!
Take Debbie!
No, Maggie, we can make it.
We’ll rest here for a minute.
We can make it.
Let’s go back.
They’ll never think
of looking for us at the house.
You know, you might have a point there.
Please, Mike! Please!
I can’t go any farther!
Listen, we can lock ourselves
in the kitchen. I have my gun.
We’ll have to go back.
Okay. It might be the safest place,
especially since they’re out here,
looking for us.
Daddy, I’m scared.
Where’s my puppy?
Please, Debbie, not now!
That sure sounded like shots.
We’d better check.
At this hour of the night? There can’t be
anybody out here – this is the boondocks.
Well, sound does travel
a long way at night.
It could be clear over in Mexico,
for that matter.
It sure is good to get away.
Damn the rain!
Vacations are fine,
but this one should be great.
Yeah, the gang’s coming up
for the weekend. What a blast!
Welcome.
I am Michael.
I take care of the place
while the Master is away.