Love in the country
Where skies are blue
All you'll be dreaming of
Are the birds and the bees
and the flowers and the trees
Till you're up to
your knees in love
There's a treehouse
in the meadow
Below the mountain peak
The perfect place for lovers
When they play hide and seek
There's a covered bridge
at Crippled Creek
Where the horses always stop
'Tween the treehouse
And the covered bridge
That's how Mom won Pop
By making love
in the country
Where skies are blue
All you'll be dreaming of
Are the birds and the bees
and the flowers and the trees
Till you're up to
your knees in love
There are roses
on the trellis
And the scent
of new-mown hay
The clingin' vine is jealous
On the fence across the way
There's a great big yellow
moon above
And a breeze to sing a song
'Tween the roses
and the yellow moon
A fella can't go wrong
When he makes
Love in the country
Where skies are blue
All you'll be dreamin' of
Are the birds and the bees
and the flowers and the trees
Till you're up to
your knees in love!
Lord to goodness.
Not again.
- Howdy, Drago.
- Morning, Curly.
Makes seven times this month
he come home swaggled.
- Six.
- Seven.
Six. Once was his birthday.
That don't count.
Give me my buggy whip.
Didn't have anything for breakfast
but two raw eggs and a mug of honey.
- No!
- Curly!
Yes, Boss?
Don't say it's a fine morning,
or I'll shoot you.
Get out of here, Bunyan.
- Good morning.
Carlos, what are you
doing up there?
I hope I get it
this time, Mr. McLintock.
My brothers... they got
the big hats already.
All right. Let 'em have at it.
Get over.
Did you want to let me drive?
You promised me you would sometime.
No! Ya!
Boss, you better
watch that turn on the road!
You're gonna kill
both of us one of these days.
Thank you, Mr. Boss!
You got cattle
in the bank, Boss.
Ya!
Giddyap. Ya!
Keep 'em going.
15 cents a pound
all the way to Kansas City.
Ya! Ya!
Now, Boss, there's
one old pensioner...
I wish you'd pass up.
- Bunny?
- Yeah.
Wish I knew where
I'd seen his face before.
He ain't an old timer.
He's just been around town
a couple of years.
Aw, you have no milk
of human kindness.
Morning, Mr. McLintock.
- Morning, Bunny.
- Well, I can see you're in good health.
Never felt better,
contrary to what you may hear.
My kidneys ain't
what they used to be,
and my liver's been leaving me bilious.
- Drago!
Eh.
- Hello, Ben.
- Hey, McLintock.
- Drago, throw that in the buggy.
- Yes, sir.
- That's a scrubby bunch of sooners, huh?
- They are at that.
That ought to make Douglas
happy, lining his pockets with land fees.
What are we going to do?
I don't know what you're gonna do, Ben.
Me... I do nothing.
200 families. Quarter of beef
a week per family.
lf they last two years,
that can be a sizable number.
I got 20 head to one of any...
other brand on the Mesa Verde.
I'm not hollering.
Some of us haven't got
all the money in the world.
Some of us ain't old and tired
and feel like being put upon.
You interest me, Young Ben.
Go on.
The first time I find one of
our hides wearing our brand...
hung on one of them settler's fences,
I aim to kill me a plow boy.
You do what you want, McLintock.
We'll do what we want.
Fellas my age generally
call me "G.W." or "McLintock".
Youngsters call me
"Mr. McLintock".
All right, "Mr. McLintock",
not because I'm afraid of you.
You're the big yeast out of this country,
and I reckon a fella my age
should call you "mister".
He's full grown now, G.W.
He's a half-owner of the spread.
I made him a full partner,
the day the doc gave me the long face.
Well, you want him to vote...
the first time this territory
becomes a state, don't you?
Of course, I do.
These settlers get burned out,
there'll be a lot of hollering...
that this country's too wild
to be a state,
and we'll go on being
a territory some more,
with a lot of political
appointees running it...
according to what they learned
in some college...
where they think that cows
are something you milk,
and lndians are something
in front of a cigar store.
I'm looking to you
to hold Young Ben down.
I'll do what I can.
Come on over to the house once in a while.
We'll rack up a few hands of stud.
G.W., that'll be just fine.
It's a nice morning,
ain't it, Boss?
Everybody's entitled
to their own opinion.
Like that again, eh?
Here's something that'll cheer you up.
About 1,000 head. l figure
they'll bring about $1,250.
They're not as fat
as I'd like to ship.
- They all off the north range?
- Yes, sir.
Settlers. Every one of them
with a plow and a Bible,
not the slightest idea
of what the range is for.
Drago!
- Drag out that hog-legg.
- Yes, sir.
Get me some attention.
Hee ya!
People, people, people!
People!
Come on, all of you! Gather around.
People, come on! Gather around.
l'm McLintock.
You people planned a homestead
and farmed the Mesa Verde.
Yes, sir. The government
give us each 160 acres.
The government never gave
anybody anything.
Some years back,
a lot like you came in.
They had a pretty good first year
good summer, easy winter.
But the next year,
the last rain was in February,
and by June, even the jackrabbits had
sense enough to get off the Mesa.
Folks, do you know who that is? That's McLintock...
"George Washington McLintock."
I told them that, Douglas.
He controls the water rights,
on 200 square miles of range.
You know that lumber you got?
That came from his land.
Cut by his loggers
and milled in his mills.
Douglas, I come close to killing you a
couple of times, when we were younger.
Saddens me I didn't.
Can you imagine
a man who owns all that...
Oh, and mines, too.
I forgot to mention them...
All that, and he's begrudging
poor people a measly...
a measly, 160 acres.
That right, Mr. McLintock?
- You begrudge us a little free land?
- There's no such thing as free land.
If you make these homesteads go,
you'll have earned every acre of it,
but you just can't make 'em go
on the Mesa Verde.
God made that country for buffalo.
It serves pretty well for cattle,
but it hates the plow.
And even the government
should know...
that you can't farm 6,000 feet
above sea level.
- Any trouble, Mr. McLintock?
- No trouble, Sheriff.
- How about you, Douglas?
- "Douglas?"
Just plain "Douglas," eh?
And you call him "Mr. McLintock".
Why?
Well, "Douglas," I guess
it's because he earned it.
- Mr. McLintock?
- Yeah?
I'm a good hand with cattle, Mr. McLintock.
I'd like a job.
Well, you look strong enough.
You come in with those sooners?
Well, yes, sir, but we don't
have a homestead.
Can't use you.
Tough life, ain't it, sonny?
Well, ain't much future in being
a farmer around these parts.
Ladies, this is the finest chantilly lace,
available anywhere.
"Chantilly", Mr. Birnbaum.
- Well, believe me, it's the best.
Oh, excuse me. Please, look around.
Take your time.
Drago, I got 1,000 Havana cigars,
and 12 of those hats for you over there.
Them big hats ain't going to
last long the way some folks...
have been dipping
into that redeye these days.
Uh-oh.
Good morning, G.W.
Good morning.
I stole some stick candy.
Please. Help yourself.
Come on in.
Davey! You can forget about
saddling up the horse!
Come in here!
- Problem?
- Yes.
Well, if I were blacks, I'd move
queen's bishop to king 4.
Yeah. You might be right.
You know, I was just starting to work this out
when the letter came.
Letter?
- It was...
- What happened? Don't you want...
- Morning, Mr. McLintock.
- Morning, Davey.
You being here
saved me a trip.
Oh, that hat and suit of clothes
you picked out for my birthday...
well, instead of
this cowboy hat,
I'd like to have this one, if it's,
uh, all right with you, sir.
Well, it's all right
with me, Davey.
Of course, that looks like
the kind of a hat...
a fella'd wear down Main Street
to start a fight
Oh, l don't need
a city hat for that.
All l have to do
is walk down the street,
and some wiseacre will call me an "Indian",
and, just like that, the fight's on.
Davey, the letter. It's for you.
And you are an Indian.
Yes, l know I'm an Indian,
but I'm also the fastest runner in town.
I've got a college education,
and I'm the railroad telegrapher,
but does anybody say, "Hello, college man"
or "Hello, runner"...
or "Hello, telegrapher"? No!
Not even "Hello, knothead..."
Davey.
It's always,
"Let the Indian do it."
Will you go out in
the store and help the ladies?
All right. I'm also
a bookkeeper, part-time clerk.
Always, "Let the Indian do it."
A lady brought that
out here this morning,
asked for it to be taken out
to the home ranch for you.
Handsome lady.
Kind of tall with red hair.
Called me "Mr. Birnbaum", just as
if she'd never seen me before...
and as if that veil that covered her face
could keep me from recognizing her.
I thought she was in New York
or Europe or someplace.
So did l.
Jake, you better throw on a couple
extra cases of the bosses favorite bourbon.
That stuff sure gets used up
fast out at our place.
Which reminds me,
you better start tapering off.
Huh!
- Katherine's in town.
- Katie?!
Ladies.
Good morning.
Morning, Mr. McLintock.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
- Fauntleroy.
Morning, G.W.
What are you doing in here?
Why aren't you out at the desk?
Helping out the bartender.
Yeah, I see. A busy day.
Give me the key to room 17.
What?
17, and don't advertise it.
Here they come,
Mr. McLintock.
Set 'em up.
- Beer.
- Whiskey.
Day off?
Off day.
Wonder what he's
so preoccupied about.
- Haven't you heard?
- No. What?
- Katie's back in town.
- Katie?
Yes, dear.
The social arbiter.
- Well, hi, sonny.
- Good morning. Oh!
He sure is a polite one.
Mr. McLintock, l don't
want to bother you...
I'm sorry, boy.
l told you, no job.
Katherine.
George Washington McLintock.
I thought you'd want this.
First dig of the spur,
but who am I
to upset your plans?
- Don't you feel kind of silly?
- I never feel silly.
It's because you have
no sense of humor.
Why couldn't we sit down
in the hotel dining room...
and talk about whatever it is
you want to talk about?
Or why couldn't you just come
over to the house?
And have everybody know
that we're meeting?
Everybody knows, and what's
the difference? We're married.
That is something
I should like to change.
You know the answer, Katie.
That isn't why you sent for me.
Let's get to the rat killing.
That's just the kind of remark
that's always endeared you to me.
Let us open the discussion.
Very well. Our daughter is coming home in a
few days, or, rather, she's coming here.
It was just a slip of the tongue that made me
refer to this ugly hamlet as home.
"Our daughter?" ls it so hard
to say her name? It's Becky.
Rebecca! l hate that name.
Anyway, she's coming home,
and l hoped to persuade you
to let her live with me...
part of the time in the capital,
part of the time in New York,
and, of course,
Newport during the season.
You're whistling
in the wind, Katie.
If she stays here,
she'll become just as crude and as vulgar,
as all of this country.
And if she goes your way,
she'll be all show and no stay.
Oh.
No go, Kate.
l hate you.
Oh, how l hate you!
Half the people
in the world are women.
Why does it have to be you
that stirs me?
- You animal.
- That's the story.
l saw your picture in the paper
at the Governor's Ball.
You were dancing
with the governor.
At least he's a gentleman.
l doubt that.
You have to be a man first
before you're a gentleman.
He misses on both counts.
- Hey, sonny, you gonna ask him again?
- Nope.
Hey, boy, you got to pocket your pride.
You got to beg.
You better listen to an expert, sonny.
I'm telling you. You got to grovel.
Human nature. Gets 'em every time.
Mister, leave me alone.
Everybody does it
one way or another.
Heh heh heh!
About that job,
Mr. McLintock.
l already told you, son,
I've got no need for farmers...
- or use for 'em.
- Just one minute, Mr. McLintock.
My father died last month.
That's how come we lost our homestead.
I've got a mother and a little sister to feed.
I need that job badly.
- What's your name?
- Devlin Warren.
Well, you got a job, son.
See my home ranch foreman.
He's over at the corral.
Step down off of
that carriage, mister.
Hold that hog-legg.
I've been punched many a time in my life,
but never for hiring anybody.
Aw, I don't know what to say.
l never begged before.
It turned my stomach.
I suppose I should have been
grateful you gave me the job.
"Gave?"
Boy, you got it all wrong.
I don't "give" jobs.
I hire men.
You intend to give this man a full day's work,
don't you, boy?
You mean you're still
hiring me, Mr. McLintock?
Well, yes, sir. I mean,
I'll certainly deliver a fair day's work.
For that,
I'll pay you a fair day's wage.
You won't "give" me anything,
and I won't "give" you anything.
We both hold up our heads.
Where do you live?
The settler's encampment
down by the mine.
- That your plug?
- Yes, sir.
Well, hop on him,
and we'll go get your gear.
Ya... Ya!
- Morning, Mr. McLintock.
- Morning.
l am sure that all you
fine people are interested...
in knowing just what portion of this new land
will be your new home.
Oh, uh... Jones and McCallister, since you've
been more or less the leaders of our group,
I'd like to have you come up
and check the exact location.
Won't be a minute, sir.
Go after that boy
and give him $30.
Tell him McLintock pays
his riders a month in advance.
From the looks of things
they could sure use it, too.
Oh, Ma,
this is Mr. Drago.
Good morning.
Well, and to what do we
owe this visit from the cattle baron?
I've got a touch of hangover,
bureaucrat. Don't push me.
Whoa-ho, McLin!
Say, those are Indians.
Are there Indians
in this homestead land?
Friendly Indians, my boy.
- Whoa-ho, McLin.
- Whoa-ho, Running Buffalo.
Ho, McLin. Long time we don't
get drunk together.
And it's going to be
a lot longer time...
because it's against the law,
and you're with the sheriff.
And have I got my hands full.
They came into town to meet the train.
The old Indian chiefs are coming home.
l heard they'd been pardoned.
They don't know when it's arriving,
this week, next week, or next month,
so, in the meantime, I've got to
do something with them.
Could I cut out a couple of head
of your steers to feed them?
Otherwise, some of these settler's
milk cows are going to disappear.
- That's right, McLin.
- Ha ha ha! Cut out whatever you need.
Sheriff, are you going to encamp these
savages with all these settlers?
You're asking for trouble.
Mr. Douglas, I already have
plenty of trouble.
Please stay off my back.
Running Buffalo, bring your
people over to the clay slide.
Hello, Mr. McLin.
Tiny Mouth, it's nice to see you!
You wouldn't believe it now,
but 20 years ago, she was
a mighty handsome maid.
20 years ago, you
thought so, too, Mr. Douglas.
Ahem.
It was just like this. I had a
dead bead on old Running Buffalo,
and my Sharp .50 caliber misfired.
That was back in that trouble
in the forties, remember?
I remember.
You want to taste something
come directly from heaven?
No.
- Where'd you get this?
- That boy's mama baked 'em.
You thinking the same thing I am?
She's a widow woman, Boss,
and she's got a long, hard road to hoe.
Hire her.
I always said you had
a heap of sense.
Mr. McLintock,
this is my mother.
- Your mother?
- And my sister.
- Pleased to meet you, Mr. McLintock.
- Ma'am, this here's my boss,
and he has a few choice words
to say about your biscuits.
Yes, Mr. McLintock?
Well... they're great.
Well, you old Cantonese reprobate,
how about it?
You fire me,
l kill myself.
I'm not talking about firing you.
I'm retiring you.
You been rustling food
for us for 30 years.
We're going to put you
out to pasture.
All you'll have to do is give advice,
be one of the family.
- l kill myself.
- l may save you the trouble.
Hey, Ching,
you kill yourself, I'll cut off your pigtail,
and you ain't never going to get to heaven.
- I'll be one of the family?
- l give you my solemn word.
Pretty crummy family...
drink too much, get in fight,
yell all time.
Cut off his pigtail.
All right. All right.
I'll be one of the family.
I hope everything is satisfactory?
This is such a big house, it'll take me
a while to get used to things.
Now, please don't hesitate
to tell me if anything is wrong.
No bird's-nest soup?
Otherwise, just fine.
Everything nice and fine.
Food's heavenly, ma'am.
Best apple pie l ever ate.
Curly's right, ma'am.
Hated to leave that last bite.
Shall we celebrate with a drink?
Carlos, come
and help me with the dishes.
Alice, you want to help, too?
- Yes, Drago.
- All right. Pitch in.
I'll wash, and you kids can dry.
Is that good?
Whoa.
Don't seem possible one woman
could use all them clothes.
You keep a civil tongue
in your unprepossessing face.
- Yes, ma'am.
- And unload my baggage, please.
Yes, ma'am.
By the way, what does that word,
"unprepossessing," mean?
- Mrs. McLintock!
- Oh, hello, Carlos.
Run and help the driver
with my luggage.
l couldn't trust anyone else in this house
to do anything correctly.
- Luggage? Give him a hand, Curly.
- Yes, Boss.
- Mr. McLintock.
- Are you moving back in?
Yes, but nothing has changed
except my place of residence,
and I'd be willing
to put up with savages...
rather than be denied
the company of my daughter,
and I'm proving that
by moving in here.
Mr. McLintock, since it's my first day,
would you excuse me if l, uh...
Go ahead.
Oh, Katherine, this is Dev Warren.
He joined the outfit today.
- Pleased, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Well, how refreshing
a polite young man here.
- Where did he come from?
- He's a farmer.
- A farmer?
- Well, I'll be doggone!
Kate, welcome home.
What on earth are you doing
in that idiotic-looking outfit?
- And don't you dare call me "Kate".
- That's my butling suit.
I'm butling for the boss.
And I'm sorry, Katherine.
That "Kate" kind of slipped out,
from the times l remembered...
you as being nice peop... people.
Oh!
Are you going to stand there
with that stupid look on your face...
while the hired help insults your wife?
He's just ignorant.
He doesn't know any better
than to tell the truth.
And I can't help this stupid look.
I started acquiring it as you
gained in social prominence.
Mrs. McLintock, where do
you want I should put...
Put them in the master bedroom.
Yes, but move Mr. McLintock's
things into another room.
Oh, the one back of the stairs
would be best...
so that he can't wake up
the entire household...
when he comes home every night...
...just before daybreak.
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, excuse me.
- Here's your cigars, Mr. McLintock.
- I am Mrs. McLintock.
Kate... I mean Katherine...
this is the cook, this is the lady
that does the cooking for us.
Mrs. Warren,
Mrs. McLintock.
How do you do.
Very pleased to meet you,
Mrs. McLintock.
- Very pleased.
- Likewise.
You see,
I just came to work here today,
and I guess I jumped to the conclusion...
that this was a bachelor's household.
It is, and then again,
it isn't.
I will explain so everything will be
quite clear, Mrs. Wallace...
"Mrs. Warren."
It has been a bachelor's
household for quite some time,
and it will be again
just as soon as I'm out of here,
which will be as quickly
as I can make arrangements..
to take my daughter
back east with me.
You see, she's coming home
from school in a few days,
and then we'll be off together,
and you can return to conducting yourself...
as you consider proper
in a bachelor's household.
- Katie!
- Shut up!
Until then, I am mistress
in this house,
and I will give the orders.
- You gonna let her? Ain't you
gonna say nothing, boss?
No!
I want one poached egg, toast...
Oh, G.W., as soon as
my things are put away,
I want to talk to you
about Rebecca.
Yes, Mrs. McLintock.
Indeed, Mrs. McLintock.
Of course, Mrs. McLintock.
The toast... lightly browned
and unbuttered.
Of course, ma'am.
Wait a minute now, Boss, where
do you think you're going?
I just remembered
I got a date.
But she said she want to
have a talk with you.
I heard.
- Good evening, Lem.
- Good evening, Mr. Mac.
Say, Mr. Mac, what does
"unprepossessing" mean?
I was called that once, Lem.
Looked it up in the dictionary.
- It's best you don't know what it means.
- Uh-huh. Thank you. Giddyap.
Hey, what am I going to tell her
when she asks where you went?
When in doubt,
tell the truth.
She wouldn't expect that
from you anyway.
- Where's Mr. McLintock going?
- There he goes, burning his last bridge.
You see a yellow streak
about a foot wide...
running up and down
his backbone?
On Mr. McLintock?
Uh-huh.
- He ain't afraid of nothing.
- I once thought that.
- Drago?
- Yes, ma'am?
- Was that, uh...
- He took off. Lit out.
- I told him I wanted to talk to him.
- Yes, ma'am.
I was standing right over here
when you said it,
and I was standing right on
those front steps...
when he walked up to a horse,
grabbed a hunk of mane,
- stepped up on him, and sunk spur.
- Where did he go?
Last time I saw him, he was
going east, but you know him.
He's liable to go
north, south, or west.
Get me a carriage.
- Yes, ma'am, but...
- But what?
Maybe you shouldn't follow him
into maybe where he's going into.
What does that mean?
I don't know,
but I wish I hadn't-a said it.
- Well, just get the carriage.
- Yes, ma'am.
- What happened?
- Get the barouche.
- Barouche?
- Hitch it up. She wants to go to town.
But Mr. McLintock never
said anything to me about it.
Look, young fella, I'm
the ramrod around this place,
the ramrod around this place, and
you better start giving me a "Yes, sir,"
or you're going to get the roof of this house
pulled down on your head.
Yes, sir.
- Hello, Davey.
- Hi, Mr. McLintock.
- New broom, eh?
- Sweeps clean.
- Hello, Bunny. How is everything?
- Oh, fine, fine, Mr. McLintock.
I'll get you next time.
Two more, Elmer.
Well, look who's here.
What'll it be, Mac?
Same as usual?
Ladies.
- Evening, G.W.
- Jake.
- Wrong move.
- What?
The chess problem.
Queen's in danger.
Whoa. Whoa.
I suppose you can do that.
Camille,
you're on your own.
Mrs. McLintock.
I'm Camille...
Camille Reedbottom.
I... I'm, uh, learning
the game of chess.
Thought it would give me
something to pass the time.
See, I have nothing
to do all day long.
I... uh... I just remembered something.
Katherine! I didn't
hear you come in.
Mr. McLintock, I told you
that I wanted to talk to you.
Not now.
Uh, could I get you
a glass of sherry, Katherine?
Oh, thank you,
Mr. Birnbaum. I could use one.
I came into town
behind a runaway team!
Drago never
could handle horses.
It was that young man whose
mother pretends to be your cook!
- Katherine, your wine.
- Oh, thank you, Mr. Birnbaum.
Now, Mr. McLintock, we have
an awful lot to talk over.
First thing I learned about Indian fighting
was to wait for daylight.
And what does our conversation
got to do with Indian fighting?
Indian fighting is good experience
for our kind of conversations.
Oh!
It'll wait, Katherine.
Evening, Sheriff, Mr. McLintock.
We had quite a ride out here.
- Oh, I finally got that team settled down.
- It's your move.
- No, it's your move. I just canceled it.
- Now, look here.
You're not going to sit here
all night long and play chess...
when the matter of our daughter
remains unsettled.
I am going to
remain here and play chess,
and the matter of our daughter
is settled.
- She stays.
- Oh, such stubbornness!
Katherine, your hair.
Oh, it must look a mess
after that awful ride.
No, no. It's just that I haven't
seen you in a long time.
It seems to me that the last time I saw you...
that your hair was a little darker, no?
- Ha, Ha, Ha, Ha.
It's a funny thing the tricks
a man's memory will play, uh?
Mr. Birnbaum, I think that you've
completely lost your mind.
- You have done something to your hair.
- I have not!
Ha, ha, ha, ah!
If I had, it would be
none of your business.
I'm certainly not going to put myself in the
place of those blondene trollops
that you seem to prefer.
- Take it.
- Oh.
- Fill it.
Good morning.
- You fellas still at it all night?
- A McLintock never quits,
but a Birnbaum has to.
Besides, the game is over. You got me.
Oh, no, Mr. Birnbaum.
You still got a good game.
Oh, you play chess?
Please, take over.
- Pretty good?
- Fair.
Well, looks like I won't have to come into
town always to get a game.
Remember, I'm a bad loser.
- It's your move.
- Yes, sir.
Good morning.
Is it morning already?
Hmm-mm.
Cup of coffee?
Oh, yes. Thanks, Jake.
You're welcome, Katherine.
- Got any cream?
- Canned cow's milk.
That'll do.
Good old condensed milk.
That reminds me...
I was cleaning out my desk
the other day,
and I found something
I wanted to return to you.
Here it is.
It is a medal, do you remember?
"From the President of the
United States of America..."
"to First Sergeant
Michael Patrick Gilhooly..."
"for bravery above
and beyond the call of duty."
It's your Papa's.
Reminds me of the first time
I ever saw you.
It was over 17 years ago.
You walked into my store...
not much bigger than
the bundle you were carrying.
And in the bundle was the most
beautiful baby I ever saw.
And was she hungry!
You walked all the way
from Superstition Creek...
just to trade me that medal
for a case of canned milk.
G.W. was off somewhere, as usual,
fighting Indians.
Sheriff! Sheriff Lord!
Well, have you
seen the sheriff?
Kind of early
for him. Did you try his house?
- Now, why didn't I think of that?
- Looks like Birnbaum's is open.
Maybe somebody
in here knows.
So there you are, Sheriff.
I told you you were headed for trouble.
Trouble?
I want to know by whose authority
you let those Indians stay in town.
Those savages are wards
of the government,
and I am the representative
of that government...
I told Sheriff Lord that he could
put them up down by the clay slide.
Because the town's named after
him, he thinks he owns it.
Well, you check the books in
the recorder's office,
and you'll find I do
own a fair piece of it.
Agard, if you knew anything
about Indians,
you'd know that they're doing
their level best...
to put up with our so-called
"benevolent" patronage...
in spite of the nincompoops that
have been put in charge of it.
Those Indians need my permission
to leave the reservation.
Those chiefs have been giving
orders all their lives.
It's pretty hard
for them to understand...
that they have to hold up their hand
like a schoolboy in a classroom.
The law is very clear.
I told you you'd get no
satisfaction from these people.
- We'll get the girl back.
- Girl?
The girl the Indians
kidnapped, but don't worry.
I armed the settlers and set them
to rounding up those red devils.
What is this about a "girl"?
Millie Jones... one of
the settler's daughters.
- The Indians kidnapped her.
- That's ridiculous
And you turned loose a lot of
farmers with shotguns?
- I certainly did.
- You're insane. Let's go, Sheriff.
- Mr. Douglas.
- Oh, Mrs. McLintock.
Much as I hate to agree
with G.W. about anything,
you haven't changed a bit.
You're still an hysterical fool.
- Come into town. I got worried.
- What about?
- Thought maybe Katie shot you.
- Not yet, Drago, but it took restraint.
Wait a minute. You better take Agard along,
not that he'll be much help.
- Drago, help him on the horse.
Just a minute.
- I'll drive.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Agard, what are you doing?
- Snatch him, Agard!
Agard,
this is serious.
Stay with him, Agard.
Stay with him.
Agard, will you stop showing off
and get in this buggy!
Mercy.
That horse is a little green.
Let's go.
Ya!
Just where
do you think you're going?
Don't use that range boss
tone of voice with me!
Carter!
We're headed
for Mr. Poorboy's mine.
Mount up some riders.
Right, Boss.
You heard the man!
I don't like it, Mr. McLintock.
I don't like it one bit.
- What don't you like?
- They're planning to hang an Indian!
Oh ho, Sheriff very funny.
Where's the whiskey?
Ha ha!
Hold it!
Not so fast,
Mr. Boss of the Whole Country,
unless you want to wear
a big hole in your middle.
How long is G.W. going to let
that cheechako push him around?
That cheechako
has a sawed-off shotgun.
How do you know she didn't
wander off someplace,
- or meet some fella, or something?
- What are you saying?
That I didn't raise my girl right?
That she'd wander off
all night with some man?
There's a lot of things
I'm not saying to you, mister,
while you got a sawed-off
shotgun in my middle.
But how do you know this Indian
had anything to do with it?
She's gone, ain't she?
She's gone!
Pa!
Pa, I'm over here!
- Been looking for me, Pa?
- Where you been, gal?
Young Ben took me for a sunrise ride,
and the horse wandered away.
- You come down off of there!
- But, Pa!
She's telling the truth, Mr. McLintock.
We wasn't doing nothing.
Well, that's not important right now.
The important thing is that
you don't draw that hog-legg,
or this'll be worse than
Dodge City on Saturday night.
You get on back to the wagon!
I'll tend to you later.
- Now for this young whippersnapper!
- Now, no harm has been done,
and Young Ben here is one of the
nicest boys in the territory.
So just put down that shotgun,
and let's forget it.
I'll teach him to fool with my...
Now...
we'll all calm down.
- Boss, he's just a little excited.
- I know, I know.
I'm going to use good judgment.
I haven't lost my temper in 40 years.
But, pilgrim, you caused
a lot of trouble this morning.
Might have got somebody killed.
And somebody ought
to belt you in the mouth!
But I won't.
I won't...
The hell I won't!
Oomf!
McLintock rider!
Yee-ha!
Ha haa!
Oh, McLin!
Hey, Buster...
remember me?
Aah!
Well, sir... nice party.
- Do you think you ought to?
- I "ought to" what?
Why, you big...
Yeeow!
Aaah!
Good morning, good party!
Great party!
Hey! Wait! I want a word with you.
Hey, just a minute! What... what are you...
My glasses!
Hey, now, stop this,
or you'll be sorry!
Oh, for heaven's sake!
- Stay out of this, Jake.
- It's everybody's war!
Aah!
Run, Old Paint!
Where's the whiskey?
Good fight, good fight!
- Ha, ha, ha!
- Oh, sorry, McLintock.
- Oh ho, McLin!
- Thanks
- Ha ha! Very funny!
- Yeah. Very funny.
Ohhh!
Gosh, Mr. Douglas,
I'm sorry!
Ha! Ha! Ha!
Bon voyage, Drago! Aahhhh!
Are you still down here?
Hey! Horse wandered away, huh?
Honest, Mr. Jones.
Honest...
Oh... get out of my way!
- Nice left.
- Thanks!
- I went to college!
- For this, you don't need college!
You're not
getting me down there!
Ohhh!
Owwww!
You beast!
You did this on purpose!
Why, McLintock, you big...
Good morning to you, Mrs. McLintock.
Bunny, you big... oaf!
Yeeoowie!
Oh, No!
G.W. McLintock, you big...
great big clumsy...
Well, it's pretty
hard to control yourself... Ohhh...
People, people, people!
Oh, McLin!
Oh, McLin, good party! But no whiskey.
We go home.
- You and your friends!
- Well, we at least saved your hat.
Oh!
Where is everybody?
Oh, for heaven's sakes!
Whoa! Whoa!
Drago, will you never
learn how to handle a team?
Yes, ma'am, I'll sure try.
I'll tell you that, now.
- Crummy family!
- You want to lose your pigtail?
I lose face!
- Lousy leathertips!
- You'll lose more than that!
- Kate.
- Yes?
We could be a big help
to one another.
Like what, may I ask?
Well, we could wash the mud
off of each other.
We used to have quite good times
doing that sort of thing.
There are a lot of things we used to do.
Good night, Mr. McLintock!
- Any luck?
- What are you talking about?
- I mean divorce! She still want it?
- Yeah.
You know something,
women are funny.
She fought like a wildcat on your side
out there this afternoon.
Come home... she slams
the door in your face.
That divorce business...
is that what you get when you pay
a woman not to live with you?
That's about it.
Some women I've knowed,
it'd be worth it.
You know, if we had
any moral character,
we wouldn't be standing here,
covered with mud, drinking...
- when we should be washing.
- G.W.
Drago.
Mrs. Warren,
these biscuits... mmmm!
Why, thank you, Drago.
- Good morning, Mrs. Warren.
- Good morning, Mr. McLintock.
Breakfast for the Boss?
If that's the way you want it, Mr. McLintock.
One poached egg, tea,
toast, lightly browned and un...
Why, Mrs. McLintock...
you have a black eye!
I do? Oooh!
- Oh! Ohh... and Becky's coming home today.
- And that's not all..
There's a little something
we'd better get settled.
Hmm?
There are no men listening now,
so we can be ourselves.
Oh, sure, I let you get away
with all that guff the other night,...
but now that we're alone...
When I want the opinion of
the hired help, I'll ask for it.
You know, you could wind up
with two black eyes.
What?
Oh... I realize you had
to put on that big act.
We always have to, just before
we get ready to forgive them...
generally for something
they haven't done.
But you and I both know, that's just to
keep them from getting the idea
they, uh... run things.
- McLintock give you that black eye?
- No!
Nobody gave it to me.
I won it.
- Morning, Davey.
- Morning, Mrs. Beech. Mr. Beech.
- Why, Miss Becky, welcome home!
- Mr. Douglas!
Hi, Dad!
- My boy! Ha ha ha!
- It's good to see you again!
Daddy!
Daddy! Oh!
It's been two long years!
I guess I'm going to have to
stop calling you "tomboy"!
- Becky.
- Mama!
- Oh, Mama! I wasn't sure you'd be here.
- Oh, I've been here a few days.
Oh, Becky, I've bought you three
of the most beautiful dresses!
Becky!
Uncle Drago!
Ohh!
Did you bring your old uncle
a coming-home present?
- Sure did!
- What is it?
A mustache cup!
And what did you get me?
Prettiest palomino pony that
ever packed a saddle.
Broke to stand ground-tied
in the county.
Uncle Jake! Ohh!
What are you doing
with Mr. Douglas' tuba?
Oh, Mr. Douglas has a fat...
had a little accident.
You know, I brought you a whole
shipment of licorice sticks!
But now that I've seen
how much you've grown,
I think we better exchange them for a
couple of bolts of dress goods, huh?
- Thank you!
- Oh, the mayor was going to be here,
but he had to go to the territorial capital
on a horse theft matter.
But I'm going to give his speech.
Oh, and don't worry about the mayor.
I'm sure that he can find
the bill of sale for the horse.
"Ladies and gentlemen,
we are here to welcome the fairest..."
What am I doing?
We are here to welcome back...
the prettiest girl
that was ever born in McLintock,
or in any part of the territory.
Now, this...
- Hey, Davey!
- Yeah?
Got something for you!
Yard manager up at the junction...
told me to let them ride,
so I locked them in here.
I've had my scalp
a long time,
and I aim to keep it!
Yatahe.
And now she's come back to us.
Gone are the pigtails....
But the freckles are still on the prettiest face
that was ever born in McLintock.
Hey, that's Puma.
Then it's true. The government
did turn them loose.
Good old Puma.
I'll never forget
when he brought G.W. home.
Your father had a hole
in his chest and a 104 fever.
Of course, they weren't
very mannerly about it.
He came past the house at a high lope
and threw him on the doorstep.
Then you do remember them
good old days, don't you, Katie?
"Katherine."
- Yatahe, my friends.
- Yatahe.
Puma, honored enemy.
Does Big McLintock forget,
also blood brothers?
No, I'll never forget that.
Old wound...
does it hurt still?
I feel it when it comes on to rain.
An inch higher, and I wouldn't
have had to worry.
Aw, Big McLintock,
that was remembered fight.
We return with news.
Our people have more trouble.
You see, I learn good English
now, Big McLintock.
Learned in white man's jail.
But we would have you talk
our cause at government hearing.
I understand that Governor Humphreys
is going to preside at that meeting.
Yes, Puma,
I'll translate your wishes.
Mr. McLintock, uh...
could I impose upon you to use your
Comanche to tell these chiefs that...
Puma is chief of the Comanches,
and he speaks English very well.
Ah, well...
Your people will have to follow
my instructions to the letter.
- It is the law of the land...
- We go.
Well, now, just a minute...
Well, for heaven's sakes!
You wait here, honey.
I'll get the buggy.
- Are you going to the McLintock party?
- Surely.
Will I see you there, Beth?
Of course, Davey, and you
can have the first dance.
Sis! Come on.
I don't want any sister of mine
talking to strangers.
Davey's not a stranger.
He clerks in Birnbaum's.
He's an Indian.
Darn you, Drago!
Now look what you've done.
Baby, this is Devlin Warren.
He works for your papa.
Dev, this is
Miss Becky McLintock.
Those are my things.
Yes, ma'am.
Aw, I'd have known you
anywhere, Miss Becky.
What do you mean?
Oh! I mean, you look so much like
your mother. Well, even prettier!
Well, Mr. Warren,
Mother's much prettier than I am.
Many a fight's started with words like that.
Come on, get in the buggy.
Hello, Ching!
- We got jelly pie for dinner?
- I'm not cooking!
No, he's not.
- Junior!
- Yes, Miss Becky!
- You remember Junior Douglas, Mama.
- Oh, of course. How's college?
- Valedictorian. 95.
- Oh, congratulations!
Oh, Mr. and Mrs. Douglas,
we will see you at the party, of course?
Oh, delighted!
Well, it'll be pretty hard
to keep young Matt away.
Yes, sir!
- Drago!
- Yes, Boss, baggage all loaded.
G.W.!
You remember young Junior?
Oh, yes.
Like father, like son.
Oh, uh, Mr. McLintock, uh, I hope
you don't think I'm being presumptuous
in asking for the honor
of calling on Miss Rebecca.
- Well, there she is. Ask her yourself.
- Well, thank you, sir!
Ching, now I'm gonna get fired.
Giddyap out of here!
Thank you, sir.
Thank you!
- Have you no manners?
- See you at the party, Junior!
- Yeah. Yeap.
- Yeah what?
Like father,
like son.
What did he mean, Matthew?
Come on, Ching,
grab a root and growl.
Well, you're doing
a good job, Miss McLintock.
Thank you, Mrs. Warren.
Dev, when you're finished there,
go over and help Drago with the beer kegs.
Yes, Mom.
Uh, Dev... could you come
and help me a minute?
I certainly was surprised
to hear you went to college.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Junior says Purdue's a good college
for a backwater place like Indiana.
Well, he did, indeed.
Oh, could you do this?
I can't reach it.
- Why didn't you finish college?
- Lack of funds.
My father got sick,
and he had to come out west.
So he took out a homestead.
You know, your mom's sure cute.
It's, uh, too bad you didn't inherit her eyes.
Well, you'd been lucky, if you'd inherited
a few things from your father.
Oh, really?
For instance?
- His common sense, for instance.
- Common sense?
Yeah. You don't see him being fooled
by some dude like Junior Douglas.
Junior's not a dude! He's nifty.
This needs a woman's touch.
- And besides, he got a letter at college.
- What sport?
- Glee club.
- Very strenuous.
Hmmph! Oooh!
Oh! Don't you dare hug me!
I have no intention
of hugging you.
Oooh!
Ladies all look
lovely, Katherine.
You know, this is a real fine party.
Oh, thank you, Ben. Of course, we had
to invite everybody.
Just everybody.
Sorry, G.W.,
this one's mine.
Well, thank you, Mrs. Warren. I guess I'll have
to be a good host in my own home.
- Well, the next one's yours, Mr. McLintock.
- Thank you.
- Drago, go and do what I told you to do.
- Oh, Katie!
"Katherine!"
And do as you're told!
"Ohh, Drago do this,
Drago do that!"
Yee-ha!
People, people, people!
- This Douglas feller...
- Drago!
Yes, ma'am.
Matt Douglas, junior...
is going to bring you folks some of the
latest terpsichorean dance steps...
brand-new, brought by him
directly from New York City.
All right, Mr. Fiddler.
Give me a whiskey!
- What?
- This turn a ten-gallon party, boss.
- We are run out of whiskey.
- Well, I can take care of that, Ching.
Indian!
And you still got any ideas
about asking my sister to dance,
get up, and we can do this
all over again.
Yes!
- That's enough! You fought it! It's all over!
- Quit butting in, Birnbaum!
- He's a hired man, not your son!
- Look, you fought him fair and square!
I don't think
it was so fair and square.
Well, you want to take up
where he left off?
If I did, you wouldn't
find it so easy.
Now, we've had
enough of this!
When are you going
to quit walking away?
Just as soon as we're
out of sight of the party.
"Don't fight in front of women."
- Well, we're out of sight now.
- So we are.
Such vulgarity.
Someone should do something about it.
You're right.
Absolutely right.
You all right, Young Ben?
I'm all right,
Mr. McLintock.
Pretty fancy fighting
for a country boy.
Two years at Purdue, Mr. McLintock,
on the boxing team.
I never thought
any farmer could whip me,
but you sure did.
Better get him cleaned up.
Get him some water, Jake.
Yeap.
Well, get yourself cleaned up.
Go ask that girl for a dance.
Who?
Oh!
Did I miss one?
Where is he? I'll find him,
that young whippersnapper!
Trouble.
Where is
that farmer boy? Where is he?
Where is he, G.W.?
Oh, so you're the young farmer boy,
that whipped my nephew!
Well, I'm Fauntleroy Sage,
Young Ben's uncle.
Well, I'm no farmer,
but if you're Young Ben's uncle,
yes, I whipped him,
and you're intruding.
- What's "intruding" mean?
- Butting in.
Oh, so he's insulting me!
Well, then I got another
reason for walloping him,
besides on account of him
thrashing my nephew Young Ben.
Fauntleroy, you can't get mixed
up in these youngsters' quarrel.
Family honor.
I can't have it said
a farmer whipped a Sage!
You're twice his size.
Don't let that
bother you, Mr. McLintock.
If Mr. Fauntleroy insists, I'll just have to
teach him the same lesson.
Say!
Sorry, young feller.
Hate to have to do that,
young fella. No hard feelings.
Not yet.
- Not yet, what?
- I mean, that isn't all.
Now, wait a minute.
Fauntleroy, we're gonna
make this a fair fight.
Course we are. Course we are, G.W.
There'll be none of this.
I wouldn't do that, G.W.
- You wouldn't do...
- Nooo, I wouldn't do that!
And, Dev, I don't want you kicking
Fauntleroy in the knee.
He didn't do no such thing!
And none of this nose-twisting.
He's all yours.
Where are my glasses?
You all right, young feller?
Ouch! I'm all right, if this Indian agent
will stop stepping all over me.
G.W, you was just funning me,
but I want you to know that boy
fought me a fair fight.
Well, I'm glad to hear that, Fauntleroy.
Where's my uncle?
Fauntleroy, what have you been doing?
- I hope my uncle didn't bother anybody.
- No bother.
I think we'd better join the ladies,
before they get curious. Drago!
Fauntleroy, let's
line them all up for a do-si-do.
Jake.
you think tincture of arnica would help?
Could be.
Used to help you.
Gentlemen,
to the medicine cabinet.
- Good morning, Drago.
- Morning, Becky.
You seen Daddy?
Took off early this morning with
a scatter gun over his arm.
Went hunting.
Oh.
- Morning, Daddy.
- Good afternoon.
What gets you out so early?
It's something I have
to get straight in my mind.
Yeah?
What?
Mama.
Why did you and Mama
stop living together, Daddy?
Why did you separate?
- Aren't you going to answer me?
- Nope.
- It's sort of my business, I think..
- I don't.
Is it another woman?
Usually is.
At your age,
you always know what's usual.
It's Mrs. Warren!
Becky, I don't want to start laying the
law down your first day back home,
but I'll have no more such talk.
The first time I ever saw
Mrs. Warren was last week.
She has a job here
at which she's very good,
and I hope you'll have
the good manners...
to not pry into
other people's business...
Your mother's and mine.
Pretty good shot, Daddy.
Oh, I can understand your trouble.
Mama's often so, well,
so petulant.
Petulant?
You learned a lot of words
back east, Becky.
I wished to God they would have
taught you some meanings.
You were only
about six months old
when your mother stayed alone with you in a
sod hut under eight foot of snow...
while I moved the herd 300 miles
south to try and save it.
Saved about half of it.
You were a little more than a year old
at the time of the great Comanche raids.
We stood off 500
Plains Indians for nine days.
Petulant, Becky?
I think you better go on home.
See that Ching gets those birds.
Becky!
Come here.
There's something I ought to tell you.
Guess now is as good a time as any.
You're going to have every young buck
west of the Missouri...
around here trying to marry you.
Mostly because
you're a handsome filly,
but partly because I own everything in
this country from here to there.
They'll think you're going to inherit it.
Well, you're not.
I'm going to leave most of it to...
well, to the nation, really, for a park...
where no lumbermill will cut down all the
trees for houses with leaky roofs.
Nobody will kill all the beaver
for hats for dudes...
nor murder the buffalo for robes.
What I'm going to give you...
is a 500-cow spread on the upper Green River.
Now, that may not seem
like much,
but it's more than we had,
your mother and I.
Some folks are going
to say I'm doing all this...
so I can sit up in the hereafter and
look down on a park named after me,
or that I was disappointed in you,
didn't want you to get all that money.
But the real reason, Becky,
is because I love you,
and I want you and some
young man to have what I had,
because all the gold
in the United States Treasury...
and all the harp music in heaven...
can't equal what happens
between a man and a woman...
with all that growing together.
I can't explain it any better than that.
All right, Daddy.
Becky!
When you're as old as I am,
you'll thank me for this.
Daddy, I'm full-grown.
I wasn't worrying about me.
I was thinking
about you and Mama.
Oh!
Well, all three of them fell
right out of the carriage.
Well, it's getting rather late, Becky.
It's bedtime.
Oh, Mother,
he brought this.
He must have intended to use it.
- Oh, well....
- Sing us a song!
Well, if you really want me to.
Gosh, I haven't played...
- You know "Just Right for Me?"
- Sure.
It's the rage now.
Oh!
Dev, what are you doing?
Oh, I, uh...
I just thought
I'd get another cigar.
Well, you've got one in your mouth
and two burning in the tray.
And that move.
The fellas want me
to play all the time.
You're cuter than
A baby steer
And softer than
A mouse's ear
I want the whole wide world to hear
You're just right for me
You're sweeter than...
Oh, no, not that rhythm, Junior.
Do it the way they do it at the Plaza.
- I know the words.
- Sure, Becky. Will you sing with me?
- Of course.
- Alright.
I love a man who's witty and smart,
And clever
It's your move.
Oh.
My heart forever
Oh, Dev, you're playing
like an amateur.
Let's call it an evening.
I'd like to know where your mind is tonight.
You're sweeter than the early stars...
Or bluebells when they start to...
Pretty good,
voice like her father.
You're just right for me
Sweeter than honey,
Finer than wine
I'm sure they found you,
On that honeysuckle vine
I would melt
In your embrace
You'd disappear
Without a trace
To die like this
Is no disgrace
This is the time,
This is the place, For you're
Just right for me!
Well, it's so good, I kind of
hate to break this up,
but we're going to have
that Indian hearing tomorrow morning...
Sir, about our conversation
earlier this evening,
- I believe I'd better apologize.
- Yeah?
Yes, sir, I've been thinking it over,
and when I called you a "reactionary",
well, that's merely my generation's
term for your generation.
- Nothing personal, you understand.
- Oh, really?
Well, good night, sir.
- Good night, Mrs. McLintock.
- Good night, and do come again.
- Good night, Drago.
- Good night.
Boss... what does "reactionary" mean?
Me, I guess.
He says that anyone that wanted to sell
at a profit was a "reactionary".
Was we "reactionaries" back in them days
when you was selling beef cattle...
for six cents a pound on the hoof?
Well, no use arguing with him.
College boy.
Devlin Warren,
if you was my kind of man,
you wouldn't let some dude walk off with
the prettiest girl west of Denver...
- without putting up some kind of fight.
- Does it show?
What can I do? I'm just one of
her father's employees.
I'm just a hired hand
around here.
Every so often, Dev...
you spill the strangest ideas.
Everybody works for somebody.
Me, I work for everybody
in these United States...
that steps into a butcher's
shop for a T-bone steak,
and you work for me.
There's not much difference.
Daddy, the most terrible
thing just happened!
Junior's horse ran away,
the one he rented at the livery stable.
You tied up a rented horse by the reins?
He's probably back in the stall by now.
I think we can get Junior
something that he can ride.
What I'd rather do, Daddy,
is drive Junior home in our barouche.
It's a lovely evening, and I'm sure
Uncle Drago wouldn't mind driving.
I would, and I got the kind of manners
don't keep me from saying so...
just to be polite.
I'll drive him home,
Mr. McLintock,
and you don't have to come, Miss Becky.
I'll see that he gets home safely.
- I can take care of myself.
- You got yourself a foot, didn't you?
- Dev, get the carriage. Drago.
- I'm going with them.
Now you got me
wrangling dudes.
You make a man
feel like a king
You're just right for me
Miss Becky, somebody better
help me watch the road.
You know, I'm new around here.
Might take the wrong turnoff.
Devlin Warren, you know there isn't
a turnoff between here, and town.
You disappear
without a trace
To die like this
Is no disgrace
- This is the time
- This is the place
Yah! Yah!
Devlin Warren, what are
you trying to do, kill us?
Would you rather
have your friend drive?
Yah!
Oh!
Daddy! Daddy!
I have never been
so humiliated in my entire life!
I said what I said, and I'll
stand by it to the death.
Shoot him, Daddy.
Shoot him at once.
- Well, why?
- My honor is at stake.
- Well, now, your honor
- Absolutely. He impugned my honor.
- "Impugned?"
What does that mean?
- Slander! He slandered my honor!
- He did?
I said what I said, and I'll
stand by it to the death.
He admits it! See?
Shoot him!
- Well, what is he admitting to?
- Why, he called me a...
I won't even repeat the word.
I didn't necessarily
call you anything,
but I said what I said, and I'll
stand by it to the death.
Well, just for the tally books,
what did you say?
I said that "any girl who would
permit a man to kiss her...
"before they're formally engaged
is a trollop."
He said it again! Shoot him!
- Now, hold on.
- No, don't hold on!
If you're my father, if you
love me, you'll shoot him.
Well, I'm your father, and I sure love you...
so...
Oh, you shot him!
You really shot him!
- Hey!
- If he dies...
If he dies, he'll be the first man ever
killed with a blank cartridge.
We use this to start
the races on the Fourth.
Hey, I'm on fire!
- Oh, you poor dear!
- Poor dear!
- You'd have had me shot in cold blood!
- But it didn't happen.
Yelling I insulted you, and all!
What you need is a good spanking!
Oh, Dev! Daddy!
Leave me out of this!
- Oh, I think I'll give you what you deserve.
- You wouldn't dare!
Oh, wouldn't I?
You'll think next time
before you have someone shot!
This kicking and yelling
isn't going to help!
Don't! Daddy, wait
a second! Daddy!
Ow!
Daddy, help me! Don't!
Devlin Warren, I hate you!
I hate you!
Mommy! Mommy!
Oh!
G.W, was that a shot?
Ohh!
- Becky, what happened?
- He spanked me!
You spanked my daughter?
Dev.
You mean you stood there while
that brute beat our daughter?
G.W, what's happened to you
in the last three years?
Better part of valor, son.
Isn't it enough that you've always
treated me like a squaw...
without subjecting dear, sweet Becky
to this crude, vulgar...
Katherine, you women are always
raising hell about one thing...
when it's something else
you're really sore about.
Don't you think it's
about time you told me...
what put the burr
under your saddle about me?
I don't intend to stand here
and hold a midnight conversation...
with an intoxicated man.
And I am not intoxicated...
Yet!
- Hello, Governor!
- Chief Puma.
- Yes, Sergeant.
Big McLintock, we know
you'll get us fair judgment.
You gentlemen, follow me.
- Well, Jake?
- G.W.
- Well, G.W., it's been a long time.
- Not long enough... Cuthbert.
- Your husband is a rude man.
- Yes, Cuthbert, I know.
Where you want the Indians,
Mr. McLintock?
Mr. McLintock is not
running this hearing.
- Sergeant, seat those Indians.
- Yes, sir.
Gentlemen, be seated.
Their whole tribe here
wanted to come into town.
Proceed, Lieutenant.
This hearing is now in session,
Governor Cuthbert Humphreys
presiding.
Good luck, Daddy.
I'm afraid
it's a packed court.
Government edict number 826.
"As ordered that the Comanche
nation be transferred..."
"from their present reservation
to Fort Sill,"
"it is the government's claim as
filed by Indian agent Agard..."
"that these chiefs, after being released
from prison by a kindly government..."
"did then rouse and incite defiance
among the tribe against said order."
It seems, gentlemen, that although some
of these chiefs speak English...
Chief Puma is quite at home
in our language...
they have chosen Mr. McLintock
to be their spokesman.
I speak for the Comanche,
or rather I offer this translation.
Proceed, Mr. McLintock.
The Comanches says...
"We are an old people,
and a proud people.
"When the White Man
first came among us,
"we were as many as
the grasses of the prairie.
"Now we are few,
but we are still proud.
"For if a man lose his pride
and manhood, he is nothing.
"You tell us now that if we will
let you send us away...
"to this place called Fort Sill,
"you will feed us
and care for us.
"Let us tell you this:
"It is a Comanche law
that no chief ever eats...
"unless first he sees that
the pots are full of meat...
"in the lodges of
the widows and orphans.
"It is the Comanche way of life.
"This that the White Man calls 'charity'
is a fine thing for widows and orphans,
"but no warrior can accept it,
for if he does, he is no longer a man...
"and when he is no longer a man,
he is nothing...
"and better off dead.
"You say to the Comanche: 'You are widows
and orphans. You are not men.'
"And we the Comanches say:
'we would rather be dead'.
"It will not be a remembered
fight when you kill us,
"because we are few now,
and have few weapons,
"but we will fight,
and we will die Comanche."
Thank you, Big McLintock.
Am I to gather the Comanche defy
the government of the United States?
Yes, you may gather that the Comanche
defy the United States government...
- or at least this commission.
- Gentlemen.
It is the order of this court, that these chiefs
be incarcerated until such time...
as the detachment
of United States cavalry...
be made avaible...
to escort them
and the Comanche nation to Fort Sill.
This court is adjourned.
McLintock,
you are important chief amongst these white people.
Sway them.
Have them give us few guns
to make the fight worthwhile.
Let us have one last remembered
fight for end of Comanche.
I almost wish
I could arrange that, Puma.
Aha loni cha!
- Sergent.
- Yes?
Left, right, carry on.
Gentlemen!
It's sad, these changing times.
It isn't the times
that are changing, Mama.
Hi, G.W.
Hello, Lem.
Bunny.
Oh, howdy, McLintock.
Figured you'd be
belly-down drunk by now.
I've been doing some
thinking drinking, Bunny.
Is that boxcar still on the siding?
- Well, sure, but...
- But what?
- I don't like it.
- You don't, eh?
You figure if
them Indians get out of there...
and lead the cavalry
on a wild goose chase,
that Great White Father's
going to get nosy.
Get nosy,
and he'll investigate,
and when they find out,
how that sidesaddle governor's...
been messing things up,
they'll give those Indians
a fair trial.
That's live ammunition
in that boxcar.
You know what will happen, if them Indians
get some guns in their hands?
Somebody is going to get hurt.
- Is Puma's word good enough for you?
- Well, I don't...
McLintock, you got yourself a partner.
Leave me out of this.
Hey, McLintock...
Ha ha ha.
Good night, Bunny.
Good night, Governor.
Governor!
Where is the Katie
With her light red hair?
Sweet as the roses
On the summer air
I'll find her somewhere
While the moon is high
And tell her
that I love her
And I'll love her till I die
Katie!
Katherine Gilhooly McLintock!
The master's home!
Katie!
"Katherine Gilhooly McLintock."
Where's the woman of the house?
Uh, Mr. McLintock.
Oh, there you...
Mrs. Warren!
Oh, good evening.
- I waited up for you, Mr. McLintock.
- Oh, how nice.
- I want to talk to you about something.
- Delighted, delighted.
- 309 times straight.
- I beg your pardon?
309 times straight, without a miss.
Got to be a record.
I suppose so. Now,
Mr. McLintock, what I wanted to say...
Two-pound Stetson with
6-inch brim,
53 feet in the air,
It's got to be a record.
I'm sure it is,
but the reason I waited...
Dagnammit, woman,
can't you hold that glass still?
Of course, sir.
Now...
Down the hatch
to my world's record.
Down the hatch!
Yes, sir.
And now...
to the governor of our territory.
T-t-the governor
of the territory, sir?
Now, don't you stick up for him,
Mrs. Warren.
You're a fine woman,
Mrs. Warren,
but you'll certainly go down
in my estimation...
if you stick up for Cuthbert H. Humphreys,
governor of this territory.
- I don't mean to change the...
- Down the hatch.
Aw... yes sir.
Down the hatch.
Cuthbert H. Humphreys, governor
of our territory,
is a cull.
Do you know
what a "cull" is, ma'am?
A "cull" is a specimen
that is so worthless...
that you have to cut him
out of the herd.
Now, if all the people in the
world were put in one herd,
Cuthbert is the one
I would throw my rope at.
At whom, at whom I would throw
my rope at.
Natural born "cull".
- Another touch, ma'am?
- Oh, no, sir, no.
- Well, I, I don't mind if I do.
- Good.
You can't walk on one leg.
Oh, I didn't mean to be vulgar, ma'am.
Can't walk on one limb.
It's all right.
Sounds silly.
Only a bird can walk on a limb.
You know my wife?
Her name's "Katie".
She insists on being called "Katherine".
Do you know her?
Of course, Mr. McLintock, and
that's what I wanted to talk...
Well, she thinks that Cuthbert H. Humphreys...
is panting for her like a bull buffalo
at the first green-up of spring.
But what Cuthbert is panting for
is my money.
Don't make me feel
like I'm drinking alone, ma'am.
Very well, Mr. McLintock,
if you insist.
- Down the hatch!
- Good!
Mr. McLintock...
I have something very important
to say to you.
Very important.
Guess it'll have to wait
till the morning.
Toodles.
Oh!
No, it's all right.
It's all right.
Beddy bye-bye.
Whoops... Oh!
Mrs. Warren,
Let me assist you.
Very kind.
Ooop... ooop... oop!
Aaah!
Whoops!
What's going on here?
Now, Katherine, are you going
to believe what you see...
or what I tell you?
Oh!
Uh, Mrs. McLintock,
hope you won't misunderstand.
It's the first hundred women sitting
on his lap that I misunderstood.
Number 101 is quite simple.
Now, G.W. McLintock,
I have something...
He's gone to sleep.
Just when I know exactly what I
want to say to him,
he goes to sleep.
I waited up
to talk to Mr. McLintock.
I wanted to tell him
I was quitting.
You see, Sheriff Lord has asked
me to marry him, and...
Oh, oh, congratulations!
I don't want to seem prudish, but if you
are going to marry Sheriff Lord,
it seems to me that you're
sitting on the wrong man's lap.
Oh!
Come on, I'll help you upstairs,
and we'll have a long talk
about men in general.
Ladies...
One moment!
Watch out!
You'll get us all killed!
Whoops!
Wait a minute, ladies,
till I catch my breath,
then I'll get you
up those stairs,
as sure as my name is
"George Washington McLintoooock".
- You may be quitting, Mrs. Wallace...
- Mrs. Warren.
But not tomorrow.
I want my breakfast in bed.
I want...
I know.
Toast, lightly browned...
Somebody sure put a knob
on my skull.
- It was Katie.
- Katie? Why?
Mrs. Warren was there...
Ooh...
And there you was, there,
and there the whiskey bottle was, there.
And Katie's temper being what Katie's
temper is, well... there you are.
Drago, old friend,
my wife does not understand me.
Why should she be
any different than any other?
Come on,
l got to get you up the stairs.
Get you ready for
that big celebration tomorrow.
Watch it!
Oh!
Drago...
I am sleeping in the den.
Hooligans!
Ain't got no respect
for your elders.
Bunny lost his temper!
Scallywags! Little imps!
I hope you get the measles!
Come on,
get him aboard.
Is everybody ready?
Uh, number five
needs a flank cinch.
Get him one.
Let us know when you're ready.
Ladies and gentlemen...
It is my honor to present to you...
the governor of our territory,
Cuthbert H. Humphrey.
Thank you, Mayor.
My friends and citizens of this
great territory,
this is the ninth
consecutive year...
it has been my privilege
and my pleasure...
to inaugurate the McLintock
Fourth of July celebration.
Now, the first event will be
the wild horse race.
But before I fire the shot to
start the event,
I would like to say
a few modest words...
regarding my stewardship
of this great territory.
Ride it, Ben!
Crush him! Crush him!
Whoo-hoo!
- All right, Professor Birnbaum.
- Gentlemen.
Sheriff, here's your horse.
Come on, get them all lined up.
Come here, Ching.
Now, boys,
you all know the rules.
It's twice around the inside
and once around the outside.
First cowboy that hits that finish line
without busting that egg is a winner.
And I caution you boys about
some of them eggs,
'cause some of them eggs
are last year's holdovers.
All right, mount up.
Katherine, my dear, you
seem to be enjoying yourself.
Oh, yes.
This is wonderful.
It's is the only thing l really do enjoy
about this barbaric country:
the Fourth of July celebration.
Well, Katherine, I've been here for three days.
I haven't heard from you.
- Is anything wrong?
- Wrong?
Well, I just hope that it hasn't been
necessary for you to say anything...
...to G.W.
What are you talking about?
Well, Katherine, you see, I'm
in a rather delicate position,
being governor of the territory
and all.
I just hope you haven't found it necessary
to say anything about...
About... what?
About you and me.
Why, you pompous windbag.
Do you think that you're the only man,
who's ever tried to play pattyfingers with me?
Who's ever tried
to lure me into the moonlight?
Well, no, but I...
Well, I'm a big girl,
and I can take care of myself.
My husband knows it.
I can assure you, Governor, that
your reputation is untarnished.
Now get out of my way.
Folks, we got ourselves a winner.
Curly Fletcher!
Mazel tov, Curly!
Give me the egg.
Disqualified!
Here you go, Curly.
G.W, G.W, you'll never believe
what happened over there.
What?
- You smell of beer.
- Well, naturally, I'm drinking beer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next event
will be a contest...
between the two bronco-busting
champions of ....
our territory
You remember the year
I rode in that event?
Wore your garters
to hold up my sleeves?
Shhh!
We had a bet, and I won it.
George Washington McLintock,
you are a very crude man.
Well, I guess so, but that was a rough horse,
like to jarred my insides loose.
But it was worth it.
Oh!
Free beers!
One... two... three...
Go!
Pull him, Dev
Pull him! Pull him!
- Dev, Dev, are you all right?
- I guess so.
Nothing busted but my pride.
Well, that ought to
even things up, farmer.
For what?
For that sore nose you gave me
the other day.
Well, that ain't
what's sore on him.
The closing event
is the cow pony race..
The finish line
is at the barbecue.
So, start meandering.
Come on!
Now, what is that?
False courage?
Why, you know a Douglas doesn't
ever use a thing like that.
I want you to get on that horse, get out
in front and stay out in front.
I'll be out in front, Dad,
- all the way.
- Aw, good boy.
Now, remember, stay out in front.
That Agamemnon's a good horse.
Whoah, Agamemnon.
11:40, and she's on time.
Whoah, boy! Dad!
Whoah!
Oh, McLin...
Big party.
Where's your whiskey?
- Whose idea was this stunt?
- Duck, doggone it, them are real bullets.
Reckon that's about
all the excitement you'd want...
for one Fourth of July, eh?
Old Puma finally got his way.
But I reckon he's riding out
his last war party.
Well, he won't get very far.
But one thing still has me puzzled.
Where did they get the guns?
I was wondering the same thing.
- My kidney's been bothering me...
- Bunny...
G.W.! Psst! Pssst!
What an idiotic joke!
- Joke! Do you think that was a joke?
- Well, shut up!
Do you want everybody in town
to see me?
You look good in feathers.
Oh!
- Dev, I think they've gone.
- Yeah!
What are you
going to do about it?
- What can I do?
- Nothing!
Just like you've always done!
Oh!
How long, G.W.?
- How long, what?
- Katherine.
She's been riding herd
on you for two years now.
I'm a peaceable man,
"You raise your voice,"
"it doesn't do any good,"
"it's time to raise your hand."
Well, I've been planning to do
something about it. I'll, uh...
- I'll have another talk with her.
- Talk to her?
Talk to her!
Talking won't do any good.
Becky, have you seen your m...
What's been happening
around here?
You've got hay all over you.
Been some mighty sneaky goings-on here
during that raid, Mr. McLintock.
Who was it said only a trollop would kiss
a man before...
they were formally engaged?
- Oh, but we are engaged, sir.
- You are?
That is, with your permission.
Well, you've got it.
Oh, Mrs. Warren?
I think it's wonderful.
I guess this is the only engagement,
that ever started off of a spanking.
Mm-hmm,
I reckon Birnbaum was right.
All right.
Lord bless us,
this is gonna be a great day.
Doggone it, folks,
let's don't let a little old Indian raid
break up a good barbecue and a rodeo.
- The meat's on!
- Let's go!
You contestants get ready
for the cow pony race.
"Shave and a Haircut, two bits"
- Who is it?
- It's me. Let me in.
Not now.
Right now!
- Are you insane?
- I want to talk to you.
It'll have to wait.
Oh, G.W.!
- I've taken all I'm going to take from you.
- You are insane.
You are going to tell me why you
packed up, picked up,
and walked out on me.
Two years ago... you remember...
you came home from Denver...
with lipstick all over your...
Aaah!
Lipstick on my collar.
- I've got the shirt to prove it.
- Who cares!
Why, you big...
Ah!
Katherine!
G.W., you are a ruffian.
Cuthbert, you are right.
Well, what kind of a family
is that?
The best!
And dangerous, fella.
Well, what happened?
Who won the race?
Who cares, Agard?
History's being made.
Yes, Rufus?
I regret to inform you I've changed
my mind about matrimony.
Rufus!
Hey! Mrs. McLintock!
Kath...
Katherine!
- Keep them out of here.
- Everybody out!
Looks like G.W.'s buying out
the whole store.
I'm afraid you're right.
Crummy family! Crummy family!
G.W!
Oh, G.W, G.W!
Oh, oh, G.W, G.W!
Aah!
Oh, Mrs. McLintock, you're all wet!
- Am I? Try it!
Wrong woman, G.W.
Oh, pardon me.
Mrs. McLintock,
you setting a new style?
Uh!
Shhh!
Mr. McLintock! In here!
If I ever get through this humiliation,
you will rue the day you ever met me!
Oh, bellyache and fight all you want.
It won't do you any good.
You've been digging those burrs
into me for two years.
Now, you're going to get
your comeuppance.
Thanks.
My father would be proud of you!
Then I'll make him prouder.
Stop it!
Aah!
Keep it.
You may need it.
Now get your divorce.
Oh!
Oooh!
- Home! Don't spare the horse.
- Home? Are you...
You heard me.
Don't think you're going
to get rid of me that easy.
Yah!
- No more living in the capital?
- No.
- No more Newport in season?
- Nope.
No more dancing
at the Governor's Ball?
No, G.W.
Happy days!
310 times,
without a miss.
That's a record.