No bad writer. Good style,
rich imagination. Very talented.
-Thank you.
-No problems.
-Room B, room A, wonders where room E is.
-I do not know.
-Are you going to the lecture?
-No.
We're looking for where she's going.
-Oh! Sorry.
-Excuse.
-Where is the Waterbury lecture?
- Are not you Owen Waterbury?
-Follow me.
-Where are you taking us?
-To room E.
-Are you a student or teacher?
Student.
-Advanced or beginner?
-What do you think?
I think you seem advanced.
-Mr Waterbury. You arrive on time.
-Mr Kilbride.
We have to wait for the laundry.
The underpants are not dry yet.
-My friend, Mr Ronnie Hastings.
-Good day, Mr Hastings.
-I'm going to get a chair.
-No, I'm sitting in the audience.
-Good day.
-Are you also going to become a writer?
-I hope so.
-The lecture will be very helpful.
-A great writer.
Most of his spreads
come from me, of course.
- You're in my seat.
-Sorry.
-Godafton, miss Gaylord.
-Mr Scott.
-Is this busy?
- Clarence Henderson is not coming.
-Why do I have to move?
-We do not talk to each other.
May I ask for your attention?
Tonight's guest lecturer
-is Owen Waterbury, author of the
bestseller "Last Year's Love".
Higher!
It is enough.
Most of you have
a job to do during the day.
Still, you have studied
writing technique in the evenings.
Now you are ready to take the pen
and go out and conquer the world.
I'm not the right person to
teach you because I do not follow any rules.
Today, a writer must think about both
the bestseller list and his art.
A conflict of loyalty
that breeds dishonesty.
WHAT DO YOU WORK WITH?
Now I have got in the middle of the dry
and intend to write a really good book.
I AM SECRETARY
The beautiful writing art
is here and here.
If the mind and the heart do not find
the right words, do not write.
Is he not brilliant?
A writer must believe in
himself. Then half the battle is won.
I interrupt the lecture for
a moment to say that ...
... I'll be able to help
someone in the room now.
From tomorrow
I will need a secretary.
The school's agency is informed
and the right man or woman gets the job.
DO YOU WANT THE JOB?
It's not a great job,
but the work environment is nice.
HOW DO I GET IT?
SEARCH IT, STUMP!
- Are you going to work for Owen Waterbury?
- Got the job from his staff man.
-Have heard strange things about him.
-You do it about everyone.
-The lecture was so inspiring.
-You have worked here for five years.
A little too long for someone
with my ambitions.
-Where does Mr Waterbury usually work?
-In his apartment.
An author does not work in an office.
He can teach me to be a writer.
In a year, I might sign
my own books at your bookstore.
-After a course by Owen Waterbury.
-And get paid at the same time.
-I'll miss you, Steve.
-No, in a week you've forgotten me.
No, but good luck anyway.
You probably understand how I feel.
You've been amazing to me.
I understand.
Steve! Call sometime
and tell me how it goes.
I'll call tonight,
when I've got the job.
-See you for how to park!
-You can back out!
Save your energy until we get up.
Give me the bags.
I can carry them.
Taxi drivers are not wise.
Floor 3 E.
A single nasty word from him
and you cut.
- They can take my license.
-You're defending a lady.
-You know I have hard fists.
-The harder the better.
- Is that a big guy?
-1.80 meters bluff.
Then I floor him.
How do you think I got this nose?
-Sure he can not fight?
-He is a writer.
-If he even opens his mouth ...
-Then I close it.
-I'm going to get my things.
- Do you mind?
He does not have that. Come on, Bill.
-Take the box and put everything in the bag.
-Yes Lady.
Not the box, just what's in it!
Come in! Come in!
Mr Waterbury's former secretary.
She quit this morning. Sit down.
This is my mink fur. So it so.
She got it from
Mr Waterbury as a Christmas bonus.
-My typewriter.
-It was ... New Year's bonus.
-Min "aujourd'hui".
-She brought it here herself.
-My pot.
-She ... cooks sometimes.
-My whiskey.
-She drank a little.
-My cigarette case.
-She also smoked.
-My lipstick.
- Shall we go to the library?
Your sausages.
- Goodbye, Mr Waterbury.
-Good luck for you that you did not open your mouth.
Come on, Bill. Do not care about
those who are inferior.
What can I do for you, miss?
-This is your new secretary.
-Yes, from Kilbrideskolan!
Look! She spilled ink
all over the carpet! It does not go away!
-Try to get it clean.
-No!
The hostess said that I would not
clean up anymore but just the usual.
-Do you want help?
-This will go well.
-I'm an expert on this.
-He gets spots like that every week.
-This is feminism.
-A woman did it.
The landlady would claim $ 100
on top of the rent in damages.
-I got on the dress.
-You take the carpet and I take the dress.
-I can take the dress.
-I'm taking the dress.
I'm taking the kitchen.
Do you like hot dogs? We take it
for lunch, and steak for dinner.
I have not
been interviewed yet!
-What's your name?
-Stephanie Gaylord. Steve.
We're taking her.
-Stenography?
-120 words per minute.
Do you wash? Learn to wash
120 silk shirts per minute.
-I'm cooking.
-And eats.
I live next door,
but I have no kitchen.
We share a kitchen,
he cooks the food and he eats.
We went to school together. I in
kindergarten and he in eighth grade.
When I went to high school,
he was still in kindergarten.
-I am in every single book.
-Who were you in my last?
Ballet girl
who was disappointed in life.
-Where did you work before?
-I?
Hos Charles Harris.
He owns all the "Harris Bookstores".
-How does Waterbury sell latest?
-Two after the Bible.
-Are you married?
- I do not care about that.
Not that?
My cookies are burning.
The secretaries' husbands
are usually a little awkward.
They were murderous.
He has very strange working hours.
That was it.
I did not think the
job would be like this.
Today was a bit unusual.
We will not be disturbed anymore.
We must work in a dignified
and cultural atmosphere.
Your bookmaker.
-Mary, he's here again!
-I heard.
-How much is it now then?
-Elva dollar.
No more stable tips.
Next time, I'll pull a load of ice.
-What are we guilty of?
-Owen 278, and you a dollar.
Here. I can not pay mine
until next week.
-Do you want to bet today?
-I'll call in that case.
No more 50 cent stakes.
The boss does not like it.
-Where was I?
-You talked about dignity and culture.
Right. Your other information ...
I open!
Have you interviewed my daughter Mary
Hastings for a secretarial job?
I have a message for you.
-I do not think I want the job.
-Why not?
You spoke so inspiringly
at the lecture.
Your novels are of such high quality
and have such a fine message.
But it's ruined now ...
Do not get angry ...
but try to find someone else.
If that's how you feel,
Miss Gaylord.
- Are you leaving Waterbury in the lurch?
-Don't ask her, call the agency.
-We both like her.
-Should I have to call the police?
They are probably already here.
I would pick up the rent.
-I sent a check this morning.
-You know that I live under you.
-No injuries this month?
-An uneventful month.
The carpet again?
Oh my God!
The fish should be here! And the duck
up here. You disturb the harmony of the room.
I heard you screaming.
New secretary?
-Employed or fired.
-New hire.
Sin. It has just moved in someone
above who would fit perfectly.
-The position has already been filled.
-You should meet her anyway.
Felicia!
I'm coming, Mrs Reeves.
This is
the famous Owen Waterbury.
-That's him.
-Good day.
Felicia wants to be a movie star.
Who does she remind?
Do not say anything. Let me guess.
ZaSu Pitts.
Felicia is a very good
secretary and a nice actress.
Take off your coat
and show them.
-She is very talented.
-I was a model in Texas.
But I wanted to make a career here.
Dad pays for everything.
-You'r friend?
-No, my father.
Felicia may be able to play the heroine
when your next book is filmed.
-How is the heroine?
-A girl from the South.
-I'm from the South!
-What a coincidence!
She's trying to catch a rich man,
she's not serious ...
... and silly.
-What is it?
- I can imagine unserious ...
-... but silly ...
-It works out.
-You can play silly, right?
-I can try.
I go to theater school. There maybe
I can learn to be silly.
-If you study hard.
-It requires a lot of work.
I have not started writing it yet.
I get interrupted all the time.
We'll let you work. I have 50
guests tonight. You entertain well?
Is it informal or should I swim?
If you are not in charge of the entertainment
at my parties, you have to pay the rent.
-Now I go to the races.
-You do not have a chance.
She inherited seven properties
from her husband and now she snoops constantly.
I stayed so as
not to embarrass you in front of the hostess.
-But I'm going to go now.
-What an idea!
-Write this down.
-Write it down, where's the block?
I need a pen.
Wait, I have a pen here.
We call it
"Notes for my new novel".
That's enough for the moment.
Tomorrow morning at ten o'clock.
He incubates. Finally he broods.
-Is he always like that before a book?
-Yes always.
At the post for "Last
Year's Love" I made a cake.
Suddenly he called out to me
and I had to take the dictation.
At three o'clock at night
we had to eat ash with chocolate.
See you at ten o'clock tomorrow morning.
I could not wait
so I call myself.
-How is the job?
-I ... have to learn a little.
-It ... is a very unusual job.
-I can imagine.
-He has started a new novel.
-What is it about?
He did not get that far, but it will
certainly be good. He's so enthusiastic.
-Should we have dinner this week?
-I call when I'm free.
A VIRTUAL WOMAN
Stephanie Gaylord
A CONFUSED WOMAN
Good morning!
-What you are up early!
-It's ten o'clock.
Have you never imagined in mink?
Keep the pen ready, the genius gets dressed.
I make mashed potatoes for lunch.
I go out to the kitchen and iron.
Good morning, Steve. In time and everything.
Let's see now ... What did we write yesterday?
"Notes for my new novel."
I open.
Hi.
-Hello.
-What did we write?
- "Notes on my new book."
Write "Notes for My
New Novel, by Owen Waterbury".
-Great! - Is it not?
- Fantastic!
Chapter one:
presentation of the novel characters.
-Chapter Two ... I'll take it tomorrow.
-A chapter a day! Are you tired now?
Can you answer the phone? I go
to the beach and get some sea air.
- Shall we go to Santa Barbara?
-Wherever you want.
Do not care about him.
He's trying to make you jealous.
Why do you think I'm
even interested in him?
Are you angry that you
have been given time off today?
It's done. I can't sit here
idle. I came here to work.
I came here to
do nothing and now I work.
You get paid to be unemployed.
Take care, you idiot!
There smoked another!
May I ask you something?
Is Mr Waterbury
really going to write a book?
Interesting question. Waterbury
is a genius. What do you think he's doing now?
-Ruvar.
-When he feels like this, something good happens.
-He's probably writing a lot tonight.
-Are you jealous?
I do not even know Mr Waterbury.
And I do not know if I want to.
-What am I doing wrong?
-All. Ge hit.
-How can you get so many folds?
-I think he does it best.
-There are nice shirts.
- They were.
I just came to think of something.
I have to be completely out of my mind!
I have studied for a year to
become a writer and stand and iron!
It's not clear yet.
It's Owen Waterbury.
Come tomorrow morning at nine o'clock.
Finally I have a spread.
Good spread.
No horse can beat him.
-Good morning.
-Keep the coat on. The taxi is here.
-Where are we going?
-The horse races.
-I've never been there.
-Good, beginner tour.
-But the spread ...
-We take it after the third race.
-I can not follow.
-You get paid! Come now.
What happened...?
That was not a good tip.
-The job has cost me 83 dollars.
-You should get it back.
-No! I played and lost.
-Losing is good for the soul.
We have the three best souls in town.
-Good morning.
-The planet takes off in 35 minutes.
-Where?
-To Las Vegas and win $ 83.
-I can 't go to Las Vegas!
-Are you complaining that you get paid?
I can not afford to work
for you anymore, Mr Waterbury.
-It only takes an hour and a half.
-You have time to go home for dinner.
-With lots of money.
-No, I'm not going!
Seven, you lose.
No dollars!
We're not in Los Angeles here.
Come on, now it's time.
Bet on four.
-Four!
- Seven, you're losing.
Right side now again?
-When are we leaving?
-I have lost 3,000!
-We would take the twelfth plane.
-It goes at one o'clock as well.
I thought that job
would be uplifting.
Craps, you lose!
- Did you see what you did?
-I did nothing.
I bet on craps.
It was going to be so intellectual.
-Craps again!
-Do you do it on purpose?
-What have I done?
-It's nice, stump.
-She bets on craps.
- Can't you hit something else?
I would
only meet literary people.
Craps!
I've never seen that before.
No more craps.
Think about what you do when you throw.
Put everything on the seventh.
Now she has to do it.
-I also write a novel.
-Craps!
-What is it?
-Think about what you do when you throw!
How dare you talk to me like that ?!
You can throw yourself.
Craps!
IM rich! Here with the money.
-Miss Gaylord! Where are you going, Steve?
-Home. I never want to see you again.
You're a cheap, selfish scam.
I do not want to deal with you.
Why should I meet you?
The image of the author is destroyed.
You must not go home alone, I
will follow you. I want to talk to you.
A person can be completely changed
when she starts playing.
-I am terribly sorry.
-Then stop, and start working.
-I think I'm scared.
-For what?
Afraid I'm not
the great writer I used to be.
I'm just a
commercial dozen writers.
Did you not see how everyone at the university
treated you with respect?
-Write a love novel again.
-It's going backwards.
Stay tuned. Think of the
clown who wanted to play Hamlet.
If you tell yourself that you
are a failure, you will be.
- Do you still work for me in that case?
-If you work, I work too.
I'm poor again.
I switched to sevens.
It's open! Come in!
Hi, Steve. Keep the coat on, the
taxi will arrive in a minute.
We will work
in the house on the beach.
He is superstitious
and always starts writing there.
Didn't you like "Last Year's
Love"? Most of it came to that.
-Should I take the typewriter?
-No, I'm dictating today.
Come on, Steve.
I dictate a draft
and then refine it.
A successful writer
who was going under ...
... morally and spiritually,
until a girl appeared.
Then everything became different.
He had seen her
during a lecture one evening.
He glimpsed a lot of faces
in front of him, but only saw hers.
Longing and wonderfully beautiful.
He said nothing but hired
her as a secretary.
At that very moment, he knew that
he was hopelessly in love with her.
One day they would work in the beach
house where he wanted to tell everything-
-but he did not dare.
Do not interrupt me when I work!
-Where was I?
- "He did not dare to tell."
She sat in front of him ...
soft and brittle like a poem.
He had looked around the corner
and there he had found her.
-What is it?
-I dropped the pen.
Shall we continue?
He ... wanted to take her in his arms and
pull her to him, but did not dare.
He did not know her
but still he knew her.
He walked around dictating
and looking at her bow ...
-What is it?
-Nothing.
Where was I?
Her collar.
He looked at her wonderful hair,
blue eyes and finely shaped mouth.
He was inspired by
this living creature.
He wanted to embrace her, kiss
her and drown in her soul.
But ... he was cowardly.
-What do you think?
-It ... can be anything.
Suddenly he released
all inhibitions ...
... leaned
over her and kissed her.
She melted in his arms
and offered no resistance.
Without words, they fell into each other's
arms in a silent embrace ...
You've got the wrong girl.
Now I'm leaving you.
Never contact me again.
You can give the salary to the next victim.
If I ever see one of
your books again, I'll burn it!
I've cooked dinner for all three of us.
Ask Steve if she likes donuts.
Steve has stopped.
She got pissed and went in the middle of the
dictation and slammed the door.
She's not smart!
I ask them to send a new one, one that
likes chicken because we'll eat it.
Do not call anyone. It will be a long time
before I start working again.
-Gone, I'm going to wash the keys.
-I compose.
I've never heard anything good from you yet.
There we have it! Do it again.
Thank you.
-What is it called? "I have a cold."
-Sing.
- I can not ...
-I just want to hear how it sounds.
Sad.
-Get water!
-In the kitchen.
That's where it burns!
This should be enough.
-You and your cooking.
-Your monks are exploding!
-Call the fire brigade.
-No, they just pour water.
This is
what I'll tell the hostess.
-I'm not going to clean up.
-Then you get no pie.
-What's in the trash?
-Pie.
30 failures out of 31 attempts.
31 failures.
We have the grilled chicken.
-What is it?
-Grilled chicken.
Made it in the pressure cooker.
It melted a little.
-He's probably eating out tonight.
-I also. I'm not eating this.
-Hey, Owen.
-He has fried chicken for you.
It is my duty as your domestic worker
to talk about what happened in the kitchen.
-Mr Ronny was setting fire to the kitchen.
-He can suck on the whole floor.
-There you got so you kept quiet.
-I'm going to tell the hostess.
-What happened in the beach house?
-Don't ask so stupid. She's quit.
-How did she dare?
-There are more secretaries.
Equally good at fishing
and just as sweet.
You never got to know
how well she typed.
-I'm calling the agency.
-No, I know something better.
I'm going to pack.
I'm going to New York.
Environmental change.
I work better there.
Terminates the floor ....
-What about me?!
-What do you think?
I'm not going to let a little
secretary get me off balance.
I also want to live,
a wonderful, exciting life.
I have a fantastic book inside me,
with intensity and breadth.
I'm actually happy about this. Now I
stand with my feet on the ground again.
It can still be used.
Elsie called and apologized for
running away and for the driver.
Tomorrow Steve calls and
apologizes, but then I'm gone.
Why am I running away?
I'm not afraid of her.
-Then a true Owen Waterbury sounds.
-We invite Elsie to dinner.
We go out and eat with them all.
one every night.
Bryant's detective agency?
This is Owen Waterbury.
I want you to shadow a girl,
Stepahnie Gaylord.
-Tonight we'll have a nice time.
-Happily for me.
Good evening.
Why here? You've always
disliked Ridgely Room.
- He's kidding.
-Sure he dislikes it?
-Yes, I do too.
- A gentleman is looking for you, Mr Waterbury.
Go and sit down with Elsie
and I'll be here soon.
Yes, but do not go.
Do not let Elsie pay the bill again.
-Where is he?
-In alcove number two.
Is that him?
-You wanted to talk to me.
-Bryant's detective agency. Devony.
-That went quick.
-She is sitting with the man there.
Should I find out who he is?
Then I shadow them both.
Find out all you can.
She seems in love with him.
-Is it your wife?
-My secretary.
-Don't let anyone notice this.
-Not even you will notice anything.
-Check her past.
-It's going to be expensive.
We've checked out a girl. It took a
year before the past caught up.
-Do a good job.
-Yes, pay my bill.
-Cigarettes?
-A package, please.
Hey, Steve!
-Silence, I'm mad at her.
-Oh, I forgot.
-Good evening.
-Do you know him?
-My new boss.
-Charles Harris, the bookseller.
-Steve's old boss.
-He's not that old.
-How dare you work for him?
- Do you have to take her old boss?
-She took mine!
Mr Harris wanted someone
with a literary background.
You've only worked for Waterbury.
-Steve is out with his former boss.
-Who is Elsie out with then?
Talk about Steve and keep me out.
Harris has probably hired you
to spy on me.
-I'm an excellent secretary.
-When did you learn to type?
-Has he asked about me?
-Just the usual about my experience.
-You did not say anything, did you?
-Stop joking about everything.
I can tell you something funny.
They will get married.
-What did you say?!
-They will get married!
-Where are you going?
-I'm going to talk to her.
-Grilled chicken.
-And my lord?
I also take a glass.
-Hi.
-Good evening.
-Mr Harris, Mr Waterbury.
-Congratulations, I just heard that.
You are getting married to Stephanie.
Can I dance with the bride?
-Thanks.
-By all means.
-So she married the wrong guy.
-Are you going to dictate a novel again?
-Why do you take someone you do not love?
-I'm not getting married to anyone.
-Now I respect you.
-Yes and everyone who does not want to get married.
- Are you going to work for him again?
-Is it quiz or dance?
We can do both.
- Do you want your old job back?
-No.
I'm giving you a bonus. We are getting married.
To you, it sounds like
marriage was cheap and vulgar.
Only Owen Waterbury invites one
and dances with another.
Give back and invite Mr. Harris.
-I would never dance with the boss.
- Are you telling me that?
Not until I had
worked for him for a few days.
So nice.
I can finally
hold you in my arms.
-We dance!
-Yes, yes, but I like you.
-You'll be back, like the tide.
-You're crazy!
Everything I said in the beach house was true,
but I did not dare admit it.
I love you.
Marry me, dare chance.
The author is looking for words.
I love you, marry me.
Lady's chicken.
Chicken in a glass for the gentleman.
Harris looks lonely.
Mr Harris,
this is Ronnie Hastings.
Do you not want to sit down
and have a glass of grilled chicken?
Have you heard the story
of the unholy three?
-Sorry, I'm going home.
- Can you drive me home?
-What about me?
-Watch the show.
-Shall We Dance?
-Most gladly!
- Are you a gigolo?
-I'll probably start with that tonight.
Life is strange. When
you wake up you never know what you will do in the evening.
Oh dear!
Also order a Remington
typewriter for the other office.
Mr Harris' office. A moment.
Hello? Yes.
What ?! When then?
Thank you, goodbye.
-Did something sad happen?
-Waterbury and Steve are married.
- He did not!
-Yes then.
-Imagine she took him!
-Imagine he got married!
In front.
Welcome to the honeymoon.
Congratulations!
May I
be the first to kiss the bride?
- Am I the first?
-The bride is a little sleepy.
-How long have you been driving?
-Las Vegas round trip.
-Whose bags are these?
-Felicias. Now she does not want to stay.
-Talk about threshold. Three stories.
-Take the threshold up there.
-Hi Felicia.
-Congratulations. You did well.
I'll help you move in
when I helped Felicia out.
Can't move into the
gate next door?
To the home of old ladies.
-Hey, Mary.
-I'm so happy for you.
-Thank you, Mary! - Strange of her.
-Yes.
-Hello Darling.
-Hi Sweetheart.
"Your luggage,
madam and sir."
I've made a wedding breakfast.
Spaghetti with meatballs.
That was kind of you, but we want to
be alone on our honeymoon.
Be kind to him, Steve.
He is my livelihood.
-Are you glad you married me?
- Are you asking that now?
It was a moment of inspiration
and you are so changeable ...
I never change about you.
You're the best thing that ever happened to me.
-Where is floor 3 E?
-Who are you looking for?
It only applies to those on floor 3 E.
Next floor in the corridor.
Excuse.
-Yes?
-I want to talk to Mr Waterbury.
He does not want to be disturbed
right now. He...
-... he's a little busy.
-My name is Devony.
Say that the woman
he is interested in has married.
Owen!
Can you come for a while?
What's the matter now?
A Devony came here and
said he wanted to talk to you.
He said the woman you
were interested in got married.
-Are you interested in a married woman?
-There is only one.
-I want to see Mr Waterbury right away.
-Owen!
The awful chicken is here!
- That's what we say in all kindness.
-What's the matter now?
-Excuse!
I did not know
that your secretary worked overtime.
-They are married.
-Married? Then she should hear this.
-What can I do for you?
-I would pick up the rent.
-I paid the first one.
-There are new rules now.
I do not take checks without coverage.
-Shen when?
-Since you moved in.
- Do you have $ 485 in the bank?
-I think so.
Can you write a check
so I can sort this out?
-How can I have so little money?
-6,000 on dice.
-Two dollars for marriage license.
-You have to live.
Thanks honey.
Thank you Mrs Waterbury. I did not
think I would call Mrs Waterbury.
-I'm following you out.
-Thank you, Ronnie.
- Does it have coverage?
-She's tight.
An explanation is in place.
Yes, I absolutely want to explain.
Excuse.
-Hey, Owen.
-Congratulations, we just found out.
Thanks Birdie. - Darling! -
Do you not want to settle down?
Honey, this is my publisher,
Mr Folton and Birdie. - My wife.
You do not take an
extra long honeymoon, do you?
No, I was going to dictate
my honeymoon in the beach house.
You have a deadline for the novel
that you must meet. You know why.
-It is finished.
-I trust you.
-Do you want something to drink?
-Thank you, we are in a double lane on the street.
-How is Ronnie?
-Good apetite.
She says that when he dies, the
crematorium has to grill him slowly.
- Do you know Ronnie?
-Yes, I have also been a secretary.
Thanks for stopping by, Dick.
-Nice honeymoon.
-Thanks.
Why did Mr Folton
look at you so accusingly?
I owe him 20,000.
I took out an advance on the next book.
Did Mrs Folton
get her mink fur from you?
Birdie? I had written
a bestseller and wasted.
Give it
in installments to Mr Folton.
-You should get a hundred coats.
-I can not afford that.
-Your rent devours everything I have.
- Did you take me for my money?
-No, but maybe you did.
- We're leaving.
I know a cabin in the mountains where
we avoid publishers, hostesses ...
-... and secretary?
-Except you. And I'm going to work!
I'll make sure of that.
-How long have you been working on the book?
-Four months.
I'm pretty proud of this one.
-Where is Mrs Waterbury?
-She buys. We offer dinner.
Unfortunately, I can not stay.
I have to take the next train home.
-Now say what you think of the book.
-I'm going to say it outright.
-You do not like it.
-It's lousy.
The worst junk I've ever read.
You would perish
if I published this.
-Fortunately, I have another on lye.
- Am I out?
-No, this happens to all writers.
-I owe you money.
I got hold of deer ...
- Mr Folton! Nice to see you again.
- Do you like deer?
-Unfortunately I can not stay.
-Why not?
-An important meeting in town.
Such a shame.
I had planned to cook my specialty.
It will have to be another time.
Goodbye, Mrs Waterbury.
- Hi then, Owen.
-He does not like it.
-No.
- Do you think he's right?
-He has always had that.
Until he married Birdie.
He may have changed.
He may see you
with different eyes.
He does not publish a book where he sees
his wife in your arms on every page.
-He only sees Birdie in the book.
-Birdie meant nothing.
He is human and man,
even though he is a publisher.
-We're leaving here tonight.
-Tonight?
You blame me for this.
Not directly. It feels strange
that your wife is a secretary too.
I need to write a new book quickly,
and ... I need a new secretary.
-Have I been fired?
-It's getting better for both of us.
Then you get a chance
to write your own book.
Now I'm making dinner.
-I have finished writing my book.
-Have you? Can I read it?
It's been
on your bedside table for two weeks.
-I read it on the train.
-You do not need that.
-You're hurt.
-No.
Call and book tickets and
ask Ronnie to find a new secretary.
Mrs Waterbury!
Have you had a nice honeymoon?
-It's nice in the mountains this year.
-Yes.
-An original Waterbury?
-The last.
-Steve! Sit down.
-Thanks.
-You look splendid.
-Four months in nature.
Would you do me a favor?
Folton does not like Owen's latest
book. Read it and say what you think.
-I will try to be objective.
-I know you are.
And here is my own manuscript.
It has taken a long time.
I have changed the title
so many times.
But I stuck with
"Dawn's longing."
Owen has not read it yet. He
has been busy writing.
-He could not concentrate.
-I will read both with pleasure.
Tack, Charles.
-Hi then, Steve.
-Bye.
-I can not find Waterbury on 3rd.
- Here's Mrs Waterbury.
I come from the agency.
Mr Waterbury is looking for a secretary.
That way? This way.
It will be so exciting
to work for Mr Waterbury.
-I barely had time to get dressed.
-You're so nice.
-I sew my clothes myself.
-Oh really?
Come in, miss ...
What was your name?
Hilda Schniedbacker.
This is your new secretary,
Owen.
This is our neighbor, Ronnie.
-Do you want something to drink?
- Do you have beer?
We have salty biscuits too.
I could
drink a whole thin beer.
-What did you ask for when you called?
-I thought they knew what we were looking for.
It's not necessary.
Bring the beer
and come and sit here.
-Can you wash?
-Shirts and socks, not sheets.
Have a seat.
- Do you use to play on horses?
-Yesterday I got two winners.
-Perfect! What coat size do you have?
-Do I have to wear a coat at work?
All secretaries
receive a mink coat as a Christmas present.
If I had known about it
, I could have saved the vomit.
Who can she mean?
I will thrive here.
You are all so quirky.
-Do you mind working overtime?
-Not at all.
I have not
seen my roommate since New Year's.
I'm afraid
it's going to be a little too difficult for you.
Some passages are in French.
You can not do that, can you?
Dad spoke French for six years.
And I've had a French boyfriend.
Can't we have a stenographer?
-Stenograph? I can not.
- Can't you?
No, they said
it was just typing.
It's mostly shorthand.
-I can learn.
-Unfortunately not.
-Then I was out of the game.
-Put away the glass!
Thanks for the beer.
It must be next. I asked the
agency to send several pieces.
-Hello, is it floor 3 E?
-Yes.
- Does a Mr Owen Waterbury live here?
-I'm Owen Waterbury.
-I come from the agency.
-Dawn O'Malley.
-And.
- Come in, Miss O'Malley.
-Thanks.
Have a seat.
This is my wife.
- Do you stenograph?
-120 words per minute.
-Talar ni franska?
- "My mother was French."
"Perfect!
Tell me, Miss O'Malley ..."
-Are you married?
-I'm divorcing.
-When do you want me to start?
-You have already started.
Shall we leave them alone and cook
lunch, Steve? They want to work.
-Have you worked for writers before?
-Yes, but I do not want to talk about it.
When I worked over time,
he became the approach. I called the police.
Publicity ruined his career.
But he begged for it.
-Don't you think so too?
-Yes, sure ...
-What about a little lunch?
-Thank you, I've already eaten.
-And you?
-I'm skipping.
You will enjoy yourself here. And
Waterburys are real bohemians.
Raw.
I open.
May I introduce
you to your new neighbor, Sylvain Scott.
-He has taken over Felicia's floor.
-I know Mr Scott.
You will meet the family's celebrity,
the great Owen Waterbury.
-And this is ...
-... the horrible Ronnie Hastings.
-New secretary!
-New hire. I'm fired.
Mr Scott is also a writer.
-We went to the same evening course.
-We sat next to each other.
Mr Scott had played ball before.
Look which shoulders. No shoulder pads.
Have you looked at the match!
He has written a radio program,
"John's Mother's Lover".
- "John's mother's girlfriend!"
-Tell me, will they get married?
-No, John's father opposes.
-John has no father!
Poor boy.
Hurry up and write.
You must not forget John.
I have problems.
My secretary has just gotten married.
I can help you. I was
Mr Waterbury's secretary before.
-Yes exactly.
-Marriage was a bonus.
-When can you begin?
-Let's say I started.
Give me a pad and a pen, Ronnie.
- How much are we going to work tonight?
-It probably takes the whole evening.
-I'm used to working in the evening.
-Do not work too hard.
-No, I promise.
Thanks, Ronnie. - Bye.
-I must have arranged everything.
-Really.
-Then I'll go.
-And I just poisoned the tea.
Jokers there!
You will enjoy yourself very much here,
sweetheart.
Hands off! I do
not tolerate affection from anyone.
I've ruined a man's
career once. Do not forget it!
-You can take time off today.
-Take all year.
-I have not started yet.
-You get paid anyway.
-When should I come tomorrow?
-Decide yourself.
-I do not understand ...
-What about twelve o'clock?
- Did you say anything about poisoned tea?
-I mixed it up.
-Where was I?
"You hear footsteps, three people."
You hear steps, three people.
A door slams, a door creaks.
Two shots, three screams ...
-How does that sound?
- Fantastic!
Uproar!
"John, I love your mother.
Tomorrow I will be your father."
John is going to be a father, and I'm
the first to know.
- "But I'm older than you, Dad."
-Is John older than his father?
-What was that?
-I wonder that too.
I do not know. But calm down,
I will not try anything.
They have just turned off the light.
It's Charles Harris. Sorry I'm
calling late. Can I talk to her?
This is her husband.
She's not home tonight.
-I do not know when she will come home.
"They just turned it off," I said.
-Can I borrow a light bulb?
-I ignore what you do.
-What is it?
-I'm going to a hotel.
-No, I do. It's your floor.
-No, you pay the rent.
Give Mr Scott this.
You're not jealous of the
man upstairs, are you ? He is inoffensive.
-You tricked me.
-Hur?
Charles Harris has just called. Have
you met him since we got home?
It's very late and
I do not want to be cross-examined.
We are adults
and must be able to trust each other.
Do not try to dodge.
Have you met him?
Yes, but it was
only for a special reason.
-He got your manuscript.
-It is too late.
At the nightclub, I noticed that you were
in love with each other. Five years is a long time.
-I've never loved Charles.
-Not me either, just a teenage idol.
I've tried to be honest with you,
but I was completely wrong.
I loved you
even before I met you.
Your way of writing, the tone, the feeling, the
quality made such an impression-
-that I imagined
you were just writing for me.
It's true I created
a schoolgirl picture of you.
I was so captivated by it that I
had gotten married after the lecture.
If you had gone down to me and
asked for my hand, you would have gotten me.
How can you say that to me?
I also put you on a pedestal.
But you tore it down in a cruel way.
You
once called me false and selfish . But yourself then?
What are you? Call him,
he's waiting for you.
-Good morning.
-I have made an appointment.
Yes, Mr Harris
has a surprise for you.
-Steve!
-Good morning, Charles.
These are Mr McNalley, Mr Hudson
and Mrs Burke from the Litterary Times.
-So you're Stephanie Gaylord.
-Sit down.
This is an important day in your life.
Mr. McNalley is the publisher
in New York. He flew here this morning.
-How long have you been writing your book?
-In five years, approximately.
I want to nominate it for the McNalley-
Windslow Award for Debutants.
-Have you shown my manuscript?
-I could not help myself.
Do you not
understand what that means for Owen?
Owen is the family's celebrity and
his novel has been rejected.
This on top of everything
will destroy him.
He must feel important.
He has no self-confidence left.
-Do you compete with you?
-You do not understand.
Owen is in trouble and
his wife has to help him out.
I thought you
wanted to write at all costs.
I wanted to, before I got married.
What do you think of Owen's manuscript?
That's good ... But it can '
t measure up to this.
This is magnificent.
-Thank you, gentlemen.
-Sit down. I want to talk to you.
-Are you going down to the kitchen again?
-I'm helping you with the monks.
Only I have time to call the fire brigade.
-No, that's not what I said.
-Sorry.
We will try again.
John: "Mom, I've changed my mind.
I do not like your girlfriend."
Mother: "I like him.
It's the only thing that counts."
John: "I
do not agree to the marriage".
Mother: "I'm the one to
marry him, not you".
-Uruselt.
-Amen.
You are very disturbing, Mr Hastings.
Do not use Mr Waterbury's
floor and secretary.
Mrs Waterbury is gone
and I have to finish.
-Go up to you and work.
-She does not want to.
-Work without her.
-I have to dictate.
-Why do not you want to get up?
-I do not work in men's bedrooms.
It's a bachelor party.
My husband ran a hotel. One room is
one bedroom, two or more one floor.
-There you got so you kept quiet.
-Now we work.
-Mr Waterbury.
-What do you want?
I'm Devony
from the Bryant Detective Agency .
A bill
of 845 dollars and 62 cents.
-Shadowing by Stephanie Gaylord.
-I'm married to her!
We have shadowed married women before.
- Drive him out.
-Should I call the police?
What is this?
Should my wife do your laundry?
-Isn't it a little too big for you?
- It's Mrs Waterburys. It is mine.
You have been fired for
dictating to someone else.
Nice! Even if you wrote well
, I would not work for you.
-Where is Stephanie?
-I know. Pay first.
- We need $ 845 ...
-... and 62 cents.
-Write a check.
-Yes exactly!
-Call it.
-Here is the report.
I had
to shadow you at the same time.
-Here you have Stephanie.
-Where are you Stephanie?
What are you doing there?!
There smoke our last chance
to be reconciled. Now it's over!
Harris floor.
Without the slightest shame.
-She might get the job back.
-Work in his home. It's not possible!
- Do not talk to me about secretaries.
-Read page three in the report.
Call the agency. Now I
want a good and efficient girl.
-She can look any way.
-Anyway, only she's good looking.
-Can you shorthand?
-Yes, 120 words a minute.
-What was your name?
-Miss Dove.
-Everyone says I'm volatile.
-Where did you work before?
-I have graduated from secretarial school.
I want to be a writer one day.
-Have you been married?
-No! Never!
-Can you imagine working on weekends?
-Yes, I only have myself.
Do you not think that
Mr Waterbury is a fine writer?
This is a clay pigeon.
I'm going to get my things. Come on, Bill.
-I know where it is.
-Empty the drawer in the bag.
-I knew you were coming.
-Just a moment.
-Where is the mink fur?
-I got none.
-In the bedroom.
-Is there a mink shortage?
- Haven't you been here before?
-Sure, with the former.
If you need a taxi, you
just need to open the window and shout.
His former secretary.
You do not love Harris
but you go home to him.
-Can you give me a sensible explanation?
-It does not matter now.
-She is very personal.
- Skilled typist.
-Charles Harris floor, without further ado.
-Was there anything else?
My photo.
-If I were a man ...
-... we would settle outside.
Hit me. I challenge you.
- Did he hit her?
-He hit her.
You were offended because I
liked your novel and said so.
The problem was that
you thought you had wasted your time.
I'll write a book about you.
"The tuber and his victim."
Goodbye, Owen Waterbury.
I never want to know about you again.
I say that too.
-Where is Miss Duva?
-She flew out of the cage.
-Where do you think Steve is going?
-She marries Harris.
Now I'm leaving too. I'm so angry
I could get married.
-Who are you going to marry?
-A woman, I know so much.
She went home to Harris.
I was disguised as a window pusatre.
Elsie was there. It probably meant nothing.
Then Harris took Stephanie's hand.
I'm looking for Mr Harris.
Owen Waterbury.
Excuse me, sir!
Sorry, I did not want to disturb you
and my secretary.
-Is a former secretary.
-You are probably in the middle of dictation.
You know what I think of someone who
behaves that way towards the secretary.
-Charles and I'm getting married.
-Congratulations.
What do you think my wife thinks of it?
She loves you.
-Stephanie is too good for you.
-What a raw person you are.
Your motives are obvious.
You've been tormenting me since we got married.
I came here to make up.
Raise your fists and defend yourself.
Listen to me, you idiot.
Why do you think Stephanie came here?
Harris wants to publish a
novel she has written.
But she was afraid to hurt you
and crash your marriage.
I read your book that Folton
did not want to publish. It's great.
Folton is just jealous of
Birdie. It's your own fault.
One day, Stephanie will
be a better writer than you.
Read Stephanie's novel
and get really jealous.
You will not get her back.
She's gone and it's right for you.
Hope I
've kicked some sense into you.
Goodbye, Mr Waterbury.
Stephanie Gaylord wins the
McNally Award for Debutants
Stephanie Gaylord
signs at 3 today
Mr Waterbury?
I would give you this.
Mrs Waterbury is seeking a divorce.
-Three. And you?
-Fyra C.
- Is not that Sylvain Scott's floor?
-I do not know.
I'm the new secretary.
Good luck.
-Mr Waterbury!
-Hej, Mary.
-Do you want a drink?
-Maybe it.
- Have you seen Ronnie?
-No, not in three days.
He must have gotten married.
-He did not even invite me to the wedding.
-Not me either.
So Ronnie got married.
And I'm going to divorce.
Did you know that?
- Mrs Waterbury wants a divorce.
-It was sad to hear.
He was a nice man.
So were you ... sometimes.
Thanks, Mary.
Scott has hired
a male secretary.
-Mr Scott moved yesterday.
-Who lives up there then?
Mrs Waterbury.
-Steve ?!
-Yes, she's a great writer.
I'll probably take care of her!
This is not possible.
Come in. - What can I do for you?
-Out! Out, I said!
-I do not understand...
- Ignore him.
-This is my wife.
Have you not received the divorce papers?
You are my wife until it
goes through and it takes a year.
-Come back tomorrow at 9.
-I see you here again you go out!
-Male secretary right in front of me.
-Above you, darling.
-Why did you take this floor?
-I found nothing else.
Try it.
I thought
you would think I was chasing you.
But we can be good neighbors,
greeting each other in the corridor.
I politely visited
your friend Harris very recently.
Elsie was there.
She told me about your book.
That you did not want to publish it,
because it could hurt me.
That was the dumbest thing!
Do you think I'm looking at you as a rival?
-Don't you think I can compete with you?
-I read your book last night.
Do you know something? You're better than me.
But do not tell anyone,
then I deny it.
Listen to me. I am also human
and have certain rights.
I had a spread and
you chased away the secretary.
You can dictate to me.
I can shorthand.
Do you know something?
I'm a better secretary than you.
Prove it.
Front with pad and pencil.
Not another word about us
before we have written this down.
We call it
"notes for my new novel" -
-"av Stephanie Gaylord."
It's about a girl who
became the secretary of a great egoist.
He thought
he knew everything about life.
Do not interrupt me!
He was attractive ...
in an ugly way.
Stop interrupting me!
But he was full of
childish frustration and complex
-as she was
stupid enough to try to cure.
-I'm not going to sit here ...
-This is my new book!
Until she suddenly discovered
that he did not need a wife.
He needed a ... psychiatrist!
That's enough! Would I be crazy?
I'm suing you if you publish the book.
Do it! If you think I ...
Hi.
Interesting. But I wonder one thing.
Did she love him?
It's done!
Deep, devoted, desperate.
Why did you not say that?
-I would pick up the rent.
-Ronnie is your new host.
No, that vase should be up there!
And this one belongs here.
-And this one belongs here.
-Ronnie, stop!