Hurry up, Dad. We gotta get outta here
'fore somebody comes in.
I'm hurrying. Keep your voice down.
- Sure you got it all, Dad?
- Yeah. You about done?
- Yeah.
- There's another.
- Buenos días, señor.
Come on, kid. Come on, Doc.
Walk out. Walk out. Easy.
Come on, kid!
Wait a second, Dad.
Young lady's trying to cheat me here.
- Hmm?
- No me lastime.
Whoa.
¡Llamen al comandante!
¡Están robando el banco!
¡Mira! ¡Mira! ¡Ahí van!
What's the matter? Ain't you coming in?
You can fight them fleas on your own.
I'll see ya later.
Well, don't get drunk!
You're getting too fat to run!
Let's go to glory, Dad!
Do you make your home in Mexico?
My home is...
oh, just any place
I throw my saddle down, I guess.
Oh, then you do much traveling.
Yeah, I, uh — You might say that.
I drift into one town out of another and...
Well, I transport money for the banks
once in a while.
You have a little something
in your eye, señora.
Oh.
Is it out?
No, I — If you'll permit me,
I think I can snag it out with this.
Just... close it.
I have made the mistake
of thinking that you were a gentleman.
Now perhaps you'd better leave.
Please go.
All right.
I never did get much upbringing as a kid.
All the manners I learned was in a saloon.
I didn't have much chance to be around
fine ladies like yourself.
I'm sorry, señora.
I just hope that...
you don't think too bad about me
when I'm gone.
Perhaps you were a little impulsive.
You may call again if you wish.
Señora, you just don't know
how nice that makes me feel.
¡Alto!
Síganme.
- Allá.
- Mmm.
- Que se desmonten y me sigan.
- Sí, mi capitán.
Óiganme, spotters.
Los últimos cuatro se van para atrás.
Los demás síganme.
- Tú vete por el otro lado.
- Bueno.
Sostenme el caballo.
No hagan ruido y cuidado con los sables.
¡Que nadie se mueva!
¡Silencio! ¡Alto o disparo!
Vete a la ventana.
Come out the window!
Shoes! Your shoes!
Date prisa.
- ¡No!
- ¡Suéltame!
No!
¡Suéltame!
My mother give me this ring
just before she died.
It'd mean a lot to me, señora,
if you'd wear it for me.
I couldn't.
I — I couldn't take that.
Please.
It'd make me feel a whole lot better.
It's — It's very beautiful.
I shall be honored to wear it.
Oh, thank you.
Hey, kid! Kid! You in there, kid?
- Yeah!
- Come on! Get on your horse! Rurales!
- Come on! Get on your horse!
- Where's Doc?
- He's dead.
- Be right with ya!
What is it?
Sorry, sweetheart. Maybe next time.
All right?
- Give me a pull on that.
- Yeah.
Here.
Hey, Dad! Come on back here!
Come on. Take the gold! Get the gold!
Hurry up. Come on, come on.
¡Deprisa!
Where's your rifle?
I dropped it coming up.
¡Ya no disparen, muchachos!
¡Ahora escóndanse!
¡Ándenle, vámonos! ¡Vámonos!
No, hold it.
We ain't gonna do no good from here.
They'll be stomping all over us
inside an hour.
We'd better think of something funny,
and quick.
Well, we still got the horse.
Well, what good's that?
You remember a little stick place
just outside of San Felipe?
With a corral?
No.
Yeah. Remember, that was when you was drunk
and killed that lady's goat?
Remember?
- Yeah.
- Well, listen.
If I ain't wrong, I think it's got to be four
or five miles right down that canyon there.
Isn't it?
Well, that's no damn good.
If we rode that horse double up,
she'd cave in on us
before we went half a mile.
Yeah, but one of us could stay and hold this rim
and the other one go get us fresh mounts.
Ah, slim chance.
Well, it's better'n sitting here,
waiting to get shot all to hell, front and back.
- Huh?
- Yeah, it might work.
- We ain't got no choice.
- Well, who rides and who stays?
Well...
let's shake up for it.
Bullet rides?
Bullet rides.
You ride.
I'd get the hell out of here.
I'll see you right quick.
- Kid.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I could use it.
- Don't go away now.
- Huh?
- Wasn't thinking of it.
Come on!
- Oye, chamaco.
- ¿Qué quiere, jefe?
¿De quién son?
- De mi papá.
- Llámale.
¡Papá!
- Buenos días, señor.
- Buenos.
Look...
- ¿Cómo está usted?
- Muy bien.
How much...
How much for those two horses?
¿Qué le puedo servir?
Quiero dos caballos.
Pero, pues, esos caballos,
no quisiera vendérselos porque
me costó mucho trabajo —
Córtale. ¿Cuánto?
- ¿Cuánto?
- Doscientos pesos.
- Anda, Manuel.
Come on!
Dame esta cosa.
Gracias, viejo.
¡Jorge! ¡Carlos!
¡Ve y agárralo!
¡Alto!
¡Y no se me dispersen!
Oye, viejo. ¿No has visto a un gringo
pasar por aquí mucho muy apurado?
Sí, capitán. Un hombre muy malo.
Y se fue por ahí. Y no traía zapatos.
No shoes, huh?
¿Es aquel su caballo?
Sí, señor.
Y se llevó al mejor de los míos.
- Te pagó, ¿no?
- Sí, mi jefe.
- A ver, ¿cuánto?
- Muy poco.
Say, I wonder what happened
to your friend, huh?
Well, uh, maybe he goes back
to find the shoes.
¡Bueno, ya vámonos, muchachos!
¡Vámonos, muchachos!
Refrescante.
We get to my woman's place,
she'll get us horses and clothes.
- You all right?
- I'm all right.
Well. Vamos para allá.
I've been thinking, amigo,
about this Longworth.
Must be very hard to find him.
It's a very big country.
I know all his old stompin' grounds.
Sooner or later I'm gonna find him.
Five years we spent in that stinking hole.
'Bout time we live a little.
- What if he's dead?
- Then I'll find him dead.
You could spend the rest of your life
looking for this man.
Let's get going.
Cinch up.
Buenas noches, señores.
Pasen ustedes.
¿Conozco un hombre?
Se llama Dad Longworth.
Yo no sé nada.
Gordito.
- A ver qué quiere el joven.
- ¿Qué quiere, señor?
¿Conozco un hombre?
Se llama Dad Longworth.
No lo conozco.
He's an americano.
- Ande, mamá. Estos viejos...
- Déjalos que pasen.
...no quieren entrar.
No, no. ¿No quieren entrar ustedes?
¿Quieren entrar o no?
Dele. Quítate. No quieren entrar.
Come on.
¿Dónde estabas?
- Por ahí.
- Paso.
Dime. ¿Tú ves a Dad Longworth?
¿Quién?
Dad Longworth es un americano
con nariz muy gorda.
No.
- ¿Quiere un pedacito de limón? Aquí.
- Look at me again, will you, please?
Boy, you've got the reddest eyes.
- Always say I'm in love when my eyes turn red.
- Easy with that knife.
You both friends, you're enemies.
You're both friends.
You're both friends of mine.
- Please.
- Sí.
Be good!
Better dig something you can eat, bub.
Buenas noches.
What do you mean by that?
Hey, you boys, you wait here,
and I'll be back right away.
Aw. Where you goin', Red?
I'll be back.
I think she's tryin' to get us drunk
so she can take advantage of me, Harv.
Chico.
Chico, you remember me?
Sure do. How you been, Red?
Muy bien, muy bien. How are you?
I'm all right.
What are you doing here?
Just killing time.
Oh.
It's five or six years since I see you.
Hey, I hear you got in some bad trouble.
Ah, a little bit.
Mmm, that's bad.
Hey, what happened to your friend?
Well, I don't know.
I kinda lost track of him.
- When was the last time you seen him?
- Not since he was here with you.
You remember. When the rurales
came and killed that guy —
¡Ay, Chihuahua!
Maybe he run back over the border.
Yeah.
Hey, Red, what you doing over here?
I'm over there.
Ah, just one moment, baby.
I'm coming right away.
I'm here talking to an old friend.
- No, let's go.
- Momentito.
She'll be right back.
I'm just asking her a few things.
Ask her questions on your own money, bub.
Let's go.
- Momentito. Momentito.
- Come on.
Don't be doin' her like that.
- What'd you just say?
- I said, don't be doin' her like that.
You know, I've had just about
enough out of you, jackass.
Well, Harvey Johnson's gonna be
a famous name round these parts.
You're gonna get yourself killed
by a fella called Rio.
That ain't him.
It ain't, huh?
I wouldn't want to lose me
a handful of brains tryin' to find out.
Now, would you, Harv?
I don't care if it is him.
You don't, huh?
My name's Amory. I'd like to
sit down with you and buy you a drink.
Got something I'd like to talk over.
Te veo, guapo.
Mind if I sit down?
Oh, don't pay no attention to him.
He's just pumped up a little.
You must have heard of me.
Bob Amory?
Nope.
Well, don't matter anyway.
You know what's a real piece of luck?
My running into you like this.
Got a good idea
I'd like to talk to you about.
How would you like to get rich
once and for all?
You could stand a piece of change,
couldn't you?
You got something to tell me?
Fourteen days' ride from here,
there's a town.
And in that town
there's the fattest bank you ever saw.
And it ain't nothin' but a cheese box.
What are you telling me all this for?
I'm gonna need some help to take that bank.
How come you don't do it on your own?
Two men ain't enough.
I never saw a bank two men couldn't take.
That's true.
But this is a little different deal.
Word's going around that you're
looking hard for Dad Longworth,
that there's dirt between you.
Now, if that's true,
I can tell you where you can find him.
Want me to keep talkin'?
Mm-hmm.
Now, here's where the fun comes.
And it's gonna tickle you.
The sheriff in that town is Dad Longworth.
Now we gonna do some business?
Yeah.
Well, there she is.
Monterey, California.
I think of the money waiting in that bank,
just makes me wanna cry.
Harv, you gonna have
diamonds in your teeth.
And you ain't never
gonna have to take that bath.
Come on. Let's get down there
and pick them apples.
You go in there and get the rooms.
I'll be back.
Looking for somebody?
Looking for Dad Longworth.
Could you tell me where I could find him?
What do you want with him?
I wanna see him.
Who wants to see him?
I do.
What about? I'm the deputy.
I don't believe you could handle it.
I asked you polite.
Read that sign?
I got a lot of funny things to do today,
but lippin' with you ain't one of 'em.
I'd say you was shy a few manners, mister.
You're looking
to get your back busted, sonny.
And I'm the man that takes care
of them kind of things around here.
Well...
could be you get your chance to try it.
Can you tell me
where I can find Dad Longworth?
- Oh, Dad's over at home.
- Where's that?
About two miles out of town.
You take the south fork plumb to the beach.
Yeah?
His is the first house
on the west side of the road.
Dad.
We have a visitor.
Somebody's coming.
Darling, give me my holster, please.
- What's the matter?
- Never mind. Just give it to me.
- Who's he?
- Close the window.
Stay inside.
Hello, Dad.
Hello, kid.
Well, how you been?
All right.
- How 'bout yourself?
- Oh, I'm sneakin' by.
What's on your mind?
Nothin'. I was just driftin' through.
I thought I'd look in on you.
I knew you'd be coming sooner or later.
I'm glad you come,
'cause there's something I been
wanting to tell you for a long, long time.
How 'bout a drink?
All right.
- Look good, Dad.
- I feel good.
Sit yourself.
Well.
Remember the last time
we had tequila together?
Sure do. That was up on the mountain
when we was hung up there. Remember?
- About five years ago.
- That's right.
No, just — Yeah, that's right.
It was just under five years.
I, uh — I guess you wondered
why I never showed with the horses.
Yeah, I thought about it.
Well, you know, knowin'
how you was in them days,
I figured you for gettin' drunk
and fallin' down onto some chiquita
and losing track of time.
No, I didn't forget, kid.
But there was nothing I could do.
When I got to that little rancho,
there were no horses.
That old Mexican couldn't talk American,
and when I finally figured out his lingo
he was saying that he had sold
the horses a couple of weeks before.
The old paint horse I was riding
was pretty done in,
but I headed straight for you.
When I got to the canyon,
I see rurales all over the place.
Well, I — I high-tailed it out of there
and got as far as La Quinta
before the horse caved in.
I hid out in a cantina
and I gave the bartender some gold
to keep his mouth shut.
Well, there wasn't too much of that,
as I recollect it.
There was enough to get me over the border
and all the way here.
Here to Monterey.
I figured I'd keep my nose clean
until the —
till that, um, fracas down in Mexico
was forgotten.
Well, I kept myself clean.
Clean enough to be elected sheriff.
Knowing me the way I used to be, I...
I couldn't blame you for not believing.
But if you're looking now
to be satisfied for what I did,
I'd be sorry for it, kid.
But if that's what you want, just let me know
how and where you want the play.
I'll stand up to you.
You're gettin' way ahead of yourself, Dad.
No need for all that,
'cause nothin' happened to me.
I just fooled around with them dogfaces
till it got dark.
Then I went down
and stole the captain's horse.
They wasn't about to find me neither.
Then after that it was just, you know,
rosemary and sweet whiskey and...
just whoopin' and yellin'.
You sure that's the straight of it, kid?
Well, you know me, Dad.
If I didn't feel right about it,
we'd have been out there
splatterin' each other
all over that front yard.
I admit I was hot about it for a time,
but that's five years ago.
A man can't stay angry for five years.
Can he?
You know what you're gonna do?
No.
You're gonna stay to supper.
Well, listen, Dad, I —
I tell ya, I was just pokin' through
and thought I'd stop in and say hello.
- But it wouldn't look good, me hanging around.
- You let me worry about that.
Well, now, you'd better think about it,
'cause... I'm still in business.
I want you to meet my family anyhow.
- All right.
- Good.
Come on.
Maria!
Just a minute, kid.
Maria! I want you to meet
an old friend of mine.
Maria?
Hello.
Are you waiting for my father?
Yeah.
Would you like to sit down?
Yes, I — I would, thank you.
- Who is he?
- I want you to meet him.
Ah. I'm glad you're here.
Rio, I want you to meet my entire family.
My wife Maria.
- How are you?
- Ma'am, it's a pleasure.
- And have you met my stepdaughter?
- Just that little.
- Well, this is Louisa, my stepdaughter.
- How do you do?
I love her as though
she were my own natural child.
Uh, Rio's staying to supper.
Wonderful. We're happy to have you.
- Well, I don't want you to do any fussin'.
- Oh, no, there's nothing —
No, no, no, no fuss at all.
You wanna wash up?
Yeah.
Take his hat.
Heavenly father,
in thy graciousness thou has seen fit
to grace this table with thy divine bounty.
We offer up our humble thanks
and ask that you bless this food
to our use
and us to thy service.
And make us ever mindful of the needs
of others. In Jesus' name. Amen.
I never knew you to pray
over the grub before, Dad. Yeah.
Have you known each other for a long time?
Oh, yeah. Dad and I go way back.
I wasn't anything more than a kid
when Dad picked me up.
I have never heard him
talking about you before.
Well, we was kinda hairy in them days.
When he was a bandit, no?
That's all right, kid. Everybody here knows
I used to be on the other side of the law.
Yeah, we were a couple of cockleburs, huh?
Had a lot of fun, didn't we?
Always full of laughs, Dad.
You know, it's a wonder
we didn't get our fool heads shot off.
That or wind up in the pen or something.
Lucky.
- Just luck, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Of course, that was a...
that was a long time ago.
You were a bank robber, Mr. Rio?
Yes, ma'am.
Me and your dad here.
But no more.
No more.
Will you be in Monterey long?
Well, long enough to get my horse shod
and do a couple things.
And after that, where are you going?
I don't know, Mrs. Longworth.
I thought I might go up to Oregon.
That's awful pretty country up there.
Thought I'd go take a look.
Will you be here for our fiesta?
- When is that gonna be?
- Well, tomorrow and tomorrow night.
But you will not be able to buy
any shoe for your horse
because everything will be closed.
You mean, the barbershop
and the blacksmith, bank and all?
Bank, everything'll be closed.
Yes, so why don't you stay here?
You heard señor. He's going to Oregon.
Well, you know, I just could
lay over a day or two.
Don't expect too much, kid.
It's just a street dance, that's all.
Well, must be enough there
to give a man a laugh.
Then you will stay?
Well, from such a lovely young lady
I don't know as how I could
rightly refuse an invitation.
Yeah, I'll stay.
Don't tell me they're for real.
Yeah.
Well, I don't know about you, kid,
but it's been a great day for me.
For five years it's been tearing at me,
and I'm sure glad it's all under the bridge.
I'll bet.
Good party, Dad.
You tell the missus thanks again for me.
Yes, I will.
Good night, Rio. Thanks for coming.
My pleasure, Dad.
Good night.
I say I got a right to know
where you been.
Just so's there's no misunderstanding, Bob,
as far as what I do goes...
you ain't got no rights at all.
Just so as you understand me...
I didn't ride 900 miles to come up empty.
Bank don't open till day after tomorrow.
What about Longworth?
Nothing about him.
When the bank opens, I'm gonna kill him.
Welcome to the party,
and we hope you enjoy yourselves.
Every year we have this fiesta
to remind one another that we're neighbors.
Friends.
Also, I'd like to take this opportunity
to thank all of you
for electing me to another term as sheriff.
I want you to know that I appreciate it...
and that I will continue to do my best
to make this city
and, well, to make this county
a place where we can be proud
to raise our children.
When...
Oh, that's it. Let's have it! Come on!
Give me some flowers.
- What kind would you like?
- Oh, it don't matter.
Violets are very nice.
Yeah, that'd be all right.
Bueno, ¿qué tal?
How much for that thing
on your neck there?
This? I'm not selling that.
But I'm glad you like it.
I like it $20 worth.
I couldn't sell it.
My husband gave it to me.
I like it $30 worth then.
Well, all right.
Muy bonito, pero... $30?
Just a little birdseed.
- Hello, Marta.
- Hello, Helen.
- Mrs. Longworth.
- Hello.
- Louisa.
I just wanted to tell you thank you for
a very lovely evening you gave me last night
and say I appreciated it very much.
Well, I'm very happy that you like it.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
- Hey, Rio boy!
- Well, there he is.
- Are you having a good time?
- Well, I didn't get started yet, Dad.
Listen, I saw you makin' that speech
out there and kickin' up there.
You must be a big man round these parts.
- Well, I try to fit in. Don't I, mother, huh?
- Yes.
- You really having fun there.
- Yes, I'm really having fun! Aren't you?
- What about that dance?
- Never mind. What about you dancing, huh?
Doggone, that was all right, Dad!
- Howdy, Mrs. Longworth.
- Hello.
Say, this is our dance, isn't it, Louisa?
I believe Miss Louisa has been spoken for.
Haven't you, Miss Louisa?
Uh, pardon me. Excuse me.
Later on, Lon.
A day late and a dollar short, huh, Lon?
Come on, let's get some of that beer.
Come on! Dance it up!
Hey, Louisa! Louisa, I think
your mother could use some help.
- Excuse us.
- I'll be back.
The barbecue stand.
- Well, Dad...
- Well, I...
I don't believe I ever met your friends.
Name's Amory.
Amory. Bob Amory?
Yep, that's me.
Yeah, I seen your picture in the post office.
You must have heard of me, Sheriff. Johnson.
Harvey Johnson.
Well, gents, the laws loosen up
a turn or two during fiesta time,
but tomorrow I'll be back
running a pretty tight town.
So as long as you fellas'll be haulin' out
in the morning, enjoy yourselves.
- You bet.
- See you later, Sheriff.
- Let's go, Harv.
- Yep.
Where did you pick up the crow bait?
Well, the pickings are slim these days, Dad.
We don't hardly run into
studs like you no more.
Yeah, I guess it's about time
to say good-bye.
Rio, I want to tell you something
before you go.
In all my life,
I've never met anyone like you.
I'm so sorry you're going
because I would like to know you better.
If you knew me better,
you might wish I hadn't.
Oh, no, I'm sure not.
Good-bye, Miss Louisa.
I thank you for everything.
Rio.
- Howard —
- I've been looking for you.
Listen.
You go on and have yourself a good time
and I'll climb on your back.
- Well!
- I want to talk to you.
- And I want to talk to you!
- No, but this is serious.
Here I thought you ran away
with a harness salesman or something.
What's serious? Let's go home, huh?
Just for a little while. Let's go home.
Oh!
Please! Now, really.
- Here! What? What? What? Huh?
- Wait a minute!
- It's about Louisa.
- What about Louisa?
I haven't seen her for an hour.
And I don't see your friend either.
Well, that's not awful.
- Please. Please.
- What?
Why don't you go and try to find them?
- Not now, not now. No.
- Yes, now. I say now.
Please, Mr. Longworth. Now.
All right, Mrs. Longworth. I'll find her.
But I'll be back.
All right, you go now.
You're drunk! Huh?
- Chet!
- Hi, Dad.
- Hello, Lizzie.
- Hello.
- Have you seen my gal Louisa?
- Let me fire you up.
No, no, we don't mix it, do we?
Yeah, she was dancing around
with that fella over there a while ago.
- You look very handsome tonight, Sheriff.
- Well, so do you. Enjoying yourselves?
There you are, my friend. What do you see?
An empty glass!
Ladies and gentlemen, I told you —
Let's go home. Let's go home.
Go home?
I'm having myself a little fiesta! Huh?
Me! Dad Longworth!
Hey! Get up!
Come on! Get outta there! Get out!
- This is mine!
- Get out.
This is my beer!
Attaboy!
- Where is Louisa?
- We'll get Louisa.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Where is Louisa?
She's around here somewhere.
She's with that Rio fella.
- I have to go to find her.
- Sit still, Mrs. Longworth.
- But we should bring her home! Please!
- I'll take care of Louisa. I'll see she gets —
- Get his foot back in there.
- You promise me that.
I'll take care of it.
Tim, drive on now! Drive careful!
I'll see that she's all right.
I'll take care of Louisa, Mrs. Longworth!
Don't worry about nothin'!
What's the matter?
I was just thinking that you're
the most decent woman I've ever met.
I'm sure you have met
many nice women in your life before.
Yeah, I met a few.
But not many like you.
Something I want to tell you, Miss Louisa.
I... lied to you about myself.
I told you I was just a drifter
and that ain't true.
I work for the government.
Why did you lie about it?
Well, I had to.
I was sworn in under oath
not to talk about my job.
Anyhow, I'm going to Oregon tomorrow,
but not just to look around.
I'll be gone as long as four or five months.
You're to come back to Monterey...
sometime?
Yeah, I'm hoping to.
Miss Louisa, I don't have
much time to court you.
And I...
I ain't exactly what you'd call
a high-bred gentleman.
But before I go I want you to know that
I think you'd make a man a wonderful wife.
And I know I ain't got no right
to say this, but...
I want you to wait for me.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to say nothin' now.
I was just hoping you'd think about it.
Yes, I will wait for you.
You don't have no idea
how good that makes me feel.
I don't have much of anything to give ya.
I don't have no ring or nothin'.
All I got is...
this necklace here.
My mother give this to me
just before she died.
And it'd mean an awful lot to me
if you'd wear it while I'm gone.
I will very proud to wear it.
I will miss you very much.
But I will write you every day.
Where can I write to you in Oregon?
I ain't going to Oregon.
But you must go.
I don't want to keep you from your work.
I don't have no work.
I make my living robbing banks.
What do you mean?
I mean that...
everything I told you about
last night was lies.
You lie?
Yeah.
About everything?
Yeah, just about.
But your mother's necklace...
True?
I never knew nothin' about my mother.
I bought that thing off a girl
for 25 bucks.
Well...
That's about it.
It ain't gonna help much to say it, but...
I shamed you.
I wish to God I hadn't.
You only shame yourself.
Scare ya?
Out kinda late, huh?
What are you doing here?
I reckon I know where you been.
I was just walking.
Let's take a little walk, you and me.
One more ain't gonna make no difference.
Get out of my way.
Dad.
Dad!
It's me, Lon.
Sure am sorry to get you up
this early, Dad.
I hate to tell you this.
She's been out all night.
Who?
Louisa.
With that Rio fella.
How do you know, Lon?
I've been round here half the night,
and she just this minute come home.
Looking kinda messy too.
Sure hate to be the one to...
the one to tell you, Dad.
Lon tells me that, uh...
you were out with Rio all night.
Is that true?
No.
Then why are you still dressed?
Why hasn't your bed been slept in?
Hmm?
Answer me!
Were you with him?
Yes, but... but...
But what? What? What?
- Nothing happened.
- Don't you lie to me!
I'm not lying to you!
We just walked on the beach!
- That's all? You just walked on the beach?
- Yes!
- We just walked on the beach! I swear that!
- What's the matter?
What's happened here? What is it?
Louisa, what happened?
Mother, I want to speak to you
for a moment.
Louisa, what happened?
¿Qué hiciste en toda la noche?
¿Te pasó algo?
¡Contesta!
Mother, I'm waiting!
I think she's lying to me,
and I want you to find out.
Louisa would never lie.
I hope you're right.
Louisa.
¿Es verdad?
¿Te fuiste con él?
¿Por qué, Louisa?
¿Por qué lo hiciste?
Porque yo creí que él me quería.
Y era mentira.
Perdóname, mamá.
Perdóname.
Hija.
Was she telling the truth?
Yes.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
But she was out with him all night.
She's all right.
You keep her in her room.
My little girl.
There you are, gents.
Here's some hot coffee for you.
I guess you can use it
after last night, huh?
Oh, what a night.
Hey, hombre.
This horse is still fighting for his life.
That's what you got
a sharp knife for, friend.
Barney! It's a party.
I told you I'll be with you in a minute, Howard.
Ay, me duele.
Oh, what a night we had. What a night.
Now what do you want?
We're bone dry.
So bone dry.
- Give us some more whiskey.
- What do you want to eat?
- You got any chili?
- I'm not hungry.
- Take a nice drink for yourself.
- Use this one.
- Come on, drink up.
- I don't want any. Please.
- Drink up. Be a nice girl.
- The night's over with.
Grab the glass. That's it.
Now, come on, drink.
- Let's see you drink.
- No, I don't want any.
Why not? Drink, you cow. Come on, drink!
Drink it!
That's it. That's the way
you gotta treat them, Barney.
- All right.
- You pay them, they don't wanna eat.
- You owe me six bits.
- Wait a minute, Barney.
She's gotta have something to eat.
I don't want my little girl to starve.
- Please, I'm sick.
- You gonna eat?
- Go on about your business.
- Come on. Take it easy!
Get it out of here! This is a nice place.
What do you think you're doing?
You're gonna give me a dollar
so I can pay this man. He's mad at us.
Please, he's breaking my arm.
- You gonna be good now?
- Will that be all?
- Yeah, just about.
- Thank you very much.
- How are you, sonny boy?
- Good morning.
You get up, you big tub of guts.
- Con esto lo mato.
- ¡Tú, ya!
- ¡Tú quítate de enfrente o te mato!
- ¡Basta ya!
¡Suéltame!
¡Quítate tú o te mato a ti también!
¡Los mato! ¡Los mato esta vez! ¡Suelta!
¡Cuidado!
If I told him once, I told him a thousand times
something like this was gonna happen.
Well, it finally got him.
Mister, you really killed him.
I better take care of this.
Bicho abusivo.
Te mataron por fin.
¡Suéltame tú también! ¡Suéltame, te digo!
Now what do we do, amigo?
This don't change nothin'.
We just wait for them two
and get on with it.
Let's get us a drink.
- Hello, kid.
- Good morning, Dad.
How'd it happen?
We took to scuffling,
and he come out from behind there
with that scattergun.
- Sounds like him.
- Yeah, he didn't give me no selection.
He was always askin' for it.
If it hadn't been you, it would have
been somebody else, I guess.
Well, better get him out of here.
I'll bring the coroner over.
- You fellas give me a hand.
- Yeah, you bet.
Let's put him in the rig.
Kid.
Think it'd be a good idea
if you'd hand over your gun.
All right.
Ephraim.
Yeah.
Ace.
Tim.
Lon.
Left hand, kid.
Dump it.
Lon.
Come on.
I warned him not to cause
any trouble around here.
But no, kid, you ignored my warning
and went right ahead and killed a man.
Didn't you?
Well,
we don't want his kind around here.
I'm going to teach you a lesson
you'll never forget.
Now, let's see the kind of stuff
you're made of.
That's a pretty good start.
Look here what's happening to Romeo.
- Oughta get down there and do something.
- Do something?
Not this horse.
Enough shotgun down there to start a war.
'Sides, it might help him
to get rid of some of that snot nose.
What's this gonna do about the bank?
Well, we'll just have to kiss that good-bye
for today anyway.
Now what do you say, kid?
You better kill me.
- Kill you?
- Yeah.
Nah. No, there's no need for that.
Your gun days are over.
Untie him!
Ephraim! Bring the horses here.
Now, I'm letting you go.
But if you ever come back here again,
I'll shoot you down like a dog in the street.
All right. That's all. It's all over now.
Go on. Back home!
Whew. Man.
Slashed you clear down to the rib bone.
Yeah, we're sure sorry about that, Rio.
We got in on the tail end of everything,
and there wasn't nothin' we could do.
It's all right, Bob.
The place was crawling all over
with deputies.
You know me, Rio.
If there was anything I could have done,
I'd been in there like a streak.
- I said it's all right, Bob.
- Well, what's it gonna be now?
There's a small fishing village
up the coast a couple of miles.
It's called Punta del Diablo.
When we get there, what then?
We'll just wait.
Just wait.
Think you can make it that far, Rio?
Say, they really did mash that hand.
Whew.
Looks like it might be all broke up.
I guess you won't be doin' no business
with that for quite a spell.
Well, there's no need
for you to hang around, Bob.
It ain't that, Rio.
It's just that I'm thinking of you,
that's all.
Come on. Let's go.
No!
- What?
- We need some rooms.
My friend is sick.
We need a place to stay.
- How many rooms?
- Four.
Phew. What is that? Fish?
Somethin' dead.
Hey, where can we get a drink around here?
There.
Howdy, Miss Louisa.
Wait a minute.
Boy, you're just as pretty
as a bird on a limb this morning.
Say, I heard from a friend of yours.
That fella, what's his name? Uh, Rio.
Thought you'd be interested.
Really? What about him?
Nothin'.
He's a-hangin' out down at the point,
lickin' his back.
How would you know?
Somebody smelled him, I guess.
Four weeks.
I think the hand is finished, chico.
It's not going to get any better.
Let it go.
Let's go back to Morelos
and lay in the sun.
Forget this Longworth.
He's not worth it.
Huh? What do you say, amigo?
You must be crazy.
Hey.
Take them stinkin' fish out of here.
I'm through with the fish, Harv.
That, and them damn waves
floppin' in all day long.
Six weeks in this puke hole,
and listen to him.
That hand ain't gettin' no better.
How's the hand, Rio?
Oh, it's coming.
You know, Rio, I've been wondering
if we oughta lay around here anymore.
Throw me the dipper, Bob.
I've been thinking a lot about
all that kale waitin' in the bank.
How 'bout the dipper, Bob?
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
We're all gonna lay for that sheriff
outside his house some sunup.
Cut him down with scatterguns
and then take that bank.
That's not my style, Bob.
It ain't, huh?
Well, maybe you better change it
'cause your style seems a touch slow to me.
I'm getting tired of listening to that bull.
We rode 900 miles because you were
supposed to be the big man with an iron.
But the way things are going,
I think even I can outpull you now.
Probably could get six into me...
before I got that one into you.
Huh, Bob?
¿Qué no piensas levantarte
en toda la mañana, hija?
Son las 8:00 de la mañana.
Ándale, levántate.
Hay muchas cosas que hacer.
Mira, toda la casa está tirada y tú aquí.
Louisa.
Louisa, ¿por qué no me contestas?
Mamá.
Voy a tener un hijo.
Padre nuestro que estás en los cielos,
santificado sea tu nombre.
Venga a nos tu reino.
- Hello.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Are you all right now?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Want to sit down?
How'd you find me here?
- Lon told me.
- Lon?
I don't know how he knows.
Well...
Don't matter.
I'll be gettin' outta here pretty quick.
Where are you going?
I'll figure that out
when I've finished up with Longworth.
Finish what?
I'm gonna kill him.
You're gonna kill him?
That's right.
But why? Just because he whipped you?
Yeah. That, and a couple of other things.
I know it was a terrible thing,
what he did.
And I was ashamed for him.
But those are not reasons
for to kill a man.
Reasons?
I got reasons.
I got 1,708 of 'em.
That's how many days I spent
down in that lead mine
in the pen in Sonora.
That's how many nights I spent digging
the maggots out of the sores in my ankles,
with the rats running all over me.
I laid awake for five years at night,
listening to men screaming and praying
while they was getting beat to death.
I don't understand.
You don't, huh?
Well, it ain't hard to understand.
Five years ago in Mexico,
we was caught on the hill by rurales.
And he run off to get fresh mounts.
And he never come back.
He was the best friend I had,
and he left me there for rot.
And you know what for?
Two sacks of gold.
Are you sure he did this?
Yeah.
Well, that's my sad tale.
And when it's over,
I was hopin' you'd come away with me.
After you murder him?
That ain't murder.
That's just standin' up,
same as any man would do.
And you think to kill him
will make you a man?
I don't know about that.
But I know that I thought about him
every day for five years.
And that was the only thing
that kept me going.
Rio.
There are not many chances in life
to be happy.
And I think that we have a good one now.
Won't you try to forget this?
Forget it?
Not as long as I breathe.
Rio.
Please.
Please try to forget this.
Please just take me with you.
We can be very happy. Can't you forget?
- Can you forget all —
- I can't. I can't.
Don't you understand? I can't.
I gotta die to forget that.
Then...
I'll be going away too,
because I don't want to be here
when they bury you.
I love you.
I know that, my sweet man.
Wait a minute.
You must've had some reason
for comin' all the way down here.
Yes, I did.
But it doesn't matter now.
Mr. Modesto,
I'm gonna raise you for a bit.
Boy, that's — that's too rich
for my blood, Bob.
Ni yo. ¿Qué? Qué suerte.
Well, now, thanks for the donations, gents.
How 'bout some of your cash there, Romeo?
Man oughta dig up something
for being around this manure pile.
Huh, Harv?
That's right, Bob.
Maybe the boy's all petered out
from playing on the beach
with that little jumpin' bean.
That's right, Bob.
He should have shared with us.
Get up, you scum-suckin' pig!
Get up!
I want you standin' when I open you up.
Now, get on up.
Go on.
You got right on the edge.
You mention her once more,
and I'm gonna tear your arms out.
Guess we forget
about the bank tomorrow, huh?
Yeah.
What are you gonna do now?
I'll be going in after her in the morning.
What about Longworth?
I just pray to God I don't run into him.
You ridin' with us, Modesto?
I don't know. You going back to Mexico?
I just might.
What do you think about it, Harv?
Might as well.
Nothin' else to do.
How 'bout your friend? Is he still set
on going in after that female?
Yeah, I guess so. I don't know.
- I'm gonna say good-bye. Then we go, huh?
- All right.
Chico.
We'll be riding out now.
I just come to say adios.
We rode a long way together, buster.
That's right.
- You think of me once in a while, no?
- You bet.
You bet. I'm gonna miss you, frijol.
Hey, listen, you get tired of around here,
come to Morelos.
I got a little place down in Tepoztlán.
It's not much,
pero you can live quiet there, huh?
I might do that, chico.
I just might do that.
Bueno. Adiós, amigo.
Adiós, boy.
You take care now.
¡Rio! ¡Adiós, amigo!
¡Que te vaya bien! ¡Cuídate!
- ¡Adiós!
Hey, where you going?
That's the wrong way, no?
Uh-uh. This way.
- That's the way to Monterey.
- That's right.
We're going to take the bank right now.
- I mean, just the two of you?
- Kind of figured on maybe three.
You in, or you out?
Not me. That's no good.
We go in now, we make a lot
of trouble for Rio, you know?
If we wait, maybe.
We're all through waiting for Rio.
No more waitin' and no more takin' that bull,
'cause he ain't the big man no more. I am.
Now, you comin' or not?
Not me. And neither are you.
You gonna try to stop me, cholo?
Yeah, I'm gonna stop you.
Well, now, Modesto,
I'm — I'm real disappointed,
you pulled on an old sidekick like that.
You're gonna give Rio time.
I tell you something.
One more word out of you,
and I cut you in half.
One more word, huh?
Let me see. Maybe I can think of one.
Yeah, I got one.
G-R-E-A-S-E-R. Greaser.
Try it again.
I'm real disappointed in greaseball.
Ain't you, Harv?
Sure am.
Maybe this is what you're looking for.
Eat 'em, greaser.
Malditos.
You had a good life, cholo.
Let's go.
- Wait here. I'll be right back.
- All right.
Hey, Longworth!
Longworth?
Mornin', Sheriff.
Rio said to tell you wait here.
- What for?
- Said he was comin' in to kill you.
You tell him I'm waiting.
All right. I'll tell him.
- Good morning.
Hold on. I'll be right with you.
Deposit?
Not hardly.
Where's your hog leg?
I ain't got none.
You ain't got none?
You better dig one up.
Right there.
Pretty fancy.
Give me the paper. Forget the hard stuff.
Good morning, Mr. Carvey.
Has my father been here yet?
He was here a little while ago.
Now, honey, you're gonna be
a real good little girl, ain't you?
You're not gonna scream, and you're
not gonna run out of here, are you?
No.
Then you get over there in the corner,
and sit down, and you won't get hurt.
Now, you better get busy
or I'll blow your liver out.
That's it.
I'll take that.
- What do you reckon that was, Lon?
- It ain't the Fourth of July. Let's go.
Harv.
- Hey, Barney?
- Yeah.
- Where's Longworth?
- I don't know.
- What happened?
- I been shot.
Whoa!
- Hi, Sheriff.
- Hello, Dad.
Dad, all hell broke loose back in town.
They shot up everything.
I run one clean out of town.
I done the best I could.
- Tell me what happened.
- They held up the bank. That's what happened.
- Who did?
- Rio's bunch.
The teller got Bob Amory,
and the other one got away.
They killed the little Ames girl.
What about Rio?
Didn't see him.
Smart.
Thought maybe they got you.
That's why I come out here.
They got me, all right.
I'll be right back.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Hold it, Rio.
Get your hands up slow.
You're all right, Dad!
Dad, I didn't mean to
take the law into my hands,
but I did what any person would do.
Take care of this one, Dad.
I want to fix his wagon.
- Take the bucket away.
- I don't need the bucket. You know that?
Who'd he ever stand up to later?
Get up there!
- Cut that out.
- Shoot. I seen the big whupping you give him.
- Get him!
- Stop!
- Get him.
- I'll remember this.
You'll remember nothing. Now, get back!
You're gonna get yours.
Hear me?
You'll get him, Lon.
Oh, no. Come in. Hurry it up.
Hurry up. Come on. Outside.
That's all.
You too, Lon.
Well, that's it, kid.
I guess there's nothing more to say.
Dad.
Got a minute?
Sure, kid.
You know I didn't send Bob Amory
in there to tell you to stay home.
Well, I could be wrong.
But then I'm not going to be judging you.
Those folks out there will.
They'll be your jury.
You're dying to get me hung, ain't you?
No, kid.
You've been trying to get yourself hung
for the past ten years,
and this time
I think you're gonna make it.
You should have quit when you were ahead.
Like you, huh?
Mm-hmm. Like me.
You're a one-eyed jack around here, Dad.
I seen the other side of your face.
You know where I spent
the last five years?
Rottin' my guts out
down in that pen in Sonora.
Now, what you think of that?
I think you're lying.
Faster than a dog can trot.
I am gonna get a trial, ain't I, Dad?
Oh, sure, kid, sure.
You'll get a fair trial.
And then I'm gonna hang you, personally.
Rio?
I had to come.
I'm glad you did.
I was kind of hoping you would.
You're lookin' fine. Just fine.
Maybe if we had seen each other again,
you would change your mind.
Louisa, I wasn't coming in after Dad.
And I don't know nothin' about that bank.
I was coming in to take you away with me.
I was gonna ask you to be my wife.
It is true?
I ain't got no time for lyin'.
Listen to me.
I want to tell you something.
I am going to have your baby.
Why didn't you tell me before?
Because I was afraid.
I thought that you don't want.
No.
He will be something wonderful...
because he is our love.
And you will be very proud of him.
I love you, Louisa.
I never did get a chance to say it.
I want you to know something, that...
I'll be thinking about you tomorrow.
Don't say that.
They will listen to you at the trial...
and they will know that you are innocent.
But you must believe that.
You bet.
All right. Let's go.
Come on.
Sorry to have to break up
this little Valentine.
You heard me.
Step back.
Turn around.
Get ahold of them bars.
Keep your feet back.
There ain't no call for that, Lon.
What's the matter with you?
Nothin'. Just sorry the county's
gonna take care of him.
I'd like to do it myself, with this,
with both barrels of double-aught shot
about waist high.
Want to?
Let's see you pull it, Lon.
All right.
Go ahead.
Make a try for it.
There ain't no need for that, Lon.
All you got to do is just squeeze one off.
Go on. You're supposed to
have so much guts.
Mm-mmm.
You're the one with the gut, Lon.
Second thought, maybe it'd be more fun
to wait till tomorrow.
How's your face gonna look?
All turnin' black,
and your tongue is stickin' out.
Why don't you just
shut your big mouth, Lon?
Why don't you tend to your own business?
You're forgettin' one thing, Lon.
Yeah? What's that?
Ain't hung yet.
Yeah, but you will be, brother.
You ain't gettin' no older than tomorrow.
Oh, say.
Let's don't forget about her.
I'll be taking care of that
before they cut you down.
You gob of spit.
I sure am, ain't I?
You watch yourself.
What's the matter? Aren't you hungry?
What is going to happen to him?
What's going to happen to who?
Is he really going to be hanged?
Oh, of course he is.
Could it be that you have your own reasons
for wanting him to die?
No. No reasons at all.
He just, uh, robbed the bank
and killed a little girl, that's all.
Why do you ask?
I hear you might have personal reasons.
Personal reasons?
Like what?
Oh, the story about you run away from him
in Mexico and leave him to die.
Did you?
Is this truth?
I've heard that story.
- Where did you hear it?
- He told Louisa.
Smart pup.
It is the truth?
The truth? Why, he'd choke on the truth.
What the hell is the matter with you?
I will tell you.
Louisa's going to have his baby.
Yes.
Please listen to me.
You have been good to us,
and I'm grateful.
But if I talk to you so, it's because
I don't want my daughter to suffer as I did.
- Then you lied to me that morning.
- Yes, I lied to you, but...
Shut up!
Is this the thanks I get
for taking you out of the bean fields
and giving you respectability?
I gave you the clothes on your back.
And I gave you a roof over your head.
And what's more,
I gave your daughter my name.
Mine.
When she had none of her own.
Everything you say is truth.
But now she needs your help
more than ever.
Help?
Yeah.
I'll help.
It's taken me five years
to build this decent life.
- I'm not gonna let him ruin —
- Killing him will not help!
- Let go my arms.
- Please.
- Let go of my hand!
- Please!
- He's guilty, and he's gonna pay.
- Don't lie to me anymore.
I saw it on your face
since the first day he came here.
Your hatred is more important to you
than anything,
including our own lives.
And you will do anything to hide
that memory of what you did to him,
even to kill.
I told you to shut up.
His execution will be a day earlier.
That's all.
What do you think you're doing up here?
Get on back down them stairs.
I brought him something to eat.
Tell you what.
Why don't you just trot on home,
'cause you ain't gonna give him nothin'.
My father told me to bring this,
and you're supposed to give it to him.
He never said nothin' to me about it.
All right. I'll tell him that you refused.
Wait a minute.
Let me see it.
- What do you got in here anyhow?
- That's just some stew.
Just take a little peek.
You're not supposed to touch that.
- I love you, Rio!
- Come here, you little runt.
I love you! I love you!
Now get back!
Take your hands off her!
Get your damn hands off her!
¡Suelta!
¡Suéltame, animal! ¡Suéltame!
- I'll stick a fork in you!
- ¡Suelta!
I'm taking you out of here and let Tim
keep you till your daddy gets back.
That's right, Lon.
Now, up in here right quick.
I count eight, and I ain't got them keys,
I'm gonna take you off at the neck.
One.
You ain't about to take my neck off
with that little old popper.
That's two.
You'll be lucky if you hit the wall.
Three.
I might get shot up a little bit
diving down these stairs,
but you're gonna hang any way you put it.
Four.
- You're runnin' a bluff, and I'm gonna call you.
- Five.
Go ahead. Try it, Lon.
Six.
All I gotta do is duck a little bit,
and you're done.
Seven.
- That's eight.
- I'm comin'.
Open that door.
Easy now.
Now turn around
and come in here backwards.
Step in here.
Left hand. Take that belt off.
Down on your knees.
Lookee here, Lon. Wasn't loaded.
Get back, you.
Get them keys out.
Take them chains off.
- Now —
- Oh, please, God, don't kill me.
You remember, Lon?
I told you I ain't hung yet.
- I don't want to die!
- How you gonna look?
How you gonna look, Lon?
Kickin' and snappin',
spittin' out your blood.
- Oh, please, don't kill me. Don't.
- Huh?
Get on up here.
Get on up, Lon. Get up!
Now just turn around and get your turn.
Don't move.
Get up.
You get in there and send me
the best horse you've got, and quick.
I ain't got any. They're all gone.
You're gonna die if you're lyin'.
Get — Turn around, you.
Put your hands down.
- McKittrick around?
- No. He's over to the saloon.
Oh.
Help! Help, somebody!
Help! Tim!
Get off that horse.
Somebody help!
Help! He's gettin' away!
Help!
Dad, it's me up here, Lon!
You killed Dad!
It's all over. Wasn't nothin' else to do.
- Come on.
- No.
Come on. There's nothin' to do.
I gotta leave you here, Louisa.
Yes, you must go now, quickly.
I want you to tell your mother something.
I want you to tell her that I tried to run,
but he didn't give me no chance.
And tell her I'm —
Well, just tell her whatever you have to.
Will you be all right?
Where can you go now?
I don't know.
I'll have to figure that out later.
Maybe Oregon.
I'll be ridin' for a while anyhow.
Why don't you go to Mexico?
I could meet you in Sonora in April.
After my baby comes.
No, I —
No.
They're lookin'
all over hell for me in Mexico.
That don't matter. Listen.
You be lookin' for me in the spring.
One of them dark nights,
you're gonna see a jackass in the window,
and it's gonna be me.
Don't worry about it.
I'll find someplace.
I better start kickin' now.
Go. Please, go.
I love you, Rio.
Take care of yourself,
because I'm so afraid to losing you.
Adiós, mi bien.