Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes
# You were meant for me. #
Don't play that, Applejack.
# I was meant for.... #
- I'm leaving.
- Julie!
Would you go down to the station
and get me a ticket on the 11:00?
And cash that check for me.
Smith will do it for you.
And I'd like you to drive me
to the train.
Julie, you'd better think this over.
I have been thinking it over,
Applejack.
I've been thinking about it for days.
You and Roger have been
married a long time.
We don't need each other anymore.
When that happens to two people...
nothing left.
# You were meant for me. #
# I was meant for you. #
# for you... for you... for... #
# You were meant for me. #
# I was meant for you. #
# for you... for you... for you... #
# You're like a plaintiff melody. #
# That never lets me free. #
# For I'm content the angels
must have sent you #
# and they meant you just for me. #
What can I do for you?
- The record department.
- They're right here.
How about that one up there,
that book?
- Beethoven?
- Yes, the furthest one, see?
Number seven.
Oh, you keep them down here.
- Needles?
- No, no.
- Who plays the sheet music here?
- I do.
-Oh, you do that?
-Hm-hmm.
-Would you mind playing that for me?
-Certainly, I'd be glad to.
# ...plaintiff melody. #
# And I'm content the angels
must have sent you #
# and they meant you just for me. #
New tune, isn't it?
I beg your pardon?
It's a new tune.
Oh, I didn't hear you.
Yes, it just came in.
-Would be nice to dance to.
-It is.
-What's on the other side?
- It's another new one.
- Would you mind playing it for me?
- No.
This way.
# For I'm content the angels
must have sent you #
# and they meant you just for me. #
- Good night.
Buy a flower, mister.
I'm going this way, honest.
I'm going this way, too, honest.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
- I live here, that's all.
- Oh.
- Well, good night.
- Good night.
Oh...
Would you mind if I ask you
a personal question?
Guess not.
- Have you got a victrola inside?
Why, yes, of course.
Would you let me hear this one?
Otherwise I'll have to take it home
and imagine how it sounds.
- Don't you have a machine at home?
- No.
Well, why on earth did you buy 27...?
# In my dreams it seems #
# your face is near to me... #
# and it's dear to me #
# oh, it's just a memory. #
What are you thinking about?
That it's our song they're playing.
At least that's what you said
when we were dancing.
What are you thinking about?
Oh, just wishing.
Wishing I could be with you
every day like this.
I mean, I wish everyday could be
a holiday like this.
I mean, never have to go back home,
never have to go to work.
It would be perfect, wouldn't it?
- What's it say?
- Oh, nothing. It's silly.
- Come on.
- No, really. It' s silly.
Those things are a lot of bunk,
they never come true.
Go on, beat it.
You don't like kids very much,
do you?
Oh, I like them, all right,
except when they're pests.
- What does it say?
- Hm?
- Come on.
- Oh, nothing, nothing.
Come on, tell me.
Come on.
Unromantic.
I thought you said we'd have
the place to ourselves.
Oh, just the ocean.
The beach I couldn't get.
Hey, you're doing all right.
Two or three more lessons
and you'll be able to swim.
You can almost float now.
When your arms are holding me up.
When you're with me, you're safe.
I don't know whether it's safe or not.
I'm darned if I do either.
It must be getting late.
Let's get dressed.
No, there's plenty of time.
I'm thinking about that last train home.
Come on, Roger.
Get dressed.
All right.
It's raining.
Put them someplace where
I can grab them faster.
I don't belong here.
Of course you belong here.
Didn't I invite you?
Come on in and meet
some of my friends.
Night's cold...
Is there a drink in the house?
Right off the boat.
That's what the bootlegger said.
- Did he say what boat?
- Well, what boat would you like?
We have all the labels.
Come on, help yourself.
-You?
- Never use it.
You know, this party
may turn out all right at that.
- Where's Roger?
-I thought maybe you'd know.
You're crazy about that reporter,
aren't you?
I'm sort of fond of him.
That's bad.
I hate seeing a nice girl like you
getting mixed up with a newspaper man.
Gosh, you never know
what they're up to.
They can get away with anything,
alibiing their work.
It's a lot of fun docking around
interviewing chorus girls
and all that sort of thing.
You think it's swell getting married...
Applejack, don't worry about me.
I don't need any advice.
I never even thought
about getting married.
- No fooling?
- No fooling.
- Well I've been worried sick.
- About what?
I've been telling him for six months
if he doesn't keep away from you
he'll find himself married.
Julie, I've got to talk to you
right away.
Where can we be alone?
I've had a real break.
Flynn quit his job over in Tokyo.
He's our Japanese correspondent.
He got fed up with the assignment,
or the weather, or something.
Imagine the spot that left the paper in.
Only one man in the Orient
and he walked out on the job.
Darling, you're cold.
Here, put this around you.
I'm just so excited.
There you are.
You're going to take his place?
That's what they want me to do.
I've got a ticket here for a train
that leaves at 3:00 a.m.
Gets me to San Francisco just in time
to catch the next boat for Yokohama.
I can't believe it yet, Julie.
Imagine them picking me.
You're able, Roger.
You have ability.
Anybody can see that.
You're going, hm?
That's what I want
to talk to you about, honey.
It's a good salary.
Two-year contract.
And I'm more or less my own boss.
It's the kind of opportunity
I've always wanted.
So look, dear, I was wondering...
Listen, little boy.
Of course I want you to go.
If that's what's worrying you,
please don't think...
No, I wasn't worrying about that.
I knew you'd want me
to take the job, sure.
But, Julie...
let's get married.
Let's get married right away, tonight.
I'll be able to send for you in three months.
I'll have the money then.
Three months?
Why the rush to get married now?
Well, do you think I'm going to let
a funny little redhead
like you run around loose here?
Suppose some other fellow
came along...
Oh, Julie, I've got to have you.
Until death do us part?
Till death do us part.
Happy New Year!
I've got a cab waiting.
All we have to do is sign a license.
Happy New Year!
For richer or poorer...
For richer or poorer.
in sickness and in health,
In sickness and in health,
to love and to cherish,
till death do us part.
All aboard.
The ticket.
We made it.
- Well, good bye, Applejack.
- Good bye, boy.
- Keep an eye on Julie for me.
- I sure will, boy.
So long, Dot.
Take good care of her.
I will.
Good bye.
Good bye, darling.
Excuse me a minute.
-Wait for me.
-All right.
Oh, Roger, I can't say good bye.
Here you are, sir.
Thank you.
It's not good bye, darling.
It's just see you later.
-Is there anything I can do
for you, boss?
-How soon does the train pull out?
- In about three minutes, sir.
Thank you.
Well, Mrs. Adams.
Mrs. Adams!
Sounds strange.
Not strange.
It sounds great.
- Does sound great, doesn't it
- Yes, darling.
There's something about a train.
I don't know whether it's the way
it looks or the way it smells, or what it is.
It always makes me feel
I want to be off somewhere.
I know, darling. I always feel
the same way.
Oh, Roger,
I wish this was our honeymoon.
Oh, I do too, darling.
Promise me something, will you?
Promise me never to take it off.
I'll never take it off,
no matter what happens.
Thank you, darling.
Roger, the train's moving.
I'll get you off in a minute.
All aboard!.
Write from Yokohama.
Roger.
Darling.
Oh, sweet.
Here we are.
- Ours?
- Yours.
Roger, I didn't expect anything like this.
It's like something in a dream.
These are our servants,
Cook-San and O'Hanna-San.
How do you do?
-  Hello.
- Hello.
Hello, there.
- Whose children are they?
- The servant's children. They live here.
I thought you didn't like children.
Who, me? They're all right.
Come on in.
How do you like the place?
It's lovely. But it's so luxurious.
How could we afford it?
Don't be so practical
when I'm being highly romantic.
Nothing's too good for my little wife.
Come on and see it.
- How do you like that?
- It's beautiful.
You are sweet.
But I would have been satisfied
with anything just to be here.
Oh, I know you would, darling.
But only the best for you.
Come on, we have an upstairs
to this house too.
- We have a shinshitsu.
- What's a shinshitsu?
Shinshitsu is the Japanese word
for bedroom, believe it or not.
That's right, you wrote me
you spoke Japanese.
Roger, it's perfect.
Simply perfect.
I thought you'd like it.
Hello, there.
Roger, are we going to keep it,
I mean, stay here right along?
Why, certainly.
It's yours.
I bought the lease from
an American that went back.
I got the lease, the furniture,
two servants, three kids...
a cat, and her kid.
All for 2,000 yen.
Two thousand yen.
How much is that?
About a thousand dollars.
- A thousand dollars.
- That's right.
How in the world did you do it?
I mean...
get the money to send to me
and buy all this too?
- I got an advance.
- Advance?
Sure. An advance on the salary.
Everybody does out here.
Only the other day a fellow
down at the office was saying...
he wished April was here.
And I said why?
And he said, so I could get an advance
on my December salary.
Oh, now, darling.
You're not going to be one of those wives
always worried about money, are you?
No, only...
Besides, you forget we still
have the inheritance.
Yes, I know, but I'd sort of
hate to start off in debt, especially...
You've got a lot to learn
about the Orient.
Roger...
Remember this?
Sure, it's one of those fortune things
you got at the beach.
Fancy you keeping that.
They're not always the bunk,
you said that.
Did I say that?
Well, well.
Sometimes, like wishes,
they come true.
Sure they do, certainly.
Well, why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't you write me?
You don't like them.
I don't like them?
Why, of course I do.
Why would I have three of them
running around the hou...?
And this will be our own.
An American kid.
Our own.
Gee, that's great.
Oh, Roger, I'm so relieved.
You funny little redhead.
Very fine kimono.
Very expensive.
- Husband must be rich man.
- He's either rich or...
- Moshi moshi!
- Hi!
- What are you doing home
this time of the day?
- What makes you so beautiful. huh?
- How did you get off so early?
Come on, let me see you.
Well, if having babies
makes you look like this
we'd better keep on having them.
- How do you like it?
- Oh, Roger, I adore it.
Why all this today?
This isn't my birthday.
It's a souvenir.
A souvenir of your stay in Japan...
because, darling, we're leaving.
Leaving Japan?
Hm-hmm.
Now brace yourself for good news,
Mrs. Adams,
because good news is what I bring.
We now belong to that class of society
known as the filthy rich.
- Roger, the inheritance.
- Yes.
- You got it!
- Yes, mam.
- That's wonderful.
- There, now, you see?
You didn't believe me about it,
did you?
- No, no, I didn't...
- Isn't it great?
Thank you for the dolly.
-  Thank you for the ball.
- Oh, that's all right.
I'm teaching him to be a first baseman.
Now, paragraph two,
Mr. and Mrs. Roger Adams,
socially prominent young couple
plan to take a trip around the world.
-The paper's sending you?
- No, I quit the paper.
We're going to have a last fling
before we settle down
and become good old American parents
But, Roger, you just didn't give up
your job on the paper
- ...for no reason at all?
- Oh, darling, this trip's an inspiration.
Do you remember the honeymoon
I promised you?
Well we're gonna have it.
But everything's different now.
We've got to think about the baby.
That's just it. As soon as the baby comes
we won't be able to go anywhere.
Besides, I want our baby born
in the USA.
Maybe even get to work
and start a little paper.
But a trip like this costs a fortune.
Did you get more than the $20.000?
No, as a matter of fact
we didn't get the $20.000.
We sold the property for cash
and got $13.500.
Well, can you take a trip, buy a paper
and all like that on $13.500?
Don't forget there's still lawyers' fees,
deductions and stuff like that.
Just how much did you get, Roger?
I'm trying to tell you.
After the deductions we got $10,000.
- Ten thousand?
- Hm-hmm.
I still got a couple of thousand
in bills around here to pay.
Then you really got only $8,000.
Yes.
Well, did you ever have
that much money in your life?
No.
Then what are you squawking about?
I'm not squawking.
I just think you're acting like a child.
We should be thinking about the future.
You rush in and pack your things
and give up a perfectly good job.
- No grown-up man shouldn't act like that.
- Oh, all right.
I thought the trip would be
a lot of fun for you.
If I had known you would feel
like that, I wouldn't have planned on it.
That's all right, let's forget it.
We won't go.
I'll go in and arrange for the packing.
Oh, no, forget about it.
Well, that's all.
Otherwise, you'll enjoy perfect health.
You'll be playing tennis
in a couple of months.
Now I've got some good news for you.
I'm letting your husband
see you today. How's that?
Pretty.
Make you feel better?
I've had my hands full
keeping that boy out of here
for the last couple of days.
- Hello, darling.
- Hello, Roger.
How sweet.
Gee, I've been miserable
not being able to see you, honey.
But I've had a chance
to do some serious thinking, dear.
I've been scouting around
the nearby towns
trying to look for that
little newspaper, you know.
No more silly ideas
like travelling around, darling.
You were absolutely right about that.
I think I found it, honey.
It's in a little town just north of here,
a place called Rosalia.
- Did you ever hear of it?
- Hm-hmm.
It's pretty nearly
the kind of place we wanted.
The fellow who owns the place
has been kind of letting it go to seed, but
we can make something of it.
Best of all, darling,
we'll have a home of our own.
Something we'll always call ours.
If I can make a go of the paper,
I'll be able to get you anything you want.
I'll be able to get you furniture,
a car, clothes, everything.
You know, it's strange, Roger...
but I can't get myself to care
about those things now.
They don't seem important anymore.
The one thing I've really wanted...
I'm never going to have.
- What do you think of this one, Skeeter?
- Quite an improvement.
Gee, Mr. Adams, I'd like to get a job
in a live wire outfit like this.
You would? All right, Skeetey,
you've got one, and a permanent job, too.
Oh, boy.
- Applejack.
- Howdy!
- Hello, fellow!
- How's the old married man?
You had me worried.
Thought you were gonna let me down.
So this is the fastest growing
little newspaper
in the fastest growing little town
in the west.
- Certainly!
- And you left the Bulletin for this.
What you got here?
Our new makeup.
What do you think of it?
You printed in code?
No, the linotype machine is stuck.
Why did you think I sent for you?
Applejack!
Miss Julie!
Am I glad to see you.
Come on up and help me
fix the bathtub. You're just in time.
Wait a minute.
Let him fix this first.
All right. The newspaper always
comes first around here.
Come on.
What've you been feeding it?
- Is the switch on?
- Yeah.
Now where's that bathtub?
Hello, Applejack.
I didn't know you were busy.
I'm not busy.
I've just been thinking about
fixing up this old storeroom.
I just wanted to show you a new ad
we got from the telephone company.
- Well, that helps, doesn't it?
- Sure does.
If we keep on with it
we'll pay the paper bill next month.
Is Roger back yet?
No, he's still out
running down subscriptions.
Said he might not be home till late.
Well, come on then. Sit down, Applejack.
We might as well have our dinner.
Miss Julie, we ought to have
a kid around this house.
I thought you knew about that,
Applejack.
Sure I know about that.
But I'm talking about adopting one.
Sure you can get
some pretty ones that way.
You know, I'm an adopted kid myself.
I know that's not much
of a recommendation, but...
it didn't turn out so bad.
Besides, I know a lot of regular kids
who wound up in jail.
Miss Julie, I wish you could have seen
some of those little sons of guns
I used to room with.
They was the cutest little rascals
you'd ever want to look at.
I don't think Roger would want
a child that way, Applejack.
One that wasn't his own.
Why not?
He's no sucker.
He don't want to gamble.
How do you know what it's gonna be like
if it's gotta be your own?
This way you just walk in
and help yourself to exactly what you want.
There's no guess work.
You know, I thought a lot about that.
I want one.
Roger was so disappointed when...
I just haven't had the courage to...
Miss Julie, do you want
to know something?
He's all for the idea.
Only a few days ago we were working
together and I was talking with him...
- You were talking to him about this?
- Sure.
He's all for it.
Why didn't he say something to me?
He was afraid to say
anything to you...
he was afraid you might have
some fool notions.
Silly notions?
Why, if he only knew how many...
Why, the very idea.
My own husband talking about
things like this with the printer.
- Press Manager, please.
- All right, the press manager.
- Are you going to be the mother?
- No, I just thought I...
Fine thing. Wait till I get
my hands on that fellow.
Hello, what's going on?
A fight?
- Hello, Roger.
I want you to take a look at that new ad.
Would you come downstairs...
No, Roger.
Wait a minute. Applejack.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Hm? Tell you what?
What you and Applejack
have been talking about.
Miss Julie, I told you in confidence.
What were you talking about?
What did you say to her?
- You know, about the...
- He told me.
- Told you what?
- You know, what we were talking about...
What were we talking about?
Roger, if you wanted to adopt a baby,
why didn't you talk to me?
Yes, you should've told her
in the first place, Roger, not me.
I'm not gonna be the mother.
Wait a minute. Did you tell Julie
I wanted to adopt a baby?
I hinted at it.
I tried to break it to her gently.
- Oh, you told her!
- Yeah.
Roger, I'm so glad
you feel that way.
Yes, she wants it
even more than you, Roger.
Well, if that's the way
we all feel about it.
I like it too
- I suppose it's settled.
- Oh, Roger, I'm so glad.
If it hadn't been for Applejack
letting it slip out
I don't suppose
I ever would have known.
Guess I'd better go fix that press.
Yeah, you fix everything up,
don't you?
Didn't do so bad with the bathtub.
Julie, one other thing...
Look, er...
When you get to this place,
don't get enthusiastic right off the bat.
You know, don't just rush in and grab
the first kid you see and go nuts about it.
What makes you think I'll grab
the first one they show me?
I've been doing the shopping
in this family for some time now...
I just don't bring home anything.
You came home with this tie,
didn't you?
It's nice.
Everybody's wearing bow ties.
I have your letter here.
Two-year-old child, blue eyes...
curly hair, dimpled chin,
sweet disposition...
We'd prefer a boy.
But we'd like to look at the girl, too.
Julie, you know we agreed on a boy.
But it won't hurt to look, will it?
All right, we'll look.
Now, what can you show us?
This is the Administration Building.
We don't have any children here at all.
Oh.
Everybody wants blue eyes,
curly hair, dimple... sweet...
Everybody wants a two-year-old child.
Will you tell me why?
Well, you see, in our case,
that would have been the age
of our own child, if...
Oh, I see.
Anyway, when they're two years old,
they're more or less
house-broken then, aren't they?
Not always.
At the moment we haven't
any children available at all.
There's a long waiting list,
there are three applications for every child.
If you get one within a year,
you'll be lucky.
- What?
- A year?
You mean to say
we might have to wait a year?
Well, after all, real parents
wait almost a year.
- Yes, certainly...
- You see, we've waited so long already.
I know, my dear.
But you're both very young.
Then, too, we have to have time
to make our investigation.
Investigation?
Yes, you see. we're just as particular
about you as prospective parents
as you are about the child.
Naturally.
What is your business, Mr. Adams?
I'm a publisher.
I run the Rosalia Courier.
- Publisher?
- Sure.
I beg your pardon.
Mrs. Green is on the phone.
What shall I tell her?
Oh..
Tell her that we're sorry.
But according to our investigator's report
we find that Mr. Green
doesn't have a steady income.
Later perhaps, if he finds himself
better situated, we'll...
reconsider their application.
You see, it's not our aim to place
our children in homes of wealth...
but it's absolutely necessary for us
to have the assurance
that the adoptive parents
are financially responsible.
Oh, sure.
I see in your letter
that you live in the country.
Good. I presume that means then
that you have a house and yard.
- Well...
- No, we don't have a yard.
We live in an apartment.
But there's a nice park nearby.
We've got a swell roof too.
We've been putting a fence around it.
And I could build a slide and a sandbox.
As a matter of fact,
a roof is better for a kid
because then he can't get on the street, see?
Look, it doesn't have
to be a yard, does it?
No, but you have a separate room
for the child, haven't you?
That's very important.
Oh, yes, we have a lovely room.
It's practically fixed up now.
Oh, well that's fine.
Now, about income.
Approximately, how much
do you make a week?
Well, I couldn't tell you offhand.
I imagine about $100 a week.
Of course, I'd have to look at the books.
Well, that's excellent.
If you'll just take that application
home with you,
fill it out and mail it in to us
so we'll have all the details.
Then in due time, one of our investigators
will call on you.
Fine.
You'll call us before she comes,
won't you?
No, we just drop in.
That's our policy.
You see, we want to find your house
as it is everyday...
- ...not when it's fixed up for company.
- I see.
- Good bye.
- Good bye, Miss Oliver.
Oh... it doesn't matter
if he hasn't got curly hair.
It doesn't really matter.
- They're darn choosy, if you ask me.
- Why do you have to be a big shot?
- When?
- You know we don't make $100 a week.
You want the baby, don't you?
They can't prove it.
We don't keep books.
Hey, quit stalling.
Get on with the cleaning.
Look, honey, left from the earthquake.
From Japan?
You'd better buy some more.
Excuse me, lady.
You should give a fellow a warning.
Does Mrs. Adams live here?
Yes, upstairs. I'll call her.
Don't bother. I'm Miss Oliver
from the orphanage. I'll find her.
I don't think she's home just now.
I think she's in church.
In church?
This time of day?
Well, you see, she and Mr. Adams
go there quite a lot.
They just go there and sit.
Fine people, mam.
Well, I'm sure she won't mind
if I just look around a bit.
No, she won't mind.
-How do you do, Miss Oliver?
- How do you do, Mrs. Adams?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
Won't you sit down?
- Here.
- No, thank you.
- You've come to see the apartment?
- That's right.
This is it. It's not very neat
at the moment. We're cleaning.
I see.
That's our little breakfast room out there.
And uh...
if you'll step right this way...
This is our kitchen.
My husband has been meaning
to fix this door for some time, it's...
he's been so busy...
And that brings us back
to the breakfast room.
- Can I fix you a cup of tea?
- No, thank you.
You spoke of a child's room.
A lovely room.
Yes, that's over here.
- Well, this is sweet.
- You really like it?
Any child would be lucky
to have a room like this.
Well, I want you to see our yard.
We're fixing that up too.
Well...
Hello, Miss Oliver.
Didn't expect you.
I just finished making it.
I thought I'd try it out see if it was
strong enough for that two-year old.
I think I have a surprise for you.
A baby came in yesterday.
- No!
- Miss Oliver, you mean...
- Here, come and sit down.
- Thank you.
Sit down.
That's the reason we came around
to see you sooner than we expected.
It's a little girl..
We don't want a girl.
Five weeks and three days old.
Five weeks!
Well, we did speak
of an older child, you know.
You might have to wait a long time.
After all, aren't you making to great
a point of a child's age, Mr. Adams?
Eventually this child
will be two years old.
But we don't know anything
about little babies.
No one does until they have them.
And this is such an unusual little baby.
Actually there's another couple
who has first choice...
and that's strictly off the record.
But somehow I feel she's exactly
the child for you.
That's why I wanted you to see her first
and I couldn't resist giving you the chance.
- Did you bring her with you
- No, she's in the nursery.
You and Mr. Adams will have to come
over to the city to see her.
What's she like, Miss Oliver?
Well, I can't describe her exactly,
but she's...
well, she's like no other child.
Like no other child.
But she isn't a boy.
But look, Roger,
there's no harm in looking at her.
If you don't like her,
I won't say a word.
What's the use? We don't want her.
Please, darling.
It won't hurt to look at her.
Well, all right, we'll look.
That's fine. You call me up and I'll make
an appointment at the nursery.
I must go now.
If you change your mind,
you will call me up, won't you?
Yes, yes.
Miss Oliver, please don't show her to that
other couple until we've seen her, will you?
I won't, my dear.
She's like no other child.
That's why I wanted you
to see her first.
Like no other child.
Well, how about him?
This is a day nursery.
All these youngsters have parents.
All except this lovely little girl.
What a grip...
For a girl, I mean.
Would you like to hold her?
May I.
How are you, kid?
Well, you've had your look, dear.
How about going back home?
All right, she's yours, I guess.
- When do we get her?
- Now, if you like.
She's yours on a year's probation.
Now?
You mean we can just walk out
of here with her like this?
It sometimes happens that way...
if we make sure that the parents
and the baby are just right for each other.
We have no clothes for her.
We don't know how to feed her.
It's such a little baby.
Miss Morgan will take care of everything.
She'll give you the formulas and so forth...
then you can go downtown
and buy whatever is necessary.
Thank you, Miss Oliver,
for being so kind.
Don't thank me.
It just happened so.
Perhaps before you make up
your minds fully to take the child...
you'd like to have me go
into her history.
I assure you it's an excellent one.
If she'll take a chance on us,
we'll take a chance on her.
- Good bye.
- Good bye, Miss. Oliver.
I'll shut the door.
I she wakes up again,
you know what that means.
Wait a minute. Wait with that baby
till I turn on the light.
I don't want you to drop him...
I mean her.
Take off your shoes.
Go get the big one in our room.
Come on... let me have it
It's all right with her.
Come on, let's go to bed.
No.
I don't think I'll go to bed.
She eats again in a half hour.
The directions say so.
Set the alarm.
Come on.
Turn the bed clothes down, will you?
Turn it off!
Press it!
Please.
What's the matter with it?
I don't know.
Do you think she's all right?
Huh?
Is it breathing?
She's certainly a cute a little baby,
isn't she?
We were lucky to get her.
Let's go to bed.
Well, do something, quickly!
What do I do?
Do something. Can't you see
the baby's suffering?
That's just it.
I don't know what to do.
Don't just stand there!
Do something!
Here. You take her.
Hm?
Go on. You do something.
Oh, no... I'm going to get Miss Oliver.
Just wanted her daddy.
Pull the chair, please.
Julie! The baby!
It's gone!
The baby's kidnapped!
She was lonesome
so I brought her in here with us.
Don't ever do that to me again!
Good morning, boys.
What are you trying to do?
Shut it off!
- What are you trying to do?
- What am I trying to do?
I'm trying to get your crummy paper out,
that's what I'm trying to do.
What's the idea of waking
the baby up?
- What baby?
- My baby.
- Your baby?
- Yeah, it came last night.
No fooling, a baby?
- A baby, a baby!
- Quiet, quiet!
Come on, I'll show you.
- Can I help?
- No.
- Sure you don't want me to help?
- No, thanks.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing's the matter.
What's the trouble?
I can't do anything as long as
you're sitting here watching me.
Get out! Go on,
get out all of you!
What do you think this is?
Go on, get down to that paper.
And be quiet about it.
Oh, Roger, I'm afraid I'll drown it.
Oh, now, darling, take it easy.
I could drown in that much water.
Here.
Now, little peanut...
your Uncle Applejack's gonna
give you a nice bath.
Give me that wash rag.
There we are.
I'll never be able to do that.
We'll have to give her back.
Sure you will, darling.
All you gotta do is decide
who's boss and throw her in.
How in the world did you ever
learn to do that, Applejack?
My sister had four kids.
She'd take two and I'd take two.
Where's that towel?
There we are.
- Where's the talcum?
- Hm? Here.
Cootchie-cootchie-coo.
- Where is it?
- What?
- It.
- Oh, here...
- There we are.
You sure is my fine girl.
Just a minute, now..
Think you can hold this a minute
without dropping it?
Here, give it here.
I forget whether...
Now watch this closely.
I'm a one-pin man myself.
There we are.
Let's see you jump out of there, peanut.
Here you go to your mama.
Better write all that down,
cause I might get a better offer.
# Just Molly and me,
and baby makes three. #
# We're happy in my blue heaven. #
- She hasn't got your smile, Roger.
- Oh, sure, she's good-looking.
- Still sorry she wasn't a boy?
- Hm?
A boy.
What do you mean a boy?
Did you hear that? You wanted a boy.
I didn't want no boy.
Trina's Daddy's little girl,
aren't you, Trina?
Roger, be careful now.
Hello!
- Hello, Miss Oliver.
- How do you do, Mrs. Adams.
Come in.
Thank you so much for letting us know
you were coming this time.
- Hello, Miss Oliver.
- Oh, hello, Mr. Adams.
Trina, this is your fairy godmother,
Miss Oliver.
Hello, sweetheart.
Yes, she's not very timid, is she?
I can plainly see that she
adores her father.
She means everything to us.
What's the matter, got a cold?
Yes, you do. Everything.
When are we going to own her outright?
- You go before the judge the 27th.
- 27th, eh?
- You'll want to see these charts.
- Yes.
One you can send back to us.
And the other you'll file with the court,
at the court with the final papers.
These are the same questions
that you answered last year.
I just want to bring them up to date.
Now let's see.
Religion?
Same.
Age?
- One year older.
- I have that.
Profession?
Still publisher, isn't it?
Yes.
Income?
Well, you see, Miss Oliver...
None.
Oh, that's the way it is
in the newspaper game, Miss Oliver.
Specially when you're starting
one of your own.
You have to close down once
before you really get going.
Oh, it's only temporary. I'm having a jam
with my wholesale paper mill.
First thing you know
I'll have it humming by the 27th.
It's only closed for a while.
I'm sure you'll find a way,
Mr. Adams.
But you and I have to prove
to the judge
that your income is enough
to take care of Trina.
You know we gave everything
Trina needed.
no matter who else had to suffer
around here.
I realize that.
Well, I must go now.
That's all we can do today.
Could I drive you to the train?
No, thank you.
I really like to walk.
This country air is so fresh.
Good bye.
The battle axe.
She doesn't want us to have Trina.
Yes, she does, darling.
Oh yes, she does.
Better prepare your facts.
- The option receipt. The Adams case.
- What?
The Adams case.
Oh, yes, yes.
And if either one or both
of you gentlemen conduct yourselves
like you've been doing today
I'll hold you in contempt, the both of you.
Oh, this is the child in question.
Yes, I see, hm...
Looking over these adoption papers here
I see that you have no income
at present.
Is that correct?
Yes, Your Honor.
What is this, Miss Oliver?
You know this case
should never have come before me.
Well, Your Honor,
I feel that this is a special case.
I kept hoping until the last minute...
that Mr. Adams might be able
to resume the run of his paper
or get a job.
But unfortunately he hasn't been able
to do either, so I thought...
Under these conditions
I can't grant the adoption.
This child will have to revert
to the orphanage.
Will you draw up a chair, please,
while I prepare these
release papers for you to sign?
It's just a matter of routine.
If you please, Your Honor...
it can't just be a matter of routine
for people to have their baby
taken away from them.
This child is ours, Judge.
But those are the requirements of the law.
Yes, but you see, we've had her
since she was 6 weeks old.
It just doesn't seem reasonable
that we should have to give her
back now to strangers.
Mr. Adams, you are not here
to plead your case.
You've had the regular opportunity
to prove your fitness to provide.
We are fit, Judge,
if you just look at the record.
Without any income I have no alternative.
Didn't you make that clear, Miss Oliver?
Yes, Your Honor, I did.
But I thought...
I'm sorry, but that is the law.
Look, Your Honor, she's not like
an automobile, or an icebox
or a piece of furniture or something
you buy on time...
and then when you can't keep up
the payments they take it away from you.
Now sit still and be a good girl.
Anyone could give up
those kinds of things.
But I ask you, Judge,
how can you give up your own child?
She is our child just as much
as if she'd been born to us.
No, Daddy isn't going to go away, dear.
Look, judge, we've had her
over a year now.
Why, we walked the floor with her
when she had the colic.
We've lost nights of sleep worrying
every time she had got a tooth.
We've gone through everything.
Everything that real parents have
with one of their own.
Ask Miss Oliver here about the inspections
we've had to have.
Her weight charts,
her vaccination certificates...
her toys, her dresses, her toothbrush.
They come around regularly
and check up on all those things
to see if we're taking care
of her properly.
How many real parents can keep one
of their own and go through that?
And you sit there
and say it's a matter of routine
for you to take her away from us.
Please, Mr. Adams.
I'm sorry, Judge.
But...
Well, you see, we weren't
as fortunate as most people.
We would have had
one of our own, only...
You don't know how badly
my wife wanted a child.
It wasn't so important to me, I...
I don't know, I suppose most men
are like this.
Children never meant a great deal to me.
I like them, all right, I suppose, but...
Well, what I'm trying to say is,
Your Honor...
the first time I saw her...
she looked so little and helpless...
I didn't know babies were so little.
And then when she took hold of
my finger and held on to it, she...
she just sort of walked
into my heart, Judge,
and she was there to stay.
I didn't know I could feel like that
I had always been kind of
careless and irresponsible.
I wanted to be a bigshot.
I couldn't work for anybody, I had to be
my own boss, that sort of thing.
Now here I am standing
in front of a judge...
pleading for just a little longer
so that I can prove to you...
I can support a little child
that doesn't weigh quite 20 lbs.
It's not only for my wife and me
I'm asking you to let us keep her, Judge,
it's for her sake too.
She doesn't know any parents but us.
She wouldn't know
what had happened to her.
You see, there are so many
little things about her...
nobody would understand her
the way Julie and I do.
We love her, Judge.
Please don't take her away from us.
I'm not a bigshot now, I....
I'll do anything.
I'll work for anybody.
I'll beg, I'll borrow, I'll....
Please, Judge, I'll sell anything I've got
until I get going again.
She'll never go hungry,
she'll never be without clothes...
not as long as I've got
two good hands to help me.
- She's yours, dear.
- Ours!
Now and forever.
Oh, Trina!
Nothing can ever take her
from us now.
You better hurry up, Daddy.
Mommie'll be home any minute now.
Yeah. You go and watch for her.
Let me know when she comes, hm?
- How are you getting along, Applejack?
- Ain't she a beauty?
- Here she comes.
- Now? Well, let's get the presents, quick.
Here she comes.
We'll get them later.
Where is everybody?
Quick!
Trina?
Where can everybody be
this time of the day?
Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, darling.
- Oh, thank you.
- Sit down. Let's see the presents.
I had almost forgotten today
was my birthday.
- This is from Daddy.
- Daddy?
Why, Roger,
I always wanted one like that.
- Look Applejack.
- I'm glad you like it, darling.
And this is from Uncle Applejack.
From Applejack?
Oh, I think I can guess what this is.
Handkerchief.
Oh, it's beautiful, Applejack.
I always figured a person can't have
too many handkerchiefs.
Thank you.
- And this is from me.
- From you?
I can't imagine what this is.
What on earth can...
I got you a record,
as you love records.
And 'cause you and Daddy
love each other so much.
Oh, Trina, that's sweet, darling.
Thank you.
- Come on, let's play it see how it goes.
- Come on, Trina.
Dinner's ready. Come and get it
or I'll throw it in the crate
Oh, this is wonderful!
Dinner in my own home
and I didn't have to cook it.
Well.
We sure changed the complexion
of that bird.
We certainly did.
What did you do
in school today, darling?
Oh, I almost forgot. I was choosed.
I'm going to be in the Christmas play.
In the Christmas play.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to sing in the carol.
Why, Trina, that's wonderful.
It'll be fun making you a carol's costume.
I don't need any costume.
Nobody sees me.
Nobody sees you?
All I have to wear is a clean dress
and some sneakers.
I'm the echo.
I'm a way off behind the scene.
You only hear my voice.
Miss Hopkins says it gives
a faraway sound like angels in heaven.
Well, why do you have
to wear the sneakers?
The sneakers are so I'll be quiet.
I have to walk up in the sky behind
a cloud and take a big star with me.
Then, when I get over the manger,
I stop.
And then the angels sing.
And when my turn comes,
I sing the echo.
Then I sneak off quietly.
And next year, when I'm big...
I get to be an angel
and wear an angel suit.
I'll get seen then.
Of course you'll get seen then,
darling.
Is it a long time
until next year, Daddy?
Oh, no, darling.
It'll be here in no time at all.
Oh, I forgot.
Oh my, what happened to the lights?
Shh!
Did you see the lights go out?
Happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday, dear Mommy,
happy birthday to you.
- Hurry up, Mommy.
- I'll park the car.
All right. See you out front.
Come on, dear.
I spoiled everything.
Now Miss Hopkins won't let me
be an angel next year.
- Yes, she will, darling.
- Certainly.
I was talking to her.
She said you did fine.
Why, you were better than
the rest of them put together.
See?
- Honest?
- Honest.
Gee, I don't know what people
would do without Christmas.
I don't know what we'd do
without you, honey.
Would you please stop that door
from banging?
I wish you wouldn't go out.
I've got to get out of here
and get some fresh air.
Isn't that someone downstairs?
There's someone at the front door.
May I use your phone, please?
Our car is stalled
and I'd like to call a taxi.
It's right here on the balcony.
If you'll just walk around that way.
Thank you.
I saw your light burning
and we're in such a hurry.
Cabs are always busy
on a night like this.
I do hope we can get one.
Tommy's in the Christmas play.
I hope we don't get late, Mommy.
Out car is right out in front.
I'll drive you over, if you like.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
But it wouldn't be too much trouble?
Not too much trouble.
Come, dear.
You can't start the car.
The battery's dead.
I'll have to crank it.
I do hope we're not late, Mama.
I can't thank you enough.
If you only knew what these things
mean to a child.
Let's get out of here.
Roger!
What's the matter?
Take the car on home.
- Roger!
- I'm not coming home.
I don't ever want to see anything
or anyone that reminds me.
All right.
Good bye.
# We strolled the lane together #
# laughed at the rain together. #
# Sang love's refrain together #
# We'll always be together. #
# You were meant for me #
# I was meant for you. #
# Nature patterned you
and when she was done... #
# you were... #
- Here's your tickets.
Those cool songs kind of
take you back, don't they?
Yes, they do take you back.
Did you decide which ones
you're gonna keep
and which ones you're gonna
leave for him?
Funny, Applejack.
I can't seem to divide them.
They belong to both of us.
Guess I'll just leave them.
While I was listening downstairs there, I...
I could remember just as clear
the first time I ever saw you.
Roger brought you into the Bulletin...
and I was cussing and pounding
on that old machine.
Gee, he didn't know we was all
gonna get to know each other
so well then, did he?
Would you get the rest of the things
out of the bedroom for me, please?
I don't blame you, Julie.
I don't blame you at all.
You should leave me.
Why don't you say it, honey?
It's all true.
I haven't done any one of the big things
I planned to do for you.
We're right where we started.
Still struggling.
I've let you down all around, honey.
All I needed to make it 100%
was for you to leave me.
And I can't think of a reason
in the world for you not to.
I'm licked, Julie.
You're not licked, Roger.
It's just us.
We're licked as far as
our being together is concerned.
When something really came along
that hit us hard enough
we couldn't face it together.
I needed you an awful lot
these last few days...
but you've been miles away.
I've been entirely alone
right here in this room with you.
I know, dear.
I wish I could do something
to help you two.
It just hasn't worked out.
It did work out, Julie.
Things were wonderful
until this happened to us.
I don't know, I...
I just haven't been able to think
straight for the last few days.
She was never sick before and then
all of a sudden it was all over.
If there was only some way
that people could know
a few days ahead
what was going to happen.
Yes...
Then the day before
she was taken sick...
she asked me for a quarter
and I wouldn't let her have it.
When she asked me to take her
to the movies I said no
run along, I'm too busy.
I know, it was the same with me.
I was trying on her angel costume and...
she was so excited
she couldn't stand still.
I scolded her.
I said, I'll never try
another dress on you again.
I never did.
Yes?
Oh...
Hello?
Miss Oliver.
It's a very strange thing,
Mrs. Adams,
but we have a little boy
who is just two years old.
Well, it's the oddest thing.
He's the exact image of the youngster
you asked for
when you first wrote to me.
You remember?
I have that old letter
in front of me now.
Curly hair, blue eyes,
dimple...
This is strictly off the record.
But really, another couple
has the right to see him first.
But he's such a remarkable baby that...
I thought perhaps you and Mr. Adams
would like to take a look.
Yes.
Miss Oliver...
please don't let that other couple
see him until we do, will you?
I won't, my dear.
Good bye.
Well, if he's only two years old,
I'd better put up the gate again, hm?
Yes.
I wouldn't want the little fellow falling
down the stairs and breaking his arm.
I guess we'd better get out the crib.
As long as he's two years old,
he can sleep on this bed, can't he?
Sure, sure.
We won't have to put
the chairs around it.
And over in that corner
I could put a little electric train.
Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes