[Men Shouting]
[SINGING]
♫ You better lock up your doors today ♫
♫ ‘Cause Abu Hassan is on the way ♫
♫ Go in hidin' ♫
♫ When I go ridin' ♫
♫ There's me and my 40 thieves ♫
♫ Your wives and children ♫
♫ And money too ♫
♫ I'll steal them from you ♫
♫ Before I'm through ♫
♫ I'm out gunnin' ♫
♫ So start in runnin' ♫
♫ From me and my 40 thieves ♫
[Hassan]: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
[Thieves]: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
♫ My gang's the roughest ♫
♫ But I'm the toughest ♫
♫ And that's no lie ♫
[Hassan]: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
[Thieves]: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
♫ You've got to hand it ♫
♫ To this bad bandit ♫
♫ ‘Cause I'm a terrible guy ♫
[Thieves Singing]
♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
OLIVE: Oh, Popeye, I got a surprise.
POPEYE: Oh, you have, huh? [Kiss]
Left guard, right guard, present arms, hup.
[HUMMING]
Vice versa.
[Kiss]
As you were. Attention. Right hup.
OLIVE: Oh, if you aren't just too, too....
MAN [ON RADIO]:
Attention everybody! Alarm!
Abu Hassan the bandit
loots town and escapes.
Last seen headed thataway.
WIMPY: Oh, which way?
Thataway!
POPEYE: Oh! Whoa!
Call to arms. All hands on deck.
OLIVE: Wait a minute. Wait for me.
POPEYE: Hey, this ain't nothing for
women. We're out hunting bandits.
Ceiling zero. Visibility zero.
POPEYE: Maybe we better try
across the street, huh?
Ho-ho-ho.
Skip the gutter.
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
POPEYE: Maybe I should trade this in.
[ENGINE SPUTTERS AND POPS]
Something is definitely wrong.
I'm right, it's wrong.
POPEYE: I wish there was a boardwalk
on this beach, huh?
POPEYE: If I had some bread,
I'd make a sandwich if I had a witch.
[WIMPY GASPS]: Food!
A bitter disappointment.
POPEYE: Oh, Wimpy, would you care to join us,
young fellow, huh?
Get in line.
That's one of those invisible mirages
that you can't see in the desert.
That's all it is.
[BELL RINGS]
POPEYE: Rest.
[OLIVE AND WIMPY GROAN]
[BELL RINGS]
Come on, we've got
the green light with us now.
You know, I can go for a nice,
cold chocolate soda right now.
[OLIVE GROANS]
WIMPY: Popeye, Olive Oyl
has collapsed completely.
POPEYE: Whoa! Uh, keep
your vitality up, Olive, huh? That's it.
Oop.
Come on, Olive. We gotta save
little women and children from bandits.
I'll get you out of this desert some way.
I tank we go now.
[POPEYE HUMMING]
POPEYE: Whoa.
OLIVE: Oh.
Water. Oh, boy.
Come on, It'll revives ya.
Here we are.
[OLIVE GASPING]
Here, I'll squelch your thirst for you.
This is on the house.
OLIVE: Is that good! Oh.
I'll ask in here for bandits.
But first, we'll go get
a cup of coffee over here. Come on in.
OLIVE: Goody, goody, am I starved.
POPEYE: After you, Olive
POPEYE: Boy, this place is wide open.
[WIMPY SNIFFING]: Ahhh...
POPEYE: l wonder where everybody is around here?
OLIVE: Yes, why don't they come over?
POPEYE: Service!
OLIVE: Yeah, that's what we want. Service.
Oh, there you are. Hey, what is this?
Double talk or something?
I didn't send out any laundry.
I can read reading, but I can't read right.
This writing is broken and rotten
if you happen to ask me, huh?
Hey, this Chinese is Greek to me.
Haven't you got something to eat?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN DIALECT]
Oh, that's better, huh?
Bring me some desert
without any sand, will you please?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN DIALECT]
POPEYE: Boy, am I hungry. Let's go into this.
OLIVE: I can't wait till I eat.
[MAN ON RADIO]:  Attention everybody!  FLASH!
Attention everybody.
Calling all towns and villages--Beware!
[SINGING]
♫ You better lock up your doors today ♫
♫ ‘Cause Abu Hassan is on his way ♫
♫ Go in hidin' ♫
♫ When he comes ridin' ♫
♫ There's him and his 40 thieves ♫
♫ Your wives and children and money too ♫
♫ He'll steal them from you ♫
♫ Before he's through ♫
♫ He's out gunnin' ♫
♫ So start on runnin' ♫
♫ From him and his 40 thieves ♫
♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
♫ In every village ♫
♫ He'll steal and pillage ♫
♫ There's none he'll spare ♫
♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
♫ If he should spy you ♫
♫ Then we defy you ♫
♫ To cross his path if you dare. ♫
HASSAN: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
THIEVES: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
♫ When things get quiet ♫
♫ I start a riot as I go by ♫
HASSAN: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
HORSES: ♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
♫ And you'll discover ♫
♫ They run to cover ♫
♫ ‘Cause I'm a terrible guy. ♫
[MEN SHOUTING]
POPEYE: Hey, what is this?
Oh!
Hey!
Hey, are you guys the 40 thieves, huh?
That's right.
THIEF: Hot-dog!
[WIMPY GROANS]
What? Another illusion?
I can't understand it.
[ALL SHOUTING]
[GRUNTING]
[HORSE NEIGHS]
HASSAN: Giddyup horsey. Hup! Hey!
POPEYE: Come on.
[HASSAN TAKES POPEYE'S HAT]
Oop!
There's a big bag of wind
blowing through here.
HASSAN: Take your shirt.
POPEYE: Shirt? Shirt!
Hey, give me back me shirt.
What's the big idea?
Stop in the name of the Coast Guard.
Come on, come a bit closer.
Who are you, huh?
Oh, you little tough guy, hey?
Do you think I make a good model, huh?
Take me home for $1.98, huh?
POPEYE: Half the price, I'll tell you that.
HASSAN: Who sent you?
Whoa!
Hey, your penknife's bent.
I'll straighten it out for you.
[GRUNTS]
HASSAN: Aah!
POPEYE: How's that?
You! I show you.
Hey, you're liable to hurt somebody
with that thing, huh? Whoa.
You got rivet-tism. I'll fix it for you.
HASSAN: Huh? Aah!
HASSAN: Why, you-- Look, look, see.
POPEYE: Yeah, I'm looking.
Hey, give me back me belt.
Watch this one.
Abu hasn't got them anymore.
Ha-ha-ha!
HASSAN: You wanna make fool from me, huh?
POPEYE: Ah, made you beat me to it.
HASSAN: I show you.
POPEYE: Huh? Whoa!
HASAN: Ha-ha-ha!
I hang him up shrimp.
[GRUNTING]
Ha, ha. You make fool
from me, hey? Ha, ha.
Huh? GRRRR!
Oh. Hey, I'm burning the candles
at both ends.
Hey, let me out of this thing.
THIEVES: Banana, banana, banana.
[GROANS]
THIEVES: Barber. Barber. Barber.
THIEVES: Teeth. Teeth. Teeth.
THIEVES: Fish. Fish. Fish.
Well, I think I'll get out of here now.
Oh, I better stay.
[THIEVES SHOUTING]
[OLIVE SCREAMS]
♫ Abu Hasan! ♫
♫ Abu Hassan! ♫
Popeye, they're taking me away
because they like me.
They're taking me away,
and I don't like it, I--
[SOBBING]
♫ Now make no error ♫
♫ I'm called the terror ♫
♫ Of every village and town, hmm ♫
Hey, what am I hanging around here for?
Come on, let's go.
Oop! Ooh!
That's using your head.
Where did those guys go to?
Wait till I get ahold of that fella.
I'll show him a thing or two.
Taxi! Taxi!
Follow that abracadabra Hassan guy,
will you? Come on.
Get going. They're way ahead of us.
Attaboy, show them your heels.
Wake up there
What's the matter?
You asleep or something?
Hey, you got four flats.
No wonder you can't run
Come on, there, camel cakes.
Step on it. Let's get going there
What's the matter?....... Whoa!
I think you're running dry.
That's what's the matter with you
[BELL RINGING]
Boy, you eat up an awful lot of gas
for only a two-cylinder.
That's enough for you, young fella.
Here we go.
Boy, we beat them
to the punch that time.
Come on, the whole 40 of you.
I'll take you on one at a time.
Come on.
Open sesame. Hmm.
POPEYE:Open what?
[SHOUTING]
HASSAN: Close sesame.
POPEYE: Wait for me. Wait for me. Oh!
I wonder what that word was
he used when he opened this door.
Open, Sissy. Open, Cecil.
Oh, that can't be it.
Oh, oh. It's giving way.
Oh, that was me that was giving way.
Oh. Well....
[GRUNTING]
It's a violation for not having no exit
that you can go into.
Oh, it's quite modernistic,
I'll tell you that right now.
I hope this isn't a one-way street.
Tippy-toe, tippy-toe.
I gotta give all these jewels back
to the people. Tippy-toe, tippy-toe
I hope I see them before they see me.
Tippy-toe, tippy-toe.
Ooh, what's that noise, huh?
Oh. Olive!
Hey! Hmm.
Must be thieves around here.
Oh, boy. Now is my chance.
Hey, you gotta give back all them jewels
to the people you took.
Oh. Oh, hello, Wimpy.
How did you get in here?
Hey! Hey, outside you.
Oh, this wash is getting heavier
and heavier, and I just--
Oh, Popeye!
My darling, my sweetheart.
Hey, out you go, out.
Hey, what is this?
A wishing well or something?
I wish I was out of this place.
That's what I wish, huh? Oh.
SHARK!
Oh, just a little flounder, that's all.
Whoa!
A little snapper, that's all.
Hey, you're liable
to hurt your teeth on me.
Whoa!
Oh, yeah?
[THIEVES LAUGHING]
POPEYE: Boy, somebody's gonna be sorry for this.
Open, says me.
[POPEYE GRUNTING]
[POPEYE HUMMING]
[THIEVES YELLING]
[FOREIGN DIALECT]
HASSAN: Go!
POPEYE: Oh, yeah?
Step right up, boys.
One at a time here.
Line up. Get right in line there.
Ho-ho-ho.
Aah! I'll get you!
Hey, how would you like to go
for a little ride? Here we go.
[HASSAN SHOUTING IN FOREIGN DIALECT]
[THIEVES SHOUTING]
Oh, two, four, six, eight....
Forty.
Alley-oop!
Here I am!
Over Here!
Peek-a-boo!
I see you!
[HASSAN SHOUTING IN FOREIGN DIALECT]
[THIEVES SHOUTING]
POPEYE: 5..10..15..20..25...30..35...40!
[CHANTING]
Oh, yeah?
How does that strike you?
HASSAN: GRRRRR!
Oh, yeah? Socko!
[GRUNTING]
[CHEERING]
[SINGING]
♫ I may be a shorty ♫
♫ But I licked the 40 ♫
♫ I'm Popeye the sailorman ♫
[PIPE TOOTS]