I'm Sindbad the sailor
So hearty and hale
I live on an island
On the back of a whale
It's a whale of an island
That's not a bad joke
Its lord and its master
Is this handsome bloke
Who's the most remarkable
Extraordinary fellow?
Sindbad the sailor!
I scare all creation on land or on sea
But talk about women
They all fall for me
I take my adventures
Wherever they're found
I don't wanna brag, folks
But I've been around
Who's the most phenomenal
Extra-special kind of fellow?
Sindbad the sailor
From the valley of serpents
These diamonds I took
I clean out those serpents
With one dirty look
Serpents.
Now look at this monster
So strong and so huge
He'd frighten King Kong
But he's only my stooge
The capture of Boola
For me was just fun
Whoever said two heads
Were better than one?
Who's the most phenomenal
Extraordinary fellow?
You, Simlaut the sailor!
How you like that? Stooges.
On one of my travels
I ran into this
Now, there was a thrill
I'd be sorry to miss
He spread out his wings
And the sunlight grew dim
He took me in his feet
But I ran off with him
Who's the most remarkable
Extraordinary fellow?
Sindbad the sailor
Who's the most phenomenal
Extra-special kind of fellow?
Sindbad the sailor
I'm afraid of nobody under the sun
All I say is "boo"
And my enemies run
Who's the most remarkable
Extraordinary fellow?
It's Popeye the sailor man
Popeye the sailor man
I'm strong to the finish
'Cause I eats me spinach
I'm Popeye the sailor man
I'm one tough gazooka
Which hates all palookas
What ain't on the up and square
I biffs an' I bops 'em
An' always out-roughs ‘em
But none of 'em gets nowhere
If anyone dasses
To risk me fist
It's bop and it's wham, understand?
So keep good behavior
That's your one lifesaver
With Popeye the sailor man
Oh, I'm Popeye the sailor man
Popeye the sailor man
I'm strong to the finish
‘Cause I eats me spinach
I'm Popeye the swag whaler man
Who fouls the air with a note so sour
and dares to challenge Sindbad's...
Why, I'll fix him.
Wreck that ship.
But bring me the woman.
Go.
Oh! Oh! Wh-what happened?
He-he-help! Popeye!
Oh, let me go. Let me go.
Let me go!
No, no, no. Don't let me go. Don't.
Oh, man the lifeboats.
Well, that was a nice ship we had once.
Hey, did you see the same thing I saw?
I'm gonna take another look at
that thing. See what that was.
That's the biggest buzzard I ever saw.
Look at that fellow go.
- Where am I?
- Hello there, sweetheart.
- Let me see here, sweetie--
- Hey, keep away from me, you.
- Stop that. Let me alone.
- Come on.
Ah, don't do that!
I'll slap you which way.
- Come here.
- I won't.
- Get up sugar, and give us a little smack.
- I'll give you a smack, all right. There.
Hey, we gotta save Olive Oyl.
Come on, Wimpy. Hurry up
before it's too late. Into the brink.
End of the line, everybody off.
Oh, what's this?
"The Isle of Sindbad. Enter not.
For whoso-ever passeth in,
passeth out. Sindbad."
Is this so? Somebody probably
trying to be funny around here.
Ooh! Luncheon.
Well, here I go within it.
I don't like this place at all. Ooh.
Sorry I ever came in here.
Looks kind of spooky to me around here.
What's this?
Oh! Oh, yeah?
Oh! Trying to scare me like that, huh?
Watch them dumb aminals try
to scare me like that. How about that?
- Help! Popeye, save me!
- Oh!
Oh, I'm coming, Olive.
I just got a little wall here.
Do I hear footprints somewhere? Oh!
I wanna stop. I wanna stop this dancing.
Stop!
Huh?
- Oh, Popeye!
- Come back here.
- Who invited you?
- I did.
What are you gonna do about it, huh?
How did you get in here?
Fowled again. Hmm.
I must resort to my last hamburger.
Oh! Huh?
Hey, I wants me goil.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Who are you?
I'm Popeye the sailor man.
- Who am I?
- You heard what I said.
- That's what I said.
Why-- Argh!
Who's the most remarkable
Extraordinary fellow?
You.
Who's the most phenomenal
Extra-special kind of fellow?
You.
Is the circus coming here?
I'm afraid of nobody under the sun
All I say is "boo"
And my enemies run
Who's the most remarkable
Extraordinary fellow?
Who?
- Popeye the sailor.
- What?
You better fix your shirt there,
young fellow.
- Hey! Hey, let me down.
- Well, let's see how great you are.
Hey, let me down, you big-- Ow!
Whoa! Oh!
Oh, what's this?
Hey, let me down,
you big overgrown canary.
What are you doing?
Taking me for a ride or something?
Hey, let me go, I says.
I'm not going your way.
Come on, let me go. Hey!
Oh, Popeye! Popeye! My Popeye.
Come back to me!
There you are, with gravy.
The old goose is cooked, this guy--
- Hey! Ow!
- Well, I--
- Don't you think we better talk this over?
- Try and get out of this one.
Oh my head, my head.
Whoa!
Come, for to sleep
My baby kin
My peaches and cream
If you don't sleep
My baby kin
I close for you
Your two eyes like this
Oh, my.
Oh, two against one, huh?
How do you like that?
What for you let that
Popeye smack our face?
How do like about that?
You hold that Popeye in this hand.
By carbonate,
if I had that mug in this hand...
...I make from him special dish
of chopped fricassee.
I don't like chop-you-apart fricassee.
I make for you to like it.
Oh! Why, you two-headed--
How do you like that?
Ow! Ugh!
Ugh!
Come on. You're gonna take
a double-header this time.
Wham!
Well, I guess I fixed those two fellows.
I would hate-- Oh, yeah?
Who's gonna make who
like chicken frica-fricassee, huh?
There's only room for one great sailor
in this world.
And that's me.
Oh, says you.
We're gonna come to terms right now.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, you can't push me just so far.
That's all I gotta say--
Beat for beet, kiddo.
That's what I-- Take that!
Whoa! Oh!
Peekaboo!
I sock you!
Come out of there, you!
How do you like that?
Do you give up?
What are you, a fresh guy
or something? I'll show you.
Uh-uh-uh! Don't leave me now.
Take that!
How do you like that?
Come on, get up and fight.
Give it to him, Popeye.
Give him the twister punch!
Twister punch coming up.
Take that!
You're going places, you golem!
Who's the most remarkable
Extraordinary fellow?
You, Popeye the sailor!