...must be stopped.
You, and all the school-parent
groups about the country,
and you must stand united on this,
can stamp out this frightful
assassin of our youth.
You can do it by initiating
compulsory education
on the subject of narcotics
in general.
But dread marihuana in particular!
That is why we are meeting,
ladies and gentlemen,
to lay the foundation for
a nationwide campaign by you
to demand by law
such compulsory education.
For it is only through enlightenment
that this scourge can be wiped out.
Out of the traffic in these drugs,
a lawlessness we can hardly estimate
has grown and is now flourishing.
lt exists in almost every city
and hamlet in the country.
You will find it interesting
and important to know
some of the methods used
to bring drugs into the country
and the work of the forces
of law and order,
which are daily
combatting the traffic,
always risking their agents' lives.
The Dept. of Narcotics, Washington,
wages this ceaseless fight.
l have a letter of vital importance
from someone in the Narcotics Bureau.
l'm going to read this letter to you.
''My dear Dr. Carroll:
''The suppression of the use of
marihuana and the forces behind it
''is the most important job
this department is engaged in.
''At the outset, there is
one vital fact l would submit.
''There is a powerful agency.
l speak of the school-parent groups
''which can be invaluable
in stamping out this scourge.
''Their help and vigilance could be
the deciding factor in our fight.
''Marihuana is grown
in every state in the Union.
''Recently, in Brooklyn, New York,
''a fie/d of marihuana was found
behind a tenement court.
''The weed was here being cu/tivated,
''regu/ar/y stripped and dried
and so/d in schoo/s
''and at government army posts
in and around New York.
''The dried /eaves and berries
are ground up
''and made into cigarettes
by a simp/e hand machine.
''The dead/y narcotic is thus quick/y
and easi/y prepared for its market.
''The sa/e of marihuana is
more difficu/t to detect and ha/t
''than the traffic in drugs such as
opium, morphine and heroin.
''They are hidden in
fake jewe/ry cases,
''in the hee/s of shoes,
''women's shoes especia//y, as the
drugs can be secreted in fa/se hee/s.
''Ho//owed shaving brushes
are another way.
''Books with fa/se centers are used.
''Watch cases are convenient
hiding p/aces.
''The va/ue of drugs
thus seized is enormous.
''Recent/y, a huge supp/y
of heroin was taken.
''/t was concea/ed in an apparent/y
harm/ess shipment of o/ive oi/.
''The dead/y drug was burned at
the Bureau of Engraving and Printing.
''And more vicious, more dead/y,
''even than these sou/-destroying
drugs is the menace of marihuana. ''
No doubt, many of you do not believe
that these things do happen,
that they cannot happen to you.
You may also believe the facts
have been exaggerated.
Let me tell you something that
happened here in our own city.
You probably read about it.
However, l'll give you
the real facts behind the case.
An apartment was near
one of our high schools.
lt was run by a woman
known as Mae Coleman.
Hey.
-Come on, Mae, get up.
-What time is it?
Time to clean this place.
lt's like the Marines landed.
That bunch last night was high enough
to defeat the Marines.
Get on the job.
Some of the kids may be up later.
Jack, we don't need to drag
those young kids up here.
Just button up your lip.
Always squawking about something.
You got more static than a radio.
Ah, greetings.
-Hello, fella, how are you?
-Fine, how are you? Come in!
Glad to be here.
-ls Mae in?
-She'll be right in. Just sit down.
-What kind of a joint is this, Eddie?
-lt's OK, Gwen.
-See, they probably had a party.
-Ahh.
-A couple of your customers, Mae.
-Yeah?
They know what they're doing, not
like the young kids you bring here.
All right, all right.
Listen, l'm gonna blow.
Where you going?
Got to make some deliveries.
l'll bring back a couple of kids.
-Oh, l wish you'd lay off those kids.
-Why don't you get over your complex?
By the way, Ralph, l'm giving a party
Saturday at my grandmother's.
The place with the pool. Coming?
-Maybe.
-l'd like to have you.
-OK, l'll probably drop over.
-So long, Ralph.
-Hey, Ralph! How are you, kid?
-Fine, Jack. You?
-Oh, great. Where you headed?
-Oh...
Hey, how do you like that?
That's the one l was
telling you about.
Very nice.
l don't know why you make such a fuss
over Ralph.
He's a swell swimmer.
Made the freshman team at college.
My dad knows his family.
None of them are any good.
-Parents just got a divorce in Paris.
-Yeah?
Ralph runs around pretty much
on his own. He's been in trouble.
Well, l don't go around with him.
You better not. He's too old for us.
That's what my dad said.
-Hello, Mary. Hi, Bill.
-Hi, Ralph.
Hi, Ralph. You know my brother Jimmy,
don't you?
How are you?
l'd like you to meet a friend
of mine, Jack Perry. Mary, Bill.
Glad to know you.
-We're going to Joe's, come along.
-We're playing doubles.
You can play anytime. Let's have fun.
We can't today. Some other time.
-Can l come?
-Sure.
Hey, l'll see you at dinner, Sis.
-Don't be late, Jimmy.
-l won't.
-Hello, Joe.
-Jimmy!
Hi, Agnes!
-He ain't no paper man!
-That's ''Hot Fingers'' Pirelli.
He swings out with a mess of jive!
-You want to dance?
-Do l!
Mae's expecting us
at the apartment later.
-Any new prospects?
-Maybe.
Oh, Jimmy, you're wonderful!
You just finding that out?
-Why can't we go now?
-Sure.
We're having a party
at my girlfriend's. Want to come?
-l'd love to. You want to, don't you?
-Oh, sure.
-Any place with you.
-Come along, we can all go in my car.
-See you later, Joe.
-So long.
-You're sweet to help me, Bill.
-Anything but Domestic Science.
Don't you want to learn about
running your own home?
The answer is no. You know, after
that session we had yesterday,
l told Mother the trouble
with her pot roast gravy was
she hadn't added three heaping
teaspoonfuls of olive oil.
-What did she say?
-She threw me out of the kitchen.
-No wonder.
-Hello, children.
-Hello, Mother.
-Hello, Mrs. Lane.
-That was sweet of you, Mother.
-Hot chocolate! Thanks, Mrs. Lane!
You can't study on empty stomachs.
Enjoy yourselves.
-He will.
-She will too, Mrs. Lane.
-May l?
-Thank you, sir. You're so very kind.
Mary, before we do that math,
let's read this. lt's swell.
Romeo and Ju/iet?
-Don't you like it?
-Uh-huh.
When l study this, l think of you.
l feel as though you're
there beside me.
Oh, listen.
''lt is my soul that calls
upon thy name.
''How silver-sweet sound
lovers' tongues by night.
''Like softest music
to attending ears!''
-''Romeo!''
-''My dear?''
''At what o'clock tomorrow
shall l send to thee?''
-''By the hour of nine.''
-''l will not fail.''
'''Tis twenty years till then.''
Well...l'll see you tonight, Mary.
Goodbye, Mrs. Lane.
-Goodbye, Bill.
-So long.
Gosh, l...
Oh, Bill!
l guess l'm all right. Bye! Bye!
-Hey, Daddy!
-Oh, Junior!
There you are!
-Hey, Dad, you got anything for me?
-Don't bother your father.
-Have you?
-There you are.
What made you so late, Bill?
l was worried.
Oh, l had to study, Ma.
He was not. l saw him out
walking with his girl.
Bill's got a girlfriend...
-Make him stop!
-Junior!
-Well, Bill has got a girl.
-Quiet! And put that candy away.
-You shouldn't have given it to him.
-His girl's name is Mary.
Hey, l'll shut you up.
Bill! Junior! Quit that carrying on!
They're all right, they're young.
Mary's little lamb.
l didn't mean it, Bill!
What l'm burned up about is that you
didn't say Bill had a swell girl!
Gee. lt must be love.
-She must be swell if you like her.
-You must want something.
-Come on, what is it?
-lt's my model plane. lt won't work.
Gosh, Bill, you could fix it.
You can fix anything!
OK, l'll fix it.
-Dad, read me the funny papers.
-Here we are.
-Hey, Bill!
-Oh hello, Jimmy.
Mary went home. Her mother
wanted her to go to the dressmaker.
Oh thanks, Jimmy.
l see Mary let you have the car.
-Can l take you anyplace?
-l wasn't going anyplace special.
How about driving over to Joe's place
with me? l'll buy you a soda!
-l never drink that stuff!
-l'll buy you something else.
-You're on the hook for a root beer.
-Swell!
-Hi. What'll you have?
-Hey, Jimmy!
Hi Jimmy. Hi, Bill.
Come on, slide in.
-Hello, Blanche. Hello, Ralph.
-How've you been, Ralph?
Two sodas...
l mean one soda and one root beer.
-How's Mae?
-Fine. We're going to her apartment.
-Could Bill come?
-Sure.
-l don't know...
-Come on, Bill!
-Thanks, but...
-Come on, Bill.
-Mary won't be jealous.
-A lot of the kids will be there.
l don't know... l really shouldn't...
Well, OK.
-Hiya, kids!
-Hello, Jack, whaddya say?
Yeah, come on in.
-Jack!
-Hi, Agnes!
Come on, Bill, don't stand there!
Billy-hillbilly!
-Hi, kids!
-Mae, this is Bill Harper. He's OK.
Hello.
Well, if you say so, he's all right
with me. l'll be back in a minute.
-Hiya, kids, how ya doing?
-OK. Hiya, Mae.
-There's a new one in today.
-Yeah, Bill Harper.
He's all right. Blanche's got
herself quite a yen for him.
Not bad. l didn't think she had
that much taste.
She got Ralph not to bother her.
Now she's got her hooks out for Bill.
We haven't many more smokes.
You'd better go and get some.
Couldn't you find that out this
morning? Now my car is in the shop.
So what? That kid out there, Jimmy.
He's got a car. He'll take you.
Come on, get going. Hurry up.
-Hey, Jimmy.
-Yup?
l've got to go to Cedar Avenue.
-You got a car?
-My sister's.
-Mind giving me a lift?
-Why sure, come on.
No, thank you.
-Well, here we are.
-Oh, thanks.
Oh, Mae, don't forget me.
l never forget you.
Oh dear. lf you want a good smoke,
try one of these.
l thought you were a sport.
Of course, if you're afraid...
That's better! That's more like it.
l know you'll like it.
Just take a puff of this.
-Just be a minute, kid.
-Give me a cigarette, will you?
-Hello, Jack.
-Hiya, Boss.
-How's business?
-Great. Those kids sure go for it.
-Swell.
-Had to get a few more cartons.
-Ran short today.
-All right.
Danny? Pack ten gross for Jack Perry.
Who? Pete Daley?
All right, send him in.
lt's all right, stay where you are.
l want to talk to you.
Go ahead, Jack's OK. What's the beef?
l never beefed
when l sold that rotten gin.
-You want dough, right?
-l don't need it that bad.
-Taking two-bit pieces from kids.
-Millions, begging to be taken.
-Don't be a dope.
-Just dope enough to draw the line.
OK, Pete. You know what
my policy's always been.
lf the boys are not satisfied,
l'm always glad to have them retire.
Retire permanently.
So long.
-l wish you had a couple of kids...
-Get out!
-Jack, pick up your stuff from Danny.
-OK, boss.
-Let's go, Jack, l'm red-hot!
-Be careful or you'll be ice cold.
Take it easy, kid!
Slow down! You'll kill somebody!
Mary, you're not eating
your breakfast again.
Bill Harper hasn't been around
lately. Anything wrong?
Why should there be anything wrong?
There shouldn't be.
Whatever it is isn't serious, l know.
-l'm sorry for snapping at you.
-Don't worry about it, dear.
Why don't you speak to Bill?
He'll be honest, whatever it is.
-l'm sure Bill Harper never lied.
-Yes, his mother says he never lies.
-There, you see?
-lt'd be all right if...
-...if l speak to him about it?
-Why, of course.
-Oh, Jimmy.
-Hello, Ma.
Sit down. l'll have your breakfast
for you in a moment.
-ls something worrying you?
-What have l got to worry about?
-Why don't you tell me?
-Don't cross-examine me!
Jimmy!
Don't let Mother see you like that.
There is certainly an organized gang
distributing narcotics to students.
Not only in my school,
but all over the city.
You government men have got to find
some way to stop it.
Of course, l agree with you,
Dr. Carroll.
But do you realize marihuana
is not like other forms of dope?
lt grows wild in almost every state
in the Union.
Thus, there is no interstate commerce
in the drug.
So, the government's hands are tied.
Frankly, the only sure cure is a
widespread campaign in education.
lt's fine to talk about education,
Mr. Wyatt.
But we educators can't do anything
until the public is aroused.
Let me show you something.
ln 1 930, the records on marihuana
in the Narcotics Division
scarcely filled a small folder
like this.
Today, they fill cabinets.
All these...devoted to
marihuana records.
Here is an example.
A 16-year-old lad, apprehended
in the act of staging a holdup.
16 years old,
and a marihuana addict.
-Here is a most tragic case.
-Yes, l remember. Just a young boy.
Under the drug's influence,
he killed his entire family.
Then there is the most
vicious type of case.
Here.
ln Michigan. A young girl,
1 7 years old. A reefer smoker.
Taken in a raid
in the company of five young men.
Here is a most flagrant case.
l remember. The papers made
quite a play of it.
-ln West Virginia, wasn't it?
-Yes. And there are hundreds of them.
l'd like to take these records.
l feel they would be invaluable to me
-in combating the evil in my school.
-You're very welcome, Dr. Carroll.
Sit down, Bill.
There seems to be something wrong.
What is it?
You were always a fine student.
You always had excellent grades.
l guess the work is getting harder,
Dr. Carroll.
No. No, it isn't that.
Bill, l'd like to help you.
But l can't, unless you let me.
You're undermining your health.
There's nothing, Dr. Carroll, really.
l'll study harder, honest.
Honest? lf you were being honest
with me and honest with yourself,
l'm afraid you'd tell me
an entirely different story.
l'm going to ask you
a straightforward question.
-l'd like a straightforward answer.
-Yes, sir.
lsn't it true that you have,
perhaps unwillingly,
acquired a harmful habit through
association with undesirable people?
-Well?
-Oh no, sir. l haven't, Dr. Carroll.
Well, that is, you see, l'm...
...worried about something at home.
All right, my boy.
We'll just have to let it go at that.
But remember, if you ever
want to confide in me,
-no one will ever be the wiser.
-Thank you, Dr. Carroll.
-Hi, Mary, want to play?
-Thanks, l'm waiting for someone.
lf you're waiting for Bill,
he hasn't been here for weeks.
-Come on, Jimmy, play something hot!
-OK!
Come on, Billy! Dance with me!
-Didn't take Bill long to catch on.
-Don't take any of them long.
-Hey, don't you ever get fed?
-You're feeding me, can't you see?
-Give me a knife and fork, will you?
-Get it yourself.
Come on, Bill!
Come on! Come on, Bill!
Come on, Bill.
-Good morning, we're the police.
-Good morning.
We're tracing a hit-and-run.
Someone caught part of the license.
-We're checking all numbers like it.
-l'll try to help.
-Do you recall the 29th, last month?
-The day before Mother's birthday.
Yes, l left school and went
to the dressmaker with mother.
-l was there all afternoon.
-Did you loan your car to two men?
-No, l had the car all afternoon.
-Thanks, Miss. Sorry to trouble you.
Tell me... Did they...?
Was the person killed?
Fortunately not. But that's still
no excuse for hit-and-run driving.
Has Jimmy Lane been here today?
He was in. He went over to
Mae's place. You know where that is.
He was going to wait for me here,
so he didn't give me Mae's address.
Are you sure Jimmy didn't leave
any message for me? Mary?
No, he didn't.
But l guess you're OK.
l'll write it down for you.
-Mary! Come right in!
-ls Jimmy here?
Oh, why, he's around somewhere.
l think he went to take Agnes home.
He'll be right back.
Sit down, Mary.
Let me take your coat.
Who's the new kid just came in?
lt's that gal Ralph's
gone overboard for.
We've never been able
to get her up here before.
Hey, hey. Scram, will ya?
-Smoke, Mary?
-Thanks.
-Are you sure Jimmy'll be back soon?
-Sure. Any minute.
Say, what's the matter?
Am l an orphan?
-Where do you put it? A hollow leg?
-Thanks, dear.
Here, Mary.
-Oh, Mary, give me a kiss, Mary!
-No! Don't! Don't!
-Please, no!
-Oh, Mary!
You leave me alone!
-Go away!
-Mary! Everybody's...
Leave me alone! Oh, leave me alone!
-Everything's over.
-Leave me be!
Ralph! Ralph!
Look!
Jack, is she all right?
She's dead.
Mae, get me some water.
Now listen, you two.
Get out of here. Forget you were ever
in here today.
l'll handle this. Now get going.
Give it to me.
Here.
Mary?
Mary? Mary!
-What happened?
-You killed her.
Mary, Mary!
Oh, Mary...
Look. After l scram,
you call the cops.
And this is your story. Remember it.
These kids came here for some beer.
From the kitchen, you heard shots.
You came in, and
that's what you found.
Just stick to that story.
Mary!
Mary! Speak to me! Mary!
-Hello, Jack.
-l was just talking to a friend.
A cop.
Sergeant on the homicide squad.
-Guy you hit that day died.
-Died? You... l mean you didn't...?
No. l didn't crack,
and l'm not going to.
-Nobody'll know you drove that car.
-Thanks, Jack.
Just don't say you were ever
up in Mae's apartment.
Why sure, Jack!
OK.
Your honor, l'd like to recall
Dr. Alfred Carroll to the stand.
Call Dr. Alfred Carroll to the stand.
Dr. Carroll, as principal of
the Lakeside High School,
did you, in the last three months,
notice changes in the demeanor of
your student, William Harper?
Yes, in a number of things.
For example, at times,
disassociation of ideas.
Also, l happened to attend the recent
interscholastic tennis matches.
While Bill Harper had been considered
an exceedingly good player,
l saw him miss the ball by
as much as three or four feet.
This, l understand, could be
attributed to the use of marihuana.
lt causes errors in time and space.
Objection, your honor!
The witness isn't qualified
as an expert on narcotics.
Sustained. Dr. Carroll has been
called merely as a character witness.
Although you didn't personally know
the defendant was using marihuana,
did you notice any changes that would
lead you to believe, as an educator,
that he was under some severe stress
which might possibly have been
induced by some drug?
Yes. l recall distinctly,
a few weeks ago.
lt was during a class
of English literature.
There was a serious discussion of
Shakespeare's Romeo and Ju/iet,
when he burst into an uncontrollable
fit of hysterical laughter.
Oh, by the way, Dr. Carroll,
six months ago, what was your opinion
regarding the character of my client?
He was a fine, upstanding
American boy.
A good scholar, a good athlete,
and representative of the caliber of
young men we are proud to graduate.
Oh, snap out of it, will you?
lt's not our fault.
Why'd l ever bring him up there,
anyway? He's just a kid.
-They can't hang him.
-Shut up, shut up!
Why don't you let yourself go? Talk.
Go off your nuts
and have me that way too.
-lt's his own fault, wasn't it?
-Shut up!
They've got us hidden out, haven't
they? The cops can't find us!
Jack. Jack, l want
to get out of this place.
You'll stay here as long as we have
to keep those two under cover.
Till the trial's over...or the boss
gets a better idea.
-But they're getting on my nerves.
-lt can't last much longer.
l'm not worried about her.
We got to keep him gagged.
Oh, he's about ready to crack.
Just keep him from having
too many reefers.
Any day now, that punk'll get hot.
He'll probably spill and tell all
if he gets a chance.
l don't think he'll get it.
-l'll see you later.
-Where are you going?
l'm going to see the boss.
-Hello, Jack.
-Hello, Boss.
-What'll we do about that Wiley guy?
-Still jittery, huh?
-l don't know what he'll do.
-Feed him hot sticks.
Mae's doing that. No good.
l got a hunch that he's due to crack
when that Harper verdict comes in.
He's liable to take a powder on us
and blow his topper to the D.A.
You mean you think we'd all be better
off if he never heard the verdict?
Well,
what are you waiting for?
You, ladies and gentlemen
of the jury, have a duty to perform.
A duty to yourselves
and to our community.
Mary Lane is dead.
The evidence you've
heard at this trial
could not have failed to convince you
of the guilt of the defendant.
By his own admission, he pressed
the trigger of the weapon
that sent lovely and innocent Mary
Lane to a tragic and untimely death.
We are not so much concerned about
the motives as about the deed itself.
While the defendant has told you that
he saw someone attacking Mary Lane,
and that his mind went blank
from that moment on,
the defense has not produced
one witness to verify that statement.
Now, ladies and gentlemen, you've
heard able men testify at this trial,
men who have tried
to bring out the fact
that the defendant might have
become momentarily insane
when he fired the shot
that killed Mary Lane.
But the defense has been unable
to prove that he was insane.
He was sane when he visited the
apartment where the tragedy occurred.
He habitually visited the place.
He was sane when he went to a bedroom
with another woman.
You heard what went on in that room,
from the defendant's own lips.
lnvolved as he was in
a tawdry love affair,
Mary Lane was in the way.
She had found him out.
ln a moment of anger, he deliberately
and willfully killed her.
lf such deeds are permitted
to go unpunished,
this community would cease to be
a decent and safe place
for us or our children to live.
l do not believe l have to plead,
or even demand,
that you bring in a verdict
to punish the defendant
for the crime that he has committed
against society.
You are upright citizens. That is why
you were chosen to judge another.
As honest, upright citizens, there is
only one verdict you can find.
And that is a verdict of ''Guilty.''
And this court will be adjourned
until the jury's verdict is reached.
l suppose you all feel the same
about this case.
-But he might have been insane.
-No, he knew what he was doing.
-But supposing he was insane?
-You'll never make anyone believe it.
We'll take a first vote.
Eleven for conviction.
One for acquittal.
There's a reasonable doubt
about his sanity. We can't...
No doubt that he murdered her.
He admitted it himself.
That wasn't the first time
he was there.
We got to make an example before such
boys contaminate all of our children.
We can't let every murderer hide
behind a gag of insanity.
Sure, they see red before they kill
somebody. But whose fault is it?
Have you reached a verdict?
We have.
The defendant will rise.
What is your verdict?
We find the defendant
guilty as charged.
No!
Stop that racket! Stop it!
What's the matter with you?
You give me the creeps.
Mae. Mae!
-What do you want?
-Bring me some reefers.
They're going to hang him.
-Blanche. They're going to hang him.
-Oh, come on. Get a hold of yourself.
Here you are.
And quit that crazy laughing!
-Where's Jack? l want to leave.
-You'll hang if you don't pipe down.
l want to see Jack. Jack.
l want to see Jack.
Jack.
-You'd better quiet him.
-l can't do anything with him.
l've got to see Jack.
We can't let that kid hang.
He'll be here. Don't worry.
He'll be here in a little while.
l've got to see him. l've got to...
Come on, darling.
Everything'll be over soon.
-Want me to play something for you?
-Yeah. That's it. Play something.
All right. Come on.
Sit down.
Honey, give me a smoke, will you?
Faster.
Faster!
Play faster!
Faster. Play faster.
Faster.
l know what you want.
You want to kill me.
You're crazy. Take it easy, kid.
l just want to talk to you.
Hurry, hurry! There's a terrible
fight going on! Yes... Apartment 32.
Stop it! Stop it! Let go of me!
Take your hands off of me!
Stop it! Take your hands off me!
Stop it!
Who hired you and Jack Perry?
Are you ready to te// what you know?
Yes!
/'// ta/k.
lf we can gain leniency
for my client, she will plead guilty,
and turn state's evidence
in the case of William Harper.
l regret this court is not prepared
to bargain with justice.
l'll tell anyway. l was there.
l saw it.
l know who killed Mary. And l'll tell
you who killed Mary Lane.
lt wasn't Bill. lt was Jack.
Jack Perry. He shot Mary and then
he put the gun in Bill's hand.
We were all at the apartment one day.
Mary came in looking for her brother.
Bill and l,
we'd been in another room.
Bill came in and caught Ralph
with Mary. They started to fight.
Jack had the gun. He was going to hit
Bill over the head to make him stop.
And then...then the gun went off.
l saw it.
l can see it now. lt was horrible!
Before we knew it, Mary...
Mary was dead.
But you see, Judge, Bill didn't know
he hadn't killed Mary.
He was so doped up,
they made him think he had.
Ralph wanted to tell you, too.
Oh, if they'd only let him.
But this is the truth, Judge.
l'm telling you the truth.
After Jack saw that Mary was dead,
he put the gun in Bill's hand.
lt was Jack's fault.
And it was my fault, too.
l got all of them to come up
to the apartment.
l'm just as much to blame.
l am. l am.
Do you wish to plead guilty to a
charge of fostering moral delinquency
-in the case of William Harper?
-Yes, yes. l'm guilty. l am!
Prepare a statement
for signature, and an order
setting aside the verdict in the case
of the People v. William Harper.
ln the interests of justice, l shall
direct a verdict of not guilty.
Sign here, please.
You shall be brought into court on
Thursday, the 1 7th, for sentencing.
Meanwhile, you will be held
as a material witness
in the case of
the People v. Ralph Wiley.
We have come in the hearings
before this court today
to what l hope will be the final
actions in a sad, unfortunate case,
one whose horrible tragedy
will forever remain with me.
l am happy to have been enabled,
before it was too late,
to set aside the verdict in the case
of the People v. William Harper.
But, young man,
although this court believes that to
convict you would be grossly unjust,
we cannot condone your acts.
We only express the hope that your
experiences may not alone keep you,
but thousands of others, from
the vicious pitfalls of marihuana.
Thus, l am ordering you to remain
in this court during the next case
so that you will have to witness what
you yourself so narrowly escaped.
Call the case of
the People v. Ralph Wiley.
Bill.
Your honor, the State waives trial
of the defendant, Ralph Wiley...
...and recommends that he
be placed in an institution
for the criminally insane
for the rest of his natural life.
The defendant's counsel joins
the State in this request.
Since counsel for the defense and
counsel for the state agree on this,
l see no reason why the request
should not be granted.
That happened right here,
to your neighbors.
lt is not too much to say that in
your hands lies the possibility
of averting other tragedies like it.
We must work untiringly to oblige
our children to learn the truth,
because it is only through knowledge
that we can safely protect them.
Failing this, the next tragedy may be
that of your daughter,
or your son, or yours,
or yours...or yours.
Subtitles
by BloodLogic