[music playing]
[SINGING] A cowboy sang his
song of fate as he wandered
the desert wide, his eyes were
burning with flames of hate
and his guns were loaded
with poison bait, as they
hung and swung at his side.
An outlaw had stolen his gal
away, an outlaw bold and fly,
so hot on the tail of
the outlaw's trail,
this cowboy rode ready to die.
Grease up your guns, outlaw,
and cinch them on tight,
there'll be blood
a-running in town
before night, there'll be
guns a-blazing and singing
with lead, tonight
you'll be drinking
your drinks with the dead.
Shot in the back, eh?
Yeah.
Now, don't try
to talk, Sheriff.
That's a nasty wound.
Stopped bleeding, though.
That's something.
Aw, you're going
to be all right.
I'll have you in
Starbuck before night.
Just a swallow, now.
You can have more later.
[coughing]
Whoa, boys-- whoa!
[gunfire]
We got him.
Well, are you hurt, Miss?
I don't think so.
Are they coming?
They're almost here.
They mustn't take me.
Really, they mustn't.
Please don't let them.
I'm not a bandit.
Really I'm not.
You see--
Hey, hey-- this is the
best place here, Elmer.
Give me a push.
Hey-- get off my neck!
Don't you understand?
It was our only way out.
Won't you please help me?
Well, I'll do what I
can do for you, Miss.
But your horse is done for.
Well, you'll have to take mine.
Hey, why don't
you stay up there?
I'll have your horse in
town for you in an hour.
You've got his horse, Bert.
Yeah.
Too bad I didn't
get the road agent.
Well, he can't get far.
[gunshot]
We got him.
We lost him.
Yeah.
You go that way.
[whack]
Oh.
Aw, come on, Bert.
This ain't getting us nowhere.
Dad-- I got it.
You got what?
Where in the world
have you been?
I beat the robbers to it.
I held up the stage,
and I got our money.
You-- you held up the stage?
Why, I never--
Pop, don't get excited.
It's all over, and I'm safe.
But I lost Prince.
They shot him from under me.
And if it hadn't been for a
stranger lending me his horse,
well, I guess I'd
be in jail by now.
A stranger?
Wha-- well, who was he?
I don't know.
But he sure was swell.
I've got to change
my clothes and get
his horse back into town.
I never heard of anything like
that before in all my life.
Hie!
The boys are sure late.
I wonder if anything's happened?
Here she comes now.
Put down them irons.
There ain't no passengers.
Well, hand down the bag.
You're late now.
There ain't no bag.
A masked rider held us
up about two miles back.
What'll the boss say?
We can't help what he says.
It ain't our fault.
Well, we'll see you in town.
All right.
Giddyup there-- ha-- ha!
[galloping hooves]
Well, Pete, we got
stucked up again.
PETE: Where did it happen?
Down by big Rock Canyon.
What kind of a
horse was he riding?
BERT: A bay.
Uh, we shot the horse,
but the rider got away.
KINCAID: Well, you might trace
the brand and find the owner.
By George, we never thought
to look at the brand.
We'll ride up there,
and see what we can find.
Oh, how do you do, Miss Denton?
How's your father?
Better, thank you.
Oh, Pete-- was there a
package for me today?
There was.
But the stage was held up.
Again?
Where's the Sheriff?
He hasn't got back yet.
You know, he went out to try and
break up this road agent gang.
We haven't been
able to find him.
Can I be of any assistance?
Well, my horse and saddle
were stolen last night.
I thought maybe he might be
able to help me find them.
What color was your horse?
He was a sort of a bay,
with a Double-O brand.
Well, there was a horse of
that description just shot.
Oh.
I hope it wasn't mine.
If it was, Miss Denton, I'll
bring your saddle to you.
Thank you.
Howdy, folks.
Could you tell me
where the Sheriff is?
Well, I take charge
when he isn't here.
Can I do anything for you?
Thanks.
I'll wait for him.
The Sheriff didn't care
especially for this job.
He might not come back.
I'll take that chance.
I have an idea he
will come back.
I don't like the way
that fellow talks.
We'll watch him.
Meet me at the crossroads,
and I'll take you home.
All right.
That masked bandit story
was on the square, huh?
Yeah.
He got us two miles
ahead of the boys here.
Well, he's afoot now.
The only place he can get
water is at Denton's, or town.
We may get him.
Let's have a look at that horse.
We'd better put your
horse in the barn.
That's a good idea.
I reckon he's pretty dry.
You were right.
He is thirsty.
Come on.
I want you to meet my dad.
Why, sure.
I'd be glad to.
Dad, I want you to
meet Mr. Saunders.
I want to thank you,
young fellow, for what
you done for my daughter.
Well, forget it, but, uh,
what's happened to you?
Sit down.
I'll tell you all about it.
Thank you.
You see, Fay and me own half
interest in the mine at Yucca.
Our partner sends us our
share every couple of weeks.
Sometimes it's
only a few dollars.
Other times, it's a few hundred.
He always writes us
when to expect it.
And almost always,
the stage was held up
when the shipment came through.
One day, we discovered our
letters were being opened.
They knew just when
the money was coming.
So I decided to
follow the stage.
Heh.
I ran into the hold-up,
and got a slug in my hip.
Today, Fay thought
she'd beat them to it.
Hm.
That's when you
happened into it.
It's Kincaid, with my saddle.
Wait here.
I'll get him on his way.
It was your horse,
all right, Miss Denton.
Here's your saddle.
Thank you so much.
Not at all.
Bert-- take it out to the barn.
Never mind.
Don't trouble.
When your father's
feeling better,
I'd like to talk to him
about buying your ranch.
He's too ill to talk now.
Give him my regards.
Thank you.
I will.
Hey, Chief.
You know that hombre what
was looking for the Sheriff?
Yes.
Well, his horse is
in Denton's barn.
I wonder what his game is?
Well, whatever it is, we'll
put a stop to it right here.
You boys wait here.
He's got to come
along this road.
Accidents will happen.
I get you.
What about the Sheriff?
Can't he do something?
It's mighty strange,
but Bill Baxter's gone.
He's the second Sheriff
to disappear in a year.
He was a fine man.
And our friend.
Well, why is Kincaid so
anxious to buy your ranch?
He's trying to buy
up all the ranches.
And he's offering the boys the
ridiculous price of $1 an acre.
He owns the water
rights to Lost Creek.
You see, Lost Creek comes up
and disappears on his land.
And he supplies the whole
country hereabouts with water.
That's why he's so independent.
No one will fight him, for fear
he'll shut off their supply.
I'm the only one
can talk back to him.
I've got the only well
in Antelope Valley.
The boys are holding a
meeting in town today.
I'll tell you, men, we're
getting a rotten deal.
Forced to sell our land
for nothing, or no water.
I'll fight first.
But he's got real gunmen.
What about our families?
Oh, you can't
start a fight now.
Give Washington a chance
to answer our letters.
They're bound to send somebody
out here to investigate
Baxter's disappearance.
That's right.
Well, let's wait until we see
what he says when he learns
we've decided not to sell.
[mutters of approval]
Well, I hope you'll be
feeling better, Mr. Denton.
Thank you.
And I may accept that
invitation of yours
to stay here.
We'd love to have you.
We sure would, son.
Well, thank you.
Goodbye.
They may have seen
your horse at the barn.
You'll be careful, won't you?
I'll be back for dinner.
Well, gentlemen?
Have you reached an agreement?
Yes.
We've decided you
can go plum to--
Wait, Mason.
Your proposition can treat
us beyond all reason.
We've worked years
for these lands,
and we don't intend to sell
for a few measly dollars.
That's your privilege.
Don't forget, the
state has deeded
me the right to the only
water in this valley.
I've spent hard-earned
money for labor and dams,
and I expect to get it back.
You're getting it
back, ain't you?
We're paying you a big
price for your water now.
In three days, my contract to
furnish you with water expires.
You'll either sell at my price,
or pay four times the amount
for water you're paying now.
So settle it among yourselves.
[horse's hooves]
Here he comes now.
[boom, boom]
[crack]
Come on.
Get together.
[crack]
Now you boys are going
for a nice little ride.
Mm, hello, Morgan.
Glad you got here.
Sit down.
What's the trouble?
Nothing right now.
But anything might happen.
I need protection.
What's it worth?
Same as before.
SAUNDERS [SINGING]:
Grease up your guns,
outlaw, and cinch them on
tight, there'll be blood
a-running in town before night.
There'll be guns
a-blazing and singing
with lead, tonight
you'll be drinking
your drinks with the dead.
[horse's hooves]
Who's that?
I don't know.
Mph.
Huh.
What a fine pair of love
birds you turned out to be.
[interposing voices]
Howdy, men.
I'm looking for a Mr. Taylor.
I'm Taylor.
Found this letter a few
miles back, on the road.
Must've been dropped in that
last stagecoach hold-up.
Thanks.
Boys, here's our
answer from Washington.
Good.
Dear Mr. Taylor-- in answer
to your letter of May the 10th,
please be advised that
we are sending a man
to investigate the situation you
mentioned as soon as possible.
[cheers]
RANCHER 1: I hope
he gets here soon.
RANCHER 2: Now we'll
show Mr. Kincaid.
RANCHER 3: This
is our water now.
Plenty of it, too.
Oh-- glad to see
you out, Mr. Denton.
Yep.
Feeling better every day.
Say, uh, is that
the old creek bed?
Yeah.
When I first come here,
it was running water
through every ranch
in the valley.
Then it dried up.
That's when Kincaid
got the upper hand.
You can't divert
a stream, can you?
No.
That's agin' the law.
Well, those water contracts
expire today at noon.
I think I'll take a run in
town and see what happens.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
I'll be glad to hear about it.
[crowd noise]
Here comes Kincaid now.
Well, gentlemen, it's noon.
My contract with
you has expired.
Have you come to any decision?
Kincaid, you've got
the soul of a snake.
We won't go into that.
This is a business proposition.
The law is on my side.
Now, what have
you decided to do?
Just this-- we are
hanging on to our land,
and we are not paying you
your price for your water.
Right.
Then take the consequences.
Boys, turn off the water.
Guard my dam.
And if anyone sets
foot on my land, shoot.
Well, Kincaid may get more
shooting than he's looking for.
[interposing voices]
Just a minute, men.
Just a minute.
I'm sure Denton will give you
all the water you can haul.
RANCHER 1: Well, we may call
on him for drinking water,
but he can't supply enough
for our stock and families.
RANCHER 2: If that man from
Washington would only come.
RANCHER 3: Well, it's about
time somebody got here.
This time, we've
got to do something.
Mm, that sure
was a good dinner.
So glad you enjoyed it.
Wait'll you taste them hot
biscuits in the morning.
Ohhh, biddie.
Dad's crazy about hot biscuits.
Well, who wouldn't be?
Gee, that was beautiful.
Won't you sing the chorus again?
That was mighty fine, son.
[guitar plays]
[SINGING] Oh sing desert breeze
of the days that used to be, oh
sing me your song of the wild.
Whisper again those unbroken
melodies that lulled
me to sleep when a child.
Down through the years
I've heard you calling me,
and through my tears I smiled.
So blow desert breeze,
wrap me up in memories,
and sing me your
song of the wild.
I could listen
to that all night.
I enjoyed that so much.
Please sing another one.
[guitar chords]
[sound of running water]
Remember what I told you.
If anyone tries to
get water, shoot.
All right, boss.
All fixed up?
Yep.
She's full to the brim.
Now, Mason, in case of
trouble, keep on going.
All right.
I'll be right behind you.
Keep your eyes open.
There's liable to be trouble.
Aw, don't worry.
We'll get through.
Be seeing you at dinner.
Goodbye.
Good luck.
So long, Denton.
Dad?
What are we going to do
about Kincaid's offer?
Well, Fay, I've decided we
better stick with the boys
and their families.
You're right.
You ride down and tell
Kincaid that we ain't selling.
I sure will.
I got more water from Denton.
Oh, I expected that.
I've got my men posted, and
they'll never get through.
Besides, I've made Denton
an offer he can't refuse.
I'll own his place before night.
Here he comes.
[crack]
[gun battle]
[crowd noise]
[shouts of water! water!]
Hurry up, boys!
Nice and [inaudible].
[shouts of water! water!]
Hey, let me have some!
Lay him down there easy.
Here, get him down.
Oh, my, my-- Fred--
Fred-- oh, Fred!
They got through.
Saunders drove the wagon.
Saunders, huh?
Slip, when I give
you the signal,
you come down the
middle of the street.
I'm ordering this
Saunders out of town.
And he may be just fool enough
to fight it out with you.
I'll be ready for him.
I tell you, men--
this has got to stop.
Your cattles are dying.
Your crops are withering.
You're fighting
a hopeless fight.
Kincaid's got the
law behind him.
Sign up and take your licking.
Sign up and stop this bloodshed.
Saunders?
You've interfered in my
business once too often.
Now, I'm giving you just one
minute to get out of town.
Quick, Miss Denton.
What's the trouble?
There's gonna be a shooting.
[SINGING] Grease up
your guns, outlaw,
and cinch them on
tight, there'll be blood
a-running in town before night.
There'll be guns a-blazing,
and singing with lead--
Why, that's Singing Sandy.
Who?
The most notorious gunman
since Billy the Kid.
Make it fast, Slippery.
This is your last draw.
[bang]
You'll never handle
guns again, Morgan.
Right through the ribs.
You better get him
over to the doctor.
Well, Saunders?
I guess you win.
Can I talk to you a minute?
Sure.
I'll talk to you.
He's Singing Sandy, I tell you.
I saw him do the same
thing down on the border.
Is he a killer?
Well, he's got a repetition
from here to Kentucky.
Oh--
I need you.
And I'll pay your price.
What's the job?
Protecting me and my interests.
The law is on my side.
But the Sheriff's gone,
and these ranchers
may start trouble.
I need a gunman.
SAUNDERS: Fair enough.
I'll take the job.
Now, how about these Dentons?
I've made them an
offer they can't refuse.
Well, why pay them anything?
Just drop a charge of
dynamite down their well
and collapse it.
They'll have no water, and then,
like the rest of the ranchers,
they'll have to sell
out for nothing.
That's an idea.
Send in the boys.
Kincaid wants you.
I'd like to talk to you
ranchers confidentially.
Why, certainly, Mr. Saunders.
What is it?
Now listen, boys.
Saunders is working
with us, now.
So let bygones be bygones.
We're going to blow
up Denton's well.
And I want you to get enough
dynamite to collapse it
for good.
If what you say is true,
Saunders, we'll owe you a lot.
Well, it's a long chance,
but I say, take it.
Well, we were going to
sign the contracts anyway.
So we'll insist on that clause.
Good.
[interposing voices]
You boys ready?
I'll go along and
watch old Denton.
Now, it'll take a
big charge, and--
I-- I'll get enough
to blow it to China.
Good.
We're all ready
to sign, Kincaid.
Providing you are
willing to insert
a new clause in our contract.
What is it?
That if you should fail,
at any time during the life
of our contract, to
provide us with water,
your water rights, and lands,
become community property.
Sure.
I'll agree to that.
Come on in.
Dad-- Dad-- something
terrible has happened.
Mr. Saunders' real
name is Singing Sandy.
He's a gunman and a killer.
I saw him shoot a man in town.
And then he joined
Kincaid's gang.
Why, I can't believe it.
I heard him tell Kincaid
not to pay us a cent.
And he's planning
to blow up our well,
so we won't have any water.
Oh, blow up our well, eh?
We'll see about that.
Let's have a look in his room.
Why, that's Bill Baxter's star.
Maybe he killed the Sheriff.
Now, when I get inside,
you boys let it go.
Now, let's do this job right.
Mm-hm.
Leave it to us.
It's him now.
Don't let on.
Hello, Dad.
Fay.
I just saw Kincaid.
I know you did.
I heard everything you said.
Well, that must have
been interesting.
We know who you are,
Mr. Singing Sandy.
You may be a killer and
do away with Sheriffs,
but you ain't never
going to blow up my well.
[boom]
FAY: Ah!
[rushing water]
That's one job we did right.
Yeah.
We opened up the
whole Pacific Ocean.
[flowing water]
We better clear out of
here, before Kincaid
catches up with us.
Yeah.
Tomorrow, Kincaid's dam will
be nothing but a mud hole.
Your well was the
headwaters of Lost Creek.
Yeah.
But Bill Baxter's badge.
Oh, he made a deputy of
me, not knowing who I was.
He'll be here today.
Well, who are you?
I'm called Sandy,
all right, but I
was sent here by Washington.
If you can ride, Dad, come on.
Let's get in on the fun.
[crowd conversation]
Well, men?
Now that the contracts are
all signed and witnessed,
I'll have the boys
turn on the water.
-Dad--
-Mom--
What's the matter?
The old creek's [inaudible]!
Come on!
Mom-- Mom-- come on, quick!
Come on.
Well-- well, what is it?
Why, what's with them?
Look!
Ah, ha, ha!
Whoo!
[cattle low]
[ducks squawk]
Fred, why do you
[inaudible] off?
Ain't had a swim in years!
Ha, ha!
Ah-- there's a time I do it!
But why are you going in there?
Oh-- you'll get drowned!
You'll get drowned!
Don't worry about me!
Ha, ha!
Ah!
Oh!
Stand back-- give me room.
Ah--
[splash]
Whoo!
Come on in, Mom--
the water's fine!
Whee--
[cattle low]
[ducks quack]
[horses gallop]
Hello, Saunders.
Hiya, Sheriff.
Hiya, Charlie.
Who is that you lead, Sheriff?
Hey-- Kincaid--
creek's gone dry.
Gone dry?
CROWD CHATTER]
Hey, men-- someone's
blown Denton's well
and turned loose
the whole river.
He's robbed himself
of his own water.
And all his [inaudible] pride.
RANCHER 4: And
we'll own his land.
RANCHER 5: Guess that
must've been a con, right?
RANCHER 6: Where are your
prayers now, Kincaid?
[interposing voices]
What's wrong, Kincaid?
I've been tricked.
Ruined.
And now, I'm getting even.
[crowd cheers]
Kincaid tried to finish me.
But young Saunders
here saved my life.
[cheers]
Kincaid-- look.
It's the Sheriff.
It's Bill Baxter.
OK, boys.
I started out
across the desert--
heading for Starbuck-- in
case that one of his gunmen
followed me.
When they got their chance,
they plugged me in the back.
You said you finished
him-- you double-crosser.
[bang]
Kincaid.
I-- I killed Warren--
and I shot you.
Kincaid paid me.
Say, who is he?
Well, I thought you
all knew who he was.
ALL: No--
Why, he's in the
Secret Service.
He's your man from Washington.
ALL: No!
Yeah.
[interposing voices]
[gunshot]
[splash]
[horse whinnies]
Well, I suppose
you're leaving us.
Yep.
I'm going to Yucca,
to send a wire.
Oh.
Son, we all make mistakes.
And I know somebody that's
taking hers mighty seriously.
Do you suppose you
could, eh, go in
and tell her you like her
biscuits or something,
to cheer her up a bit?
I'm gonna tell her
more than that, Dad.
You're going away-- aren't you?
Yes.
I-- I don't want you to.
But I'll be back for supper.
That is, if you'll bake
me about 100 biscuits.
Gosh.
Fay-- where you going?
I'm going to bake
a million biscuits!
[music playing]