What is it, Phipps?
The Duke of Landguard
to see His Majesty.
His Majesty is out.
PHIPPS: Yes, sir.
Any message for the Duke, sir?
No message for the Duke.
Very good, sir.
[telephone ringing]
Hello.
Yes.
What?
No, madam.
This is not the Royal
Cleaning Company.
This is the Royal Palace.
You have the wrong number.
That's quite all right.
[clears throat]
His Majesty is out.
Yes, sir.
It's the Marquis of Birten, sir.
Oh.
Send him in.
His Excellency, the
foreign minister.
Your Excellency.
Well, how'd do you do, Granton?
And where's His Majesty?
He went out, sir.
For a walk, I imagine.
Hm.
And, uh, Her Majesty?
GRANTON: Finishing the
preparations for her trip.
The palace has been in quite
an uproar this morning.
No wonder the king
went out for a walk.
And what time does
the queen leave?
The procession leaves
the palace at 4:00 sharp.
The boat sails at 6:00.
Well, I must see
her before she goes.
I have some important
news for her.
I will tell Her
Majesty that you called.
I suppose the
king is quite upset
over the queen's departure.
Oh uh.
Yes, sir.
He feels very badly about it.
Oh, he does.
Does he?
[chuckling]
His Majesty is out.
Her Royal Highness,
Princess Anne.
Oh.
Alone?
GRANTON: Yes.
- Freddie.
Anne, darling.
Give me a cigarette quickly.
Oh what a nuisance mother is.
GRANTON: You know I feel
sorry for your mother.
She has to settle all
the affairs of the nation
before she leaves for America.
I know, but she doesn't have
to make such an infernal fuss
about everything.
She's furious now, because
father has gone out.
Mother tries to boss everything.
Well, she's not
going to boss me.
I'm not her husband.
I'm going to lead my own life.
And may I ask when
you intend to start?
As soon as she's safely
away on her trip to America.
One of these days mother
will pick up a New York paper
and discover her
daughter has eloped.
You are going to elope with
me, aren't you, Freddie?
Oh yes, Anne.
I wouldn't let you elope alone.
Oh.
You are sweet, Freddie.
You're giving up everything
for me, aren't you?
I giving up everything?
Well, I like that.
It's you who's giving
up everything for me.
You'll never be forgiven.
But I don't want
to be forgiven.
I only want to get away
from this stifling place.
I want to be happy and free.
You know, there's no one
here who will really miss
me for a minute when I'm gone.
Well, there's your father.
Yes, there's father.
But father won't mind.
He'll understand.
He'd like to be free too.
If only he'd abdicate.
Oh, if he only would.
But he won't.
He wouldn't dare try anything
as strenuous as abdication.
Mother wouldn't let him.
You know how mother is.
Oh.
I do.
Father thinks it's our duty
to keep the throne occupied.
Duty.
That's all I've been
allowed to think
about since the day I was born.
Well, I'm going to
think about myself,
my own happiness for a change.
I'm going away with you.
Oh, but when can
we start, Anne.
I'm trying hard to be patient.
But I... I can't
wait much stronger.
It's terrible having to wait.
Terrible for me
too, Freddie darling.
But we mustn't take any
chances until mother's
safely across the Atlantic.
Well, I wish her bon voyage.
Her Majesty the Queen.
Has His Majesty taken the
trouble to come here yet?
GRANTON: No, ma'am.
He hasn't.
Doesn't he realize that we're
to leave here in another hour?
Doesn't he know that he's put
on his [inaudible] uniform for
the procession to the harbor?
GRANTON: Yes, ma'am.
I am quite certain His Majesty
has been advised to that.
Then, why hasn't he come here?
Wouldn't you think
that he would know
that all this was terribly
worrying, terribly upsetting
for me.
Anne, your father is a very
inconsiderate, very thoughtless
man.
Oh, don't be silly, mother.
Father probably thought
he'd just be in the way.
Well, he would have
been in the way.
But just the same,
he should have spoken
to me before he went out.
Uh, Lord Birten called, ma'am.
He asked to see you.
Suggested he had
good news for you
and said he'd come back later.
Then, I shall wait right here.
You two go and get ready
for the procession.
BOTH: Yes, ma'am.
Has General Northrup been here?
No, ma'am.
The Prime Minister hasn't
been to the palace all day.
I hope he doesn't come.
I hope I never see his
scowling face again.
Now, mother, you know you'd be
perfectly furious if he didn't
stop in to wish you goodbye.
I don't want any kind
wishes from General Northrup.
I don't like him.
He's no business to be prime
minister of this country.
Yes.
And if it weren't for General
Northrup and his army,
this country would
be a republic.
And where would you be then?
I know where'd I be.
I'm happy to say there
is no danger of that.
Thank Heaven.
Thank Heaven we have the
confidence and loving
loyalty of our people.
The monarchy will never fall.
Oh, where is the king?
What on earth does he think
he's doing, wandering aimlessly
around when he's needed here?
Oh, forget it, mother.
There's plenty of time.
There'll never be plenty
of time for your father.
Probably, he'll need a shave.
And that always takes him hours.
Anne, some day you'll
be a queen, and then
you'll know what troubles I've
had, what sacrifices I've made.
Then, you'll know what
I've had to put up with.
Don't worry, mother.
You're going away on
a nice long vacation.
Vacation?
Do you think for
one moment that I'm
going to America for pleasure?
I'm going to work for the
good of my dear country.
I never do anything that isn't
for the good of my country.
Well?
Yes, ma'am.
General Northrup, together with
the Marquis of Birten, ma'am.
There you are.
Important business
to be attended to,
and the king is not here.
I will see them.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll speak to the
king about this.
With everything that
I have on my mind,
and he's dawdling
about in this manner.
Simply disgraceful.
His Supreme Excellency
the Prime Minister.
His Excellency the
Foreign Minister.
Your Majesty.
Your Royal Highness.
Gentlemen.
I've been given to
understand, ma'am,
that His Majesty is not here.
You've not been misinformed.
I have some matters of
vital importance to discuss.
Then, you may discuss them now.
We're leaving in a
short time, and we
cannot wait for the king.
I've had another
conference with the people's
leader, ma'am, Dr. Fellman.
You can't ask me to become
excited about that, general.
You're always
having conferences.
And if I weren't,
we'd find ourselves
involved in a revolution.
A revolution.
What nonsense.
Fellman wouldn't dare
try anything like that.
Ah, but Fellman isn't
the only one, ma'am.
There are others,
hundreds of thousands
of them, determined to
overthrow the monarchy.
Are you arresting any of
these violent minded men?
We're arresting
them by the hundreds.
There can be but one
punishment for such traitors,
and that punishment is death.
Then why not execute them?
There's a reason
for that, ma'am.
You may or may not know that
our constitution provides...
You don't have to
tell me anything
about our constitution.
My great grandfather wrote it.
Hm.
Go on.
Then, you are aware that no
political prisoner can be put
to death until his
sentence has been
counter-signed by the king.
Well?
There are over 50 such death
sentences in His Majesty's desk
at this very moment,
waiting to be signed.
They've been there
for over a week.
Is this true, Granton?
Why... why, yes, ma'am.
I tell you, ma'am.
The situation is intolerable.
These executions must
go through at once.
They shall go through.
His Majesty the King.
Good afternoon.
Where have you been?
I've been down to the
royal zoo, my dear.
I've been watching
the penguins walk.
I love to watch the penguins.
You know they walk
just like human beings.
We've no time now
to discuss penguins.
Mhm.
What's the matter?
I've just heard
that you've neglected
to sign hundreds of
orders for the execution
of dangerous characters.
Who told you that?
I told her that, sir.
And I should be happy to
repeat my words to you.
You needn't bother.
I can't understand how you
could be so callous, how you
could neglect your duty in
such a slipshod irresponsible
manner.
Well, don't you realize that
these criminals will murder us
all if you give them a chance?
Can't you see that the
monarchy's in dreadful danger?
My dear, I know...
Her Majesty is right.
Naturally.
Now, just what am
I to do about it?
You're to sign those
orders of execution.
They've been accumulating
on your desk for weeks.
On my desk?
Why.
There must be
something wrong here.
Where could they be?
I never heard of anything
quite as ridiculous
as that in my life.
[roaring]
Oh.
Granton, where are
those papers gone?
I'm afraid it's my fault, sir.
I took them down to
the Lord Chancellor's
office for verification.
Well, then, you go right down
to the Lord Chancellor's office
and get them right back again.
- Yes, sir.
- There.
You see.
It wasn't my fault after all.
In my opinion, that man
should be instantly dismissed.
I should hope so.
He's a pest anyway.
I'll attend to him later.
And the signed orders
will be in my hands today?
General, you may rest
assured that I shall
make every effort in my power.
QUEEN: They will.
I will see to that.
There.
You see.
You can put it right
out of your mind now.
I understand that Lord Birten
has something to say to us.
Well, we're all prepared
to hear from Lord Birten.
I think you'll be glad to
hear what I have to say, sir.
I am happy, I am proud
to say that I have
completed a little
arrangement on which
we've all set our hearts.
So what was that?
I received only an hour ago
telegraphic communication from
the foreign office in Grec.
Yes.
What is it?
I think that a
marriage can be arranged
between Prince William of Grec
and our own beloved Princess
Anne.
What?
Is it settled?
Practically.
And I may add that
this could never
have been accomplished
had it not
been for the tireless
efforts of Your Majesty.
QUEEN: My darling child,
you're engaged to be married.
Allow me to offer my
heartfelt congratulations,
Your Royal Highness.
Add my congratulations.
This will give us the prestige
we've so long deserved.
Congratulations for what?
It's a glorious triumph
for our diplomacy.
And you've made a
perfectly marvelous match.
I have made a match?
What have I had to do with it?
Have I been asked?
No one has even bothered
to consult me about this.
Well, I believe I can explain.
It was advisable to keep
this matter a profound secret
for diplomatic reasons.
Thus, we deemed it unwise
to divulge the terms,
even to Your Highness.
The terms.
Oh, so there were terms.
Oh yes.
Your Majesty, the
marriage agreement
provides that the Princess
Anne will, of course, become.
Empress of Grec in due time.
Now, the eldest son will
become the heir to the throne.
The second son will become...
Two brothers?
My sons.
So the contract
provides that I shall
produce two male children.
Well, how do you know I can?
Anne, how shockingly
indelicate.
That's just what it is.
Indelicate, horrible, revolting.
Anne, come with
me this instant.
Come to your rooms.
Do you hear?
Father, you love me.
You understand me.
Can you let this
terrible thing happen?
Are you going to let
them do this to me?
It'll be all right, my darling.
You go to your room.
We'll talk about it later.
QUEEN: Come with me.
Go with your mother, Anne.
And don't cry anymore.
I'll have a little
talk with her.
Poor child.
She'll get over it when she
realizes what this means.
Just what does it mean?
This is beyond question
the greatest diplomatic
victory in the history of our...
Now, Northrup, let us not
go into all that again.
I know it is a glorious triumph.
You all deserve to be
very proud of yourself.
But I also know
that I do not care
to entrust my
daughter's happiness
to Prince William of Grec.
Now, look her, sir.
You're all wrong about this.
I can imagine no
light in which this
would appear other than
disagreeable and distasteful.
Your Majesty...
I do not care to hear
or speak of it again.
Your Majesty.
Well, king or no king, he
needn't think he can block
our plans for this wedding.
Don't worry.
It's all settled.
Here's the marriage
contract, signed and sealed.
They're as good as married now.
Ah, good.
Good.
But I glad we'll be rid
of the queen for a time.
We'll be able to
get things done now.
Oh, she won't interfere
in this marriage.
She's as anxious for it
to go through as we are.
Yes.
I know.
But she's too officious.
The king, at least, knows
enough to keep his place.
But she's very
useful sometimes.
Yes.
As a press agent.
She'll make these
rich Americans pay
heavily for the privilege of
shaking hands with the royalty.
But here at home, we're
not dealing with Americans.
Dr. Fellman and revolutionists
are looking for trouble,
and I'm going to see
that they get it.
Phipps.
PHIPPS: Yes, sir.
What the deuce have you
done with that checkerboard?
Begging Your
Majesty's pardon, I
placed it here for safekeeping.
Well, I wish you'd all
get together and come
to some definite
permanent hiding
place for this checkerboard.
Yes, sir.
Perhaps, I should explain,
sir, that Her Majesty found the
old one and had it thrown out.
Well, there's one
satisfaction, Phipps.
There's always plenty
more checkerboards.
Yes, sir.
Come on now.
I'm going to beat
the hide off you.
Oh, sir.
You know, Phipps.
You have an unfair
advantage over me.
An unfair advantage, sir.
Does Your Majesty imagine
that I should be guilty
of petty cheating in checkers?
Don't be a fool, Phipps.
What I meant was is that you
get a chance to practice.
Now, I'll wager that
when you're off duty,
you practice with the finest
checkers players in this city.
I never get any
chance to practice.
You're the only one around
the whole place who'll
ever play checkers with me.
You know, I thought
at time that I might
interest the queen in the game.
But she couldn't seem to
appreciate the charms.
Remarkable woman,
Her Majesty, Phipps.
A remarkable woman.
But she simply will
not play checkers.
Hm.
It would be Your Majesty's
first move this time.
Ah, so.
Well, there we are.
Beg pardon, sir.
But you've got the jump.
Oh, have I?
So you do practice.
Don't you, Phipps?
Hm.
Tell me.
Tell me, Phipps.
Have you any children?
Six, sir.
All sons I presume.
No, sir.
There's one daughter.
Married?
Yes, sir.
She is.
To a young man
of her own choice?
Yes, sir.
Unfortunately, she chose
the scientific farmer, sir.
And I may say it's been
a source of some regret
to me and to her mother.
You wanted her to
marry someone else.
Yes, sir.
We didn't consider him quite,
uh, eligible shall I say.
We'd hope the girl might
marry in her own class.
Is she happy?
Yes, sir.
I suppose she's happy and in a
rather rustic sort of way, sir.
[buzzing]
Beg pardon, sir.
That's the buzzer.
See who it is.
Will you, Phipps?
Yes, sir.
I want to talk to you, father.
Yes, my dear.
Alone.
You, uh, you may go, Phipps.
It will be my next move, sir.
I want you to tell
me something, father.
I want you to tell me the truth.
What is it, Anne?
Did you know about this ghastly
thing they're trying to do.
Were you part of the conspiracy?
No.
I didn't know.
Oh, I'm glad, father.
Well, they're not going to make
a political bride out of me.
You know this man
you're supposed to marry.
Prince William.
No, but I've seen his picture
in the newspapers surrounded
by a lot of chorus girls.
Well, you shouldn't read
those kind of newspapers.
Everyone knows
what a rotter he is.
If I marry him, they'll
all be laughing at me,
or sympathizing with me.
It'll be just as bad either way.
I tell you, father,
I won't do it.
I'll renounce my position.
I'll go into exile.
But I won't marry that foul man.
But my dear child, you
have to marry someone.
You must do your share toward
perpetuating the family.
The family can end here
and now for all I care.
If they must have two male
children, they can adopt them.
I'm sick of being royalty.
I want to be a person.
Well, being a member
of the royal family
has its advantages, Anne.
Think of all the orphan
asylums you can inspect.
Oh, don't joke
about it, father.
It's terribly serious to me.
Well, when we drive
through the streets now,
I look at the poor beggars.
I think to myself...
I know you think
yourself cheerfully,
gladly, would I change
places with even such as you.
I know.
I have read that
speech to myself
a thousand times in
the days of my youth.
And did it do me any good?
Have I ever become a person?
Have I ever found
that freedom that
is enjoyed by the celebrated
beggar in the gutter?
I'm afraid not, Anne.
I turned out to be a king.
And you intend to be just a
king all the rest of your life?
Well, I'm afraid I'll have
to stick to the job now,
even if there isn't
any future in it.
Well, never mind, father.
You're a good
king, a noble king.
Well, I could be a bad
king for all the difference
it would make, Anne.
Take young Granton for instance.
He's a commoner by birth.
But he's a royalist at heart.
And I'm quite sure that if
we were languishing in exile,
you would find young
Granton perched on a soapbox
in the park arguing
for the restoration,
and he'd go to his death
crying, "Long live the King."
Oh, no he wouldn't.
Granton would go into exile
with us and be glad to do it.
Well, how do you know that?
Well, I talk to him
now and then naturally.
Oh, I see.
Ah, Granton.
We were just discussing you.
Me, sir?
Yes.
What would you say if I told
you I decided to abdicate?
Would you tremble in
every fiber of your being.
Would you draw your
sword if you had one,
and would you cry, "No.
No."
No.
A thousand times no.
Over my dead body,
you leave the throne"?
Or would you murmur
devoutly yourself,
"It's about time the old boy
got on to himself and retired."
I can only say,
sir, that I support.
Your Majesty in any venture
he might choose to undertake.
There.
Thank you, Granton.
Thank you.
That's all I want to know.
May I make so
bold, sir, as to ask
whether you have any such
revolutionary idea in mind?
You may make so bold.
But my answer is no.
I haven't faintest
idea of abdicating.
Oh.
Here are the papers,
sir, for which you asked.
Papers?
Did I ask for papers?
Yes.
The orders for the
execution of the prisoners.
- Oh, you found them.
- Yes, sir.
They're ready for signatures.
Well, well, you take them
right out and lose them again.
Yes, sir.
Will that be all, sir?
That'll be all.
How long has this
been going on?
What?
This little romance.
How did you know?
The king knows everything.
You'd know that if you
paid strict attention
to your school books.
Oh, father.
You've got to help us.
You're the only one
who can help us.
I know, but you
haven't told me how
long this has been going on.
For months.
We fell in love.
We couldn't help it.
Well, that's a natural
impulse, I suppose.
Have you made any
plans for the future?
Yes.
We're going to elope as soon
as mother's landed in America.
We'll go to France.
That's a free country, isn't it?
Reasonably so.
And after we get
there, we'll be married,
and Freddie will find
work of some kind.
He's always wanted to write,
or paint, or something.
I'm going to have
babies and be happy,
and you'll come to visit us.
And the third day of my
visit, Granton will say
is your father going
to stay here forever.
Oh.
He won't say any such thing.
He loves you.
And besides, he's much too
sweet to be mean to anyone.
Well, are you aware
of the character
of your fiance's family?
Of course, I am.
Freddie's father is one of the
richest men in the kingdom.
I know.
Old Mr. Granton is one of
the pillars of the state
financially.
But he is a plumber.
A wholesale plumber.
Nevertheless, he does mess
up with bathroom utensils.
Well, I don't care
what he is or isn't.
I love Freddie, and
nothing in Heaven or Earth
is going to stop me
from marrying him.
I'm afraid your
mother will not be
very enthusiastic about this.
[buzzing]
I think I hear the buzzer.
Her Majesty the Queen.
Do you happen to
realize what time it is?
My, my.
It is.
Isn't it?
There you two sit talking,
talking, talking of Heaven
knows what.
And in half an
hour, I'm going away
across 3,000 miles
of ocean to America
into a strange
barbarous country.
It isn't barbarous at all.
It is barbarous.
I've seen moving
pictures about it.
[gasp] Where did that
checkerboard come from?
General Northrup must
have left that here.
Are you going to change your
clothes for the procession?
Yes, I am.
It's the bazaar uniform.
I believe it is.
Bazaar uniform.
Then, why not do
something about it?
And you too.
The procession
starts at 4:00 sharp.
And I want you to
look very neat.
There are to be over
30 photographers
between the palace and the dock.
I hope they don't
take any close-ups.
I look awful on the film.
[band playing music]
[cheering]
Lord Birten, while I'm away,
I want you to be very sure
that nothing happens
which might in any way
jeopardize the coming
marriage of Princess Anne
to Prince William of Grec.
You understand?
Yes, Your Majesty.
In two months, Her Royal
Highness will have a birthday.
I've arranged a ball
for the occasion.
You will see that she
has an enjoyable evening.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Anne, it's most unfortunate
that I have to go away
at this time, just when your
engagement to Prince William
is to be announced.
But the mission which takes me
away is a very important one.
I am going to do my duty.
I want you both to bear
that in mind while I'm away.
Don't worry, mother.
You can leave everything to us.
We'll do our best in our
small way here at home.
[gun salute firing]
[waltz music playing]
I wonder what is
detaining His Majesty.
Very likely, matters of
great political importance.
- I tell you Phipps, you did.
- Oh no, sir.
Now, listen.
Don't argue with me.
No, sir.
I'm very sorry.
I'm not arguing with you, sir.
I don't care to argue.
But begging your pardon.
But know you're wrong.
I don't care...
I'm very sorry to say, sir,
that Your Majesty has lost.
- I didn't lose...
- Excuse me, sir.
I've just come from the
extra session of Parliament.
Never mind, Parliament.
I want to go on with the game.
But sir, it's
desperately important.
Bugger Parlia... will
no one obey my commands?
Now, I want to talk
about it later.
Forgive me.
Please, sir.
But their actions this evening...
It's a foregone conclusion.
Your Majesty has lost.
I didn't lose.
I... what?
Your Majesty, Her Royal
Highness, the Princess
Anne wishes me tell you that
the ball awaits your appearance,
sir.
Oh.
Thank you.
There you are.
Thank you, sir.
[waltz music playing]
His Majesty the King.
[entrance music playing]
Happy birthday, my darling.
[waltz music playing]
The time has come when we must
forcefully show our resentment
to Northrup's iron heel.
Tonight, he made
a violent speech,
and there was nothing for us to
do but to declare a revolution.
[cheering]
[shouting]
[waltz music playing]
Bonsoir, Monsieur Ambassador.
[speaking french]
What is it?
Forgive me, sir.
I must speak.
What's the matter, Freddie.
You look worried.
Well, is there anything wrong?
You said something
upstairs about Parliament.
Yes, Parliament has
proclaimed Northrup
dictator with absolute power.
Dr. Fellman got up and
spoke to the people
and said they
wouldn't stand for it.
Good for Fellman.
Well, Northrup then
replied that if the people
were in for war, so was he.
He pounded the table with
his fist when he said it.
It's a crisis.
Now, Northrup's dictator,
with his guns and his army
he'll butcher them.
You run right over
to the War Office.
See what their latest plans are.
And hurry back.
All right, sir.
Father, you realize
this is our chance.
Who's chance?
Mine and Freddie's.
This revolution will give
us a chance to get away.
Oh, we can't talk
about that now.
There's enough
disturbance as it is.
Freddie and I would have
eloped long ago if we could.
Mother had me too
closely watched.
But tonight, tonight,
they will have
forgotten to worry about me.
They have enough to worry
about, and so have I.
But this is our last chance.
I am to be married next week.
If I don't go away
now, I never will.
This is no time
to talk about love.
I don't care what's happening.
The Army and Navy can
shoot their heads off
if they want to.
I'm going, to be married, to
be free, and you won't stop me.
You wouldn't dare.
At times, you remind
me of your mother.
[blasting]
- What's that?
- See.
It's started.
Look.
I can see the flashes.
Why.
They're on the cathedral.
[boom]
Look.
The fight has started.
That looks like the
Continental Bank Building.
[boom]
Your Majesty, General
Northrup called us, sir.
All officers are to report to
their commands immediately.
My men will escort
the ladies to safety.
Very well then.
[excited chatter]
The fighting has
started, Your Majesty.
[boom]
So glad you warned us.
Is General Northrup
with the firing line?
No, sir.
He's at the War Office.
That is undoubtedly the
safest place in the city.
Come.
We've got to go.
[gunshots]
[shouting]
[distant booming]
Well?
I'm sorry to
disturb Your Majesty.
But we're taking measures
to defend the palace.
There might be
unexpected developments.
Well, go ahead and take them.
You won't disturb me at all.
Very good, sir.
In with those sandbags, you men.
On the double.
[booming]
Look.
They're putting machine guns
right in front of the palace.
Your Highness mustn't
stand at that window.
But I want to watch.
Anne, dear, you
mustn't stay there.
Why not?
And what are those things?
Sandbags, sir.
They make rather good protection
against stray bullets, sir.
Who ordered them?
General Northrup, sir.
Well, it's very
charming of Northrup
to be so concerned
for my safety,
but you take them
right out of here.
I don't want my apartment
all messed up with sandbags.
Yes, sir.
Out with those
sandbags, you men.
On the double.
Thank you very
much, Major Blent.
Not at all, sir.
Everything shall
be as you say, sir.
Who told you that?
It goes without saying, sir.
Thank you.
It's very nice to have
you around, major.
Thank you, sir.
And may I got now, sir?
You may go now.
Excellent.
You know I have half a mind to
give that fellow another medal.
Is the yacht at Stannidge?
- Yes, sir.
- The road open?
Oh yes.
About a two hours
drive, isn't it?
Father, are we running away?
No.
But you are, and
Granton's going with you.
- But I can't do that, sir.
- Well, you wanted to escape.
Here's your chance.
But how are we going to do it?
The yacht is
anchored at Stannidge.
I'll give orders for
her to sail tonight
for Sherberg with you on board.
Now, go upstairs.
Pack your things.
Change your clothes, and don't
forget to take your toothbrush.
Oh, Father.
At last, at last, I'm getting
away from this prison.
I'm through will be royalty.
I'm going to live.
But Your Majesty, we
can't leave now with all...
Oh, don't argue
with him, Freddie.
We're going.
Yes.
And you'd better hurry.
I'll hurry all right.
Oh, thank you, my darling.
Thank you.
You'll never be sorry
you've done this for me.
I'll be so happy.
And you'll be happy
too, won't you?
I expect so.
If I could only see
mother's expression
when she hears about this.
Sir, I thank you too.
But I can't accept this
gracious offer, sir.
Really.
Well, why not?
I couldn't leave you with all
this danger threatening, sir.
Oh, don't be silly.
I have a whole army
and navy to protect me.
I don't need you.
So what is it
you want me to do?
You're to marry my daughter.
You're to write, or
paint, or something,
and you're to have babies.
I forget what it all is about.
General Northrup
to see Your Majesty.
There.
You see, the palace
is perfectly safe.
Even Northrup's
willing to come here.
Do you want to see him, sir?
I do not.
You see him.
Find out what he wants.
And I'll get the orders
off to Stannidge.
All right.
Show him in, Phipps.
PHIPPS: Very good, sir.
Here's um...
His Supreme Excellency
the Prime Minister.
Where's the king?
He's gone to his room.
I have a communication
from Dr. Fellman.
I thought he might care to see.
Well, I can take
it to him, sir.
Oh, never mind.
Doesn't matter anyway.
I suppose His Majesty
doesn't care to be annoyed
with business matters just now.
Here.
Give that to the king.
I beg your pardon,
General Northrup.
Those are His Majesty's cigars.
I know it.
Get me the Admiralty Office.
I gave you an
order, Mr. Granton.
Do you intend to obey it?
Or must I entrust it to a
more dependable servant?
[laughing]
Who's laughing at whom?
I want to talk to Lord Ennol.
This is General Northrup.
Yes.
Are the rest of the ships
ready to go into action?
Good.
That'll be all.
Well?
Lord Birten to see His Majesty.
Send him in.
I'll see him.
Very well.
Lord Birten.
Northrup, you... you seem
to be in full possession.
Yes.
The king has gone to his room.
He's hiding under
the bed I suppose.
[laughs] Well, it's
the best place for him.
How goes the battle?
Oh, don't call
that farce a battle.
Well, I hope you get
it over with soon.
That noise is simply terrific.
[boom]
I know I shan't be able
to sleep a wink tonight.
Well, we won't quit until
we've made a clean job of it.
Well, you had
better hurry it up.
Prince William of Grec arrives
for the wedding next week.
I am told that he is a
very nervous young man.
[laughing]
Ah, good evening gentlemen.
BOTH: Your Majesty.
Ah, Northrup.
Have a cigar.
Oh, you had one.
Did you get my note, sir?
Yes, I did.
I've had the
Admiralty on the wire.
The rest of the ships are
ready to start shelling.
Well, you can't do that.
You'll kill thousands
of men and women.
Well, I've given
them fair warning.
I've issued an
ultimatum giving them
a half hour in which to lay
down their arms and surrender.
And what was their
answer to that?
They said they'd never give in
until I was ready to arbitrate.
Well, then, why not arbitrate?
I arbitrate to that rabble?
Well, I appreciate the delicacy
of your feelings, Northrup,
but the naval guns will
not go into action.
I regret to say, sir, that
I must be allowed to handle
this crisis as I see fit.
I merely told you of my plans
just as a matter of courtesy.
I am overwhelmed
with gratitude.
Sometimes, frankness pays.
And I'm here to tell you
that I am running this show,
and I intend to run
it in my own way.
You're quite right.
Frankness does pay sometimes.
So I'd like to ask you
what are your intentions.
Are you going to
set up a republic?
You've already bullied your
way into the dictatorship,
thereby making me more
of a cypher than ever.
Your next step is
evidently the presidency.
When are you going
to take that step.
I resent that insinuation.
I resent it bitterly.
That was not an insinuation.
That was a frank
statement of fact.
Well, whatever it
was, I resent it.
[boom]
[glass breaking]
What was that?
[booming]
It's the stupid
field artillery.
They're shooting the wrong way.
Something gone wrong
with your plans, general?
I asked them to put a
stop to this nonsense.
I think they're aiming at us.
I'll break a few
colonels for this.
Certainly.
Here.
Don't forget your Sunday hat.
Oh!
[groaning]
[boom]
I think I better go
to the foreign office.
You take my advice
and try the cellar.
[boom]
You mustn't stay here, sir.
It's very dangerous.
Blent, you've assured
me of your loyalty.
I think I can depend on you.
Always, sir.
I want to get the
Princess Anne out of this.
A yacht is at Stannidge.
Granton will take her there.
You escort them both as
far as the harbor to see
that they get away safely.
Now, get a car, a good one.
Have it at the Quince
Street entrance right away.
And hurry.
Yes, sir.
[boom]
The car will be ready
in a few minutes.
You must go once.
But what were those explosions?
Shells, my dear, the
fact of the matter
is the revolution has stole
General Northrup's artillery
when he wasn't looking.
And they're trying
to shell the palace.
It seems that way.
What are you doing?
You think I'd go now?
But my dear child, you must go.
This is your one chance,
you can't lose it.
It's too late now, father.
I'm going to stay here,
because I love you.
And because we must be
together when they come.
Good for you, Anne.
Well, there's nothing left
for me to do except burst
into tears I suppose.
[boom]
That one seems to have
landed in the queen's room.
I wish Phipps were here.
What do you want of Phipps?
Anything you want, I'll do it.
Go down to the
cellar right away
and get about a dozen
bottles of champagne.
It seems to me the time has come
to all get gloriously drunk.
Oh, father, that's
a marvelous idea.
I think so.
BLENT: Your Majesty.
- What?
BLENT: Dr. Fellman is here.
- Fellman?
- He wants to see you.
He insists that he must.
Oh, father, don't see him.
He might...
Nonsense.
Show him in.
You go get that champagne.
Look, sir.
I've got to say here...
Do what I tell you.
Get the champagne.
Get lots of it.
You never can tell.
This fellow Fellman
might want a drink too.
Go on.
[boom]
Come in, Dr. Fellman.
Thank you, sir, for having
the courage to see me.
I hope you'll pardon the
appearance of this room.
It's a bit upset at the moment.
Is the bodyguard
absolutely necessary?
I am unarmed.
You may go, Blent.
Well, tell me, doctor, to what
am I indebted for this visit,
et cetera, et cetera?
A great many lives are
being lost tonight, sir.
Unnecessarily lost.
Otherwise, I should not have
risked my own to come here.
I commend your courage, doctor.
But tell me, why are
your people trying
to batter down the palace?
You know they might want to use
it for a museum or something.
You, sir, have never come
into contact with reality.
You have lived your
quiet detached life here.
No one has ever
told you the truth.
No one ever takes the
trouble to tell me anything.
I understand.
But you are the
ruler of this nation.
That's where you make
a great mistake, doctor.
I am not the ruler.
I am merely the king.
And are you satisfied, sir,
that you have been a good king?
Well, I've always been on
time at all official functions.
My public speeches have been
brief and of good taste.
I've always appeared
presentable on rest parade.
My home life is above reproach.
I don't know what else I could
have done to, uh, fulfill
my obligations to my people.
You could have prevented them
from being driven to despair.
I could have done that?
You have an exaggerated idea
of my importance, doctor.
Well, the people have the vote.
Why don't they use it?
Why don't they throw
Northrup out and put you in?
The issue is up to you, sir.
It is not up to me.
I have no right to meddle
in the state's business.
I'm merely a figurehead,
and a none too
ornamental one at that.
Then, sir, on
behalf of the people,
I must demand your abdication.
[explosions]
Naval guns.
Now, the murder will start.
Hello.
Put me through to the Admiralty.
FELLMAN: Now, you will see
what your reign has come to.
Hello.
I... I want to speak
to Lord Ennol please.
This is the king.
The king.
This is the king speaking.
What?
It's spelled K-I-N-G. King.
Thank you so much.
[gunfire]
Hello, Ennol.
Ennol, those guns
must be stopped.
I don't care who
ordered you to fire.
I want [inaudible] the entire
fleet on my authority at once.
Thank you.
Now, that might be
known in history
as the final act of King
Eric VIII, the last of a long
of line of non-entities.
[gunfire]
Now, it's up to your
people cease firing
and declare an armistice.
But an armistice
will do no good.
This country must have
a permanent peace.
I warn you, sir.
If you wish to save your
country, you must abdicate,
and you must do it at once.
There's nothing to be done now
except that your people must
surrender.
And trust ourselves to
the mercy of Northrop.
He'll overrule you again.
Oh no, he won't.
I give you my word that he...
You must take my word for it.
I accept your word, sir.
You do.
Thank you, doctor.
You're a very unusual fellow.
Your Majesty, General
Northrup is on his way up.
He is, huh.
Well, Dr. Fellman, I don't
know how you got here.
But you must go away
as soon as possible.
Here, Blent, take Dr.
Fellman through my apartments
and escort him as
far as necessary.
[shouting]
[booming]
Goodbye, doctor.
Now, we must keep
this conversation
secret, especially from our
mutual friend who's on the up.
NORTHRUP: [shouting]
Blent, take him that way.
NORTHRUP: Out of my way!
What's the matter, general?
Something gone wrong
with your artillery?
Did you give that order of
the naval guns to cease firing?
I did.
Well, I've come here to tell
you that's the last order
you'll give out.
You don't have to
remind me of that.
Oddly enough, I commented on
that very fact at the time.
I want you to understand
that I am in charge here.
And I won't have
any interference
from you or anyone else.
Do you realize that you're
talking to your king?
Bah.
We're talking as man to man.
I won't stand for you
meddling in my affairs.
Get me the Admiralty Office.
The battleship
will resume firing.
The battleships will
not resume firing.
I warned you not to
interfere with me.
I gave those orders to the
Navy, and the orders stand.
I'm the one to give
orders to the Navy.
I am the dictator by
act of Parliament.
I am the king by
the grace of God.
Ah.
Don't use that
catchphrase on me.
You'll be king only as
long as I and my army
are on hand to keep
you on the throne.
Now, look here, Northrup.
I'm getting awfully fed
up with you and your army.
I'm fed with up
your bombasting and
your flag-waving patriotism.
And in fact, I'm
getting awfully fed
up on your personal appearance.
[blustering] Your Majesty!
Don't Majesty me.
As you said before, we
were talking man to man.
Now, I'm going to
take this opportunity
to remind you of something.
I hope the revolution wins.
Ah.
You're a contemptible traitor.
Possibly I am.
Possibly I've been
a traitor all along.
But if my throne depends
on you and your army,
I don't want to sit on the
rotten thing any longer.
[phone ringing]
Hello.
It's the War Office for you.
Oh.
Thank you.
Hello.
Yes.
What?
[laughing]
Oh, the coward.
Yes.
Good.
I'll be right over.
Well, they've surrendered.
Who has?
Fellman and Laker on the
condition that we arbitrate.
Well, of course,
you'll arbitrate.
Oh yes.
We'll arbitrate right
enough with machine guns.
This matter will be settled
without machine guns.
- And by whom?
- By me.
[laughs]
By you.
I don't need you and your army.
I don't need your
hand-picked Parliament.
I have another power on my side.
And what power may I ask?
The people.
[laughs]
Use the people.
Use the people for
all they're worth.
But first, be sure
they are on your side.
[laughing]
What's he bellowing about?
He was just putting
me in my place.
Well, don't worry about him.
What you need is some champagne.
I know, my dear.
But the revolution is over.
Then, we have
nothing to celebrate.
You know, sir.
That fellow Northrup is becoming
absolutely insufferable.
He came in here this morning and
acted as if he owned the place.
I know, but I
talked back to him.
[shouting]
[gunshot]
Was that a cork?
It sounded like a shot, sir.
Yes.
Someone just made an attempt
on General Northrup's life.
But the bullet only
grazed his cheek, sir.
The crowd outside are in a
terrible state of excitement.
[boom]
Well, perhaps, if I
appear on the balcony,
I can reassure them.
Oh, I wouldn't do that, sir.
The temper of that mob
is violently hostile.
Father, I wouldn't
go out there.
They might try to
assassinate you, darling.
Don't worry, Anne.
If they couldn't hit
Northrup at close range,
they won't harm me.
[shouting]
MOB: The King!
The King!
Long live the King!
It's up to me to outline
your duties for you.
Do I have to think
of everything?
Do I?
Answer me that.
Will the king so much as lift
his little finger to help me.
Now, see.
Will my daughter
take the slightest
interest in her own wedding?
She will not.
Oh no.
All the work, all the
responsibility is left to me.
If I weren't here
to toil and slave,
there wouldn't be any wedding.
His Majesty the King.
Where have you been?
Now, Martha, don't scold me.
I've just been getting all
dressed for the wedding.
Come here, and
let me look at you.
Where is the Order
of St. Christopher?
Well, to tell you the truth,
I didn't have room for it.
Well, find room.
I've had trouble enough
getting this palace
patched up without
having to worry
about your personal appearance.
Where are you going?
I was just going to
put that order on.
I want you to go
up and talk to Anne.
But I haven't anything
particular to say to her.
I don't know what's happened
to Anne while I was away.
This absurd revolution seems
to have gone to her head.
If there were to be an
outburst of temperament
during the ceremony,
well, you know
what Prince William is like.
He'd... he'd pack up and go
home without another word.
Well, you wouldn't
call that a tragedy.
It would be a disaster.
I want you to
explain this to Anne.
She pays more attention to you.
Heaven knows why.
You must talk to
her, and be firm.
Yes, my dear.
I will.
PHIPPS: His Majesty the King.
Come in, father.
Well, what is it, father?
Sit down, Anne.
Anne, I'm going to be
very firm with you.
And if you find me being
otherwise, you must remind me.
Well, what is it that mother
has told you to tell me now?
Anne, I'm to give you
this bit of advice.
When the archbishop says to
you, "Do you take this man"
to be your lawful husband?"
You are to respond, "I do."
You are not to tell him
where you think he should go.
Suppose I feel like
saying just that.
You are to have absolutely
no feelings at all today.
If any apropos
remarks occur to you,
you are to direct
them to your husband.
I'll kill myself first.
That's another thing that you
positively must not do today.
Father, can you stand
by and joke about it?
I gave you your chance
during the revolution.
You wouldn't take it.
I couldn't take it.
I couldn't.
Can't you understand that?
You did the right
thing then, Anne.
And I was glad and I
was sorry that you did.
But you bare the curse
of royalty, Anne.
You will always do the
right thing, even when
you know it's the wrong thing.
I wished they'd have stood
us up before a firing squad
that night.
Prince William of Grec
to see Her Royal Highness.
Shall we see him?
Yes.
Perhaps he's changed his mind.
Pst.
Phipps.
Send him in.
His Imperial Highness
Prince William of Grec.
Ah, how are you, William?
That is, I should say Willy.
Your Majesty.
Your Royal Highness.
We're surprised to see you.
Pleasantly surprised
I might add.
I came here expressly
to see the bride.
To tell truth, sir.
I had hoped I might
see her alone.
You have something of an
intimately personal nature
to discuss, I take it.
Exactly.
Well, that being the case,
I shall take this opportunity
to take a ride on my bicycle.
Shall we both sit down?
No.
You appear to have
something on your mind.
I have.
It's killing me.
I would like to have it there.
You're worried
about our marriage?
I am.
I thought so.
I may as well begin by
telling you, I don't like you.
I don't like you a bit.
And you'd like to be released?
I most certainly would.
Then, I release you.
I wouldn't think of holding
you against your will.
Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh.
I merely said I should
like to be released.
It doesn't mean that I'm
asking to be released.
Then, what do you want?
I merely want to talk to you.
I'm anxious to say a few things
while our relationship is still
on a fairly friendly basis.
After all, I shall have to live
with you for fully two weeks.
The thought is revolting to you.
It's none too palatable to me.
The fact remains, we
are about to be married.
Why not make the most of it?
Go ahead and make
the most of it
if you like, but don't expect
any hearty cooperation from me.
Look here, Anne.
I'm perfectly willing to swallow
my prejudices against you
and pretend to be
highly romantic.
Why not respond?
Oh, so that's it.
You want me to make love to you.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Freddie.
Why, Anne.
What's the matter?
If you don't mind.
This is the man I love.
The man I'll always love.
Why, Anne.
I've misjudged you grossly.
Granton, my apologies.
I've been making indecent
proposals to your fiance.
She's not my fiance.
She's yours.
And I love her.
And I love you.
I can't pretend to
love anyone else.
It does make it a bit awkward.
Doesn't it?
I know it does, and
I'm terribly sorry.
Not for you, but for her.
Well, is everything settled?
Yes.
Everything's settled.
Then, the wedding is
not to be cancelled?
Oh no, Your Majesty.
We're more desperately
in love than ever.
How perfectly charming.
Well, I really
must be moving on.
However, we will meet
again at the altar.
With the wedding bells ringing
merrily and the organ booming
forth its impressive message...
Oh, shut up.
Goodbye.
Good day, young man.
My congratulations.
Good day, sir.
Good afternoon, Willy.
What a curious young man.
He's loathsome.
It's my duty to tell you,
sir, that I must resign
from Your Majesty's service.
Oh, you're going away
to forget, I suppose.
Yes, sir.
Oh, father, I can't
let Freddie go.
I'd much rather kill myself.
Well, you may have
that done for you.
- What do you mean?
- What?
Well, I have an
appointment here
with Dr. Fellman and Mr. Laker,
his friend, very shortly.
And if we don't pacify
Laker before the wedding
there will be bomb,
bullet, and so forth.
Well then, sir, we better
notify General Northrup
and the police.
No.
This is my private secret.
I'm not sharing it, even
with General Northrup.
But sir, no member
of the royal family
ought to venture
out into that mob.
Let them have their
ceremony here.
No.
The ceremony will be at
the cathedral as planned.
We mustn't disappoint
the archbishop.
Why he has an elaborate
candle display
all ready for the occasion.
Father, have pity on me.
I'm desperate.
I have nothing but unspeakable
horror to look forward to.
Let them throw their bombs.
Don't try to talk
them out of it.
I'm not going to.
I'm going to introduce
them both to your mother.
Her Maje...
Oh, get away.
Here, Granton.
I want you to give
this to the archbishop.
It's the prayer he's to
deliver at the conclusion
of the ceremony.
Yes, ma'am.
Something you composed
yourself, my dear.
Yes.
I wouldn't leave it
to that old numbskull.
He'd say just the
wrong thing, and it
would get into the newspapers.
I have to think of everything.
Anne, don't you realize that
you're to be ready to leave
the palace in 20 minutes?
Yes, mother.
I've memorized the whole
list of instructions.
I'll start.
What on Earth's
the matter with her?
Well, she just had an
interview with Prince Willy,
and she's not feeling
quite herself.
Poor Anne.
Poor Anne indeed.
That rebellious
young lady doesn't
know when she's in love.
Do you remember the
day of our wedding?
I do.
What were your emotions then?
How did you feel?
What... what were
you thinking of?
I know what I was thinking of.
I was grimly determined
to do my duty.
And you did.
But didn't you feel a spark
of rebelliousness, Martha?
Wasn't there a small but
persistent voice within you
that kept saying, "Run away now."
Run away before it's too late.
Save your one chance of love.
"Save your happiness."
Didn't you have to fight
hard to suppress it?
I did suppress it.
My strength is greater
than my weakness.
I didn't run away.
I went to the cathedral.
I faced you at the altar.
And when we stepped
out on the balcony
to be cheered by the crowds,
I smiled on them to let
them know that I was happy.
Have you forgotten
that I smiled?
No.
I haven't forgotten.
I haven't forgotten
that smile, Martha.
It was a gruesome smile.
And when I saw it, I wanted
to say to you, "Go away now."
Go to the man you love.
Go before it's too late.
"Don't... don't ruin
your life for me."
I didn't ruin my life.
I've made a success of it.
I've served my country well.
And I want my daughter to
be worthy of the honorable
tradition which she inherits.
Poor Anne.
She'll be a rotten queen.
General Northrup and Lord
Birten to see Your Majesties.
Oh, Great Scott.
I don't want to
see him right now.
Why not?
Well, to tell you the
truth, Northrup and I are
not exactly on speaking terms.
What nonsense.
You need pay no attention
to that blowhard Northrup.
Phipps, show Birten and
Northrup to the counsel chamber.
I'll settle him.
Come.
Your Majesties.
Your Majesty, I've
just been informed
by the Grecian ambassador
of a conspiracy
to prevent the wedding.
And that the Princess Anne
is planning an elopement.
An elopement?
With whom?
With Frederick Granton.
Yes, with that snippy
young secretary of yours.
Who told you that?
Why, Prince William
himself, Your Majesty.
And the princess told him that
she was in love with Granton.
And her actions confirmed it.
Yes, I've had Granton arrested.
He's in the palace
guard house now.
Well, what do you propose
to do with Granton?
Oh, Your Majesty, I have
a suggestion to offer.
There's a tramp steamer
sailing within the hour for the
eastern coast of South America.
Why not place Granton
aboard that boat?
No.
It's safer to shoot him.
General Northrup is right.
Oh, the scoundrel.
I could kill him myself.
No.
I... I think an execution
would be messy.
It would cause talk.
I favor Birten's plan.
It's much more sensible.
But no one need know that
he'd been put to death.
Oh, but Your
Majesty, his father
might become inquisitive.
Who cares what
his father thinks?
He's a plumber.
Ah, but he's a
wholesale plumber.
And don't forget Northrup,
Mr. Granton Senior contributes
to your campaign fund.
Oh, well.
Well, we'll put him
aboard the ship then.
This is a crowning outrage.
To think that this has been
going on in this very palace,
and that I shouldn't have
known anything about it.
It does seem
incomprehensible, doesn't it?
Phipps, send me Blent
right away please.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Who started this
miserable, sordid affair?
It wasn't an affair.
It was a romance.
Northrup, will you countersign
that to make it entirely legal.
Please.
Oh, Blent.
I've just written an order
of exile for Mr. Granton.
You're to execute that order.
You're to take him in a
closed car to the harbor
and put him on board, uh...
What's the name of that boat.
Oh, the steamship Caleo, sir.
Captain Whitley commanding.
Friend of yours?
BRETIN: Oh yes, sir.
You give this order
to the captain.
Signed by me, countersigned
by General Northrup.
It contains full instructions.
And see that the prisoner
isn't put aboard until
the last moment before sailing.
And I suggest, major, that you
remain with him until the ship
is well out of the harbor.
He might be a good swimmer.
Well, sir.
We got that in time.
Oh.
The blow would have finished me.
Dr. Fellman is here
accompanied by...
Fellman?
What does he want?
He says he has an
appointment with His Majesty.
He is accompanied by...
This can't be true.
What does this mean?
It means that Dr. Fellman
has an appointment with me.
Is Dr. Fellman alone?
No, sir.
He is not alone.
As I've been attempting to
explain, sir, for some time,
he is accompanied by Mr. Laker.
Laker!
Why that dirty...
I won't have him in the palace.
But he's already in.
- Then, have him put out at once.
- No.
We can't do that.
We must speak to
him very kindly.
If not, he's liable to upset
all our plans for the wedding.
What could they do to
prevent the wedding?
Well, they could assassinate
Prince Willy, thereby
removing the bridegroom.
Very well.
I consent to see them.
Under protest.
Yes, but you better
let me do the talking.
Thank you, General Northtrup.
I think you can leave the
situation in my hands.
Bring them in, Phipps.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Dr. Fellman and Mr. Laker.
Gentleman, permit me to
present Her Majesty the Queen.
Your Majesty.
General Northrup, Marquis of
Birten, of course, you know.
Now, that's all settled.
I'll hear what you have
to say, because none of us
is to be late to the wedding.
Your Majesty
knows the situation
so far as we are concerned.
You have been warned.
Thoroughly warned.
Your Majesty, a week ago, after
an extremely violent battle
the revolutionist
announced that they were
willing to lay down their arms.
Our surrender constituted
an acceptance of our terms.
What were those terms?
That the chief cause of all
trouble, the unemployment
situation, be relieved.
You, General Northrup, have
refused even to consider
a council for arbitration.
Quite right too.
I can do nothing about
unemployment until we
have the money available.
May I ask, sir.
What is being done with the
loan of $100 millions of dollars
recently negotiated in America?
Ah.
I knew it.
You're trying to rob our
country of the money I earned.
The people must
pay the interest.
Some day they must
pay the principle.
They have a right
to their share.
Is that unreasonable?
I tried to tell you.
Is that unreasonable,
Your Majesty?
I beg your pardon.
I wasn't listening.
I told you so, Fellman.
We wasted our time coming
here to talk to these tyrants.
Your Majesty, I have tried
to bring this business
to a sensible conclusion.
I am afraid it cannot be done.
I don't care to be
dictated to by you people.
I shall arbitrate when I
am entirely ready to do so.
And on my own terms, not yours.
LAKER: Very well, we'll
show you our strength today?
But every royal
family in Europe
is represented here today.
The Emperor and Empress
of Grec are here.
They'll have to
take their chances
along with the rest of you.
And if any of you reach
the cathedral alive
it will be due to an
oversight [inaudible].
NORTHRUP: All right.
We'll settle this matter
once and for all today.
It shall be a
fight to the death.
To the death.
And the blood guilt
will be yours.
I accept it with thanks.
Come on, Fellman.
We've talked enough.
Now, just one minute.
Now, Northrup I'm quite sure
that you'd be willing to take
the blame for my death.
But I couldn't allow you to
assume that responsibility.
I have here a very
interesting volume.
A very rare one.
The constitution of our country.
I took it out of the
library last night
and read it cover to cover.
And really, it is surprisingly
interesting reading.
I must ask Your
Majesty to excuse me.
I have much to attend to.
Now, Laker, you attend
to me just a minute.
I won't take much of your time.
As I said, I read the
constitution last night,
and I was deeply impressed
with the passages
that describe the
duties, functions,
and powers of the king.
General Northrup,
it is my command
that Parliament be dissolved.
What?
Parliament is dissolved.
Have you gone completely mad?
But you can't do that.
Look at it in the constitution.
But Your Majesty,
with no Parliament
the state ceases to exist.
No.
It doesn't.
I am the state.
I shan't be a party
to any such idiocy.
- You mean you resign?
- I do.
Splendid.
I've had your resignation
typewritten for quite some time
just in case.
Sign right there.
Oh.
Dr. Fellman, I appoint
you prime minister.
You're to form a cabinet
and have a general election
for a new parliament at once.
If the fate of our country
is entrusted to these men
it'll mean death
and dishonor for us
all, for everything
we've cherished.
Northrup, it's high
time you were taken down.
You've been
insufferably arrogant.
You seem to forget
that in this as
in every well-ordered monarchy,
the throne is supreme.
There, Northrup.
That's that.
Your Majesty, I am a soldier.
I should continue to devote
my life to my country.
Very well said, Northrup.
As a soldier, you can help us
enforce the laws, the new laws.
Good day, general.
Good day, Lord Birten.
You're out of a job too.
Your Majesty, my services
are always at your command.
We can always do
with a good diplomat.
Good afternoon.
Good day, sir.
It worked.
You both handled splendidly.
Your Majesty, your people
will bless you for this.
Thank you.
They will never cease
to honor your name.
I know, Mr. Laker.
You are a king, sir.
We must got to the cathedral.
A real [inaudible].
We are proud of you, sir.
Goodbye, doctor.
Goodbye, Your Majesty.
What possessed you to do this?
I wanted to save
the wedding, my dear.
I wanted to prevent
a revolution.
It seemed the only way to...
Nobody had any intention
of throwing bombs,
and you know it.
You made the whole thing up.
The revolution was
nothing but a bluff.
How'd you guess that?
I'm not a fool.
Well, I had to get
rid of Northrup.
And it seemed the only way.
I had to do something desperate.
So quietly without anyone
knowing, not even you, my dear,
I made friends with Dr. Fellman
and his friend, Mr. Laker.
If you'd left it
to me, I'd have
got rid of Northrup and with
no assistance from Dr. Fellman
either.
But I shan't complain of that.
The fact remains
Northrup is gone.
The wedding is safe.
The supremacy of the
throne is established.
And I shall now
be able to conduct
this state without
interference of any kind.
Yes, my dear.
I knew you'd be pleased.
[horns blowing]
Well, we're late already.
We must start at once.
So do please hurry.
And I'll wait for Anne.
Now, remember...
Attend!
When you and Anne are driving
through the crowded street,
and especially when you
are walking up the aisle,
I want you to appear
radiantly happy.
We'll all be smiling
brightly, my dear.
Salute!
- Oh, Phipps.
- Yes, sir.
That son-in-law of yours.
Oh, him.
Does he play checkers?
I... I believe he does, sir.
Good.
We'll have a tournament.
Oh, no, no, no, sir.
You mustn't do that.
I want to teach you
not to be such a snob.
And Phipps...
Yes, sir.
Tell that to Major
Blent at once.
It's important.
Yes, sir.
Very well, sir.
I'm ready, father.
My darling child, wherever
you go, whatever you do,
I want you to know
that I love you.
Never mind all
that, we have to go.
We mustn't keep them waiting.
It wouldn't look right.
We must never do
anything as long as we
live that doesn't look right.
You do blame me
for this, don't you?
Of course, I blame you,
but I'm going through
with it, every bit of it.
And I never want
to see you again,
or mother, or anyone else in
this hateful, cruel place.
(WHISPERING) Your
Majesty, he's here.
Send him in.
Freddie.
Why, Anne.
- Oh, darling.
- Darling.
Don't let them take me.
Kill them.
Do anything.
But don't let them take me.
Would you step this way please?
Frederick, do you take this
woman for your lawful wife?
You do.
Anne, do you take this man
for your lawful husband?
You do.
Do you promise to
love, honor, and obey?
You do.
You wed her with this ring.
You endow her with all
your worldly goods.
Let no man put asunder.
As king by the grace
of God, as lord vicar
of the holy church
in this our country,
I pronounce you man and wife.
Blent, give me that
order of exile.
Father, what are you doing?
I'm adding the words "and wife"
to Frederick Granton's name.
Are we married?
I should hope so.
Phipps.
Yes, sir.
You and Blent
are the witnesses.
Thank you, sir.
You're sailing in a few
moments on the steamship Caleo.
I thought it best
for you to be married
respectfully before you left.
I don't think your mother would
like it if you went under less
conventional circumstances.
But sir, does... does the
queen know about this?
Not yet.
Oh, father, I can't
forget the things I said.
And neither can I.
But the memory of them
will give me many laughs between
the long winter evenings.
Now, Blent will take
you to the boat.
But sir, I'd like to
say something really.
I... I know.
But don't say it.
You'd only stammer.
Goodbye, my darling.
I'll send you the marriage
license to Panama.
But what are you going to
say to mother, and Prince
William, and all the rest?
I'll be very firm.
I'll let them know
that I am the king.
Now, Granton, take her away.
Take her.
She's messing up all my medals.
Goodbye, darling.
Goodbye, dear.
Goodbye.
Take off that bridal veil.
Put on a heavy overcoat.
Go with them, Blent.
I hate this hat.
It always gives me a headache.
But you won't be going
to the cathedral now, sir.
Will you?
Yes, I'll be going
to the cathedral now.
But I will be back shortly.
And you have that
checkerboard ready.
[music playing]