Sagebrush Trail
Ask for the Express,
the prisoner escapes.
Last edition,
the murderer escapes.
Brant gets the best of it!
This telegram indicates
that the fugitive is on this train.
- We'll check it out.
- Go ahead. Who is it?
John Brant, accused of murder.
I heard about it,
in the newspapers.
It's here!
He doesn't know the area,
we'll get him by going around the hill.
No trace of him.
Look at him.
We got it.
Let's head back to town,
the guys will drag the lake.
This time you've got me.
Get out of there,
I'm not the sheriff.
You're a smart guy...
you've got the nerve.
My boss needs a guy like you.
What is your name?
Smith, right?
All the guys like you
are called Smith.
Anyway, it doesn't matter, I'm Jones.
You're not well.
I'll take you to our hideout,
you'll meet the chief.
We're missing some guys.
I'm taking a guy to see our leader.
- Dick, I want you to meet a friend...
- Don't tell me,
let me guess.
- Smith, right?
- Right.
You can hold your own
an army here.
Through the underground, we can
make our way towards the mountain.
It's easy to run away.
Wait here a minute.
Now that it's here,
you have to deal with it.
We need a cook,
ours got banged up yesterday.
Smith, come clear the table.
Without me, guys.
I know where it came from, boss.
Your eyesight is failing, Jones.
No way.
Well done.
If he wants to stay a cook,
he should mind his own business.
1000 dollars reward
for any information
to capture John Brant.
Convicted by the State of Maryland
when he was found near the body
of George Wagner.
His apartment adjoined
of Mrs. Joseph Conlon.
Brant escaped on May 14.
He headed west.
That's the guy we lost yesterday.
I have to send a report.
It's a weird case.
The husband is also involved.
He's also hanging around.
I got a notice about him.
He could have saved Brant
if he had testified.
At least that's what they said
at the trial.
What would happen if they met?
Brant must be mad at him.
I've been on a roll.
Thanks for taking my side.
You didn't have to,
I won't forget.
I won't either.
Smith, go water the horses.
I'm a cook.
Do as you're told.
Just a minute,
I want to talk to you.
What do you know about this Smith?
His name is not Smith,
but he is solid
and he can be useful to us.
Besides, I know how to recognize
a good guy.
What if it was a sheriff?
They're good too.
You're worried...
I'll prove to you that he's legit.
Do you remember
our little project,
well, Smith and I
are going to take care of that.
A sheriff wouldn't do that.
All right, take it with you.
If you have any problems,
just hide out at Pete's.
Are you sure there's no sheriff?
Sure and certain,
they have other things to do.
Do you need anything?
- Surely.
- Do you have any rutabagas?
Of course I do.
Don't forget the purpose of the visit.
Tonight, leave the store lit up
and two men inside.
You are going to be robbed.
When is the next mail coming?
At three o'clock.
- Will he be on time?
- He's never late.
Do you want a ribbon?
That will be all.
Anything else?
Maybe for my friend.
What do you want?
The same thing.
The eggs.
You really don't want a ribbon?
Next time.
My friend pays for everything.
I'm sorry.
You want your syrup
for rheumatism.
- How do you know that?
- My little finger told me.
I got the wrong bottle.
No, this is the right one.
I don't know what
what I have today.
Look, Dad.
Do you think these two guys
have anything to do with it?
They didn't have time to write.
I stayed with them
the whole time.
I better tell the sheriff.
We'll be ready to welcome them,
but there will be no light.
No light.
This is bad.
Let me go first.
They were waiting for us.
- Go away, leave me here.
- I'll be all right.
Go hide at Pete's
and I'll come later.
These guys look familiar.
I wonder if...
No need to insist, it's too dark.
July 28th
August 10th
What's up, Pete?
The three-hour stagecoach
will carry the miners' pay.
I didn't expect so much.
My darling,
since I saw you yesterday...
And Smith?
I'm having trouble holding it.
- Where is it?
- In there.
How are you doing, partner?
I'm glad to be out of here.
You should wait a little while,
we're up to something big.
We attack the three o'clock coach,
near the river.
There is no room for an invalid.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
I'll see you later.
By the river, huh?
I'll be there.
Just a few more minutes.
The thieves never rob on this
on this path.
We scare them.
Drop your weapons,
don't turn around.
Throw away the money.
Continue straight ahead
without turning around.
This is going to be a big one.
They're coming in.
He got us from behind,
impossible to see his face.
He must be telling the truth,
the money is nowhere to be found.
It's okay, get out of the way.
Someone has passed us.
Did you tell Smith?
He can't move, he's at Pete's.
Let's go, guys.
Let's split up and try
find that money.
Hurry Sally, this is important.
He could have cleared me,
but he let me go to jail.
One day I'll find him.
- And on that day...
- I'm sorry,
but why do you work
for this band?
It's among this kind of people
that I can find my man.
And then I have a friend
in this band.
I'd better go.
Don't forget, in the hollow tree
near the crossing.
Tell the sheriff that you've been
you were warned by mail.
You lost your ribbon.
I'll get another one.
I wasn't expecting your visit.
What about the stagecoach?
It didn't go well.
Someone has passed us.
The guys think it was you.
It's suspicious that you got out.
If it wasn't for the other night,
I would have suspected you too.
But maybe it's me.
Where were you, anyway?
Still at Sally's, huh?
We're buddies and I like you,
but if I find out
you're talking to Sally...
You think you're enough for her,
maybe?
What about you?
No, not at all.
Maybe you're right.
I've been suspicious ever since
a woman betrayed me.
It's been years.
I'm from Baltimore, actually.
Yes, why?
I knew someone in Baltimore.
I came here
to get my health back.
When I got home,
my wife was in the arms
of another man. I killed her.
I came here to hide.
I've been a fugitive ever since.
Her name was Conlon?
Why do you want to know?
I read this story
in the newspapers.
Everyone had to talk about it.
I don't read them anymore
since that day.
So, you don't know the rest
of the story?
Never heard of it again.
Come on, you need a drink.
We should drop this whole thing
or we'll end up on the end of a rope.
This is Pete's pipe.
Let's do it again, guys.
The mine is sending gold
by the afternoon coach.
- Tomorrow.
- After this shot, I stop.
Let me laugh,
you'll lose everything in poker.
- I don't trust this guy.
- He's legit.
Since he's been here,
somebody's been calling the sheriff.
I think it's a snitch.
He doesn't have the right information
for this one.
Why do you dress so well?
I'm going shopping.
- Why?
- Hold this.
I'm going to buy...
eggs.
Otherwise the guys will be unhappy
tomorrow morning.
Maybe you were right
about Smith.
It took you long enough.
He went to warn them
about the attack tomorrow.
But the stagecoach will be here
this afternoon.
The gold will be too heavy
for our horses.
I'm going to follow him, just to see.
If we come back together,
it's all right,
but if he comes back alone...
We'll know what to do.
I think Brant is alive.
I'm sure this is the man
who attacked the store.
He managed to get out of the lake.
Let's take these posters
and go see Sally.
Give this note to Miss Sally,
please.
And hand it to her personally.
A man told me
to give you this note.
I need to see you,
meet me at Pete's.
I want you to identify
these men.
Aren't they the ones from the other night?
I don't think so, Sheriff.
I wouldn't be able
recognize them.
Maybe we're wrong.
I've known Sally since
she was a little girl,
but I find it hard to believe her,
she's hiding something from us.
We should follow her.
Hi John,
what are you doing here?
I came to help you
to carry the eggs.
What's wrong with you?
I don't recognize you.
It's nothing.
I need a drink.
Go away, the sheriff suspects
something,
since I told him about
about the stagecoach robbery.
He showed me your
He showed me your wanted notice.
Thank you for letting me know.
Hands up, guys!
We're arresting you, Brant,
and you too, Conlon.
Let's get some backup.
Two of us don't stand a chance.
No chance.
Run to the corral,
get a horse and go to the mine,
I'll take care of them.
- Why are you taking this risk?
- I know the area.
I'll meet you at the hideout.
Where is he?
Is he okay?
Him, always him!
Yes, he's fine.
You'll never see him again.
He's going to have a great trip,
he won't betray anyone anymore.
He won't get you either.
- What a fool I was!
- That's right.
You are a fool,
you're the traitor.
You are betraying the best friend
you ever had.
He was charged in your place,
he escaped to get back at you,
but he changed his mind,
to finally help you.
You have to save him.
I'm such a bastard.
Tell the sheriff to go to the mine.
I'm going to get Smith
before they kill him.
They're over there.
Smith arrives alone.
Places, guys.
The whole gang is waiting for
Brant at the mine.
Take cover.
John has betrayed us too.
We're going to catch them
by going around.
They're coming from everywhere.
They are surrounding us.
Come on, we've got them.
Let's not stay here.
- We don't have a choice.
- You're forgetting about the tunnel.
You shoot, I'm driving.
They went this way.
There are more over there.
Don't stop, I'll climb a tree
a tree and surprise them.
Put him on a horse,
we'll bring him back.
Don't move me.
I'm bleeding...
inside.
This time, you won't escape me.
We won't try.
He's about to die.
I escape the rope,
but before I die...
I want to tell you...
I killed Georges Wagner.
Brant is innocent.
I didn't know...
Sorry, partner.
I'm glad.
I always said he wouldn't make
a good gangster.
© BF-WATCH TV 2021