[MUSIC - "HOORAY FOR SANTA
CLAUS"]
NEWS ANCHOR (ON
TV): At this time,
Station KID-TV brings you the
special event of the year,
a first in television history.
At this very moment,
KID-TV has standing
by a television crew at
Santa Claus' workshop.
And in just a few seconds,
our special correspondent,
Andy Henderson, will bring you
a person to person interview
with Santa Claus himself,
direct from the North Pole,
where at the moment,
the temperature
is 91 degrees below zero.
And now KID-TV takes
you via Telstar,
Andy Henderson at
the North Pole.
ANDY HENDERSON
(ON TV): Hi, kids.
This is Andy Henderson
at the North Pole.
Whoo, it's cold up here.
From this spot, there's only
one direction you can go,
and that's south.
Living up here is pretty rough.
I don't see how Santa stands it.
Since we've been here, we've
eaten nothing but frozen food.
At least, that's the way it
is by the time we get it.
And now, let's take a looksee
into Santa's workshop.
Hello again.
Boys and girls, it's just
weeks before Christmas,
and Santa and his helpers are
working overtime to make sure
that there's enough toys for
the kids all over the world.
Santa's a pretty
busy man, but I'm
sure he'd like to say a
few words to you kids.
Hello, Santa.
SANTA CLAUS (ON
TV): Oh, hello, son.
Oh, well, hello boys and girls.
Hey... oh, Andy, you caught
me at a very busy time.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON
TV): Well, uh, you
think you'll be ready
by Christmas Eve?
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV):
Well, we've never
disappointed the kids yet.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON TV): Tell
me, is it true that this year,
there's a rumor that you're
going to use a rocket sled?
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV): No sir-ee.
We're going out the
good old fashioned way,
with my reindeer... Prancer and
Dancer, and Donner and Blitzen,
and Vixen and
Nixon... hey, Nixon?
Oh, where'd I get... Oh,
I always... confound it.
I get those names mixed up.
But the kids know their names.
MRS. CLAUS (ON TV):
Santa, there you are.
We have so much to
do, and you stand here
dawdling, talking
to this visitor.
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV): Mr.
Anderson, this is Mrs. Claus.
Uh, well, dear,
we're on television.
MRS. CLAUS (ON TV): How
do you do, Mr. Anderson.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON TV): Ma'am.
MRS. CLAUS (ON TV):
Now, I want you
to go and finish painting
those hobby horses.
Television?
Did you say we're on television?
Oh, oh dear.
Oh, why didn't you tell me?
Oh, my hair's a mess.
Mm-mm... H-hello there.
Oh, oh!
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV):
Come along, Mr. Anderson,
and I'll show you some of the
new toys we're turning out.
How's it going, Winky?
WINKY (ON TV): Everything
is A-OK, Santa.
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV): Good man.
Winky is in charge of
our space department.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON TV): Ah.
SANTA CLAUS (ON
TV): Oh, now here,
here is the latest toy rocket.
It runs on real rocket fuel.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON TV): Really?
I've been wondering, what is
this strange little creature
over here?
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV):
Oh, uh, Winky made that.
That's his idea of a Martian.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON
TV): A Martian?
Wow-ee-wow, I'd hate
to meet a creature
like that on a dark night.
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV): Oh-ho-ho.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON
TV): I wonder if there
really are people on Mars.
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV):
Well, who knows.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON
TV): Well, if there
are, I hope they have someone
like you up there, Santa,
to bring joy and good cheer
to all the Martian children.
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV): Oh,
Mr. Anders... Ho-ho-ho.
Well, keep going, Winky.
Christmas Eve is coming soon.
Now Mr. Anderson, I want to
show you some more things.
Now you...
Dropo?
Dropo, you lazy,
good-for-nothing,
where are you?
Dropo, Dropo, wake up.
Wake up.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, please turn
off that tickle ray.
KIMAR: Stand up.
Stand up.
I'm sorry, Ki... Kimar, sir.
Dropo, you are the
laziest man on Mars.
Why are you sleeping
during working hours?
I wasn't sleeping, Chief.
It's just that I haven't
been able to sleep
these last few nights.
I forgot how.
So I was just practicing.
Well I suggest you
practice doing your work.
Where's Lady Momar?
Oh, she went to
the food pill center
to get some new food pills.
The children haven't
been eating well.
No appetite at all.
Oh, it's no wonder.
They sit in front of
the video set all day,
watching those ridiculous
Earth programs.
It confuses them.
Where are they?
Oh, in there watching
Earth programs.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON TV): Say,
Santa, what have we here?
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV):
These are new dolls.
Now, this little doll
walks, talks, cries,
and she even sings.
ANDY HENDERSON (ON TV): Almost
like a real, live little girl.
SANTA CLAUS (ON TV): That
she is sir, that she is.
All she needs is
tender loving care.
Bomar, what is a doll?
I don't know, Girmar.
What is tender loving care?
I don't know, either.
Bomar, Girmar, I
told you not to watch
those silly Earth programs.
Now go to sleep.
Must we go to
sleep now, Father?
I want to see Santa
Claus some more.
I want to see more toys.
No.
Go to sleep.
Hello, Dropo.
I see you're keeping busy.
Oh, I've been working
very hard, Lady Momar.
I've been vacuuming the room.
Good.
Is the master here?
Oh, he's in there.
And Kimar is very angry, too.
Kimar, I bought
some new food pills.
I hope the children
will eat these.
We have hamburger, buttered
asparagus, mashed potatoes,
and a special treat for them,
chocolate layer cake pills.
Momar, I'm worried
about our children.
So am I. They've hardly
eaten a thing in three days.
It goes deeper than that.
They're behaving strangely.
They appear to be troubled.
They don't care to sleep.
I had to use the sleep
spray on them again.
I mentioned this to my
council chiefs today,
and I learned it's the same with
children all around the planet,
in every district.
Something is happening
to the children of Mars.
Kimar, as the leader
of the Martians,
you must do something about it.
I know, but what?
Why don't you go to
the forest and see
Chochem, the ancient one.
He'll know what to do.
He's never failed you.
You speak wisely.
I will go.
Attention, council chiefs.
Please report.
COUNCIL CHIEF (ON
INTERCOM): Lomas reporting.
INTERCOM): Rigna reporting.
COUNCIL CHIEF (ON
INTERCOM): Hargo here.
Voldar?
Voldar, please report.
COUNCIL CHIEF (ON
INTERCOM): Voldar reporting.
Gentlemen of the council,
we will meet immediately
at Chochum's Chair
in Thunder Forest.
COUNCIL CHIEF (ON INTERCOM):
What's wrong now, Kimar?
I don't know, Voldar.
But I mean to find out.
Where's Kimar?
He should be here any moment.
What's this all about?
We'll find out
when Kimar arrives.
We are probably going to
seek the advice of Chochum.
What does Kimar think we
are, a kindergarten class?
Can't we make our own decisions?
Must we always come crawling
to that [INAUDIBLE] old man?
Chochum is 800 years old.
You can't dismiss the
wisdom of centuries.
I can.
Gentlemen.
Thank you for coming.
Chochum?
Chochum, are you here?
Ancient One of Mars,
I call upon you.
Chochum, it is I, Kimar,
and the council chiefs.
We need you, Chochum.
You called me, Kimar?
We need your advice, Chochum.
Something is wrong
with our children.
They eat not.
They sleep not.
Their only interest is
watching meaningless Earth
programs on the video.
Wh-wh-what time
of year is it now?
KIMAR: It is the
middle of Septober.
No, no.
Not here.
I mean on Earth.
Ah, yes.
It is early December on Earth.
Close to the time
of the Christmas.
That explains it.
What is a Christmas?
It is an occasion for great joy
and peace on the planet Earth.
And for children, it is
also a time of anticipation,
as they await the arrival of
Santa Claus and his gifts.
Bah, what nonsense.
What has this to do with
our children, Ancient One?
We have no children on Mars.
They have children's bodies,
but with adult minds.
They do not have a childhood.
I've seen this
coming for centuries.
They are born.
Our electronic teaching machines
are attached to their brains
while they are in their cradles.
Information is fed into their
minds in a constant stream.
And by the time they can
walk, they are adults.
They've never played.
They've never
learned to have fun.
And now, now they are rebelling.
What do you advise?
The children must be
allowed to be children again.
They must learn to play.
They must learn what
it means to have fun.
We need a Santa Claus on Mars.
Santa Claus on Mars?
Where will we
get a Santa Claus?
There's only one Santa
Claus, and he's on Earth.
Well, I guess that
takes care of that.
Didn't I tell you it
was a foolish idea
to seek advice
from that old man?
This is a serious
matter, Voldar.
And desperate problems
require desperate deeds.
Earth has had Santa
Claus long enough.
We will bring him to Mars.
I'm against it.
Our children are fine
the way they are.
I don't want any Santa Claus
bringing them toys and games.
They'll start
playing and laughing
and running under foot.
They'll become a nuisance.
I've made my decision.
We leave for Earth tonight.
Rigna, Lomas, prepare
spaceship number one.
Approaching
projected Earth orbit.
Fire port side rockets
number one and number two.
Port side rockets number
one and number two, fired.
Entering Earth orbit.
All right, Voldar.
Now to find Santa Claus.
Turn on your magnascope
to third power.
We're over a city of some kind.
So that's what the Earth
people call a city, eh?
How primitive.
Look at all those
buildings above ground.
Why, we could destroy that city
with one blast of our Q-ray.
We've not come here
to destroy anyone.
Our only purpose is to bring
Santa Claus back to Mars.
Turn to fifth power.
Let's see if we can
locate Santa Claus.
He wears a red suit,
trimmed with white fur,
and he has a long white beard.
But there are millions
of people down there.
It's like looking for a speck
of space dust in a comet's tail.
Wait a minute.
I see him.
I see Santa Claus.
I see him, too.
He's standing on the
corner, ringing a bell.
No he's not.
He's standing near the
entrance of a large building,
next to a large black kettle.
He's standing on
the corner, Kimar.
He's... wait a minute.
I see another one.
Why, there are hundreds of
Santa Clauses down there.
Are we going to bring them
all back with us to Mars?
Just one.
And with so many,
they won't miss one.
Prepare for landing
on next orbit.
NEWS ANCHOR (ON
TV): We interrupt
our program with a
special bulletin.
An unidentified object
has been spotted
in orbit around the Earth.
The Soviet Union
denies it has launched
any new space satellites.
Our radar stations are
tracking the spaceship,
or whatever it is.
The US Air Force has
alerted all defense
commands and retaliatory units.
Sir, Earth radar beams
are bouncing off our ship.
Well, it certainly
took them long enough.
Voldar, turn on
the radar shield.
Dysfunctioning of radar shield.
Rigna, check the radar box.
Radar shield functioning.
What was wrong, Rigna?
A slight case of Dropo.
Oh, hi Chief.
What are you doing here, Dropo?
Oh, well, Chief, I went
to the launching pad
so I could say goodbye
to you, and I remembered,
I've never been to Earth!
So I thought I wanted to see...
I may leave you there
in place of Santa Claus.
Now get below.
I'll deal with you later.
Dropo, get below quickly.
Yes chief.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Prepare to land.
We'll set down in that
field near the lake.
Rocket silencers set.
Rotor rockets number
one and two, fire.
All this trouble over a fat
little man in a red suit.
NEWS ANCHOR (ON TV): Here
is another UFO bulletin.
The Defense Department
has just announced
that the unidentified
flying object has suddenly
disappeared from
our radar screen.
They believe the object has
either disintegrated in space,
or it may be a spaceship
from some other planet, which
has the ability to
nullify our radar beams.
Because of the
ominous situation,
the president has
ordered the Strategic
Air Command into action.
[HORN BUZZING]
NEWS ANCHOR (VOICEOVER):
The Defense Department
believes that the object
spotted on our radar screens
might have been nothing more
than a meteor which burned up
when it entered our atmosphere.
Professor [INAUDIBLE] Von
Green, our leading space expert,
is still convinced it
was a Martian spaceship.
Stay tuned for
further bulletins.
Billy, what does a
Martian look like?
I don't know.
Nobody's ever seen one.
I don't believe there
are any Martians.
You don't, huh?
What would you do if a Martian
walked right up behind you?
I'd scream.
[SCREAMS]
Ah, stop doing that.
I'm trying to sleep.
I see a Martian.
Boy, you and your imagination.
Come on, let's go home.
Who... who are you?
We're from Mars.
Don't be afraid.
We have children just
like you on Mars.
What are those funny things
sticking out of your head.
Those are our antenna.
Are you a television set?
Shh.
Stupid question.
Is this what you want to
do to our children on Mars?
Turn them into
nincompoops like these?
Hold your tongue, Voldar?
What's your name, little boy?
Billy.
Billy Foster, sir.
And this is my sister, Betty.
Well perhaps you
can help us, Billy.
We're looking for one
of your Santa Clauses.
There's only one Santa Claus.
We've seen many of
them in your cities.
Oh.
Those are his helpers.
There's only one
real Santa Claus.
And he's in his workshop
up at the North Pole.
That's what we came
here to find out.
Let's go.
Come on, you two.
Let me go!
Where are you taking us?
Leave them alone, Voldar!
What?
And leave them here to
inform the authorities?
He's right, Kimar.
We'd better take them along
with us to North Pole.
Very well.
Come along.
NEWS ANCHOR (ON TV): This
morning, two children
disappeared mysteriously in
the vicinity of Welsh Lake.
The police have found no clues.
And it seems as though
Billy and Betty Foster
have simply vanished
into thin air.
This appears to be a
day when everything
is vanishing into thin air.
While local police are
continuing their search
for the missing children,
the armed forces
are continuing their search
for the mysterious object
from space.
All right, Billy and Betty.
Nobody here.
Come on in.
Golly.
Now, I'm not supposed
to bring you here.
The chief's going to be
awful mad if he finds us.
Boy, wait 'til the
kids at home find
that I was in a real
Martian spaceship.
No... no, don't touch anything.
Now, here.
That's the
anti-gravity generator.
And these are the retro rockets.
Does this light up?
Only when radar waves
are bouncing off our ship.
Then we put up
this radar screen.
Then nobody can
find us in space.
Boy, that's pretty sharp.
Yep.
What's this, Dropo?
Oh, that's the elevator signal.
That light starts
flashing when somebody's
coming up from the
navigation deck.
Oh... oh, oh.
BILLY: Somebody's coming up.
We better get out of here.
No, no, no!
There's no time for that.
Oh, oh, I'm in trouble.
Oh, no time.
Here.
Here, here.
Quick.
Thinking of taking another
nap in the radar box, Dropo?
Oh, oh, no sir.
As a matter of fact, I
was just looking in there
to remind myself never
to hide in there again.
I bet.
No.
Approaching North Pole.
I can see Santa Claus' workshop.
Prepare for landing.
Hargo, set the rocket silences.
Dropo?
You stay aboard and
guard those children.
They must not
leave the ship now.
Now, or never?
What do you mean, Voldar?
If we take them
with us to Mars,
Santa's disappearance
would remain a mystery.
No one on Earth will
ever know that Santa
Claus was kidnapped by Martians.
Perhaps you're right.
Dropo?
Yes sir?
Get back to those
children, and don't
let them out of your sight.
Understand?
Yes, sir I understand.
I... I'll keep an eye.
We've landed.
Secure the ship.
Lomas, you remain
on guard and have
the ship ready for
immediate blast off.
Rigna, Hargo, Voldar,
you'll accompany me.
Come.
We'll activate Torg.
Torg?
To capture a roly poly
little man like Santa Claus?
We don't need Torg.
We won't take any chances.
Come.
Nothing can stop Torg.
They're going to kidnap
Santa Claus, and us, too.
Not if we can help it.
We've got to get out
of here and warn Santa.
What's a Torg?
I don't know, but
I'm not afraid of it.
It's not going to stop us.
Come on.
Wait, Betty.
BETTY: Why did you do that?
If this ship ever
leaves Earth, we'll
have the whole US
Space Force after them.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
BILLY: Come on, Betty.
This action must
take place swiftly.
We can't afford to
make any mistakes.
Hargo, you cover the
rear of the workshop.
Rigna, Voldar, cover
the front entrance.
I'll direct Torg.
Voldar isn't here.
Rigna, go up and
tell Voldar... Voldar,
this is another one of
your delaying tactics.
You've been opposing
me at every turn.
Now I'm warning you,
change your attitude.
You finished, Chief?
Yes I am.
And you will be, too,
if you're not careful.
Oh, but I am carefully, Chief.
So careful that I looked
in at the children
before I left the ship.
You stay away from
those children.
That will be easy to do.
They've escaped.
Voldar, if this is
your idea of a joke...
Ask Dropo.
They overheard our plans.
At this very moment, they're
on their way to Santa Claus
to warn him.
It's true, Kimar.
Their footprints.
We must stop them.
Those children mustn't
reach Santa Claus.
Follow them.
I'll put Torg on the trail.
Torg, come out of the spaceship.
Torg.
Come out of the spaceship.
Billy, I can't run anymore.
I'm cold.
And I'm tired.
And it's beginning to snow.
Please, Betty.
Try.
We've got to warn Santa.
We can't stop now.
They might catch us.
Where is Santa?
BILLY: I don't know.
His workshop must be
somewhere around here.
Betty, look.
It's Voldar.
BETTY: He's the mean one,
the one who doesn't like us.
Come on.
Get back.
Don't move, Betty.
I'll go take a look.
It's all right now, Betty.
Come on.
I'm cold.
I wish it wouldn't snow.
That's the best thing
that could happen.
It'll cover our tracks and
be harder for the Martians
to find us.
And it'll be harder for us
to find Santa's workshop.
I'm scared.
We'll find it.
Which way is north?
I see it!
Santa's workshop.
BILLY: Where?
Right there.
See the light?
Where?
The lights are moving.
They're coming towards us.
Betty, that's
not Santa's house.
Wha... What is it?
BILLY: I don't know.
Good work, Torg.
Now destroy them.
Crush them.
Crush them, Torg.
Do as I say.
Voldar, I knew you'd
try something like this.
I set Torg's controls
so he will obey only me.
Release them, Torg.
You were very lucky.
Now don't try to escape again.
You may not be so
lucky next time.
Hargo, take them back to ship,
lock them up, and rejoin us.
You won't get away with
this, you... you Martian!
The danger grows
with every minute.
Let's get Santa
Claus and blast off.
We'll surround the workshop
and send Torg in to get Santa.
Nobody is to be harmed
unless they get in our way.
Right.
No one is to be harmed.
What has happened to the
great warriors of our planet?
Mars used to be
the planet of war.
Mark my words, Kimar, your
softness will destroy us.
Santa Claus, toys,
games, laughing children.
Well we shall see.
But for now, to your posts.
Torg, follow me.
Get him, Torg.
You can't come in here.
No one's allowed.
Well, where did you come from?
You're the biggest
toy I've ever seen.
[LAUGHING]
And very well, made too.
By the great dog star, Santa's
treating him like a toy.
Get him, Torg.
Grab him.
He's become a toy.
Rigna, we'll have to
get Santa ourselves.
Come on, Voldar.
What have we here?
More toys?
Those are Martians.
Santa Claus, you're
coming with us.
No.
You can't take him now.
It's too near Christmas.
Quiet, you.
But...
We don't want to
hurt you, Santa Claus,
so come along quietly.
Why... why did you have
to do that to my helper?
It's harmless.
It'll wear off in a short while.
Oh.
Well, why didn't you say
so in the first place?
Now you come with us.
We need you on Mars.
Are you sure this is harmless?
Oh, I never saw
such lazy people,
standing around like statues.
There's work to be done.
Let's get to it.
Oh me, oh my, oh me,
oh... oh, Mrs. Claus
is going to be very
angry about this.
Take him, Torg.
Torg, take him.
Obey my command.
Forget it, Kimar.
Rigna was right.
He's nothing but a toy now.
Best to leave him here.
Believe me, I had nothing
whatsoever to do about this.
You know my dear, I
can't recall a time
when you were so
silent for so long.
Let's go, old man.
NEWS ANCHOR (ON TV): And Mrs.
Santa Claus has positively
identified the
kidnappers as Martians.
Never in the history of mankind
have the nations of the world
reacted with such
unanimity and cooperation.
Tonight the lights will burn
until dawn in the United
Nations building as the
leaders of the world
a map of course of action.
And at Cape Kennedy,
our correspondent
interviewed
[INAUDIBLE] Von Green,
the man in charge of
America's Starshot program.
CORRESPONDENT (VOICEOVER):
Mr. Von Green,
what is the space
agency doing about this?
VON GREEN (ON TV): Well, they
have mobilized all the men
and equipment in our
Starshot project.
And we have rushed
our astronauts
into an intensive program
for the final phase
of their training.
Now, our Starshot
ship is supposed
undergo six months
of test flights.
But we are going to
forget about the testing
and go after those
Martian monkeys.
CORRESPONDENT (VOICEOVER):
Isn't that risky?
VON GREEN (ON TV): Of
course it is risky.
But every one of our astronauts
is begging for the chance
to go after the Martians.
Who wouldn't give
everything to bring
Santa back to our children?
Earth hasn't reacted yet.
No radar beams being
bounced off our ship.
Looks like we made
a clean getaway.
[LAUGHING]
How's our captive?
He's having the
time of his life.
He's such a funny little man.
Why, I've only been with
him for five minutes,
and he has me laughing
just like an Earthling.
What's soft, and round,
and you put it on a stick,
and... and you toast it in
a fire, and it's green?
I don't know, what?
A Martian-mallow.
That's what you're all
becoming... Martian-mallows.
Soft.
Weak.
That old man is a menace.
Gee, Santa, it's all our fault.
We told them where to find you.
Oh, balderdash and a
fiddle-dee-dee, Billy boy.
Everybody knows
where Santa lives.
Besides, I've always
wanted to visit Mars.
Mommy and Daddy are
going to be angry.
You think that's something?
I can just see Mrs. Claus now.
Christmas coming,
and I'm not there.
She'll have a fit.
Oh me oh my oh me.
Come and get it.
Dinner time.
Here's Dropo.
If I can't cheer
you up, Dropo can.
He always makes me laugh.
Oh, you'll have a
wonderful dinner tonight.
Oh, there's soup, and beef
stew, and chocolate ice cream.
No thank you, Dropo.
I'm not hungry.
Come on, Billy.
Oh.
Well, is it all right if I
have your chocolate ice cream?
Sure.
Oh, I just love
chocolate ice cream.
Kimar, look at this.
That small blip is
not an asteroid.
It's a spaceship, and it's
on our tail, getting closer.
Impossible, Rigna.
They couldn't have spotted us.
We have our radar shield on.
I know that sir, but
they are gaining on us.
Is it possible Earth
has a secret device that
can penetrate our radar shield?
They have a secret device,
and his name is Billy Foster.
I warned you that these
Earthlings are dangerous.
They'll destroy us
if we allow them.
Well I won't allow them.
I think we underestimate
the resourcefulness
of these Earth people.
Very clever of the boy.
Make the repairs, Rigna.
I'll take evasive action.
Well.
And how is Santa, and
the little Earthlings.
My, it must be tiresome
cooped up in this little room.
Say, how would you like to
see the rest of the ship?
You're not fooling me.
You don't like us.
You're mean.
Oh, come on now.
That's not true.
Why, Santa makes everyone
feel good, even me.
I don't trust you.
Now, now, Billy boy.
That's not the Christmas spirit.
Why, of course, Voldar.
We'd love to take
the grand tour.
All right, children.
This room is called...
Airlock.
That's right.
Sure.
This is where you
come when you're
ready to go out in space.
It's airtight.
You put on your space suit,
and go out through that door.
When you come back,
the door closes,
and they pump air back into
the room through there.
When it reaches the pressure
of the rest of the ship,
you can take your
space suit off.
Smart lad.
Well, where's the control that
opens the door [INAUDIBLE]?
Not here.
That's in the control deck.
You see, once you
pull that switch,
the warning bell sounds, and
in 60 seconds, that door opens.
Santa, that clock stopped.
60 seconds.
That must be the door timer.
Santa, he locked us in.
Oh, I don't think so.
He probably just stepped
out for a moment.
It's locked.
I don't trust Voldar.
He's not like Kimar
and the others.
I don't like him.
I'm worried, Santa.
Now, now, children,
let's not get excited.
It's Voldar.
He's going to open
the space door.
Help, Kimar!
Kimar!
Help!
Gee, Santa, what
are we going to do?
Once that door opens,
we haven't got a chance.
Eh.
Where'd you say this
leads to, Billy?
VOLDAR: Seven six, five,
four, three, two, one, zero.
Who's in the airlock?
No one, now.
What's going on, Voldar?
Oh, Chief, Santa and
the children are missing.
Where are they?
Drifting around in
space, along with the rest
of the space junk.
Before I'm through
with you, Voldar,
you'll wish you were floating
around out there in space.
[LAUGHING]
Merry Christmas, everyone.
Santa Claus, you're all right.
I... I thought you were...
Well, when Voldar accidentally
left in the airlock,
and then came up here and
accidentally threw the door
switch, we knew we had to
get out of there in a hurry,
or that would be the end of us...
Eh, accidentally, of course.
So we crawled up
through the air duct.
The air duct.
But the air duct
is just a little,
and... and you're so big.
[LAUGHING]
Well, you're talking
to Santa Claus, son.
KIMAR: But, how...
Well, well now, you wouldn't
want me to tell my secret,
would you?
[LAUGHING]
Oh... oh, oh, poor man.
He's fainted, just like
someone who's seen a ghost.
KIMAR: Begin landing operation.
CREW: (SINGING) Jingle
bells, jingle bells,
jingle all the way.
Oh what fun it is to ride
in a one horse open sleigh.
Uh, Merry Christmas, Voldar.
[MUFFLED SQUEAKING]
All right, on your
feet, come on.
Dropo!
Oh, whoa... I was handing him
food pills through the bars,
and he grabbed my wrists...
Shut up, Dropo.
Kimar, come in quickly.
Kimar?
Yes, Rigna?
RIGNA (ON INTERCOM):
Voldar has escaped.
What?
He's gone.
KIMAR (ON INTERCOM): That
can only mean trouble.
Put a constant guard on
Santa and the Earth children.
Voldar will be back.
Oh, Kimar.
Are you alone?
No.
MOMAR: Well.
KIMAR: Earthlings...
Billy and Betty.
Welcome to our home.
There's someone else, too.
Oh?
Come on.
Come on in.
Lady Momar.
I'm not accustomed to
entering people's homes
through the door, but
you have no chimney.
Welcome, Santa Claus.
We hope you'll make the
children on Mars very happy.
I'll try, dear lady.
I'll try.
Where are they?
KIMAR: Well, we'll start
with my youngsters.
How are they, Momar?
MOMAR: The same.
Quiet, remote, and very unhappy.
They're inside, studying.
Well, let old Santa
say hello to them.
And I'm sure these children
would like to meet them.
I'll tell them you're here.
COMPUTER: Y over 5 pi r squared
to determine the correct orbit
from Mars to Jupiter,
traveling along Vector
A through the 17th quadrant
at the power of 12 megatrons.
Father!
Father, we missed you.
I missed you, too.
Children, I brought some
visitors from Earth.
Will you come in
please, children?
Billy and Betty, this
is Bomar and Girmar.
Hi.
There's nothing in it.
What are you giving me?
My hand, to shake.
How old are you?
10.
I'm 10, too.
And Girmar's eight.
So is my sister.
We have another Earth
person that wants to see you.
What's that?
They're laughing.
Bomar and Girmar, too.
They've never laughed before.
Come.
I can't believe it.
That's the first time
in months they've
gone to sleep without
the sleep spray.
Santa, tomorrow we'll
set up a workshop for you.
It won't be exactly the same
as the one you have on Earth,
but I'm sure it'll
serve your purpose.
Good, good.
Now, I'd like to get going and
have the toy shop operating
full blast, so as I can
return to Earth for Christmas.
You know, Mrs. Claus is a
very good-natured woman, but...
Santa Claus, you will
never return to Earth.
Wha...
Now you belong to Mars.
Ho, ho, ho.
Well, we've no time to lose.
We must go into action.
Now we cannot
eliminate Santa Claus,
but we can just
discredit him, make him
a laughingstock throughout Mars.
Come on.
Now listen, carefully.
That workshop closes
at 10 o'clock.
The guards will be at Kimar's
house, guarding Santa Claus.
Now this is what we'll do, see?
You take...
Two dolls.
Yes, Betty.
BETTY: Three baseball bats.
Three baseball bats.
Look at me, Santa Claus,
the great toymaker,
pressing buttons.
That's automation for you.
Technology, oi.
Well, that's enough for today.
Let's close up shop!
OK, Santa.
Boy, we sure did a lot today.
SANTA CLAUS: Yes, well, there's
another day gone, children.
As they say on Earth,
another day, another dollar.
Well, hello, Santa.
How are you feeling today?
Tired?
No, no.
I'm not tired.
But my finger is.
It's been pressing
buttons all day long.
Well, I think I'll go in
and put my finger to bed.
Here, children.
Here's your milk.
You can play for half
an hour, and then
you'll have to go to bed.
Daddy, may we watch
the Earth program?
Certainly, dear.
But only for half an hour.
Billy?
Betty?
Don't you want to watch
the Earth programs?
Oh, no sir.
We're not interested
in Earth programs.
I'm going to sleep.
Goodnight.
Me, too.
Just a moment.
Goodnight, Mr. Kimar.
Goodnight, Lady Momar.
Just a moment, children.
Are you feeling well?
Oh, we feel fine, sir.
Goodnight.
KIMAR: Has someone
been mistreating you?
Oh, no sir.
You and Lady Momar have
just been swell to us.
Goodnight.
What could it be, Momar?
They're behaving the way
our children used to behave.
Can't you tell, Kimar?
They're homesick.
They miss their
parents, their friends.
Kimar, you've got to
send those children back.
Impossible.
Oh, now I'm Santa Claus.
Ho, ho, ho.
Merry Christmas everyone!
My finger isn't tired.
I think I'll go
down to the workshop
and make some more toys.
Ho, ho, ho. (SINGING)
Jingle bells, jingle bells,
jingle all the way.
[HUMMING]
VOLDAR: Shim, pull the light.
No, the light.
Oh, ah, this is
going shake 'em up.
These toys will never
be the same again.
Shh!
Someone's coming.
Quick, down.
(SINGING) Jingle bells, jingle
bells, jingle all the way.
Oh what fun it is to ride the
one horse open sleigh, hey.
What a break.
It's Santa Claus.
He's alone.
No guards.
(SINGING) Jingle bells, jingle
bells, jingle all the way.
Oh what fun it is to
ride... oh, oh, oh.
Now stay put, my
fat little friend.
Hey, Santa.
How do you like this toy?
Ho, ho, ho.
My friend asked you a question.
Answer him.
Ho, ho, ho.
Quiet, Shim.
Put on a nuclear curtain.
Tomorrow marks the end
of Operation Santa Claus.
And Mars returns to normal.
Dropo, we're here.
He's hiding, Santa.
Oh, playing hide and seek, eh?
All right, Dropo.
Here we come, ready or not.
He's not here, Santa.
That's funny.
Oh, well, he'll turn up.
Let's get started.
Hey, ho!
Ready?
OK.
Let's go.
One teddy bear and one doll.
Santa, stop the machine!
Look!
The doll has a
teddy bear's head,
and the teddy bear
has a doll's head.
I can't understand it.
Oh, let's try it again.
What's next, Betty?
One baseball bat.
SANTA CLAUS: A baseball tennis...
Why, this will never do.
The machine isn't working right.
Oh, dear.
What else, Betty?
A toy train.
Well, all right.
Yes.
Look at that.
Wha... Why, this
doesn't make sense.
Well, this never happened
when we made toys by hand.
Something very strange
is happening here.
Bomar, I think you'd
better call your father.
Father?
Father, this is Bomar.
KIMAR (ON INTERCOM): Yes, Bomar?
Father, we're in the toy shop.
Dropo was in here,
and there's something
wrong with the toy machine, too.
KIMAR (ON INTERCOM):
I'll be right over.
Just a word of warning.
If you got any big
ideas, forget them.
If you walk through
that nuclear curtain,
you'll be disintegrated
like that.
Sabotage Somebody
switched all our wiring.
Dropo's gone.
Your suit is missing.
And now, this machine's
been sabotaged.
Put them all together,
it spells Voldar.
He was here, and he
thought Dropo was me.
He's got Dropo.
And I've got to find him.
Poor Dropo.
Surprised to see us?
You're under arrest, Voldar.
Stop playing with toys.
Put it away, Kimar.
We have a weapon that's
much more potent than that.
As you may know, we are
holding Santa Claus a hostage.
One false move, and your
little ho, ho, ho man
will be destroyed.
All right.
What do you want, Voldar?
These are our terms.
First, destroy the toy machine.
Second, we will
release Santa Claus
if you promise to send
him and the Earthlings
back to their planet.
Third, no more joy through
toys nonsense on Mars.
Well?
Well, you win.
Are you sure you
have Santa Claus?
VOLDAR: You know we have him.
You mean you had him.
How did he get out of the cave?
Shim, that idiot!
A-a-and how'd he
get here s-s-so fast?
Santa Claus has powers
that you don't know about.
All right.
Arms up.
Rigna, Hargo, Lomas, report.
RIGNA (ON INTERCOM):
This is Rigna, Kimar.
Hargo and Lomas are with me.
Good.
I've got Voldar and Stobo.
I'll keep them here in the
storeroom of the toy shop.
Rigna, you come here and
take them off my hands.
I want Hargo and Lomas to
look for a man named Shim.
Tell them to search the caves
along the Transverse Canal.
RIGNA (ON INTERCOM):
Right, Kimar.
All right, you two.
In there.
All right, you
might as well relax.
You're going to be
here for a while.
Sit down.
SHIM: Where are you going?
Ho, ho, ho.
Can't you say anything
else but ho, ho, ho?
DROPO: Ho, ho, ho.
If you're thinking of leaving,
Santa, let me remind you.
Once you hit that
nuclear curtain,
there won't even
be a whisker left.
Ho, ho, ho.
SHIM: Hey, Santa!
Be careful!
What are you going
to do with us?
You're going to stand
trial before the council.
I don't think you'll be
causing any more trouble.
Well now, I think that
should do it, Billy boy.
Close the door, son.
Now, I think we need
a little red paint.
And you'll find it
in the storeroom.
Sure, Santa.
Yes.
That's a good boy.
VOLDAR: This time I'll take
care of Santa Claus for good,
and smash that machine.
Santa!
Voldar and the other man
are in the storeroom,
and they're coming to get you.
Oh, they are, are they?
Yeh... well, maybe they'd like
to have some fun with our toys,
and we'll see that they do.
Won't we kids.
Oh-ho, we meet again, eh?
I don't know how you escaped
Shim, but you won't escape me.
You're through.
Voldar, why don't
you, uh, relax?
You're going to
relax... permanently.
You?
Wha... but, you're not here.
You're in there.
Oh, yeah, you're right.
I'm not here.
I'm in there.
Wait a minute.
I'm going to see who
Voldar's fighting in there.
What happened?
I don't know what's
going on in there,
but I'm going to take
care of you myself.
Now... now, just a minute.
Now I'd like to
talk to... Oh, boy,
Chief, am I glad to see you.
All right, inside, Stobo.
All right, kids,
you can stop now.
I said cease fire.
All right, Rigna.
Take them away.
They've had a rough day.
Ho, ho, ho, everybody.
Merry Christmas!
You don't need me here, Kimar.
You've got a wonderful
Santa Claus of your own.
Ho, ho, ho!
Goodbye, Billy.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Betty dear.
You take care of yourself.
Bye.
I've got something
for you, Billy.
Gee, thanks.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Gee, we had fun.
We're going to miss you.
Do you think we'll
ever meet again?
I'm sure you will, children.
Thank you, Santa, for
bringing happiness
to the children of Mars.
And the Christmas
spirit to all of us.
Son, from the
bottom of my heart,
I wish you and yours the
very best of everything.
Ho, ho, ho!
Merry Christmas, everybody!
Dropo Claus is here.
Ho, ho, ho, Merry Christmas!
Dropo, you put on weight.
Oh, yes.
No pillows, look.
Look kids, no pillows.
Now, if we hurry, we can get
back in time for Christmas Eve.
KIDS: Yay!
Shall we get going?
Goodbye, dear friends.
Away!
Merry Christmas, everyone!
MARTIANS: Bye!
Goodbye, Santa Claus!
Goodbye!
[MUSIC - "HOORAY FOR SANTA
CLAUS"]