[horn honks]
- [horn honks]
- [vehicle approaches]
[woman screams]
[gunshots]
When you get to the next intersection,
why don't you turn south?
Chocolate Mountains are east. Well, they
were the last time we headed that way.
Who needs the mountains?
Why don't we go to San Felipe?
Nothing to do in San Felipe but fish.
Well...
that was the idea, wasn't it?
Yeah, I guess so.
We might just pick up a drink in Mexicali.
Remember Floribel at the Alhambra Club?
Yeah.
She's probably dead by now.
That was a long time ago.
Yeah. Poor old Floribel.
Well, there's no harm
in drinking a toast to her.
Okay.
You know, except for the war,
this is the first time
I've been away from Maudie and the kids.
- You wanna turn back?
- No, no, no.
We've come this far.
[sighs] Mexicali's
beginning to sound good.
Just maybes.
[horns honking]
I remember that joint.
[muttering] The Alhambra...
It's right down the block.
[man speaking Spanish]
This is the place, señor, come right in.
Juanita's just starting
her famous fan dance. You're just in time.
Ah, might as well take a look.
Hey, Gil! Gil?
- [groans]
- Mmm.
Sorry, friend, no sale.
Oh, well. San Felipe, here we come.
- Out of gas?
- Yeah.
Hop in.
We're going to San Felipe. You can pick up
some gas there and hitch a ride back.
- Waiting out there long?
- Yeah.
Gil, light me a cigarette.
Smoke?
No.
What are you doing, rolling 'em?
Face front!
And keep driving.
Sure, I'm Emmett Myers.
Do what I tell you,
and don't make no fast moves.
There are a lot of dead heroes
back there got nervous.
From now on while you're driving,
keep both hands high on that wheel.
And you, keep one hand
along the top of this seat...
the other hand, high on that window.
All right. Now turn off
the next side road we come to.
Pull up.
Open the glove compartment.
What's the box?
- [Gilbert] Cartridges, .22s.
- [Myers] Give 'em to me.
Close it.
Now this is how we get out after this.
First, give me the keys.
Now we all get out the side, this one.
I get out first, then you.
Stand away from the car. And then you.
Let's go.
Drop your jackets around your elbows.
Turn around.
We're gonna open the trunk. Move.
Pull your jackets up.
You, open the trunk.
Both of you, keep your hands on the lid.
Throw me the keys.
Now get the blankets.
[Emmett] You'd never make it!
Get the groceries, you.
- Whose gun is that?
- Mine.
- You like to shoot?
- Yeah.
So do I.
So I'm warning you,
don't try anything smart with me.
Move!
[Emmett fiddling with gun]
I told you my name. What's yours?
Mine's Gilbert Bowen.
He's Roy Collins.
What do you do for a living?
I'm a draftsman. He runs a garage.
That makes you smarter.
Or does it?
[trigger clicks]
You oughta be all over that windshield.
You got lucky.
It hit an empty chamber.
I had to use it a while back.
Now don't make any more fast moves! I told
you, the last guy made that mistake.
When are you due back?
No particular time.
Yeah, we told our wives
to expect us home when we got there.
You got wives, huh?
Any kids?
I have.
Just keep thinking how nice
it'll be to see 'em again.
There's the checkpoint. Slow down.
No talking.
If I give you the word, step on it.
This car rides pretty good.
When I get where I'm going,
I think I'll sell it.
Where are we going?
Pull in to the next pump.
We'll fill up with gas and get a road map.
I got an idea.
A pretty good one.
[both speaking Spanish]
- [Emmett] Speak English, you.
- I told you,
he doesn't understand English.
And I don't understand Mexican.
Never mind the change,
let's get out of here.
Loco.
Gimme the map.
Take the first side road we come to.
Pull up.
Keys.
All right, now get out like I told you.
Here, you're the smart guy.
Spread the map out on the hood.
Get your hands up on the car.
Look for a town called Santa Rosalía.
How far is it?
- It's about 500 miles.
- Is it on the Gulf of California?
Yeah.
Say anything in there
about a ferry across the Gulf?
Friday.
Not bad.
We're loaded with time.
We can make that, easy.
After that,
I won't be needing you guys anymore.
[gun blasts]
Well, I guess we won't be having
rabbit for dinner.
I wasn't trying.
Collins, put the can
out on that rock there.
Gimme the map.
Not that one! The other one.
That's it.
[Emmett laughs]
All right, Collins.
Put the can back on the rock.
Don't forget, this is loaded too.
Let's see you try. See how good you are.
Go ahead.
[fires rifle]
Not bad.
Collins!
Pick up the can.
Take it out on that point there.
If you don't, I'll let Bowen have it.
Out on the point, that's right.
Further!
Now hold it up.
You won't get hurt,
your buddy's good with guns.
You're crazy. I won't do it.
It's just a game. Go ahead.
Collins, hold it closer to you.
What's the matter, you scared?
Hold it closer.
You want me to try it again?
I might miss this time.
Shoot.
Come on, Gil, get going.
[fires rifle]
Nervous? Relax.
All right, Collins, come on in.
Fun's over.
You guys worked up quite a sweat.
Collins.
Collins!
- What do you want?
- Turn on the radio.
Why bother?
All you'll get is Mexican commercials.
Never mind. Turn it on.
[man on radio speaking Spanish]
Get something else.
- [Collins] Like what?
- One of those news guys from the States.
[man on radio continues in Spanish]
[male reporter] And scheduled for 10:00
tomorrow morning at the White House.
On the crime front,
the police of nine Western states,
from Washington in the north
to Colorado and Utah in the east,
have been alerted
to keep a continuous search
for the Kansas desperado, Emmett Myers.
Reports have placed the killer
in Florida, Detroit and Seattle
within the last 24 hours,
although most of these tips have been
discounted by police authorities.
His latest victim, William Johnson,
a salesman from Portland, Oregon,
was found late yesterday
in Imperial County, California.
The victim's car, possibly with Myers in
it, has not yet been found.
- The United Nations passed...
- [Emmett] Shut it off.
[switches radio off]
[laughs] They're not even close!
You guys don't have to worry.
Not yet.
You can start sweating
when they put me in this car.
If they ever do.
[chuckles]
And a good, good evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
this is Sam Hayes
reporting your news final.
At the top of the news tonight
is the report
that the hitchhike murderer,
Emmett Myers, is still at large.
Yesterday, the devil thumbed another ride
and William Johnson of Portland
asked him to hop in.
Now, William Johnson is dead.
In an all-out effort to apprehend Myers,
the police have set up roadblocks
on all major highways
in the Western states,
and all border stations
are being closely watched.
Myers is slight,
28 years of age, is wearing a dark shirt,
dark gray trousers
and a black leatherjacket.
His right eyelid is partially paralyzed.
If you are in possession
of any information
regarding the whereabouts
of this individual,
please communicate
with your nearest office of police
or office of the Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Pull up.
Keys.
Out.
Move.
Each of you take one.
Get around the car.
We'll camp here tonight.
I know what you're thinking, Collins.
You haven't got a chance.
You guys are gonna die, that's all.
It's just a question of when.
Santa Rosalía...
that's the end of the line.
If the cops find out we're together,
or if you try to cross me up.
[laughs]
You know, you make
pretty good targets from where I sit.
Anyway, you couldn't tell
if I was awake or asleep.
Got one bum eye.
Won't stay closed.
Pretty good, huh?
We're getting out here and buy some grub.
We get out of the car like usual.
You guys go in the store ahead of me.
No Mexican. I'm talking to you.
When he tells you how much,
you pay. Is that clear?
Now one other thing.
I'm gonna have my hand in my pocket.
So far, my record's clean,
I wanna keep it that way.
Let's go.
[speaks Spanish]
[speaking Spanish]
What'd he say about Tijuana?
He says their prices
are about the same as in Tijuana.
Never mind the kid.
- What do you want?
- Some beans and stuff.
And tomato soup.
I like that. Get four cans.
He wants four can of beans, four cans of
tomato soup, three cans of chili.
It's no use.
He doesn't understand English.
Well, you're not talking Mexican.
Take the cans off the shelves,
give them to Collins.
I can take some more.
Go on, load it up.
That'll hold us. Pay him.
[clerk speaking Spanish]
[girl speaking Spanish]
Get her away from me.
Put the kid down.
Let's get outta here. Come on, Collins.
[speaking Spanish]
[speaks Spanish]
- [Emmett] What'd you say to her?
- You wouldn't understand.
What did you say to her?
I said, "Go you with God, little one."
Get in.
Hey, mister. You live in El Centro.
I live there some time. Nice place, huh?
Where'd you get the watch, Bowen?
My wife gave it to me.
Throw it over here.
Didn't you hear me?
I told you to throw it over here.
I had a watch like this once
when I was 17.
Nobody gave it to me. I took it.
I knocked off a broken-down jewelry store
in a little jerk town outside of Tulsa.
It was a cinch.
You guys are soft.
You know what makes you that way?
You're up to your necks in IOUs.
You're suckers.
You're scared to get out on your own.
You always had it good, so you're soft.
Well, not me.
Nobody ever gave me anything.
So I don't owe nobody.
My folks were tough.
When I was born,
they took one look at this...
puss of mine and told me to get lost.
I didn't need 'em.
I didn't need any of 'em.
I got what I wanted my own way.
When you got the know-how
and a few bucks in your pocket,
you can buy anything or... anybody.
Especially if you've got 'em
at the point of a gun.
That really scares 'em.
You ever been at the other end of a gun?
No. And I never will be.
I'm gonna listen to the news.
[muffled radio chatter]
Turn it up.
We'd like to hear what's going on.
You just get the grub ready.
Anything interesting, I'll let you know.
We've got to find an excuse
to raise the hood of the car
and put that radio out of commission.
First time he finds out they're looking
for us together, we're through.
Never mind the radio. I'm not gonna take
it anymore. We gotta get him.
You can't beat him that way.
You give him one good reason,
and he'll kill us.
We gotta take the chance.
As long as he needs us, we'll stay alive.
When he gets ready to jump us,
we'll jump him. Not before.
Maybe today, maybe tomorrow.
[car door closes]
Or right now.
They found Johnson's car.
They know I'm in Mexico.
And they're looking for you, too,
in the Chocolate Mountains.
Where are the Chocolate Mountains?
- In Arizona, near home.
- [Emmett] Not in Mexico?
No.
[chuckles]
Well, what do you know?
That's where you told your wives
you were going, huh?
Then you came to Mexico.
What for?
Dames?
You boys oughta be ashamed of yourselves.
Causing all that trouble, telling lies.
They got everybody and his brother looking
for you in them mountains.
- I told you, turn the radio on.
- I did.
It takes time to warm up.
Try another station.
- [clattering]
- [horn honking]
- Stop it. Stop it!
- I can't.
I gotta pull up and disconnect it.
Then pull up!
[horn continues]
Go on, raise the hood.
And keep your hands on it.
[horn continues]
All right, Collins, get to work.
Get the right one the first time.
Don't pull the radio wire!
[horn continues]
Faster, faster!
I thought you were a mechanic!
I'm going as fast as I can.
The threads are frozen.
[horn continues]
[horn stops]
Watch it.
Come on.
Throw the tools in the back.
The radio, remember? Make it work.
I can't.
Pull up.
So you did bust it, Collins.
Cut it out! He didn't do it.
It's the static in the hills.
The stations aren't strong enough
in the daytime.
- Tonight, it'll work.
- Tonight, it better.
Take the wheel.
Now, in Punta Prieta,
in August the 7th,
three Americans stopped for provisions
at a store owned by José Andrade.
Andrade gave an accurate description of
Myers as being one of them.
Another witness stated
that three men came out of the store
and drove away in a green sedan
bearing the same plate.
This confirms our theory
that Collins and Bowen are with him.
He seems to be heading south, all right,
staying clear of all main highways.
Exactly. Now to the west,
this is more or less barren
and would afford no means of escape.
His most logical move
would be Santa Rosalía.
Then Guaymas.
Make sure that fire's out.
Pour the coffee on it.
Get down!
I've gotta get a closer look at that car.
On your feet.
Through there.
At the other end, lie flat. Get going!
Get a move on!
What are you trying to do, wreck it?
Drive like I tell you.
[tire blows out]
[car screeching]
[Emmett] Out!
- What did I tell you?
- Shut up!
Get that spare tire out,
and go to work. Move!
You keep working.
Keep your traps shut, no matter what.
I'll be watching.
[speaking Spanish]
Do you need any help?
[both speaking Spanish]
The search for Gilbert Bowen
and Roy Collins,
now believed to have been
last seen with Emmett Myers, mass killer,
is being stepped up by the hour.
Helicopters are working in shifts,
scouring the entire area
from El Centro south
to the Gulf of California.
The planes are maintaining
close liaison with the ground,
reporting isolated cars and campers.
The Mexican police have now joined
this strange race against death.
[both speaking Spanish]
[both men continue speaking Spanish]
[all speaking Spanish]
[all continue speaking Spanish]
Hold it right there.
Around.
Break the lock.
[dog barking in distance]
Okay, one of you on the pump.
[barking continues]
[barking stops]
[speaking Spanish]
[man speaking Spanish]
"Maudie and Gilbert Bowen."
[speaking Spanish]
Now, as you will notice,
when interrogated at the roadblock,
the man and his wife
were very definite in their statement
that they only saw two men.
This was below El Arco.
There is a point, however,
which we feel is of importance.
The couple stated that
the behavior of the men seemed strange.
That they refused to talk to them.
Of course, there's a possibility
that Myers concealed nearby,
covering the two men,
which would account for their behavior.
We are following through
on that possibility.
Now, on the assumption
that Myers is listening to the car radio,
we're issuing these broadcasts
in the States,
containing false information
as to his whereabouts
and not connecting the two men with him.
We'd appreciate your cooperation
in following the same procedure.
- This ought to be the main highway.
- It isn't.
- What do you mean?
- Looks like an abandoned airstrip.
Well, it's okay for tonight.
Head over there.
No, Roy, you're wrong, you're wrong.
It's no use, your trying
to talk me out of it.
- Tonight I'm gonna chance it.
- You're out of your mind!
I've played it your way long enough.
From now on we're each on our own.
It's no good,
we gotta stay together. I told you that.
If I get a break, I'm gonna take it,
you do whatever you want.
But I...
Across the runway there's trees. Let's go.
Keep going!
- You guys are really dumb.
- Why, you dirty...
You thought I was asleep, huh?
You know, you're beginning to get ideas.
I don't like that.
Load him in the car.
Your buddy's all washed up for the night.
Over there.
Move!
You, Collins,
throw a rock down that shaft.
[water splashes]
Nice and deep.
This is fine.
Cut it out! If you're gonna kill us,
do it and get it over with.
Thought you never killed without a reason.
Go get the rest
of the canned goods out of the car.
We'll have a real good meal.
[birds squawking]
[chamber music on radio]
[whistles]
Save 'em for the next guy
that picks you up.
[chuckles] Anything you say.
[male reporter] We interrupt this hour of
music to bring you a flash bulletin.
Californian and Mexican
police officials have abandoned
their previously held theory that Emmett
Myers is connected with the disappearance
of Gilbert Bowen and Roy Collins
of El Centro, California.
They have been missing since last Sunday
night, supposedly on a fishing trip.
The police of both sides
of the border now feel
that Myers is traveling alone
and has apparently abandoned his intention
of seeking escape by way of Santa Rosalía.
[chamber music resumes on radio]
[chuckles] What do you know?
This kind of changes my plans.
Looks like you and me
are going fishing after all.
On your feet. Head for the car. Let's go.
We're not going anyplace.
Stand up!
What did you do to it?
There's a great big hole
in that crankcase.
All right, we'll walk.
Just what that sore ankle of yours needs,
Collins, a nice, long hike.
Get up!
Now get the fishing gear
out of the back. Move!
Stay with it.
He'll never leave you out here alive.
- Yeah.
- Cut the gab.
[helicopter approaches]
Get down!
Let's get going.
Maybe we'll have to leave you here.
Too bad.
Come on, Roy, try.
Here we are! Here we are!
Can't you see us?
Look! Here we are! Down here!
Oh, please, God! Hear me!
Hear me!
Come back! Come back. [sobs]
Leave him alone.
Can't you see he's praying?
[Emmett] Get under the bridge, quick!
[car crossing bridge]
Relax.
Go ahead if you can stand
the filthy stuff.
You know, Collins,
you're just about my size.
Put you in a black shirt and dark pants...
with a leatherjacket...
you'd look just like Emmett Myers
to anyone who never saw him.
Ain't nobody in Santa Rosalía
ever saw him.
Let's change.
[cocks gun]
Get up on the bank,
and take your clothes off.
Come on, get up!
[shouting in Spanish]
- Looks great, doesn't it?
- You won't be there long.
Collins! There are cops down there.
In those clothes, they might shoot you.
That'd solve all your problems,
wouldn't it?
Not if they found they'd made a mistake,
it wouldn't.
We'll hit some little joint
on the outskirts.
I might even buy you boys a beer.
Get moving.
[speaking Spanish]
Give us three beers.
[speaks Spanish]
He doesn't speak English.
[both speak Spanish]
When I want you to talk Mex,
I'll tell you.
Sit down, Collins. Rest your sore foot.
You can talk it now.
Ask him about the ferry to Guaymas.
I'll be watching his face.
If he starts looks frightened,
I start shootin'.
[both speaking Spanish]
[Gilbert] Friday, that's today,
and Tuesday, at 9:00.
- Ask him where we catch it.
- [Gilbert speaks Spanish]
[speaking Spanish]
You're out of luck.
The ferry burned up.
It's being repaired in Guaymas.
[Emmett] You're lying.
Ask if he knows anyone speaks English.
[speaking Spanish]
He says he has
a cousin who speaks English, follow him.
Up.
José! [speaks Spanish]
José, José. [speaks Spanish]
[both speaking Spanish]
[speaking Spanish]
What can I do for you?
We wanna find out
about the ferry to Guaymas.
You wanna go fishing?
Too bad. No ferry anymore
for the next two months, maybe.
- She burned up.
- Thank you.
Fishing is pretty good here. Not as good
as Guaymas or La Paz, but okay.
- [José] You have motorboat?
- [Emmett] You know someone who has a boat?
Sure, sure. My friend Jaime, he have one.
Motor runs good.
- How do we get to this Jaime?
- [José] In the mine, where he works.
- Let's go.
- He's not finished until 6:00.
- I'll fix it for you tomorrow morning.
- I wanna go now.
At 6:00, then.
By the time my friend gets the boat ready,
there is no sun.
My friend does not like
using too much boat at night.
He... He sees his wife and kids
- only at night.
- [Emmett] Give him some more.
- For me?
- Yeah.
- You pay my friend too?
You be at pier at 8:30.
The name of the boat is Estrella.
A thousand thanks, señor.
Good.
We'll go 'round to town
and wait by the water till it gets dark.
Let's go.
Hold it a minute, will you?
Hang on.
Better go fishing
while you've got a chance.
That's what you
came down here for, wasn't it?
You guys are really fools.
If you weren't, one of you
would have got away.
But you kept thinking about each other.
So you missed some chances.
You got tired. You slowed down.
Now it's pretty late.
Yeah, tomorrow I'll be in Guaymas.
Too bad you're not making
the whole trip with me.
[laughs]
That'd be kinda silly, wouldn't it?
You stink, Myers!
You smell. Just like your clothes.
Sure, you'll make it to Guaymas,
but they'll catch up with you
and put you out of your misery.
You haven't got a chance.
You haven't got a thing except that gun.
You'd better hang on to it,
because without it, you're nothing.
- You're finished!
- Shut up!
Gracias, Carlos.
Caramba!
[speaking Spanish]
No, Carlos! [speaks Spanish]
- Hold it.
- [cat meows]
[meowing]
All right, Collins.
Now you get to take
a nice little walk all by yourself.
Down the alley and out on the dock.
Me and Bowen will follow.
If you try to tip anyone off,
I'll let Bowen have it.
You wouldn't want that
to happen, would you? Get going.
[dock creaks]
Go ahead, Collins.
All the way out. Keep under the lights.
[boat motor cranks, starts]
- [man shouting in Spanish]
- [gunfire]
- [man shouts in Spanish]
- [gunfire continues]
I'm not Myers! I'm not Myers!
[gunfire]
Do you hear me? I'm not Myers!
[man shouting in Spanish]
- [man shouting in Spanish]
- [footsteps approaching]
[shouts in Spanish]
Put your hands up. Walk this way.
[Gilbert] Do as he tells you, Myers.
You're all through.
[handcuffs ratcheting]
[panting, grunting]
- That's enough.
- All right.
That's enough!
[spits]
[speaks Spanish]
I'm sorry. We have to have full report.
- You understand.
- Yeah.
Gracias.
It's all right, now, Roy.
It's all right.