Good night, good night.
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
That I shall say good night til it be 'morrow.
Good night, good night.
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
That I shall say good night til it be 'morrow.
Good night...
Good night!
Help! Help!
Murder! Police!
Help!
Mr. Stevens!
Peters, help!
Help! Help!
Help!
Help! It's after me!
Help! Help!
Please, help!
Help! It's after me!
Help!
Mr. Stevens! Mr. Peters!
Stevens!
Mr. Stevens!
Help!
Please!
Well, Kitty, what is all this racket about?
Peters! Oh, Peters! I saw 'em! I saw 'em!
He's here in this house! He almost killed me!
The Gorilla! The Gorilla!
- It was awful! He'd've gotten ahold of...
- Be quiet!
- You have been dreaming.
- Oh, no!
- What's that?
- I don't know. I tell you, I don't know anything!
Call the police! Call Mr. Stevens!
He'll kill somebody!
- Be quiet, can't you!
- No, I can't!
I can't stay here or we'll all be murdered!
Mr. Stevens! Mr. Stevens!
- Were you calling me, Kitty?
- Oh, Mr. Stevens!
We'll all be murdered in our beds!
It's that gorilla fellow the papers are so full of!
The killer! He was just up in my room!
Why, now, come, Kitty, you're hysterical!
Oh, no, sir, I ain't hysterical! I've seen him
like I said, sir!
Oh, Kitty, you're imagining things. Just you
go back to bed.
That's what I said, sir, only there is this.
The Gorilla's paw.
Shall I call the police, sir?
The police? Yes, yes, call them right away.
Just a minute.
I'll handle this my own way.
- Yes, sir. Only...
- Only what?
You're thinking of the time, sir.
The time?
According to the newspapers, the Gorilla gives
his victim only twenty-four hours notice.
Oh, nonsense!
Now you go back to bed and don't worry about this.
- Back to bed? Who, me?
- Or don't go back to bed. I'm not particularly
interested in where you go.
- Oh, but, Mr. Stevens!
- Kitty...
- Yes, but...
- I...
Hello?
Oh, now, come please...
Just a minute.
That'll be all.
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah, but...
I wouldn't be frightened like that
if I were you, Kitty.
Look, you be frightened any way you want.
This is my way.
Hello?
I begged you not to telephone me here.
Yes, I know I promised, but...
You gave me until Monday.
Saturday?
Tomorrow?
That's impossible!
I can't possibly raise that amount of money.
Yes, I know I owe it to you, but..
A quarter of a million dollars?
Look, please, now...
Oh, please be patient.
I have a plan.
But it's only just started.
Give me time to work it out
and I'll repay you dollar for dollar.
Hello?
I want to send a radiogram, please.
To whom is the radiogram going, please?
Ms. Norma Denby.
'D' as in 'Denver'.
Aboard the S.S. Paris.
'Regret unable to meet you at boat. '
'Mightily important that I see you at my home,
tomorrow evening, without fail. '
Sign it, 'Fondly, Uncle Walter. '
Read that back please.
I'm Norma Denby.
Mr. Stevens is expecting you, Ms. Denby.
- May I take your coat?
- No, thank you. I'll keep it on.
Nice cozy little place your uncle has here.
He likes it.
He'd have to live in it.
This way, please.
Well, well, well! If it isn't the prodigal niece!
Oh, it's swell seeing you again, darling.
And good to see you again, too, dear.
I took the liberty of bringing along my accomplice.
- Good, I'm glad you did.
- This is Jack, Uncle Walter.
This niece of mine isn't much of a correspondent.
But the few letters she did write,
they were full of you!
Congratulations, young man.
Thank you, and I hope you'll excuse me
for barging in like this.
Nonsense, I'm delighted.
I was more than pleasantly surprised
to hear that you set your marriage for June.
Do you realize it's only a month away?
Well, we decided we didn't wanna
rush things too much, so...
- So we put it off until...
- The day after tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow?
Does it startle you?
Why... Why, no, no, that's fine.
That's one of the things I wanted
to talk to you about.
But I'm forgetting my role as host.
Sit down, my dear, sit down.
We may as well come to the point...
- Perhaps you'd rather talk to Norma alone, Mr. Stevens.
- Oh, no, no.
No, not at all. As Norma's future husband,
what I have to say concerns you, too.
Now, as Norma knows, she and I were named
joint heirs under the terms of her father's will.
And until she marries, I'm the executer of her estate.
But should anything happen to either of us...
Why, then, the survivor is the head of the entire estate.
And I think that you, Norma, and you, Jack,
as her future husband...
...should know of what that estate consists.
To that end, I have prepared a record of your estate's holdings.
And I want to talk it over with you both after dinner.
But your radiogram said there was something urgent.
Well, if it hadn't been urgent, I wouldn't have sent it.
Well, something's worrying you. What is it, Uncle Walter?
Well, perhaps I'm unduly alarmed, but...
Last night, I received this note of warning.
From the Gorilla.
The Gorilla?
You mean that murderer, the ones the papers
have been so full of?
I do.
Well, isn't it possible that this is all just a joke,
that someone's playing a prank on you?
I wish I could think so.
But, Uncle Walter, why should he or anyone want to kill you?
I don't know.
Oh, it's possible some old enemy of mine...
I bet I made enemies in my day...
It's possible that one of them in a spurt
of revenge has hired this maniac...
...this professional killer, or whatever the Gorilla is.
But this note is exactly like the one that was in the newspapers.
After he murdered that widow.
Still, I can't bring myself to believe it.
Of course, you've notified the police?
No, I haven't.
- But, surely, if there was anything in all this...
- I'm taking other precautions.
Peters and I are armed, and in addition, I've
engaged the services of a private detective agency.
Their operative should be here any moment now.
Well, obviously, this Gorilla is no ordinary murderer at all.
And judging by his past, shall we say, successes...
It is apparent the workings of the police
were a load of bullock to him.
Of course there's a slim chance that, by not
notifying the police, we might upset his plans.
Ordinarily, I'm not easily frightened, but...
I must admit this whole affair's giving me the creeps.
Well, it's nearly nine o'clock.
Now suppose you freshen up a bit.
We'll talk it over after dinner.
Oh, Kitty, show Denby to the green room,
and Mr. Marsden to my room.
- Yes, sir.
- Don't worry, Uncle Walter.
Oh, excuse me, Mr. Stevens.
- Yes, Kitty?
- Oh, I know it's customary to give notice...
Why, Kitty, you're not trying to tell me
you're going to leave me?
Oh, no, sir. I'm trying to tell you I have left you.
But, Kitty, you're perfectly safe here!
Besides, we have guests. You haven't the heart to leave me now!
Well, my heart is willing, but I'm gonna have
an awful time trying to convince
the rest of my body.
I'll bet there's a dead body in every room.
Dead body won't hurt you.
Can't do you any good.
Well? What are we waiting for?
Let's go.
- Who did it?
- You!
- Who's with it tonight, chief?
- Make a note, then.
Keep doing it every once in a while.
It keeps me on edge and thinking.
Right.
Now what do you suppose they want detectives for?
I've got an idea. Let's go in and find out.
You're terrific.
By George, it's Peters!
- Who are you?
- Me?
- Why, I'm Peters, sir.
- Nevermind that, nevermind that. What's
your name?
- Peters, sir.
- Just a minute, just a minute.
Where were you last night?
- I beg your pardon!
- Oh, so you did do something.
- I don't like your looks.
- What's that got to do with it? This is no
beauty contest.
- Who's Stevens?
- I am.
- I'm Harrigan.
- I'm Mulligan.
I'm Garrity.
Harrigan? Mulligan? Garrity?
I sent for you because I need protection.
- My life's been threatened.
- Now, tell me. Any clues?
One very vital one.
This warning from the Gorilla.
That's weird. You got nothing to worry about.
- Mark that down, Garrity.
- Right. How do you spell Gorilla? Two R's or two L's?
Gorilla? Gorilla...
G- O-R... G! G?
G- O... Oh!
Gori...?
Did you... did you...?
Did you say Gorilla?
Why, gentlemen, you're not afraid?
- Oh, no. No.
- No, we're not afraid. We just thought
maybe we...
- Thank you.
- The Gorilla coming here?
- It was nice to have met you, Mr. Stevens.
- Quiet!
Quiet!
Ah, yes.
I've already taken the precaution
of arming my servant and myself.
And I think you'll find every door
and window securely bolted.
I couldn't've done better myself.
With that sort of job, Mr. Stevens, you've
got nothing to worry about.
- What's your plan, Mr. Harrigan?
- Well, first we'll take a look around the house.
Come on, men.
Now, you just sit tight, Mr. Stevens.
The Gorilla will get you over our dead bodies.
- Jack?
- Yes, darling?
- Who were those men?
- Probably the detectives your uncle hired.
Jack, I'm terribly worried. What are we going to do?
Well, it seems there isn't anything we can do yet.
Listen, darling. It isn't that I'm trying to appear
skeptical. It's just that, well...
Somehow I can't make myself believe all this.
But that note! You saw the note.
Of course I did. But, still, I...
Look, darling. We'll wait.
We'll wait and see if something really does happen.
But what if it does?
I just don't believe it will.
Jack!
Excuse me, sir. I try to put your car away.
But unfortunately, there's something wrong with it.
What do you mean?
It won't start.
Excuse me, sir.
He gives me the creeps.
He doesn't exactly give me an appetite either.
But I wouldn't let him worry you if I were you.
Honestly, darling, don't you think there's any cause for alarm?
I'm afraid I don't.
Oh, there you are. Have a sherry before dinner?
Thank you, no.
Uncle Walter, how long have you had that butler?
Not very long. Why?
Well, are you sure he's alright?
I've found him so. Why?
Well, because I...
Dinner is served, sir.
Oh. Shall we go in?
You'd better drink a little of that, Kitty.
It'll quiet your nerves.
Why? Can you hear them?
Oh, here, take it.
What my nerves really need is a good, long trip!
Here!
Now, look here, where were you last night?
- Me? Why, I...
- Answer yes or no!
- I was...
- What were you doing there?
- Doing where?
- Well, how do we know?
Besides, I don't like your looks.
Did you ever take a good look at yourself?
- Yeah!
- Yeah, did you ever take a look...?
Here, now wait a minute, you. Where were you last night?
I spent the night with Shakespeare.
Yeah? Where is he?
He's dead.
Dead!
A murder mystery!
Have any idea who did it?
Look, Shakespeare's been dead hundreds of years!
Hundreds of...? This is a fine time to
call us in on the case.
Say, but she couldn't've done it.
- How do you know?
- She can't be hundreds of years old.
That's write. Mark that down, Garrity.
Yeah, what do we do now, chief?
Well, you two have a look out there. I'll look here.
- Yeah.
What's this?
That's a door.
It leads to the back stairs.
Back stairs?
Well, remind me to have a look up there sometime.
That's an ironing board.
Yes.
It's an ironing board.
- Look, do you want this thing?
- Certainly we want it. Why do you think we iron on it?
Well, I...
Well, here, take it!
Garrity! Garrity! Garrity!
Come in here! We found it!
- You found what?
- The mystery.
- Well, that's hash.
- Ain't that a mystery?
- Some very good turkey, chief.
- I'll be the judge o' that.
I'm afraid, gentlemen, you won't find the Gorilla in there.
Why will we not find the Gorilla in there?
Now, listen you! I've had...!
Let that be a lesson to you.
Perhaps you gentlemen had better look
outside for clues.
Maybe he killed Shakespeare.
Mark that down, Garrity.
Yeah.
Look, how do you get out of here?
That's what I'd like to know.
- Where's the back door?
- In back of you.
In back of me?
Don't you recall that the paper said the Gorilla always
sends a warning to as many as half a dozen people at the same time?
To sorta throw the police off.
Maybe that's what he's doing now.
Perhaps it's just a ruse.
Well, let's hope so.
You know, it's wonderful how much more optimistic
a good dinner can make one feel.
Shall we have licueurs in the study?
- Walter!
- Peters, Peters, a light, quickly!
Jack!
What is it? What happened?
Oh, uncle, are you hurt?
Why, no. No.
I don't know what happened.
- Look here.
- It seems to have been thrown in, through that window.
Oh, Uncle Walter!
What are we going to do?
The first thing you're going to do, or
rather Jack is going to do...
Is to take you away from here.
But you're coming with us.
It's him! It's him!
Uncle Walter!
Who is it?
Oh! It's alright. It's one of those detectives.
He did give me a turn!
Did you see that face?
I bet when he gets drunk, snakes see him.
What's the matter with you, scaring us half to death?
I'm just trying to let you know I'm not the Gorilla!
This is my niece, Ms. Denby, and her fiancée, Mr. Marsden.
Harrigan, Mulligan and Garrity.
This seems to be a bit more serious than I thought.
I just received this from the Gorilla.
A note. Who brought it?
No one brought it. It was thrown in through that window.
Through that window? Ha, through that window!
- He's right!
- Wait a minute.
This is my good ear.
Oh, say, that's right! You can't kid us!
We were outside patrolling the grounds!
What do you mean?
Why, the note couldn't have come through that window.
- Why not?
- Well, I'll just show you. Stand back, ma'am.
- That's why.
- But it was wrapped around a stone.
It was... a stone?
Well, why didn't you say so?
Anyway, what do you know about this thing?
Well, I don't know anything about it. We were
preparing to leave the room...
...and suddenly the lights went out and...
...then there was a crash and...
So the lights went out, eh?
- Make a note o' that, Garrity.
- Fine.
You were outside a few minutes ago. Didn't you see anybody?
Nobody but us. Say, this note says at midnight.
- At midnight?
- Yeah.
What time's it now?
- It's 10:30.
- I got 11:10.
I got 11:30.
It is exactly 11:45.
Remind me to put some hands on this watch.
- Yes. Well, make a note o' that, Garrity.
- Right.
Now, look. The Gorilla's after Stevens. We'll have
to keep an eye on 'em. Everybody, into the study.
Come on, let's go.
Who said that if you give a criminal enough rope, he'll hang himself?
- You, chief!
- Oh, that's where I heard it before.
Come on.
Now that you're all here, I don't want anybody to move, understand?
Is it alright if I breathe?
Yes, but come right back.
- Quiet!
- Personally, I don't believe the Gorilla's coming here.
Neither do I.
Why not?
I'll give you three good reasons, pal.
Harrigan, Mulligan and Garrity.
It ain't enough.
Now, look here!
- I don't wanna have no
... Now, wait a minute. I'll handle this.
- Yeah, but you always...
- Yeah, but you...
You've received the Gorilla's warning, Walter Stevens.
You've just five minutes to live.
Oh, Uncle Walter! Jack...
- Excuse me.
- Here, here, here. Now where you going?
- I'm getting out of here.
- There's no door there!
Well, that's alright. I'll make one.
Quiet, quiet everybody!
Did you hear that?
I wish I didn't.
He's up there, men!
- Where you going?
- I say, he's up there!
That's what I thought you said.
Quiet.
Alright, men. Follow me!
Stick 'em up! I got you covered!
- What happened? What was it?
- Nothing. Nothing at all.
Hey! Did you just pass here?
Yes. Yes, of course. I brought the trunk down from the attic.
- A trunk?
- Yes.
Were we here?
I couldn't say.
Well, maybe we're not here now.
Maybe.
May...
It's two minutes of twelve. What about Uncle Walter?
Uncle Walter, yes... Uncle Walter, we've...
Just going in here... We'll...
Now, everybody!
Stay just where you are.
Mulligan, you watch those doors. Garrity, you watch that one.
Mr. Stevens, you've... got nothing to worry about.
I wish I thought so.
Me, too.
You have one more minute, Walter Stevens.
I can't stand it any longer! I can't!
You've got to call the police! You've got to!
Mr. Stevens, I'm sorry, but Norma's right.
I don't know what this is all about, but certainly if
there's something to it, the police oughtta know about it.
I no longer know what to think.
Perhaps you'd better.
Hello? Hello?
The phone, there's something wrong with it!
Mulligan, Garrity, it's me!
Uncle Walter! He's gone!
Gone? How can he be gone when every door
and window in this room has been locked?
Mulligan, check those windows! Garrity, check that door!
How did you get in here?
Why, through this door, sir.
How can you when the doors are locked?
- I beg your pardon, it was not locked.
- I locked it myself.
- It is locked.
- That leaves us deadlocked.
It would be impossible for me to walk through the woodwork.
Why? Termites do.
Oh, this isn't getting us anywhere!
Now, leave everything to me!
Gorilla ain't gonna make a monkey out of me.
Now, you...
Come on, boys.
- Where do these stairs lead to?
- To the bedroom.
Mulligan, Garrity, you have a look upstairs.
Marsden, you come with me and we'll
have a look around the grounds.
You two to the servants' wing.
With the Gorilla prowling around? Not me!
Well, alright, then, come with me!
Oh, nevermind. I'll take my chances with the other Gorilla.
But, wait a minute. We can't leave Ms. Denby here alone.
- Well, what are you waiting for?
- I don't know, but I wish I could think of something.
- Me, too.
- Oh, go on!
- Don't worry, darling.
- Oh, that's alright. I'll do all the worrying.
Marsden, come with me.
Oh, you first, sir.
Thank you very much.
Why couldn't this've all happened tomorrow?
What difference would that make?
Tomorrow's my day off.
Poor Uncle Walter.
Right from under our very eyes!
I don't understand how he got out of here.
All that's worrying me is how I'm gonna get outta here.
Oh, it's him, it's him!
I seen 'em! I seen 'em! It's the Gorilla! I seen 'em!
- What's up?
- It's the Gorilla! I tell you! He's in the closet there!
Oh, Jack, I'm so frightened!
- Come outta there, you.
- Get 'em, Mulligan.
- You heard him, Garrity.
- What did he say?
Are you sure it wasn't a hallucination?
Not unless a hallucination has hair on it.
Come on.
- Now, ready?
- Yeah, yeah.
Is he dead?
- Who's he?
- I've never seen him before.
- Do you know him?
- No, sir. And this is no time for no introductions.
He's not dead.
- Mark that down, too.
- Right.
Come on, darling. We're getting out of here.
I'm afraid now, too. For you!
And I'm afraid now, too, for me!
Oh, Jack, it's horrible.
I don't know what to make of it.
All I can say is the Gorilla's around here somewhere!
And I know Mr. Stevens is around here somewhere!
And if you all look, we'll find 'em somewhere!
- Where you going?
- Somewhere!
Alright, men. Take 'em upstairs.
- Come on, Garrity.
- You! Lead the way.
I'll take care of 'em. Kitty, get a basin of hot water.
Do you mind if I go outta town to get it?
You and I have a look around the house.
Wait a minute. There's something funny about this.
Kitty said she saw the Gorilla's arm.
We open the closet and find the sailor's body.
Now, how did the body get in there?
And how'd the Gorilla get out without our seeing him?
That's just what I was about to ask you.
Stevens was sitting right here in this chair until
the lights went out.
Gorilla? Night-night!
That's funny.
What's funny?
Nothing. I think I'll have a look around this house.
Have a look around the house?
Yes... and have a look around the house.
Yes. I'll go, too.
Hey, that guy won't talk.
- Why not?
- He's still unconscious.
You're unconscious and you talk.
- Hey, that's great, chief.
- Mark that down, Garrity.
- Right.
- What do we do now?
Well, first we'll have to reenact the crime.
So how do we do that?
Now, let's see. When the lights went out,
Stevens was sitting in that chair.
You're Stevens. Sit down.
- I'm Stevens.
- Mulligan, close the doors.
Hey! I'm Garrity!
You're Stevens! Now sit down!
I'll work the lights.
One, two, three.
Ah, it's no use.
I don't know. It works for Sherlock Holmes.
I don't know why it won't work for me!
That's what I've been trying to tell you.
- He's gone.
- He's gone?
Gone... Garrity!
Garrity!
Now we have two mysteries to solve.
- Look, I've got an idea.
- What is it?
If we can find out how Garrity disappeared,
we'll find out what happened to Stevens.
That's a very good idea.
Shoulda thought o' that myself.
Alright, we'll reenact the crime. Sit down.
- But I'm not tired.
- Do you have to be tired to sit down?
I do.
You make me tired!
Well, then, why don't you sit down?
If I sit down, who's gonna work the lights?
- I never thought o' that.
- Yeah, well, sit down.
- Yeah, sit down.
- Sit down...
One... two... three!
Mulligan!
Did you lose something?
Yes, Mulligan and Garrity!
Go over there.
Now, look. Sit down.
Oh, I don't wanna sit down.
You don't have to want to! You'll sit down and like it!
Oh, alright. I'll sit down but I won't like it.
What're you gonna do?
What I'm gonna do ain't important.
Well, what am I gonna do?
That's just what I wanna find out.
One...
Two...
Two and a... two.
Three!
Did I hear somebody scream?
Well, if you didn't, you ought to have your ears cleaned out!
Say, where's Mr. Harrigan?
The detective! He's disappeared!
Disappeared? What a pity.
Pity? Why, it's entirely...
How did you get in here?
We... Why, you're...
Don't be frightened. You're safe with me.
Safe with you, I?
Who wants to be safe?
Now, look. I'm very sociable.
I wanna go where there's people!
Hey, what's the matter? What's happened?
Look, I'm standing here, and all of a sudden...
Everything goes black.
Next thing I know, I'm here.
That's funny.
Hello?
Hello, I'm sorry I kept you waiting.
No, no. You turn on Willow Drive.
Off Highway 22, and hurry, will you?
Thank you.
Look, it ain't human, I tell you.
It ain't human!
What isn't human?
For a guy to be standing here one minute...
...and the next minute, he's gone!
- Who's gone?
- I'm gone, they're gone, everybody's gone!
It don't make sense.
Certainly doesn't. Will you have a cigarette?
I don't mind if I do.
He takes us right from under his very eyes.
Who does?
The Gorilla!
Hey! Who are you?
What do you want?
What are you doing here?
Listen, man. You got me all wrong. I just came in
to use the telephone. You see, my car broke down and...
This phone?
Look, that phone is out of order.
- Is it?
- Yes.
Number, please?
Well, if you'll excuse me, I'll be on my way.
Now, wait a minute, you!
You're the guy we're looking for!
- You're the Gorilla!
- Surely you don't think I'm the Gorilla!
I stopped thinking two hours ago.
- But you don't understand!
- I don't have to understand!
- Shall I try?
- No, you've tried enough, not get 'em up!
Listen, you're making a big mistake.
Well, it won't be the first time.
No... alright...
Alright, I got you covered.
Help!
Shake 'em up... shake 'em up.
Oh, help.
Help!
Help me!
What's the matter? What is it?
I got 'em, I got 'em. I tell you, I got 'em!
- Got 'em, where?
- Yes, he... Well, I did have 'em.
Here, get me outta these.
Keys are in my pocket.
They're right there.
Oh, it was terrible. The Gorilla, the Gorilla!
How'd you get all tied up like this?
The Gorilla, I tell you. It wasn't my fault.
He came in and hit me.
It was... Did I leave him in there?
I'm Stevens...
Wait a minute! How'd you fellows get in there?
You tell me. What're you doing with those things on?
Oh, look. A fellow walks right in.
It was the Gorilla, I tell you!
- Yeah?
- And starts to use that phone!
But he didn't get very far, not with me on the job.
Lucky thing for him you had your handcuffs with you.
Where is he? Where'd he go?
See, I'm the victim. How should I know?
Look, boys, I'm telling you, he walked in,
six of 'em. Six big gorillas, they attacked me...
Hit me right on my crown. Look at that lump.
Yeah, look at this lump.
Right there.
These windows are locked.
From the inside.
You're not kidding.
Kidding? With the Gorilla right under my nose
and a ten thousand dollar reward, he says I'm kidding!
Well, are you?
Who belongs to this?
What is it?
- Coat.
- Why, gorillas don't wear coats.
Sure, they do. Fur coats.
There's something screwy about all this.
Look, if there's anything screwy about this...
...it's me.
It's me!
But I'll soon find out. Each of you grab a wall.
What do we do with it?
Mulligan, you take that one.
Marsden, you take that one.
- I'll take that one.
- I'll sit this one out.
You won't sit anyone out! Grab it!
Now, take it easy.
Alright, now tap, each one of you.
See if you can find some trap doors.
Oh, must be out there. Come on, men, right out here.
Alright, cover the door, men.
What's the matter with all of you? I've been pounding on that door for the last ten minutes!
- Who are you?
- That's right. Who are you?
Nevermind who I am. I wanna know where Walter Stevens is.
Oh, you want to know where Mr. Stevens is, eh?
He wants to know where Walter Stevens is!
Who do you think we're looking for?
I didn't come here to play games.
I wanna see Walter Stevens and I wanna see 'em right now!
You don't understand. These gentlemen are detectives.
Detectives, bah! What are you trying to pull on me?
I talked to Stevens on the telephone last night.
He told me he had a plan to pay his debt.
- Plan?
- Yes, said he'd only just started working on it.
Well, did he tell you what this plan is?
I wasn't interested.
He wants to square up with me here tonight!
When I talked to him, he wanted a couple
of days more to raise the money that he owes me!
Now where is he?
Well, Mr. Stevens' been kidnapped by the Gorilla!
Kidnapped by... Poppycock!
Now, look here! I don't know who any of you are!
But I do know this. Walter Stevens owes
me two hundred and fifty thousand dollars!
And I'm going to collect it! Tonight! Or else!
- Now, wait a minute.
- Don't, buddy.
How do we know you're... Say, who are you, anyway?
I'm one of Stevens' clients.
I have proof that Stevens has been stealing from
his clients' accounts for over a year.
I gave him until tonight to return my money.
And I'm not going to leave this house until I get it.
Yeah, but wait a minute, wait a minute...
I think he's mad.
Jack! If what that man says is true...
- I don't believe Uncle Walter could...
- It's almost impossible to know what to believe, darling.
Yet things are adding up. If your uncle did have a plan,
if this business of sending for you was part of the plan...
Take her upstairs and keep an eye on her. This has gone far enough!
- It's gone too far!
- It's even gone farther than that.
I'll be alright. It's just too much excitement for one night.
Get your hat and coat, darling. I'm gonna see that
you get to town if I have to push the car all the way myself.
I can't go til we find Uncle Walter.
We'll take care o' that. We'll break this case, won't we, boys?
- Won't we?
- Oh, sure we will! Sure!
Like it was walnuts.
- You know, I feel sorry for that poor girl.
- Yeah? What about poor us?
Strange men zooming in an out. Animals running
around like this was a zoo!
Crazy goes on! I wanna go home.
Oh, so you wanna go home? I'm ashamed of you.
I'm ashamed of you!
You wanna take a run off and leave
that girl here to take the blame alone?
- We're detectives, aren't we?
- Are we?
Haven't we looked all over this house?
- Yes.
- No.
- Where haven't we looked?
- Well, if there's a cellar, we haven't looked there.
- I'm glad I thought o' that.
- Say, this looks like a cellar.
Where?
- It's locked.
- Well, try your key.
Oh, yes, never thought o' that.
Alright, come on, men.
- Anybody down there?
- Uh, yes. We are.
- Now, look for a switch.
- It's around here somewhere.
Alright, come on outta there, you.
Come on. Get outta there.
Alright, come on...
Alright, come on outta there!
Mulligan?
- Where are you?
- I'm right here, chief.
Garrity, where are you?
Over here, chief.
Is anybody with me?
No, you're alone.
Mulligan, Harrigan! Something bit me!
What? First time I saw a mousetrap catch a piece o' cheese.
Harrigan! Garrity! Please get me outta this!
Get me outta this thing!
- Maybe you'd like a ride.
- Oh, come on, Garrity...
Garrity! Harrigan!
Now, don't worry. I'll handle this.
- It's a pleasure.
- Yeah, don't worry about it.
Okay, buddy. Come on, bud. Get that raccoon coat off.
Come on! Get that thing off!
Want me to hit you over the head with this thing?
Well...
We've been double-crossed!
Let's get outta here!
- Peters?
- Yes, sir?
What's all that commotion?
Sounds like our friends, the detectives.
You stay here with Ms. Denby.
I'll go see what's up.
Cognac, Ms. Denby?
No. No, thank you.
What's the matter? What's all the racket?
I got him, I tell you! I got him!
You got him? Got who?
- Yes, the Gorilla! He's in there!
- He's in there!
- I can hear him breathe!
- That's you.
Well, open it, open it!
Have you men been drinking?
No, but it's a good idea.
What was that?
- Norma, what's happening?
- It's the Gorilla!
Norma, where are you?
Jack!
A couple o' you get after 'em, quick!
- You heard 'em, Mulligan.
- So did you.
Nevermind, then. You take the hall. I'll go this way.
I'll stay here.
- Is something wrong?
- Where were you?
- I just went to get some tea, sir.
- Didn't I tell you to stay here with Ms. Denby?
I'm very sorry, sir. But I thought that perhaps
a little tea...
What right have you got to think? We're not even thinking!
Ms. Denby might've been killed.
It's fortunate she wasn't, sir.
Why is it that something always happens when you're not here?
An unfortunate coincidence, sir.
- What did you find?
- An empty closet with Harrigan in it.
- Harrigan, Harrigan, Harrigan! Wake up.
- Get up.
- Wake up.
- The Gorilla, the Gorilla!
Did you get him? Did you get him?
- No, he got you.
- Well, it won't happen again.
- Okay, men. Follow me.
- Okay.
Follow me.
Go down and see where these stairs lead to.
- Who, me?
- Yes, you.
- Oh, me!
- It's awful dark. I shoulda brung my glasses.
- You never wore any glasses.
- That's right. I forgot.
- What's that funny tapping?
- Yeah!
It's my knees.
It's a fine time to be scared!
- You try and think of a better time.
- Yeah, well...
Look, look.
I've had about enough o' this!
Me and the Gorilla's gonna have a showdown right now!
- That's right, chief.
- I'm telling you I can't stand it!
Now, don't argue with me!
I know what I'm talking about!
I'm going in there, and we'll look over this house.
And he'll take orders from me, understand?
I'm gonna tear this house apart!
Tear it limb from limb!
Now, come on, follow me!
I'll show this monk who's a monk!
You fellows stay close behind me.
If anything happens, leave it to me.
I'll do all the talking.
Come on, men.
People here running here to there all day.
All day long. I've never seen anything like this in all my life.
First... Hey, where are you going?
What's eating you?
What've you got there?
That dame musta saw something or she wouldn't
be running away like that.
Make a note o' that, Garrity.
Garrity! Mulligan!
- Good evening.
- Good evening...
- What do you want?
- Don't be frightened.
Frightened? Who's frightened?
Don't you come near me! I'll wrap this
thing around your neck like it was a pretzel!
- There's nothing to worry about.
- That's what you think.
- May I give you some advice?
- No!
If I were you, I'd go to my room and stay there.
Why, yes, sir. I was just planning on that!
Wait a minute. Where have you been?
No place. Honest, sir! I was just getting
ready to go to town!
- Good.
- Don't open that!
- Why not?
- The Gorilla! He's in there!
Don't be silly.
- Get going now. Get going.
- Yes, sir. I'm practically there!
That ain't a man. It's a gorilla. We saw it and we felt it!
I tell you, the Gorilla is a man. I ought to know.
I've read enough about him.
But how could a monkey possibly have
written those notes to Uncle Walter?
Maybe it's got an education.
Poe! Poe!
Poe! Where is he, have any o' you seen him?
- Who?
- Poe.
- Who's Poe?
- Poe's the gorilla.
- The Gorilla?
- Oh, you know 'em, too, eh?
Know 'em? I trained 'em since he was that high.
You're just the one we're looking for.
Don't any of you understand? Poe is a gorilla, a trained gorilla.
- A real gorilla?
- Sure, a real gorilla.
Well, so we don't know what we're talking about, eh?
Yeah, we know a monkey when we see one.
Listen, this is serious. Poe ain't no pet.
There's no telling what he's liable to do when I ain't around.
'Specially with women. He hates women.
Well, what's he doing here? What're you doing here?
We was hired to come here. We're working at the County Fair.
Yesterday, a guy comes along, says
he wants me to bring Poe here.
He says he's giving a party, wants us to put on our act.
- Who hired you?
- I don't know. I don't know nothing.
All I know is I bring Poe here, we're waiting
out in the garage like he tells me.
Waiting to do our stuff.
All of a sudden, somebody gives me a clunk over
the head and I wake up in a lady's boudoir.
But the gorilla... how'd he get loose?
You're asking me! That's what I wanna find out.
Listen, this is serious. We gotta find 'em.
We gotta. Somebody's liable to get killed.
The note from the Gorilla!
Fall against your fifty they were addressed to me!
Notes? Poe can't write no notes!
Even I don't know how to write.
Now, look. The next time I buck up against that gorilla...
I'm telling you, I'll...
Well, I'll...
He'll never know!
He'll do it!
- Listen, have you seen 'em?
- Yes, he's in the kitchen.
- Which way is the kitchen?
- Through the panel.
We'll go with you.
Listen, you fellows better wait here. There's
no telling what that ape'll do.
Oh, Jack, I'm so confused.
A real gorilla, and those notes, and...
Listen to me, everybody.
The Gorilla has done his work.
Walter Stevens is dead.
You will find his body in the garage.
Oh, Jack!
Alright, everybody. Follow me to the garage!
Come on.
- Come on.
He's gone! Poe's gone!
- I tell you, he's in the kitchen!
- The kitchen's a wreck. He must be on a rampage!
Outta my way, brother. I got my own
troubles to worry about.
Alright, all of you! Out in the garage! Come on!
I'll stay here and protect Ms. Denby.
This way, please.
I'll never forgive myself for not calling the police.
Why call the police with us around, lady?
You couldn't save Uncle Walter.
We couldn't, eh?
- Well, you didn't, did you?
- Well, we...
That's right, we didn't.
I gotta find out how that gorilla gets in and outta here.
There must be a secret spring around here someplace.
I think I'll look in back o' these books.
Help!
Somebody! Get me outta here somebody!
Don't tell me she's the Gorilla!
I told you I didn't like her looks.
- Oh, wise guy!
- Come on, we gotta find the body.
- What'd I do with them keys?
- Look under the mat.
- That's funny!
- Oh, very funny. Will you get me out of here?
Listen, what're you doing in Poe's cage?
What do you think I'm doing, waiting for
somebody to feed me peanuts?
Get me outta here!
Don't you know Poe hates women?
So does Kipling. So what? Will you please
get me out of here?
Alright, don't get excited.
Say, wait a minute. I think this was a trick
to get us outta the house.
Come on.
- Who are you anyway?
- I'm the gorilla's keeper!
- Are you the one that gave me the clunk on the head?
- No, but it was a good idea.
Oh, yeah?
Look!
- He's got her!
- Don't talk! He'll drop her!
Poe! Bring her down, Poe!
Bring her down to me!
Down, Poe! Down to the ground!
Put her down, Poe!
Poe! Stop it, Poe!
Bring her down, Poe!
Bring her down to me!
Put her down, Poe.
Come on.
Poe, Poe, come back here! Help me catch him!
Oh, thank you, thank you.
He hit me again!
Right here, he hit...
Poe! Let him alone!
That's a fine way to treat me.
After I give you the best years of my life.
You act like that... Listen here.
No, no. No kisses.
He might have killed somebody!
What do you mean, might have?
That's alright, lady. I got him.
You can keep him!
Okay. Scram, but take this
character with you.
I was only kidding.
Just for that, he gets no c-a-n-d-y.
Oh, well, that's just c-a-n-d-y.
Sorry if I caused you any trouble, folks.
Yeah, and just for that, I won't
read you the funny papers tonight.
Put you in bed without any supper, you bad boy.
You wait'll I get you home!
You have heard the last of this!
Come on!
Look at that.
Why, it's somebody's coat!
Alright, come on outta there, buddy.
So that's how I got clunked on the head.
Come on, come on outta there, you!
Look! It's opening!
Come on, come on...
Oh, so it's you!
- Do you know him?
- Do I know him? He's the guy I caught
using the telephone!
- There's no law against that.
- Nevermind law, buddy. Get 'em up.
Now, just a minute. Don't you think you're
a little premature?
Prema... Well, I can't remember that far back.
Just who are you?
I'm Detective Kletty.
An investigator for the Securities
and Exchange Commission.
And I'm on the trail of the Gorilla, just as you are.
- A detective?
- How do we know that?
Yes, we...
Yeah, well, what were you doing in there?
Investigating. I've been on this case for some weeks now.
And I've discovered a little about
the construction of this house...
...that my good friend here don't seem
to have found out yet.
What do you mean?
This house is a maze of secret panels.
Now, undoubtedly, the voice of the Gorilla came
through that radio from someplace right in this house.
That means that if we find the wire leading away
from the radio...
We'd at least find the Gorilla's hideout!
And what's going on here!
Well, here it is. Here's the wire going right in here.
It's found.
Now, let's see...
Just as I thought!
Here's the wire!
Now, by tracing this, I think we may find
the answer to this entire riddle.
The wire goes in here.
Back of this wall is the man we want.
Now, make a note o' that, Garr...
- Are you all armed?
- Yes, I'm armed.
Quiet, you!
Here it is.
There's your microphone, and as I expected,
there's your Gorilla.
Mr. Stevens, the Gorilla?
Why, sure, I could have told you that all the time!
I guess the party's over, my Gorilla friend.
Yeah, but who tied 'em up like that?
I don't know. He figured the game was
up and that this would throw off suspicion.
This is a homemade job. A child could've done it.
Ah, proposterous! Don't believe him!
I never saw this man before in my life! He's insane!
Now, what's that?
Why is it, with all the men in the house, they have to
leave us here with you?
Quiet!
Why, it's Mr. Stevens!
- Alias, the Gorilla.
- The Gorilla?
Him?
Oh, I'll never trust another man if I live to be a thousand!
You can make that two thousand.
Uncle Walter, the Gorilla?
I don't believe it!
I think I can make it very clear.
- Oh, sure we can!
- Now, first of all...
- What's that?
- I didn't hear a thing!
Neither did I, but what was it?
We'll soon find out.
Hey, what is this?
Who hit me?
What's going on around here?
- It's that man again.
- Oh, there you are!
Kidnapped! Kidnapped by the Gorilla!
- Not kidnapped by the Gorilla, Mister...
- Conway. A.P. Conway.
Ah, the A.P. stands for ape!
Mr. Conway, this gentleman is the Gorilla!
- The Gorilla?
- But if Uncle Walter's the Gorilla...
...I don't understand why he should send
himself those notes of warning.
For two reasons!
To keep you here and to throw off
suspicion from himself.
Ms. Denby, under the terms of your father's will,
if anything were to happen to you...
...who would inherit your estate?
Uncle Walter.
My hunch was right.
Your uncle brought you here tonight
to kill you for your money.
Well, at least he had a reason!
So that's why he wouldn't let us call the police.
That's exactly why.
But what about these men, these private detectives?
They almost speak for themselves.
Do you think if Stevens life had actually
been threatened...
...he would've called in three morons such
as these for protection?
- Protection...
- Morons!
Hey! Wait a minute, I resent that!
But I tell you, I saw the Gorilla! Right there in that closet!
I saw his hand, then his arm...
And it was no optical confusion!
What you saw was this sleeve!
Another ingenious little invention of Mr. Stevens.
A very cute little idea!
Well, that about clears the whole matter up.
And since it's stopped raining, I think I better go.
- You're okay, buddy!
- You're okay!
Congratulations! Let me congratulate you! You were wonderful!
Oh, no you don't, buddy! Okay, folks.
Say howdy to the Gorilla!
- Howdy.
- Alright, give out or this moron is gonna blow
your brains out.
Well, you see...
Now, all of you stick your hands up.
I'm the Gorilla, alright.
But the cops haven't been able to get me, so don't
you halfwits get any crazy notions.
And as for Mr. Stevens, he's just as
crooked as I told you he was.
The trouble with him is he talks too much and too loud.
I got tipped off on what was gonna
happen here tonight.
How he was gonna pretend to be me!
How he was gonna get the two hundred and
fifty thousand dollars and at the same time...
...let him get the blame for all the Gorilla murders.
We were careful.
I'm a little nervous tonight.
Drop that gun. And I advise you not to move.
Hello? Police station, quickly.
What is this? I thought the phone was out of order!
- Maybe he paid his bill.
- Hello?
This is Walter Stevens speaking.
Send a squad car to my house.
We've got the Gorilla.
Things are so mixed-up around here that
even the Gorilla doesn't know who the Gorilla is!
He's the Gorilla, he's the Gorilla.
Do I know what I'm doing?
Look, what's going on here?
Don't look so sad, darling. Your uncle isn't a crook!
The estate's all safe and sound now.
You know, you never can tell. This is liable
to wind up to be a mystery!
You see, the Gorilla murders were threatening
to bankrupt our insurance company.
Most of the victims were clients of ours.
So Conway, our special investigator, cooked up
his little scheme to trap the killer.
I'm sorry I had to frighten you, dear.
- And you, too, Kitty.
- Oh, I wasn't frightened. I was numb.
You fellows are certainly great detectives.
- Oh, yes.
- We could have told you that!
Did you know that Kletty was the Gorilla all along?
- Sure we did!
- No, we didn't.
When did you find out he was the Gorilla?
When I shook hands with him.
- I don't get you.
- Well, you see, I was a window trimmer.
In a department store.
And I oughtta know a phony feel when I feel one.
We'll never be able to thank you, Mr. Harrigan.
Oh, well, that's alright. I understand you two
are getting married soon.
Well, if you call tomorrow soon...
Well, remember, if you have any trouble with her,
our specialty is following wives!
You know where to send the check.
And be sure it's certified.
From a detective's bank.
- Bye.