Hi Frankie.
Hello.
Get in here.
Nothing like that first drink of the day
Go on, drink up! Enjoy
They tell me, you're quite a dancer?
Well how about a dance anyway?
No?
Hey give them back. What's the big idea?
Frankie...
Frankie, when did you get back?
How are you?
You all right? You know.....
- The monkey is gone.
- Let me look at you.
- Not even a postie card.
- You can't read anyway.
- You're good at drawing pictures.
- Oh, you goof-ball.
How's the lost dog business?
As soon as they see me walking around,
people start locking up their mutts.
I tell you folks just don't have that
trust in their fellow man anymore.
- Hey Antic, look who's out.
- Frankie!
- You all right? Good kid.
- Enough already, buy me a drink.
- Look what the cat dragged in.
- Frankie!
You've been gone so long, I thought
maybe you'd been made warden.
- Well you're looking good.
- Put on 6 pounds.
6 pounds!
He's been gone so long, I thought
maybe he'd been made warden.
- How was it down there Frankie?
- Greatest place you've ever seen.
I知 telling ya, ball games, great food.
I even learned how to play the drums.
You make it sound as
if I missed something by
not going to jail years
ago. It's a prison, no?
More of a hospital kind.
Let me show you something.
Ah, Federal Pens is always best.
Ask anybody.
He's been gone so long, I
think he's been made warden.
Ever see anything so pretty.
- Don't touch!
- Hey, how'd you sneak them out Frankie?
- Them guys gave them to me in the band.
- They let you have a band?
Yeah, I was in it. They chipped in
and bought me these when I left.
Long time. How was it there? Bad?
- lt wasn't bad.
- Six months. You could hardly wait, I bet?
- Come over to my place
- No thanks.
You broke? Now ain't you being stupid?
It's for free.
I don't need it, that's all. I kicked it.
Oh, kicked it?
- One of them.
- I mean it.
Sure
I'lll be around.
Frankie, don't do it. Don't start
up with that peddler again.
I'd rather chop my arm off,
before I'd let him touch it.
this Dr. Lennick who took care
of me down at the hospital,
real good guy he told
me at least 10 times....
He told me Frankie, you get out of here
and take one fix, you're hooked again.
Don't worry about me buddy boy
Let's get out of here. Thanks Antic.
Take care of the dog for me. I've
got a customer coming to get it.
- Don't let him give you no gas.
- Him? I ain't going to be around
here long enough to let him bother me.
- Don't let him give you no gas.
- Him? I ain't going to be around
here long enough to let him bother me.
- I知 going to get me a job in a big-name band.
- You're kidding?
What do you think I stretching
my wrist for buddy-o?
The guy that teaches drumming
down there, says I'm a natural.
I can't miss he says.
Arm's made of pure gold.
You mean a job winding these drums?
- I've got everything planned too.
Going to call myself Jack Duvall.
- Probably I ain't going to see
you around so much then, huh?
Maybe I can set something up for you.
Carrying the instruments or something.
- Traveling around the country high
-type night clubs.
- How does that sound to you?
- When is it going to be, when??
Right away, today. I知 the kind
of guy boy that when I move,
watch my smoke. But I知 going
to need some good clothes.
- Well you go on up. I知
going to find you some.
- Yeah, yeah, size 39.
- 39.
- Stripes.
Something nice.
You stop that noise! You and your
husband or I throw you both out.
Who is landlord? Me! You do as I say.
Your mother's eye socks, I do like you say!
Frankie...
You look great! How're ya
feeling Frankie? I mean....
- Fine, fine, just
fine. Hi ya landlord.
- She and husband fight all
the time. Holler throw things!
- Nothing changes.
- This is respectable house,
and I am respectable man!
Respectable my eye! Go on get out,
you're late for the parole board.
Frankie...
You're home.
Oh Frankie, I love you so much!
I've missed you so.
I've been so lonely Frankie, without you.
- I've been so lonely without you.
- Sssh, stop crying.
Let me look at you.
- My eyes are going to be all red.
- No, you look fine.
- ls the cold sore gone?
- Yeah, you look real good.
I've had this cold sore, and I wanted to
look real nice for you when you came back.
I was afraid that it wouldn't
be gone, so I put this cream on.
Everything is going to be all right..
Oh, you didn't see. Look, Vi
got the cake by the bakery,
but the sign I made. Sort
of like a welcome home.
Gee, it's like a real party or something.
Real nice.
- How are you Frankie?
- I知 clean.
Sure?
- I kicked it for keeps.
- Did it hurt?
How was it there for you?
They treated me fine down there.
There was this doctor, Dr. Lennex,
he was real good to me.
Frankie! Did you miss me?
Of course I missed you. What
kind of silly question is that?
Of course I missed you. Honest, no kidding.
- What have you got there?
- You'll see. Oh, I brought you something.
- Oh, it an exquisite thing.
- You like it? I made it myself,
out of cigarette wrappers.
It's just an exquisite thing, that's all.
- You made it? Yeah.
Yeah, for a hobby like.
You see part of the cure,
was to keep yourself busy,
doing things you enjoy
Like for instance, I wanted
to learn to drum and music.
And Dr. Lennex got
them to help me do it.
During the day I was kept busy
enough, but during the night I'd
get restless and I wanted to
keep my mind of the craving.
I made that.
- There's something important I've got to tell you.
- What?
I forget right now.
A whistle?
I was scared sometimes being alone.
So I got it for me and I should blow
for her when I wanted her
Go on, you were telling me.
The first thing you
do when you get there,
is you talk to a doctor
for about 2 hours.
I know! I know what it is. I
know what I wanted to tell you.
I took me to this movie
and the girl's kid brother
had a friend and who do
you think he looked like?
- Who?
- You!
That was a good movie.
Stage show was real good too.
We owe thy 80 cents for
the movie, I was broke.
We owe her for the cake too.
How come you didn't have any money?
Swrick didn't kick in regular?
- No.
- Well, he was suppose to.
lt was his joint they raided, not mine.
I was just the dealer.
I kept my mouth shut and took the rap.
- If he didn't send 50 a
month regular, how much did he?
- Well he sent 50, but not regular
See I had to kick in for me sometimes.
She took good care of you?
You had fun with her?
Yeah.....but not like when you're here.
lt was terrible being
alone Frankie... and my
legs when they hurt, she
don't massage like you.
- What do they say by the clinic?
- I stopped going by that goofy clinic.
The clinic must know
what right. You got to
start the clinic again.
You got to get well.
I dreamed that this new doctor
around the corner, he cured me.
I'd have gone to him already,
but he ain't free like the clinic.
But now you're back making
money again, and I'lll go.
I知 finished with Shrika. I
won't deal for him no more.
But you always deal. You're a dealer.
You're the best dealer in the business.
No more. I知 a drummer now..
- Don't make jokes Frankie. I
never know when you're making jokes.
- Who's joking? Listen.
Nice huh?
It's Dr. Lennex. I told him my whole
life story from when I was born, almost.
And about you and me. But he told me
that if I lived when I got out, like I
lived before I went in there, chances
are I would be hooked again in no time...
So that's why I want to get with a band.
Listen.
- How's that?
- Cute.
- What did you tell him about me, this doctor?
- I told
him about getting some
money and getting you well.
Then he said getting with a band
was a good way to go at it.
He even gave me the name of a guy
right here in town, to get a job.
I mean with this man, if he's
ever heard of this great doctor.
Most time these things
just don't come through.
- I got this.
- What is it?
It's a letter from the Doc.
- I think I'll go call him now
- Now? Let's talk about it tomorrow.
- You'll be all right.
- You've haven't even tasted the cake yet.
- I'lll only be a minute.
- I'lll be right up. No, now Frankie.
First, taste a piece of nice....cake.
- Hey, you coming baby?
- Yeah, I知 coming John.
- Molly!
I want to talk to Mr. Harry Lane, please.
- How about it huh?
- Machine, Mr. Frankie Machine.
Yeah, I've got a letter of
introduction for him. From Dr Lennex.
- Hello Frankie.
- Dr. Martin Lennex.
- How have you been Molly?
- Okay.
Come on baby, let's go.
A guy I met while you was away.
- Mr. Lane. I've got a letter for you.
- Come on, what do you say kiddo?
This afternoon huh? Well I sure do
appreciate it Mr. Lane, thank you very much.
Okay, good-bye.
Frankie! A new thing,
by Brax Department Store.
No sales girls, you just help yourself.
It's what they call an honor system.
What's the matter Frankie?
Feel that material.
And I figured, as long as I'm there....
Nice huh?
You all right? Frankie?
- I got the drummer job.
- Already? Wow!
When I move, I move like a streak.
Think it looks all right?
How come you ask me all of a sudden?
- I just want to know if
it looks all right Sash?
- And my name ain't Sash, it's Sophia.
What's the matter?
Nothing's the matter, 'cept how would
you feel if your spine was hurting?
- Why didn't you say so?
- On account of it being
your first day back, and
I didn't want you to worry.
- Don't be like that Sash.
- ls it bad? Maybe
the new doctor will do me some good huh?
- We'll go see him when I get back.
- Oh, take me now Frankie.
Sash, I've got this appointment.
You know how much it means to me..
We'll go as soon as I get back.
- Please Frankie.
- I'lll hurry.
- Well give me a little
more massage first then, huh?
- Sash, I知 doing this for you to get
some money so we can get you a good doctor.
- Frankie...
- Look, I'lll get you a dog
too. Get her a dog, will ya?
I'lll give the job
my personal attention.
Just have confidence in the management.
Wish me luck Sash.
Frankie!
Wait. Wait Frankie!
- Wishes or wants, what could I do?
- Yeah, she just don't realize.
- Shut up punk. Just don't realize. How
would you like to be nailed to a chair?
Frankie, Frankie, how are you? Well, it
didn't do you no harm, did it Frankie?
- You look good.
- That's right Shrika, it
was a real country club.
- They give you this
when they let you out?
- They didn't give him
nothing. I got it at Brax's.
I come as soon as I hear
you are out. I figured
you was worried about
getting this job again.
Don't worry. Shrika don't forget.
- Job's waiting.
- You need a dealer, you say?
Do you? No! I've been dealing myself and
I've built up a game
like nobody's business.
I've got a great following.
The play is bigger than ever.
- I hear that you wasn't doing so good.
- From who?
When I say "great", I don't
mean a lot, a few..loaded.
- So, what do you want me for?
- Like I知 telling you.
I take care of my friends.
Can I polish your halo
Shrika, only a quarter
Look, I've been doing all right.
But I don't say the customers
like me better than they like
you. The dealer makes the house.
- What do you say?
- No!
- You're dealing for some other joint?
- I ain't dealing
for nobody I ain't
dealing for nobody no more!
ls that the way you re-pay me?
Didn't I send money to Sash? Here,
I've gone and told all my friends
that you'd be working for me again.
What am I suppose to do?
As far as I'm concerned, you
can go back to matching
pennies with school kids.
Who is he?
- ls that a thing with them?
- They see each other.
You want to meet him?
- See ya Frankie.
Hey you...
- Get in dealer.
- Who me? What for?
- You too punk.
- I didn't do nothing.
Now wait, listen. I知
on my way to get a job.
It's important to me.
- You can pick me up some other time.
- I just need an hour
Are you looking at being
sued for liable or something.
I could sue you right now
- You're looking good
Dealer, real good.
- When did they let you out? Monday
- What's the charge?
- Shop lifting from Brax, this suit.
- Who told you a thing like that?
- A little birdie.
- A little bird with a cigar.
- Shrika.
ls that all you could stay out
of trouble, two days, dealer?
Listen, I got a chance at a job,
playing with a band. Honest, if
you don't believe me, call the
guy on the phone, he'll tell you..
- Just give me half hour, please.
- Sure, you can have my badge too.
- Book them and hold these two.
- Look, all I need is a half
hour Give me a break, will ya?
I don't make the rules dealer.
You can't hold me. I知
incapable. I ain't smart enough to
be running around loose, but
I知 too goofy to be locked up.
- Let go of the neck.
I've got a complaint.
Let go of the neck.
Hey you, I知 talking to you.
Oh the old silent treatment huh.
Let's have your number fella..
Frankie, you got a cigarette?
Do a cigarette trick, you know just
to break the dirty monotony.
Hello dealer. I come
running as soon as I heard.
You want I should get you out dealer?
The store will drop the
charges, but 37 bucks is
a lot of dough. How do
I know you'd pay me back?
- You fink! - ltd be different
if you was dealing for me.
- If you want to deal
for me, I can get you out.
- You dirty lousy, stool pigeon.
I don't know what you mean.
Just trying to do you a favor.
Yes, or no?
Okay...
He took off like a whipped dog.
He's scared of you Frankie.
- Nobody's ever been scared of me.
-Them Krautz
was scared of you. You
was a big man in the army.
Big man. I was the guy that picked
the fly spots out of the pepper.
Get me out!
Can you get me a fix?
- Big Ace's and here
we go down and dirty
- Better luck next time.
I'lll see that. Coffee!
Doesn't mean a thing,
unless you have the King.
Bet more, win more.
you still take tips dealer? Or
don't they pay in the music game?
What happened to that
big job you had lined up?
You stink out the joint?
Give us a fresh deck..
I decide when we need a
fresh deck at this table..
- Hey Louie. Borrow me a dirty dollar.
- Get back at the door, lame
-brain.
- I take orders only from Frankie.
- Don't give me lip
you cheap little hustler
Hustler? I知 legit
compared to some. Ain't no
14 year old junkies
waiting around to see me.
Do you want to die?
nd here we go, down and dirty
I'lll deal the next one down..
- Sorry.
- What's the sign of when a
dealer's hands begin to shake?
Take over for a while, will ya?
All right men, new deal.
Okay men, here we go, down and dirty
Ace.....seven.....
You know what's eating at you? You showed
up the mob, for kicking it for keeps.
So now you're ashamed to think,
well even what you think..
Ain't that right?
You know I don't talk about my
customers, so who'd be the wiser?
Why fight it dealer? Who, for what?
Come over to my place. What do you say?
I'lll be around.
They told me you was working
here, so I was passing
by and thought I'd come
in and have a drink..
- Well, I've been here awhile.
- Doing any good?
All right. Small cut of the
game, usual cut of the drinks.
- Ain't got all night.
- Right. Have something.
- Fine.
- Two doubles.
- You didn't have to do that Frankie.
- No reason you should be losing money
by wasting your time talking to me.
You know you're no waste.
I was hoping you'd come see me.
- You know how it is Molly.
- Sure, so busy now.
Here's to it Mollyo.
Mollyo. I haven't heard
that since you went away.
- You're looking good Frankie.
- Feel good.
- They tell me you're going to be a drummer now
- Yeah!
- I've got an appointment with a man tomorrow.
- Oh, that's swell.
- Probably I won't get the job though.
- Sure you will.
- I don't play good enough.
- I bet you play fine.
You were always whistling and drumming
on tables and things. Real good too.
I mean it! You've got a natural rhythm.
I was thinking, maybe of taking
a stage name. Jack Duvall.
- Jack Duvall, Yeah, that's real class.
- lt is, ain't it?
- That's a swell name.
lt fits you Frankie.
- This guy I知 going to see
tomorrow, he books all the big bands.
- If I get on with him and wear a tux.
- You look swell in a tux.
- I already got the drums.
- Pardon. I need a buck.
Ante up kid.
I got lonely..
I needed somebody and he's a poor
beat guy who needs somebody too.
Everybody needs somebody.
- But you can do better than him.
- Can I Frankie?
Molly I....
I thought a lot about you when I was
away About you and me and Sash.
lt would never work out
between you and me as
long as she is sitting
upstairs in that chair
ltd be different if she didn't love
me, and she wasn't so helpless.
You can't make a fool of someone if
they love you and they're so helpless.
That's why I didn't
come around sooner. And
that's why I ain't
coming around no more.
You understand?
Sure......sure I understand..
- You're a good girl Molly.
- ...real good.
Frankie...
Good luck with that fellow tomorrow
You're not the first to come to
me with a letter from Dr Lennex.
- I've taken care of a lot of you people.
- The doctor told me.
I like doing it, you
understand. So don't feel
that this is charity,
or anything like that.
- Have you played professionally before?
- Only down at Lexington.
I see, then you wouldn't
mind auditioning?
I mean I know some band leaders
who might have an opening, but they'd
have to be sure that you can play
- Oh sure, sure.
- Okay...
There's only one thing Frankie.
You see......
A good many people
like yourself, they mean
well, but they're
weak. They let me down.
I mean I go to all this trouble. Vouch
for them, and they go back on the habit.
- lt makes me look bad.
- Oh, I wouldn't honest!
I知 telling you this because, once a
man lets me down, I知 done with him.
Even if he comes back on his knees. And
don't think that some of them haven't.
- I wouldn't let you down Mr. Lane.
- Good!
I'lll call you a week from
Friday, about noon. Okay?
- I sure do appreciate it.
- Oh, forget it.
- Good-bye.
Do you like my hair better
this way, or swept up Frankie?
Well you could at least tell me.
lt ain't my fault he don't phone.
What did I say? Just
don't hold your breath
to hear from that guy,
that's what I said.
He told you noon. Here
it is almost 6 o'clock
already so how do you think he'll phone?
I just don't want you should
eat your heart out, is all.
Forget the whole thing
Frankie, I bet he has.
You think he's got nothing better
to do than to worry about you?
You think he don't sleep at nights
in account of Frankie Machine?
Ha!
Excuse me....
Hello. Oh, just a minute.
It's for you.
Hello..
- Are you Dr. Dominaski?
- Yes, I came as soon as I could.
Well, how you feel little lady?
- See, the doctor asks how I知 feeling.
- We'll have you feeling
fine in one, two, three.
What is this?
This happens to be an electric blood
reverser and spine manipulator.
- What's the gimmick?
- Gimmick?
lt so happens brother, that I am a
member of the American Association
of Medical Psychology, Hydrology and
Divine Healing. Where's the socket?
Cold hands.
Poor circulation. Eat lots of hot things.
Chilies, peppers, hot sauces.
- Pickles?
- Not more than 3 a day.
Now lean forward, and we'll
vibrate the vertebrates.
- Know how I got like I am? My
spine was hurt. Oh I can see that.
Your ligaments and vertebrates
are locked together.
ln a car accident it was hurt.
Three years ago, May 11th.
Maybe you read about it in the papers huh?
This is the car that it happened
in. That's me, laying there.
My husband was the one driving
the car and he was drunk.
- Drunk?
- He got me in this accident and smashed me up
good, so that I can't walk
anymore or dance anymore.
- And he married me right here, in the hospital chapel.
- Sash!
- Feeling a little better?
- Yeah, much better.
Hey Frankie, guess what?
I got that dog for Sash.
Free spirit! Every claw and hair on
him is a champion. Champion of what?
He brings back empties.
Here, I'lll show you.
He's all dog. You can make money out of him
Frankie.
What he's really good at,
is catching those squirrels
in the park, and shaking
the peanuts out of them.
Only thing he is trained to chase is a
certain kind of squirrels and they're getting
kind of rare in Chicago, because of the
climate changing. You know what I mean?
So he's just hanging around, waiting for
the climate to change back a little.
He's got a real fighting heart. He's
dizzy, but he still in there trying.
- Take the dog up to Sash.
- Frankie! You're not going with him!
No!
ln a minute dealer.
- Five bucks.
- Last time, it was two.
lt was more than 6 months
ago, before you went away..
They keep raising the price on me.
If they keep doing that, I'lll have
to find something to take its place.
The monkey's never dead dealer.
The monkey never dies.
When you kick him off, he just hides
in a corner, waiting his turn.
The monkey will die waiting. He ain't
climbing up on my back no more.
Never again. I mean it.
Sure.....
Look Frankie! Look how he drinks it.
It's so cute.
He's got a thirst like a bar-fly.
Hello.....
You still expecting
that connection to call?
For you own piece of mind, forget him.
The Doc said that I could count on
Mr Lane, and the Doc doesn't lie.
The Doc. Look at me, a doc told you I'd
be up and around in no time, and am I?
Have you seen my sticks? Have you seen my
drumsticks anywhere?
You know what I知 going
to get for this little dog?
A little rain coat,
like for when it rains.
Plaid maybe, or maybe all yellow
Where are my drumsticks, Sash?
- How'd they get up here?
- You liked that, didn't you?
- Sash, I never keep them up here.
- You drank it all up didn't you?
Sash!
I put them there. I stood right up
and I put them there, all right?
- No kidding?
- Maybe I, when she was straightening up
for me. I don't know. Stop picking on me.
Frankie...
You can't keep stoning yourself about it..
There must be a million drummers that
play better than you, who can't get jobs.
Just remember that and
you're going to feel better
Yeah sure, I will.
Can the noise.
- What's this for Sash?
- What?
Oh I. She laid it out for groceries.
We owe her even more.
- You got any?
- No.
I don't know what we're
doing with all our money
Don't you get enough cards by Shrika?
- I just do it to kill
pass time, that's all.
- Well, what about my pass time?
- What did you say this was for?
- I sit here all the time
and you don't even talk to me.
We got any more beer? I'd like some.
Beer bloats Sash, when you can't exercise.
Here pick a card.
Nothing is good for me. I am only 25
and it's like I'm an old lady already.
- ls it my fault I can't exercise?
- Do you want to pick a card,
or don't you want to pick a card?
No, I don稚 pick a card. All
I want is just, is just a Tittle....
- A little what Sash?
- Oh, just a little.....
A little beer, a little
fun, a little anything.
I can't dance anymore, I can't
swim and I can't even drink beer.
I don't even know what
kinds they got anymore.
What other kinds they
got these days Frankie?
All right! Pretend I ain't
here. You're wishing all
the time that I'd have
gotten killed that night.
I don't wish any such thing.
If I don't talk, you get mad. If I
say anything, you bite my head off..
I don't know whether I'm
coming or going Sash.
I told you, it gives me headaches.
Well, I've got to
practice sometime Sash.
If the job comes along,
I want to be ready.
The job, the job! Take it to your
girlfriend if you're going to practice.
What?
Take them down and give her the headache.
Do you know what you're saying Sash?
Do you know what you are talking about?
- Don't give me that innocent look.
- I haven't said two words
to her since I come back.
- Just cause I sit here, you
don't think I know what goes on?
- Not two words.
I know plenty.
Cut it out will ya Sash.
Take them down to that tramp
if you want to make noise.
Take them down to her, why don't you?
All right, I will.
Frankie.....Frankie, I didn't mean.....
- I have 12 cents to a beer.
If I had 15, I'd be all right.
- I've got 6 cents, here ya go.
I ain't going to stand it much longer
The heartaches my old man gives me.
You know what he likes to do most? Tear
the dates off the calendar, watching him.
That's suppose to be my
big Saturday night pleasure.
Sometimes he loses all
control and tears off the
whole week at once. He'll
eat them like a billy-goat.
- Know what would fill up
that empty spot in your life?
- What?
A dog. Ask a satisfied
customer. Frankie that dog I got
you, it makes a big difference
in your life, doesn't it.
Yeah.
I want to see.
- I want to see you.
- After the inning.
Hi Frankie.
- You make out all right
with the fellow with the job?
- The drumming job? Yeah, fine, fine.
Well not so fine. He sort
of tapped out on me.
He promised to call me, but..
It's too bad.
There's a million drummers in
the world and how do I rate?
Maybe he lost your number?
lt happens.
Maybe he just wishing you'd keep in touch.
He'd think I was a pest.
Why should he? A good drummer, that's
something that don't turn up everyday
Come on Frankie, call him.
Call him Frankie.
Come on Molly, watch the game huh?
Oh I don't feel like it Johnnie. Why
don't you go ahead, I'll wait for you.
Yes studio B, Monday
morning, thank you Mr Lane.
Monday! I got an audition
Monday Me! He told
me to join the union
and get ready to work.
- Oh that's wonderful.
- You know, he did lose my phone number
He was trying to find me all week long.
Here I was ready to forget the whole thing.
Gee, if you hadn't opened your
mouth, I wouldn't have called him.
- Sure you would have.
- I've got an audition with a big band.
- Me on TV.
- Practice a lot Frankie.
Practice? I'lll beat
those heads to a shred.
Only I got to find a place where.
Sash can't stand the noise.
Molly? Do you think I
could put the drums in
your place and sort of
drop in once in a while?
Why not?
Molly, why not?
- Johnny wouldn't understand.
- So, what could he do?
lt ain't a question of
what he could do Frankie.
A fellow like Johnnie
can't do much of anything.
It's a question of what
it does to him. I知 all he
has in the world, and I
don't want to hurt him.
- Molly, for crying out loud....
- I want you to know Frankie,
a fellow like him.......
- ...Sometimes when we're all alone....
- What does he do? Cry?
He's a lush Molly. He's a
100 per cent habitual drunk!
Look, everybody's a habitual something.
With him it's liquor, that's all.
- Please Molly. Mollyo.
- lt ain't just that Frankie....
I don't want it to start
with us again. Look what you
said about us not seeing
each other, it was the truth.
Even if we went away, I'd try to.....
It just doesn't add up. lt
never did, it never can.
- Well give it a chance.
I told you it would one day
- All my life's been "one day".
- On and on and on.
- I've got drums, I知 headed for a
good job. ls that so on and on and on?
I make some money, I make Sash well.
What's so on and on about that?
- Don't shut me out Molly I知 trying.
- You wanted to see me?
- No!
- What do you mean "no"?
- Here, for what we owe.
- Frankie, I says can't trust me.
Tell her Frankie, what
an honest hustler I am.
Frankie! I guess maybe you
could drop in once in a while.
Thanks Mollyo.
See you tonight Molly.
- How's that?
- Real nice.
- You should have heard what
I did a little while ago...
- Good huh? I hope the
neighbors liked it too.
I知 very big with the
neighbors. They keep banging on
the pipes to let me know
how much they appreciate it.
- I won't let it go to my head though.
- You keep playing drums at 5 a. m.....
and you'll see what goes to your head.
Slip me a smile and I'lll give
you my autograph. You won't
have to fight your way through
the bobby soxers to get to me.
I bet those bobby-soxers go for that.
Tired?
Yes, but in a very nice way. I've
been feeling good all night.
- I joined the musician痴 union today.
- Shrika loan you the money?
- Him? Who did?
- Nobody. I知 going to hock the drums.
- Oh Frankie!
- I've got it figured out pretty good.
When I get a job, I'll take an
advance and get the drums out again.
ln the meantime, I'll
use the practice pads.
- You should have asked Shrika.
- Haven't even seen him.
- You didn't go to work?
- No, I've been practicing here all night.
- I quit the game Molly..
- lt wouldn稚 have hurt you
to wait a couple of days Frank.
I wanted to quit. I'm
quitting a couple of things.
ls it bad?
Not too bad.
- You shouldn't have started again.
- Who knows why I started
in the first place?
I guess in the beginning
you do it only for kicks.
I got my first shot for nothing.
I thought I could take it or
leave it alone. So I took it.
And I took it again and again.
One day Louie wasn't around. I
nearly went crazy till I found him.
Lord I was sick!
I was so sick. You can't
be that sick and live.
That's when I knew I was hooked.
There was a 40 pound monkey
on my back. The only way to get
along with a load like that,
is to keep getting a fix.
Don't.....
I知 one of the lucky ones, Molly.
I kicked it and I'm not too far hooked
to kick it again. I've had my last fix.
Tell me something. Do you think those
bobby-soxers' will really go for me?
Yes, they will.
Maybe I'lll get Sparrow a
job with the orchestra.
And when I can get enough
money together, I can get Sash
into a real good hospital, so
she can walk and dance again.
And then maybe...
- Who is it?
- Shrika, open up!
Just a minute.
- All right where is he?
- Frankie?
- Frankie! Where is he?
- Well what is it, what did he do?
What'd he do? You know what he did, he quit!
No notice, no nothing.
He sends words by that
mistress that he's through.
I had to take the spot
myself. Where is he?
- He wasn't at the game?
- Would we be looking for him all
over, if he'd been at the game?
He eats my bread. Six years, he
eats my bread. He gets put away, I
send you money regular. He gets
out and I give him his job back.
- Shut up!
- What do you mean "shut up"?
Do you think it was easy
talking men like Williams
and Marquee up to a
two-bit game like you?
- Louis.......Louis.....
- I sold them on Frankie.
Why are we getting excited?
They were a bat in the
pocket and hungry for action.
We finally get a chance to score big....
..and you lose the deal.
Look Louie I swear. When
Marquee and Williams come,
the dealer will be there.
Or a player just as good...
There ain't none as good.
- Why didn't you offer him
more money, a piece of the play.
- From your end or mine?
What's the difference,
whose end? You expect
me to stand here and
argue about pennies?
Look.
I知 a musician..
Well, how does it feel?
Well, it feels like....
You'd better hang on to my arm,
or I'lll go up like a balloon.
I知 a musician.
- Where are we going?
- I don't know, but I
want to buy you something.
- No. - I've got to spend
some money or I'lll bust.
- How about one of those, only in green?
- Frankie...
- Maybe a color TV set. They're pretty.
Would you look at this production...
And only for cooking. Now who
would want a thing like that?
- Boy, it's goofy huh?
- It's pretty huh?
- I wonder what he does for a living?
- Him?
He must make a nice
dollar. Look at the way
he dresses her and a kitchen like that.
I notice he doesn't help her. I
bet he didn't even marry the girl.
Look she ain't even wearing
a ring on her finger.
She takes it off when she cooks, maybe
and he's tired after a hard days' work.
Okay, let him sit there, but at least
he could talk to her once in a while.
He doesn't have to sit there with
his nose buried in a magazine.
- I would talk to her.
- What would you say?
I'd say, how you been? How did it go today?
What's for supper?
Steaks for supper and
everything went fine today
Steaks! Good. Now how about you and
me stepping out tonight after we eat.
- Why don't we just stay
home and listen to music?
- Yeah.
I like that better. We'll just
stay home and turn on some music.
I wish it were Monday already.
- Hi Sash!
- Where have you been?
- Shrika has been here. He said you quit.
- Where have you been? Look!
- Why did you quit him? I've got
a try-out on Monday -If the band
leader likes me, I知 hired.
Frankie, go tell Shrika you
was fooling, you'll deal.
Maybe this band leader
won't like how you play
Sash look. I joined a musician痴 union.
Why do you got to go around
changing things? Why can't it
be like always? Why do you
got to quit dealing Frankie?
- How we going to live
with no money coming in?
- It'll start coming in Monday.
Suppose they call this
great "try-out" of. You
can't tell me it's a
sure thing, can you?
Frankie, deal for Shrika like always.
Forget this "great" job!
I quit dealing Sash. I can't take the
chance, don't you understand? If the joint
gets raided and I get picked up again,
Mr. Lane would be through with me.
- And then how will I play with a band?
- How you going to play if
Shrika gets your arms broke?
- What?
-Yeah, right here he said it.
And he wanted to slap me around too.
Why can't it be like always?
Antek!
- You miserable piece of humanity.
- I've got a right to quit if I want.
- Marquee and Williams
are coming tomorrow.
- Don't you realize the
significance? Leave me alone.
I'lll leave you alone. ln the
alley with the cats looking.
That's enough Shrika. If he don't
want to deal, he don't want to deal.
- What are you talking about?
- Don't you raise your voice to me, you slob.
He's no slave. You can't force
him, so what's the use?
- He....
- We've had the best of him all these years. Don't be a pig!
He ain't interested.
All right, all right. Marquee and
Williams have never heard of him.
Money? Something to blow your nose on.
I wash my hands.
He's just a pig, that's all.
Still you can't blame him, so
much. Let the biggest ones get
away, because the best dealer
isn't working for you anymore.
That ain't easy to swallow.
You're the best all right.
- You're a squeeze player Louis.
- Been tried on you before?
NNah, I知 new around here..
- Are we really asking so much dealer?
- One night. I will...
You help us make a bundle and
we'll spread that sunshine around.
Couldn't you use a couple of hundred?
Maybe 2 5 0?
2 5 0 pays a lot of doctor bills.
- Tomorrow huh?
- Frankie...
Let him make up his own mind.
Okay, but for one night. Win or lose.
Sunup, I case the deck.
Sure, you're the
dealer. What a load off.
Now I can sleep. Take care of that arm.
Quite a character huh? Are
you jacking up the price
right now, or do you
really have that music job?
If they like what they hear.
Chancy huh? Nervous?
- So, what are we waiting for?
- Don't talk about it. It's tough enough.
I know, I know. I put down a craving once.
No, candy, sweets. I used to
be eating it all the time.
Got examined for the army and they said
you've got sugar in your blood friend.
You've got to give up sweets
forever, or it's good-bye Charlie.
- I had to give up candy.
- My gums bleed for you. It's awful.
lt was. That unfinished feeling
that you got all the time.
Well, I don't have to tell you.
- So don't! -I mean you got this one
thing on the mind all the time.
- Can't stop thinking about it.
- You're just a mine of
information aren't you?
You know what I did?
I said to myself. Okay,
off sweets forever.
Well, forever can start tomorrow.
For once in my life, I知 going to
eat all the candy that I can hold. I
bought 18 dollars and 20 cents worth
of candy and lugged it up to my room.
All night long, I ate candy
I was sick. I was sweating,
but I kept shoving it in.
Ever since then, when I think
about candy I say to myself,
well you can't complain. You
once had it and had it good.
You know what I mean?
How's it Mollyo?
- All right Frankie, but where have you been?
- What'll you have?
-A couple of ryes.
All day, I was expecting
you'd be in to practice.
Practice? I'lll get down
there and knock them dead.
It's all in the wrist and
I've got the touch Molly.
Look at that, steady as a rock. lt
can do anything I want it to do.
- Keep the change pal.
- Thanks.
- You got a cigarette Frankie?
- Sure.
You're on it again Frankie. Why, why?
No, listen Molly, listen.
- Why?
- Molly!
- Molly...
- Beat it!
- Take a walk!
- Molly listen to me, I can
explain. Molly I just want to talk.
Will you get out of here!
- Molly.
- Stop it please!
- You'll lose your job.
Can't you manage this.
- Molly, listen to me.
Leave me alone, both of you!
Molly!
Molly... Molly!
Molly... listen to me.
Molly. open the door.
Molly would you open the door
Molly!
Molly! Molly, open the door!
Where are you going Molly?
- If you let me explain, you'll know why I did it.
- Taxi!
Molly w Iii you listen. Let
me tell you what's happened.
Where you going Molly?
No Molly! Molly!
- Don't forget to get it cleaned out.
- I already cleaned it.
And say please when you talk
to me, or I'lll buy my own
and go into business for
myself. How's that Frankie?
Nothing huh?
I知 reminding you Shrika,
I get 2-21/2, maybe more.
Would I go back on my word?
How're you feeling dealer?
- Hi ya Shrika.
- Good-evening.
- Yeah?
- ls this the place?
I don't know what place
you mean buddy This is the
leather belt and company
You want to buy a belt?
Come right in. We've just started.
How have you been?
- I could handle the door
better if I was blind.
- Oh, you couldn't
heat towels for a barber
- Good-evening Shrika.
- Good to have ya!
You the machine? Man
with the golden arm huh?
Let's see you try and take this away..
Here we go, down and dirty.
No ladies allowed, you know that Vi.
- ls Frankie in there?
- What's the matter?
Sash. I can't get her to
sleep. Her and Frankie had an
argument and she's almost out
of her mind. ls he in there?
- Well, I can't call him now
- I just want to know if he's here?
- I've been bounced around on
the street like a pool ball.
- I got to get back in.
- Well tell him she's worried, if you get a chance.
- Three aces. Two pairs.
Possible straight flush.
- Aces, two hundred.
I'lll call your two hundred
and raise you two.
I'lll have a look for four hundred and
I'lll spot you three hundred more.
It's up to you.
- I don't know, I just don't know.
- You've got three aces, show him.
- He's got a possible straight
flush, with a queen showing.
- I tell you he's bluffing.
He bluffed me out of a couple tonight.
You wouldn't be jerk enough
to try it again, would you?
- Bet and find out.
- Well bet, bet. I tell
you he's a bluff artist.
- Call it.
- I call it and raise it 500 more.
- Sammy!!
- I know what I'm doing!
I'lll have a look and house
bumps you 500 more.
- I told you, I told you he had it.
- Shut up and let me think.
- It's up to you.
- What's the rush, I want to know?
- Your bet, two pairs.
- I heard you. What is this? A forced
game? A man has a right to study his hand.
Bet or fold!
- Lose your hand Sammy.
- I tell you he's got it, don't throw good
money after bad. I know what I'm doing.
What'd you have?
You didn't pay to find out.
Nothing. A lousy two
nines. You let him bluff you
out of a full house,
with a lousy two nines.
You do that again at this
table, and you're through.
Ah, forget it this once dealer.
He paid plenty for it.
- You're good dealer, maybe too good.
- What do you mean by that?
- Cut the talk. Deal, deal.
- Come on, get some of
this smoke out of here.
- What do you mean too good?
- If the shoe fits brother.
- Okay, that's it for the deck.
- What?
- Well, we always break up around now
- One more round. What about my money?
- Frankie, how about it?
- Nope, just give me what's coming to me.
- One more round huh? I'lll deal.
- You? We want to play Machine.
You think I can't sell you a thing or two?
Sit down and we'll get going.
- What about my money?
- As soon as we break.
- Give us a chance. Go home.
- home. You'll get it later.
Okay, ante up, here we go.
- 100.
- Yeah....100...
Okay, here we go.
Good morning Frankie.
- ls Louis still here?
- He's doing an apple plexy but
they're doing a sweet in there.
- We're getting murdered.
- You got to get in here and start
dealing. I ain't taking the slot.
- Look. You got to make it stop.
- No deal, no fix.
Give me my money and
I'lll go see someone else.
- You owe it to me.
- Take me to court.
You got to make it stop.
I've got to get some sleep.
I've got to be fresh tomorrow.
Work a few hours, do us a favor. I'lll
guarantee you'll feel like a week.
- Please Louis, now.
- Drop dead!
Wait a second.
Okay...
Louis says you've got money for him.
So give it to me, he's waiting.
I know he's waiting. They
all say the same thing.
Tell Louis, like he tells us, nothing.
- Not a penny?
- Nope.
- How is it up there?
- The dealer is losing huh?
- What happened to that golden arm? Don't worry about the dealer.
The game's just going on a day
and a half, he'll come through.
Why not, with those educated fingers.
Now you see it, now you don't.
You keep your dirty mouth off the
dealer. Frankie runs a clean game
and there ain't nothing in the world
that could make him change that.
Hey Antak....
All right, all right.
Can you let me have 1000?
- How about 500?
- 200
I know it's sunday night.
I dind't call you to find what day it is!
How checks to you?
Hold it a minute.
Give me some of that.
I've got to get out of here Louis. I知 dead.
I haven't slept in two days.
It'll be just a little while now
I ain't doing you any good.
The house is still losing.
Stay with it dealer, the class is
beginning to tell. Just stay with it..
- I just can't. My
head won't work no more.
- Louis Louis, I'm
running out of guys to call
- Lippy.
- Can't find him.
- I'lll find him. He's loaded.
- I知 getting out of here.
Just a little longer I知 going to make a
call, then I'lll take you over to my place.
- Now where were we.
- Coffee?
- Good and black!
- I can't raise another cent
- How it's going
Every pot almost, they're raising and
raising until we are forced out.
- What day is it?
- Can't you think of anybody
we can tap for a few thousands
- What day is it? ls it Monday yet?
- Listen to me...
- Are you listening to me?
- Wha Wha?
The next big pot they try are forcing
you out, you've got to stay with them.
Shrika won't let me.
He keeps nudging me to fold.
That's 'cause he ain't sure you'll win!
You can't be sure though.
There's a way you can be sure.
You can do anything you
want with those cards.
That's only for fun. I haven't
got nerve to do it for real.
- You want to get out of here, don't you?
- What?
- You want to get to that try
-out in good condition, don't you?
- Yeah, I want to get
there feeling good.
Well then make sure, you know what I mean.
Let's get on with the game, I feel hot.
Okay dealer...
- I知 in.
Three. King. Jack..
- I think that's enough.
Call.
- Pair of strays.
I知 back with 500.
House sees.
Three strays, King, Jacks.
I bet 500 bucks.
- Take off your glasses.
- No!
- I didn't know. I didn't know.
- I'll get to you in a second.
I didn't know. lt hasn't happened before.
Ask anybody.
You don't deal for me no more.
- You want him?
- I wouldn't dirty my hands.
How was I to know. You fellows, you know
I've been running an
honest game. Tell them!
Frankie...
Everything's all right now Frankie.
Frankie, what's a little
cupping around huh?
Nothing. Am I right? You'll see.
You should have seen Shrika's face, when
Williams said he'd get to him in a minute.
He went white! lt was so funny
Cut it out, you hear me!
- You was the best sport I knew my whole life.
- You hear me?
Stay away from me punk!
- Hurry quick!
- I want to get some sleep.
It's beginning to wear
off quit for you? You're a
graduating student. You're
going to have to step it up.
- Please hurry.
- All right
- Let's see your money.
- Later, later!
- Right now.
- Trust me this once, will you?
No, I don't do that.
I'lll pay you twice as much later, but
I got to do something right now.
I'lll even push for you. Louis heard.
- A flipping junkie always says that.
- Louis, please.
Get your dirty hands off me.
Frankie...
- Wake up. Get up!
- Where did you put it?
- Where do you keep it?
- Let him go.
I can't find it.
Frankie, please let me take you home.
I've got to be on time.
Frankie...
What's the matter. Come on,
let's try to really cook it.
- Mr. Machine.
- Mr. Lanes.
- Can you read music?
- Yes.
Shelby, let Mr. Machine sit in on this one.
Number 37, it's right in front of you.
Do you know it Mr. Machine?
Okay, let's try.
Mr. Machine, the first four bars are all you.
Come on, let's try it again.
One, two, three, four.
- I知 sorry..
- Are you all set?
Once again. One, two, three, four
Okay Shelby, let's go.
- Sash, have we any money?
- I need some money.
No, what's the matter?
There was some around here
yesterday, wasn't there?
I need some money Sash.
Well, there isn't any.
What is it Frankie?
What is it?
You can walk? Since when?
What's the angle? What are you
and Frankie trying to prove?
Come on tell me. One hustler to another
Let me in on it or I'lll
croon for it, you hear?
I'lll tell everybody you
can walk, you always could.
I'lll tell them all you can
walk, you old phoney!
No....Louis!
No Louis, you can't do that. You
can't tell anybody Please Louis.
- Keep your hands off me.
- Please Louis.
Molly... Molly.
Ain't that the way it
happened? They had a fight
and the next thing you
know, Louis is falling.
Come on, level Sash. Don't try to
out-think me, you'll only get tangled.
I don't know anything about
a fight. I was sleeping
the whole morning,
right here in this chair
Then for all you know,
it did happen that way
While you were sleeping,
Frankie shoved him over.
- He didn't!
- How do you know it? You were sleeping.
lt wasn't like I was sleeping,
more like dozing kind of.
I'd have heard a
fight, if there was one.
Frankie didn't do it, he wasn't even here.
- When wasn't he here?
- When it happened.
How can you be sure if you was dozing?
I was up when he left. That's how I'm sure.
I saw him go.
And he was home this morning.
Only a second. He didn't get in a
fight, he was here only a second.
Why didn't he stick around?
Was somebody after him?
Nobody was after him, nobody. He
just wanted some money is all.
- Money? What for?
- I don't know what for.
A fix! He wanted it for a fix from Louis.
- lt had nothing to do with Louis.
- How do you know?
Cause there was no money.
Why would he want to
see Louis for a fix,
he there was no money?
To try and get one without money
Okay, I can wait. Wherever he is, sooner
or later he's got to come up for a fix.
Molly, Molly wait please.
It's finished Frankie. Like I told you.
- But I've got to talk to you Molly,
- No!
Once and for all!
Molly, I've got to talk to you.
You got any money Molly?
I need a few dollars.
10 dollars would do it. I'd get
it back to you in a few days.
Or 5 even. Five would be fine, please.
I feel so sick Molly. I hurt all over.
I feel so bad.
Don't say no, please don't say no.
Why not Molly why not?
Jump off a rope if you're going to kill
yourself, but don't ask me to help you.
I'lll do anything for you Molly...
- But right now you've got to help me. I need a shot.
- No!
Five would do it, or three or
two even, but please hurry.
You mustn't take that dirty stuff no more.
I know, I know you're
right. I promise, but
right now I just need
a fix. Just one fix.
It'll help me stop
hurting. Then I promise you,
I'll kick it for good.
Just a few dollars Molly.
Hello Molly. I just wanted
to come and say hello.
- Ain't you going to let me in?
- I asked you please to
not bother me any more.
- I miss you.
- Look, I'm awfully tired Johnny.
- I'lll stay only a few minutes.
- No.
- Who's in there with you?
- Go away Johnny and don't come back.
Who is it? Not the dealer! You
ain't hiding him, are you?
- You wouldn't be dumb enough
to be an accessory would you?
- What do you mean accessory?
He killed Louis. The cops are
looking for him this minute.
- Frankie Machine.
- ls he in there?
- No.
- I知 coming in!
Not if you ever want to see me again.
- Will you meet me tomorrow.
- Yeah, I'lll be around the bar
Maybe not tomorrow, but soon.
I miss you.
Honest, I didn't.
What am I going to do?
- Go tell Bedner, it wasn't you.
- I couldn't.
I couldn't stand up to
the cops the way I am.
Look at me. I'd say anything they'd
want me to say just for a shot.
- Then get cured first.
-What are you talking about?
How am I suppose to get cured.
- You did it once..
- That was with help, with medicine and doctors.
I can't go apply at Lexington with
a murder hanging over my head.
Couldn't you do it without going there?
You mean just stop?
Cold turkey?
You don't understand. The pain.
What else can you do?
All I need is just one shot, just one.
Okay.
All right, here take it!
Here, go on take it all. Cause after that one
shot, all you're going to need is another.
And then another and another Take it!
Take it!
- Why should you hurt,
like other people hurt?
- You had a dog's
life, but never a break.
Why try to face it, like most
people do? No just roll up all
your pains, into one big hurt
and then flatten it with a fix.
What do you think you'll
find just outside that door?
Don't you think Bedner knows
what you are, and what you need?
Just to get through that next hour...
Don't you know, he's just waiting
for you to come and get it.
Go on. Let him kill you!
Let him kill you. It'll be quicker
and better than doing it your way.
No!
I won't let him kill me. No!
And I won't run into no grave.
But kicking it......
A guy can't do it by himself.
I'lll help.
You know what you are letting yourself in for?
lt ain't pretty.
And it could be dangerous.
If they find you here, then
they find you, is all.
I don't mean dangerous from Bedner. I mean
dangerous for me.
Sometimes a junkie will kill,
to get away from the treatment.
Understand?
So if you've got any
knives or scissors in the
house, you've got to put
them away for a while.
And don't let me out
of the room. No matter
what I say, or promise,
or how much I beg.
Cause if I get out, it'll
only be for a fix.
That's the way it is. Do you understand?
Just lock me in the room.
And if I try to make a
break for it, just stop
me any way you know how
And no matter how much you
see it hurting me, don't
try to help me with pills
or dope or anything else.
Do you think you can handle it?
Here we go.
Down and dirty.
You can't hold me.
Sit down.
You can't hold me. I ain't got all
my marbles, you know that Captain.
Write down the cases Sparrow.
- I didn't do nothing.
- But Frankie did something all right.
Now, I want you to tell me about it.
Whoever killed that peddler, should
get a ticker-tape parade. Yeah, and
maybe I'd lead the band, but I
still want you to tell me about it.
Listen to me Sparrow. When
we catch him, he stands
trial, whether you talk,
or whether you don't.
The only question is, do I
ticket you as an accessory?
Bedner, don't nail me to the cross. He's
the only guy I've ever had for a friend.
He's nobody's friend anymore.
He smash you with a steam
roller, if you got between
him and a pop in the arm.
Come on talk Sparrow.
Okay, beat it.
Let me out!
Yes?
- I thought I'd come and
see how you've been Sash.
- All alone, that's how I've been.
Something to eat. Sausage.
All alone and worried sick. Where is he?
Do you know where he is?
Did he go to you?
What do you want anyway?
I didn't tell Bedner anything. The
papers, they twist everything all up.
They wouldn't be able to,
if you didn't let them.
I can't help what they do. What do
you expect me to do, sitting here?
Just tell Bedner that Frankie wasn't here
when it happened. That he didn't do it.
- I never said he did.
- But that's how it sounds, if he
was the only one around at the time.
And you know it was somebody else.
What do you mean? Who?
don't know. But maybe Bedner could figure
it out if he didn't think it was Frankie.
What business is it of yours anyway?
I just want to help, that's all.
Who are you kidding? You think I
don't know what you really want?
You think I don't know what
you and him have been up to
behind my back, while I had
to sit here all these years?
- Had to sit here all these years.
- No Sasha, you've got it wrong.
No! You've got it wrong!
He put me in this chair,
and as long as I sit
here, he'll never leave me.
- He knows he belongs to me.
- Sash, I came only to help.
I wouldn't want to live it he left me,
and I would rather see
him dead, than go to you.
- Sash, please.
- YES, get out of here!
Get out of here you lousy tramp!
Get out!
Frankie no!
- I can't stand it any longer
- Just a little longer.
Please help me. Keep me warm.
I've got to get out and get a fix.
Open the door, or I'lll kill you..
- I'lll kill you.
- Frankie, listen, if you......
- But I do have something
put away to make it stop.
- Give it to me quick!
Where? I'lll get it.
Molly! Molly!
Let me out!
Molly open the door.
Frankie? Frankie, answer me.
Frankie answer me. Are you all right?
Don't think you can fool me
into opening this door I won't.
Are you all right Frankie?
Please answer me.
Molly, if you love me, kill me, please!
Oh, I知 so cold.
Make me warm.
Molly...
Please Molly, make me warm...
Oh Molly, I知 so cold!
Oh God, Oh God.
Please make me warm Molly.
I知 so cold..
- I waited for you in the bar.
- I told you it might not be right away
I thought maybe you were sick or something.
I just wanted to tell you, don't look
for me at the bar anymore. He threw me
out last night, we had a little argument.
- So make it the Safari huh?
- Yeah, sure Johnny, sure.
Pretty good, huh Molly?
- Take it slow now.
- Oh, I知 all right.
Just a little rocky.
It's the most gorgeous day I ever saw.
I think it's the first day I ever saw.
I've got a craving for something sweet.
Have you got anything sweet?
- Sugar?
- Gimme!
More, come on, more.
How can you Frankie?
I never felt this good In my life. I feel like all
the things inside of me are settling Into place.
Thanks Molly. Mollyo!
- Look out, you'll scrape your face off!
- I don't care.
- You got a razor I can use?
- Can I trust you with one?
Cross my heart.
- ls this the place?
- Yeah.
- Okay, come on.
- No please, you don't need me up there.
- Where is he Molly?
- He didn't do it, honest.
I知 not a judge. They pay me
to bring him in, that's all.
If you tell me where he is, I promise you
that he'll get every break a jockey can get.
- He's no jockey either. That's finished.
- Oh sure, you bet.
- You can see for yourself.
- He ain't running away
from you. So, where is he?
- With Sash.
- All right Molly. Let's go see.
- Hello Sash.
- What are you doing here?
- Frankie, don't you know
that Bedner is looking for you?
- Don't worry about it
Sash, I ain't afraid.
- I didn't do it and you know that
- Who did then?
I've come to tell you something Sash.....
- I知 leaving here.
- Bedner will arrest you. He told the newspapers you.....
- What?
- I知 leaving.
You won't have to worry
about money or anything.
I find a way to send
some regular to you.
- And I will take good care of you.
- Leaving me!?
Not leaving you Sash, just leaving.
You saw what happened since I came back.
Like Dr. Lennex told me.....
I got in the same old routine and
before I knew it, I was on it again.
But you can't leave me. You've
got to stay and take care of me.
I know I'm responsible
for how you are Sash....
but I can't go around the rest of
my life stoning myself about it.
I've been carrying my heart
ever since it happened.
Even now it hurts me to
think about it, but.....
Well, it's not that I want
to leave, I've got to leave.
You mustn't leave Frankie! You mustn't.
Sash....
- Say good-bye to me Sash.
- You think you're fooling me?
I know what's pulling you away Molly!
- No. - Yeah, you just go so that
you can be with that little tramp!
- Frankie no...
- Good-bye Sash.
No Frankie, please don't leave.
Frankie no, don't leave me.
Get dressed Sash..
Sash!
Sash Stop!
Sash, don't move.
Don't try to talk. You're
going to be all right.
I love you so much!