Christine...
Why, Chris.
- Oh, hello, Janet.
- Explain yourself.
- Explain what?
- Brooding on the balcony.
It just isn't being
done this season.
- I wasn't brooding.
- Lying to one's sister's
out this season, too.
- Strangest thing happened.
I thought I heard a man's
voice out over the ocean,
calling my name.
- Next time he calls, ask him
if he has a friend for me.
- I'm serious.
- How can you be serious?
It was the wind,
or those fog horns.
- Perhaps, but it
sounded like...
Paul.
- It's been two
years now, Christine.
- I know.
But for a moment
out over the ocean,
I felt very close to him again.
He used to love the ocean,
you know, especially at night.
He'd go racing down to
the beach for a swim,
no matter how late it was.
And usually I'd be fool
enough to go with him.
- Any husband of mine ever
chased me into the ocean
in the middle of the
night, I'd shoot him.
- He did a lot of crazy
things, some of them bad,
but I don't think I could
ever love another man
the way I loved Paul.
- Chris, you've gotta
stop talking like this.
You're getting morbid!
- Oh, it's not as bad
as all that, brat.
- It is bad.
Look at this dress.
You can't wear black when
you're going out on a date.
Looks as if you
were still, well...
- In mourning?
- Well, yes.
- I just happen to
like black, that's all.
- I know, but just for tonight,
it isn't exactly appropriate.
And Chris, don't wear your
wedding ring tonight either.
- Why not?
- It might make it
awkward for Martin.
- Oh, is Martin going to
propose again tonight?
- Well, he might.
And he can't very well
put an engagement ring
on your finger if
that's already there.
- By the way, what kind of a
ring has Martin bought for me?
- An enormous diamond with...
Oh, Chris, you will say
yes tonight, won't you?
- I suppose I'd better,
otherwise he might sue you
for breach of promise.
- Darling, I'm so
excited, and I've got
just the right dress
all picked out for you.
Will you wear it?
- Anything you say.
And bring out my new
ermine, will you?
- You know, Chris, I think
your cloak with the sequins
might look better
on you tonight.
- I take it you have a
date for tonight, too.
- As a matter of fact, I have.
- All right, I'll wear the
sequins, you wear the ermine.
- Well, if you insist, thanks.
I like your hair like that.
Of course, you could do
with a little more lipstick.
- And you could do
with a little less.
- Do you suppose it's Martin?
- You know Martin would
never honk a horn at a lady.
It's probably your young man.
By the way, which young
man is it tonight?
-It's...
You know, I've forgotten.
- Have a good time
and come home early.
- Well, I can't do both.
- Then you come home early.
- You come home engaged.
- Mrs. Faber's residence.
Yes sir.
Mrs. Faber.
It's Mr. Labbitz, ma'am.
- Thank you, Emily,
I'll take it here.
Hello, Martin.
Don't tell me you're
standing me up.
- No, no, it's just
that some idiotic client
came into the office at
the last minute, and I...
Well no, I know it's not
serious, but I particularly
didn't want to have anything
interfere with tonight.
Well, no, you see, I wanted
to show you that I'm not
always the lawyer with his
mind on cases and affidavits.
No, I'm really the romantic
type with my mind on you.
Yeah, I thought it
was a nice speech.
I dreamed it up this
afternoon in felony court.
- It doesn't matter if
we're a little late, Martin.
The first act's no good anyway.
I'll walk over along
the beach to your house,
then you won't have to waste
the time driving over here.
- Oh, I wouldn't do that.
- But I want to
walk over, Martin.
I'll enjoy it.
Oh, of course it's safe.
Now stop talking
like an old maid.
Goodbye.
- It is dark down there, ma'am.
- And you, Emily, stop
talking like Martin Abbott.
Lock the patio door
after me, will you?
Good night.
Christine...
Chris...
- I don't blame you
for being frightened.
You made a decision
tonight that angered him,
and now you're
fighting to sustain it.
You have all my hopes
fighting with you, madam.
I think you were married.
I saw your husband dead,
and you were moving toward
a new marriage, but
I see I was wrong.
Sometimes I am.
Good night, goodbye.
- Wait.
You weren't mistaken.
My husband died two years ago.
- In my fate I
could not be wrong.
I saw him, dead, and
his car in flames.
I'm sorry.
- I don't understand
how you know all this.
I suppose people do talk.
Do you live around here?
- No, I wish I did
live on the ocean.
Here is my name
and where I live.
- Alexis.
Psychic consultant.
Oh.
- I see you place me
in the same category
with fortune tellers, snake
charmers, and magicians.
Oh well, many people do.
- But you must know who I am.
How else would you
know all these things?
- Perhaps because we're
very much alike, you and.
Free spirits, both of
us, like my friend here.
We like the night,
the mist of the ocean.
The wind whispers
to us and the sand
feels cool under our feet.
We're not like, oh, I have
his name now, like Martin.
- There's nothing
wrong with Martin.
- Of course not.
If only he would understand
how little he understands.
- Well, Martin is very logical.
- Yes, that's why
you should marry him.
Even free spirits
have to come in
out of the night sometimes
and put on their shoes,
pay their bills,
go to the dentist,
and of course, family
dinners on Sunday.
You really shouldn't
be so irritated
by his little mannerisms, like
when he clears his throat,
announcing that he's going
to kiss you any minute,
or when he counts
off all his plans
on the tips of his fingers.
- How could-
- How?
I can't tell you how
I know these things.
But it hardly matters, does it?
Since we're not
going to meet again.
- Christine?
Chris!
Oh,
over here, Martin.
- Hello
- But you certainly
had me scared.
What kept you so long?
- Well, I was
talking to this man.
Well, he was here.
Or I've imagined him.
He was fantastic enough.
- Well, let's get going.
- Oh, I tore my dress, Martin,
I'll have to go
back to the house.
- All right.
We'll go to your house
first, skip the theater,
directly to the Blue Angel.
What's the matter?
- Nothing, it's just
that it's so late,
and I'm a little upset, could
we make it some other night?
- Of course.
- Are you sure you understand?
- When it concerns
you, Christine,
there's nothing I
don't understand.
Here, you better take
this off my hands,
or I'll have to wear it
to the office tomorrow.
- Fix yourself a drink, I've
gotta change this torn dress.
- Right.
- Martin, how flattering.
I should have thought
of this in the first place.
This is much better
than any nightclub.
- Yes, and just think, no head
waiter, no smoke, no people.
- And at the end of
the evening, no check.
- Oh Martin, you think
in such practical terms.
- I'm a very practical man.
For instance, I just said
that to make you pout.
The better to do this.
- I've been trapped.
- Right.
Now, if you'll just step over
here to the sofa by the fire.
- Another trap?
- Definitely.
Darling, what's the matter?
- That music.
- It's just the phonograph.
- But we don't have that record.
- Of course you do.
It was right on
top of the cabinet.
- That's strange.
- What's the matter, Chris?
- I'm sorry, but that was
Paul's favorite prelude.
I've heard him play
it a hundred times
right here in this room.
Turn it off, will you?
- No, I won't.
Look, darling.
Paul's been gone too long
for you to act like this.
- I know.
- Chris...
I'm not saying this for my sake,
but your whole
life's ahead of you.
You can't waste it
probing into the past.
If I can't make you forget Paul,
well, find someone else who can.
- You're right, Martin.
I'm sorry I acted like a child.
Would you get me a drink?
- Right here ready for you.
- So you think I should
go find somebody new?
- Oh...
Only if it's
absolutely necessary.
- But I've been so out of touch
with people lately,
especially men.
- What do you expect me
to do, bring some around?
- Well, that would
be very nice of you.
Well, you know how hard it
is for me to meet new people.
- Well, I can see I'll just
have to propose to you.
- Oh Martin, I
talked you into it.
- You sure did, and very
fortunately for you,
I just happen to have an
engagement ring on me.
- Martin, it's lovely.
Yes, Paul?
Can't you
hear the ocean calling?
Come on, Chris, race
you to the beach.
- Last one in's a coward.
- Oh!
Chris!
Chris.
Darling.
- Janet.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
The music.
Paul.
- Let me help you up.
Look darling, you
must've had a nightmare.
It's all right now.
It's over, you're
awake, and I'm here.
- Janet, it wasn't a dream.
The windows blew open.
- What's so unusual about
a window blowing open?
- My engagement ring was gone.
The flowers were all withered.
- Chris, look.
- But the picture,
Paul's picture.
You see?
Just a bad dream.
- I was awake.
My wedding gown,
there in the closet.
It came toward me,
I swear it did.
- It's just your bathrobe.
You probably pulled
the door open like this
and it flung out like that.
- My wedding dress isn't there?
How
could it be, Chris?
It's been locked in the
trunk room for years.
- It wasn't a
nightmare, I tell you.
I saw those things.
I think it was Paul and he
doesn't want me to marry.
- You got some feeling
that it's not loyal to Paul
if you marry again.
It's in your conscience
and it makes you dream.
Why don't you talk it
over with an analyst?
- He wouldn't understand.
He'd think I was losing my mind.
Nobody would understand.
Except perhaps Alexis.
- Alexis?
- Just somebody I once met.
- Come on.
Get to bed.
It's after three.
You haven't got time for
any more dreams tonight.
- Janet!
While you're up, would you
get me a glass of water?
Thanks.
Janet.
- I thought I was supposed
to be the baby in the family.
Here, give me that water.
Move over, baby.
Night, Chris.
- Night.
Childish, isn't it?
- I think the ocean and the
fog were more effective.
- I agree.
But in my work, I deal with
many different kinds of minds.
Generally speaking, I
think you could say that
three types of people
come here to see me.
The first, a very large
group, come here to scoff,
and sometimes a few of
them remain to pray.
The second have childlike,
credulous minds.
They long to believe.
They're tired and
sad and need comfort.
All this helps them.
It creates an atmosphere.
You see?
Mood, like music,
and in it, they find
a few brief moments of
comfort, which helps them
to continue with their
gray little lives.
And so I do not think it is
so childish after all, do you?
- And the third group?
- Ah.
The third group is those
of us who honestly explore
the secrets of the outer world.
I feel that you have come
here today to join that group.
- Well, I did want to talk
to you about something.
- I know.
He was close to you last night.
And he's close to
you now, but wait.
Maybe I should repel him,
not bring him closer.
- Why?
- His presence is so strong,
it might be dangerous.
- How could Paul's presence
possibly be dangerous to me?
- To your plans.
You want to get married
and lead what is
termed a normal life.
- But if Paul is
trying to reach me,
then I want to help him.
- Have you thought
what people will think?
What Martin will think?
- I'm not afraid to
think as I choose.
- Then, Christine, if
you have the courage
and the will to explore,
I will help you.
Now relax.
Let your mind be
free and receptive.
- Janet, you do have a
tendency to dramatize, and-
- Stop treating me like a child.
I tell you she's been going
to see him for weeks, and-
- Shh!
- Now do you believe me?
- Hmm.
- She's been reading
psychic books, too,
talking about Paul as
if he was still alive.
Gives me the creeps.
- Let's go.
- Now what are we gonna do?
- We're gonna get a
detective, see what he can
find out about
this spook chaser.
- For 20 years,
I've been operating
among these phony mediums
as a private detective,
and I've yet to find one
concrete bit of evidence
of communication with the dead.
- But my sister's
absolutely convinced.
He's told her things
he couldn't know,
unless he were psychic.
- He's probably gone
to a lot of trouble
to investigate her past.
They're thorough and clever.
-What I can't
understand is Christine
falling for such drivel.
- You'd be amazed
what people will do.
- No thanks.
- But there's a millionaire
right in this town
wouldn't buy a bag of popcorn
without consulting his medium.
What's this one's name?
- Alexis.
- That's a new one on me.
But then they change
their names often enough.
How about a description?
- There's a picture of him
in this pamphlet he wrote.
- Oh, this?
I used to be a magician.
That's how I got
into this racket.
I know all their tricks.
Alexis.
I was called to
Chicago on a case once,
gentleman named Maru.
Swindled a society lady out
of a whole hat full of money.
If that's Alexis, he
certainly used to look corny.
If that's
Alexis, we can
report him to the police.
What charge?
He served his stretch
and that's that.
- At least Christine'll
be through with him.
I mean, if we can
prove he's a crook.
- How can we identify him?
- Well, I could go out
there and try to get
his fingerprints, but
I think the only time
that these fakes
are really psychic
is when there's a
detective around.
- Yeah, and they look in their
crystals and see you coming.
- Maybe we could send
somebody he wouldn't know.
- Oh no, I think that...
- Your name, please.
- Harper.
Mrs. Charles Harper.
- Not Mrs. Charles G. Harper.
- Yes.
I mean no.
- Now concentrate,
and soon your thoughts
will merge with mine.
Perhaps both hands
would be better.
Yes.
So much better.
I can feel your vibrations
much more clearly now.
But your pulse is racing.
Are you excited, nervous?
- No.
- Oh, but of course this
problem is troubling you.
The question you
wrote comes to me,
but faintly, almost
as though it were...
False.
But then another
question comes through,
with all the power and
strength of love and truth.
You are concerned about
someone you love, a woman.
Your sister.
Is it your sister?
- Yes.
- Older than you,
but still you have
a maternal, protective
feeling about her.
In many ways, you are
more mature than she.
- Golly, I'm glad somebody
finally realized that.
- Of course, you didn't
always feel that way.
Once you were jealous of her.
You envied her popularity
and her pretty clothes.
You used to try them
on when she went out,
and this suited you
because there is an air
of maturity and
sophistication about you.
In many ways, especially
intellectually,
you are much older than the
many young men who admire you.
- You know, I noticed that.
- Does this feel
uncomfortable to you?
- I think I'll have a cigarette.
- Mrs. Harper?
Mrs. Harper?
May I?
- An attractive case.
- Did you know
why I wanted them?
- No.
Nor do I need to.
It is enough for me to
know that you wanted them.
- Alexis, I hope that
nothing you've done
to help my sister will get you
into trouble with the police.
I mean, if they should investigate you,
or your past life,
will they find anything that
would make trouble for you?
- No.
There are there are
many things in my life
of which I'm ashamed, but,
and this may sound strange,
the memory that I cherish
is a term in prison.
Oh.
There are many brave
men who were imprisoned
in their fight for
science and truth,
and I'm proud to be one of them.
I think you may be able
to understand this.
Oh, but anyway, do with
this as you think best.
I trust you.
- Hey Janet.
- Oh, hello, Martin.
- Did you get the fingerprints?
- Yes.
- Good.
- But I erased them.
Oh, Martin, he isn't at
all the kind of a man
we thought he was.
- Ah, hello dear, did
you get the day off?
- No time to.
Yeah, Mrs. Faber,
no, Mrs. Faber.
I'm getting sick of it.
- And how is our clown?
- She's hooked good.
- Hmm, good, she is.
And does she feel that her
beloved husband is close to her?
- I'm surprised she
hasn't me to lay
an extra place at
the dinner table.
Here's a photograph
of her parents.
It was in the trunk where
I found the wedding dress.
- Oh, that will be very useful.
- When are you gonna
put the bite on it?
- Oh, Vivian, you put
things so crudely.
I imagine that very soon,
Mrs. Faber is going to
press money on me to
continue my psychic research.
- Good.
I'm getting sick of
this Swedish accent.
I need a new role.
- Oh, I have a new
assignment for you,
straight from the
obituary column.
A lonely millionaire who...
I had no more
appointments today.
Oh, here, help me get these
things out of the way.
- What do you pay for those
chunks of glass these days?
- $3 a piece, used to $1.95.
You know, somebody
ought to do something
about this high cost of living.
- You should complain.
You're selling 'em for 25
bucks to your psychic students.
- I used to, but who am
I to fight inflation?
I'm charging 50 now.
Hmm, expensive car.
Expensive clothes.
I would say no brains
and lots of money.
So long as you're here, Vivian,
you might as well
check the car for me.
There might be some
papers or something
in the glove compartment.
- Okay.
- I'll use a turban in case
you find out something.
- Oh!
This is such a pleasure,
I mean, I've heard...
- I'd rather not
tonight, Martin, really.
I'm much too tired.
Well, let's decide
about Friday later.
Call me tomorrow.
Good night.
- Will that's be
all, Mrs. Faber?
- That's all, Emily, thanks.
Chris.
- Hmm?
- Can't you and I spend
the evening together?
If you're tired we
could go to a movie.
- Actually, I'm busy tonight,
Janet, I have an appointment.
- Chris, don't see
Alexis tonight.
Don't see him ever again.
- Janet, I thought we
agreed not to discuss this.
- I'm not attacking,
Alexis, honest.
I think he'd be very
good, for certain people.
- But not for me?
- Well, you see,
when some people meet
a fascinating
personality, they're swept
right off their feet.
Like me?
- Yes.
But other people can be
more objective, like me.
It's true, Chris, in many ways
I'm more mature than you are.
- Janet, I have lived through
most of your growing pains,
and often times you've been
insufferable, but tonight-
- You see, you
can't be objective.
You're getting sore
just because I'm trying
to give you some good advice.
- Give me advice?
Janet, please.
- It is good advice,
Alexis agrees with me.
- Alexis agrees with you?
- Well, you see, I've
talked to him a few times
about your problem.
I went to his house.
- How did you find him?
- Fascinating.
Absolutely fascinating.
You know, he has one of the
most vibrant personalities.
- And you came to
this conclusion
while discussing my problem?
- Well, we talked a
little about me, too.
- Janet...
Good night.
I'll leave you alone
with your objectivity.
- Alexis, I had to see you.
Don't pay any attention to her.
- I feel a disturbance.
If we are to reach the
outer world tonight,
we must leave behind
us all thoughts
that are hostile, and on
a low emotional level.
Now Janet, this is
your first seance.
There must be some
skepticism in your mind.
- Oh no.
- Perhaps in your subconscious
mind, but nevertheless,
we shall proceed
under test conditions.
If you would be good enough
to hold this key for me?
And Christine, will you tie
my wrists together securely?
- Oh, there's no need
to do that, Alexis.
I have every faith in you.
- Oh, but I insist,
for my own sake.
- Here, Chris, you take the
key, I'll tie his wrist.
- All right, Janet,
start with the right one.
Tie one knot in the center.
Tightly.
That's good.
Now tie my hands behind my back.
Very tightly.
Thank you.
Now lock the cabinet,
so that you know
that I cannot possibly
move from this chair.
Now Christine, will you
switch off the light?
The switch is right
in behind you.
The room must be
completely dark.
Sit down on the table.
And clasp your hands
together tightly,
with the key between your palms.
If you see anything at all,
do not move around or cry out.
- Chris, look.
I'm remembering very well.
Isn't that...
- Yes, Janet.
It's Dad.
Do you feel it, Janet?
The chill?
- Cold breeze, like ice.
I'd
sure like to know
what's going on in there.
If he's staging a seance,
it'll be a good opportunity
to prove he's a phony.
- Let's sneak around back.
There may be a window
we can look through.
- Or climb through.
- Paul.
Martin, what are you doing?
- Showing you what
a phony this man is.
Where's the key?
- If you think he's
still in here...
- What is it?
- He's quick on his feet,
I'll say that for him.
How could he get
out when I locked him in?
- He could show you
if he wanted to.
You tie a knot like
this, and then...
- Martin, this is dreadful.
- Yes it is.
I'm afraid I must insist
you don't come here again.
- Insist?
By what right do you insist?
- Well, we're engaged.
- Even if we were married,
I'd think as I pleased.
And I won't close
my mind to truth
just because you don't
happen to understand them.
- Truth, poppycock.
Be logical, Chris, be logical.
- Pardon me Mr. Abbott.
Do you think you could
possibly defer your discussion
long enough to untie this rope?
- Oh, I'm sorry
Alexis, I'll do it.
- I happen to understand
more about these things
than you do.
Do you realize that man
has a criminal record?
- Alexis told us he
was once in prison,
if that's what you mean.
- Sometimes a prison record
is something to be proud of.
- I'm terribly sorry about
this interruption, Alexis.
I saw him, I saw Paul.
- Oh, we will bring him back.
- Even if you could
bring him back,
she'd be better off if he
stayed where he is, dead.
She never meant anything
to him but money.
- Martin!
- He'd been married
and divorced before,
each time with cash settlements.
If he'd lived, he'd
have made you miserable
and ended up where
he belongs, in jail.
I never
thought you'd attack
a dead man with lazycan answers.
- Chris, it's in the records.
When Martin disappeared,
did you or did you not
ask me to investigate?
Yes.
- Well, in the course
of my snooping,
I found a second Mrs.
Faber, divorced in Las Vegas
just six months
before he married you.
I think he went over
there to see her.
I never could find her,
though, and Paul was dead, so-
- Seems very strange
that, if it were true,
you didn't find it necessary
to tell Mrs. Faber.
- Yes, I suppose it is strange.
And very silly to try and
protect the girl you love.
She only runs as fast as she
can to another phony like you.
Come on, Hoffmann,
let's get outta here.
- Going so soon?
I hoped we might
stay around a while.
- You should stay.
You'd soon learn what
amazing powers Alexis has.
- I'm always willing to learn.
Perhaps you'd like
to resume the seance.
- Yes, under real
test conditions.
- And have you report me
for conducting a seance?
I should say not.
- He probably could
report you now,
but if you'll sit down
here at this table,
and while we all hold hands
like real good friends,
you can make any of your
spirits walk or talk,
I think Mr. Hoffman will
let it ride this time.
- It's ridiculous.
- Show them, Alexis.
- Yes, Alexis.
Do.
- I'm afraid under such
hostile circumstances,
any contact with a spirit world
will be practically impossible.
- Yeah, yeah, I've heard
that patter routine before.
I know it's easier when you can
run around the room in the dark.
- He doesn't run
around in the dark.
Go on, Alexis, let them see
for themselves what you can do.
- Okay let's go.
Ah.
- You know you really
ought to have a hand
on the premises for
tight spots like this.
- We checked, you see,
to make sure you hadn't.
- Shh, you talk so loud.
You mean we'll frighten
the ghosts?
Christine.
-You see?
- It's Paul.
It's his voice.
I didn't mean
to frighten you ever,
but I had to get
through to you somehow.
I've always loved
you, you know that.
- Yes, Paul.
- And if you could only believe,
we could be together for always.
- There wasn't
anybody out there.
- 20 years, never
anything like this.
- If everybody will excuse me,
this has been a terrible strain.
- Come on, Chris,
I'll take you home.
- Let's go.
- What are you so
startled about?
You're used to raising
the dead, aren't you?
Although I guess with me,
it was a little easier,
because I'm only legally dead.
You know, I've
been watching you,
ever since my widow started
coming to you, Alexis.
I find your methods
quite amusing.
Hmm.
Excellent.
How do you get out
of that rope thing?
- Manipulation.
But how do you-
- The cabinet?
Just push a button
and the idiots
reach for their checkbooks.
- It isn't quite as
simple as all that.
There's a lot of psychology
involved, and research.
- Sounds dangerously like work.
However, your bag of
tricks can be useful to us
in our present plans.
- We have plans?
- I didn't help you out tonight
just for the fun
of it, my friend.
I can use you.
You see, I need
money, a lot of it.
- I don't understand.
If you went back to Christine,
you could have
anything you want.
- You don't seem to have
a very analytical mind.
- I know that Christine
still loves you, she...
Oh.
You mean if you weren't
dead, the police
might want to know
who it was they found
burned to death in your car.
- Mm-hmm, exactly.
- Have I been using the
wrong piece of music?
- What?
Oh no, no, no.
You have the right
one for Christine.
I used this one
for my first wife.
- Was it her ashes
they found in the car?
- It was me they found in
the car, and don't forget it.
Perhaps I should
point out that I'm
in a very curious position.
Since I'm believed dead,
I could even kill a man.
Nobody'd think of
looking for me.
You're in a curious
position, too, Alexis.
You can't tell anybody I'm
alive without exposing yourself.
- That's right, I can't.
It is a very curious position.
- And a profitable one.
I don't think it's too
premature to congratulate you
upon an extremely
advantageous marriage.
- Marriage?
- Come come, my friend.
You must be prepared to
make some small sacrifice.
- You don't expect me
to marry Christine?
- No, no, the little one, Janet.
She's still young enough
to be dazzled by you.
From then on,
getting that estate
will be like taking
candy away from a baby.
- I don't think
Christine would allow it.
- I'll take care of Christine.
I'm a little rusty on this
one, I'll have to practice.
Have this piano tuned, will you?
- Thanks.
- Oh, no ma'am, not
for you, not after
the night you've been having.
And that's for you.
- Hot milk?
- Yes ma'am.
- I'd rather have coffee.
- I'll see that she
drinks it, Emily.
- All right, I'll take it,
but it won't do any good.
- You should really try and
get more sleep, Christine.
-I just can't.
I'm never alone anymore.
I keep hearing his voice
now and seeing his face.
It should comfort me, I suppose,
but it's been frightening.
- Drink your milk while
it's hot, it'll help.
- Alexis, do you suppose
we've made a mistake?
That first day when
I came to your house,
you said it might be better
to repel Paul's spirit
instead of bringing it closer.
Perhaps you were right.
- Perhaps I was right.
- Then would it be
better to try to
break the contact
now, and not go-
- It's too late.
At this stage I could
never break the contact.
We'll have to finish
what we started.
- It would only bring me rest.
Well, let's begin
the seance now.
- I think that before we
start, you should relax,
and I should be more familiar
with the surroundings.
It is very difficult for
me in a strange house.
Perhaps if I walked around
the outside for a while.
- I'll show you.
We can even go to the ocean.
- Go ahead, Janet, I'm
feeling rather tired.
- Watch your step,
it's awfully steep.
You know, I think I have
talent along spirit lines.
- You do?
- Yes.
I've been reading and studying.
I think maybe I'm even a mystic.
- Oh?
- You know, that seance we had
at your house when
Paul appeared?
- Yeah.
- Was that Paul's
first visitation?
Alexis?
- Oh, oh yes, it was.
- You see, maybe it's
because I was there,
all tuned in and sensitive.
Well, it could be.
Did you ever see a better
spirit manifestation?
- No, darling, that
was an all-time record.
- Are you thinking
about my sister?
- Yes.
- She's very
attractive, isn't she?
Most men admire Chris.
- But Christine will
always belong to Paul.
- I suppose that's true.
I wish she wouldn't
be so unhappy.
Do you suppose they'll be
joined together someday,
in celestial companionship,
through all eternity,
like it says in the books?
- Yes, I'm sure they will.
- Alexis.
Do you think I'd make a
good celestial companion?
- Darling, I think
you'd be wonderful.
- And we'd love each other
through all eternity?
- Oh, even longer.
- Alexis, why don't we start
right here on the Earth plane?
- I've come for you, dear.
Hurry, Chris.
- Paul, wait.
I'm frightened.
- There's nothing
to be afraid of.
- Paul, I'm afraid.
- Race you to the beach.
- Last one in's a coward.
- Alexis, she's not badly hurt.
She's all right?
- I think she's all right.
What
are you doing here?
- Well, at the moment,
I'm opening the door,
but not very wide.
You're not exactly welcome here.
- Where's Emily?
- It's Thursday, Mr.
Abbott, her day off.
- Where's Frieda?
- Frieda left yesterday.
She said she thought
the house was haunted.
I see what she means.
I want to talk to Mrs. Faber.
- I don't think she
wants to talk to you.
- Janet.
Where's Chris?
- She left.
- She's making herself ill
with this morbid nonsense.
- Oh, it isn't that.
Chris had a fall last
night on the cliff.
She might have killed herself
if Alexis hadn't caught her.
What was
she doing on the cliff?
- Well...
She thought she
heard Paul calling.
- Janet?
We'll always
be together, Chris.
Together for always.
- Yes, Paul.
- You'll always be mine, Chris.
Chris, I'm waiting.
We'll be together,
Chris, together always.
- What'd the doctor say?
- Chris wouldn't have a doctor.
- You've got to be
logical about this.
- She's not badly hurt.
She's just bruised and shaken.
- Well, in the first place,
she's in a state of hysteria.
In the second place, she
shouldn't be in this house.
Everything in it
reminds her of Paul.
And finally, she shouldn't
be left alone for one second.
There's no telling
what she might do.
- But I'm with her all the time.
I haven't left...
Chris!
Martin!
Chris.
- Martin.
- Chris, are you all right?
- Yes, of course.
- What's in that bottle?
- It's just aspirin.
I've got a headache.
- Chris, it's dangerous
for you to stay here.
You need rest and care,
perhaps in a hospital.
- You're trying to separate us.
I won't go to a hospital.
I won't leave this house.
- Only until you're better.
- No!
You'd try to drive
him away again.
Now get out.
Get out.
- I'll leave before
I upset her any more.
- I'll see you to
the door, Martin.
- They've left the room.
- Then you can
resume the treatment?
- If you hadn't tried to
play the hero last night,
all this wouldn't be necessary.
- I had to save Janet, didn't I?
- You're not falling in
love with her, are you?
- Look, if I'm going to
marry into this estate,
there's got to be
somebody for me to marry.
- Just by way of
making conversation,
that wife of mine in Las
Vegas, the one who tried
to back out on me and wanted
the cash settlement back,
I settled with her,
but not for cash.
Now, if you should
back out on me,
I wouldn't hesitate to settle
with you either, Alexis.
- I know, because you're
in such a curious position.
- Paul?
Paul.
- How long, Chris?
How long must I wait?
- Janet, get out of here.
- Why didn't you tell me
you wanted money that badly?
I'd have given it to
you just to get rid...
Paul.
- Yes, I'm alive.
Legally I'm dead, I'm
going to stay that way.
If you're alive, I
won't be able to.
It's too bad you came
down here, Janet.
- Operator, get
me Bradshaw 7425.
Martin, this is...
Martin!
- Operator.
- Chris, Chris, wake up.
I can't explain, quick,
we'll take the back stairs.
- Paul.
You forgot, Paul.
My profession is
raising the dead.
- You're losing quite a bit
of blood, aren't you Alexis?
- Spirits don't need any blood.
Do you think bullets
can harm us ghosts?
Too bad you missed.
Those were...
Your last...
Two shots.
The police are here, my friend.
Your gun is empty.
For the police, you
have been privileged
to witness my best performance.
- You made one little mistake.
I started with seven shells.
I have one in the chamber.
- Alexis, you were wonderful.
- Yes, I guess there must be
a better side to my nature.
But now you must forget me.
- No, never.
-I don't need a
crystal to see that
your future is bright, Janet.
Don't you go
clinging to the past.
I lived by feeding people's
desire to escape the present.
But you can't escape for long.
- Alexis, I'm afraid for you.
- Oh, I'll be all right.
I'll find some spirits that
want to contact people.
Open the window, Janet, please.
Fly away, my friend.
I won't need you any more.