[MUSIC PLAYING]
[CLOCK CHIMES]
[DOG BARKING AND HOWLING]
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
But how else can we explain
these terrible deaths?
Von Ilse last night.
Five others before him.
That's six within as
many weeks, Inspector.
Our friends, neighbors that
we've known for years, drained
Of their life's
blood, found dead
In bed, likely skeletons
of skin and bone.
Vampires are at large,
I tell you, vampires!
Yeah, malignant demons who
issue forth from their graves
In the dead of night
to attack their victims
And drink the blood
from their veins.
Brr!
God in heaven,
Brettschneider, don't jest!
Ah, that blood-sucking legend
belongs in the same category
With werewolves and all
other peasant superstitions.
But the bats, man!
The bats!
God, yes!
Big ones, so!
Oh, now we're
switching to bats again.
There was an epidemic of giant
bats in Klineschloss in 1643.
And at the same time, there
was an outbreak of vampirism.
Rot!
Why, this record from the
town archives proves it.
Says it, not proves it.
Well, I'll show you.
I'll show you.
Now, ah, here it is.
"And on this day was
von Hausmen hanged"
From a gibbet in
the public square
After being convicted on a
proven charge of vampirism.
And on this same day, there
did occur the departure
Of the bats, thousands of
horrible flying creatures
Which infested the
town for weeks.
And on the night
of this same day,
February 13 in the year of our
Lord, 1643, was there a stake
Driven through von
Hausmen's heart
"And his head cut off with
a gravedigger's shovel."
There.
Well, all the
records in the world
Can't make me
believe in vampires.
There are bloodsucking
bats, yes,
In South America, thousands
of miles from here.
But not in Klineschloss.
But bats fly!
They could fly here!
You saw the
buggers, all of them.
Two wounds on the neck,
right at the jugular vein.
pierced and spread apart
Just as if two
fang-like teeth had
Bitten through the flesh
and right into the veins.
And in every case, a blood clot,
eight inches from the victim's
Neck, the mark of the feast,
the devil's signature.
Does that appear the mark of
a human being or a demon's?
God save us, the devil's.
You ought to make a pretty
fair meal for a vampire.
But let's be consistent.
Are these human
vampires or... or bats?
Vampires can take the
shape of a human or a bat,
Just as they choose.
Oh.
They're magicians.
Well, it doesn't
make sense to me.
The whole village is in terror.
We live in closed houses,
behind locked doors and bolted
Shutters, not daring
to close our eyes,
Fearful lest this unseen, silent
death may find us in our sleep.
For it is then that it strikes,
swiftly, silently, ghastly.
My room is tightly closed.
The windows are
barred, nailed down!
Nothing can get in, nothing!
But they tell me vampires
can go through stone walls,
Like that.
God save me, so they can!
We've got to do
something, I tell you!
Klineschloss will become
a deserted village.
Well, you might
capture all the bats
And drown them in the river.
Karl!
While you're hunting for
vampires and chasing bats,
I'm looking for a human
being, a murderer, a thief!
Well then, don't jest about it.
Do something!
I'm trying to!
Every hour, every day, every
night since this thing started!
[DOG BARKING AND HOWLING]
Do you hear it?
Yes!
Night after night, lying
awake until dawn, waiting!
For what?
I don't know.
That's what I thought.
Good night, gentlemen.
Don't let the vampires get you.
[POP]
[LAUGHS]
Are your kisses dynamite!
Don't you like my kisses?
Well, how's my
mastermind this evening.
Well, if you want the
truth, not so good.
The Burgermeister
and his grand council
Still stick to the
vampire theory, huh?
Stick to it?
Ha!
They're quoting
history to prove it.
I think you and Dr. von
Niemang are the only
Sane people left in the village.
And you?
What about you?
Hmm, me.
Well, I'm beginning
to think I'm seven
Different kinds of a fool.
Murders are being done
under my very nose.
I must be as blind as
the bats themselves.
I can't find a single clue.
Oh, but you will,
Karl, you will.
Well, I haven't.
AUNT GUSSIE: Oh, Ruth!
And here comes dear Aunt Gussie
to spread good cheer and hope.
Just what I thought,
slaving your life away
In this awful place.
It hasn't got that nice, plain,
wholesome smell of a hospital.
How are you, Karl?
Oh, quite well, thank you.
Well, I'm not.
This clammy old place is
bound to give me pericarditis,
[INAUDIBLE], neuritis,
[INAUDIBLE]...
Well anyway, Ruth.
You want some coffee?
No, no thank you,
Frau Schappmann.
Well, just as well.
There's only two cups.
Here, dear.
Anything to chill
out your bones.
Thank you.
Speaking of chills,
Frau Schappmann,
Did you know the
villagers are supposed
To be infested with
ghouls and vampires?
Oh, Karl!
Vampires!
Pariahs among fiends,
demoniacal creatures
With huge canine
teeth who bite deeply
Into the necks of
their victims, to quaff
And gorge on blood,
warm human blood!
There's no such thing as a
vampire, Karl Brettschneider.
I don't believe in it.
You're just saying
that to frighten me.
And I just won't be frightened.
I'm entirely too sensible
to believe in such rubbish.
I beg pardon.
[GASPS] Oh, that was you.
I'm sorry if I frightened you.
Who said you frightened me?
I'm not afraid of anything.
Could you tell me where
Dr. von Niemann is?
Well, he drove to
the village to see
Martha, the old apple woman.
Thank you.
Is this what Dr.
Hobb prescribed?
Yes, sir.
She takes it in water.
Hmm.
Well, continue giving it to her.
Yes, sir.
It's stifiling in here.
Open these windows.
Herman open windows.
Me do, me do.
[SIGH] Well, she'll
sleep well now, poor soul.
It won't be necessary
for you to stay here.
A good night's sleep will
work wonders for her.
It was kind of you
to come, Doctor.
Oh, Martha has sold me
apples for many years,
Always the good,
ripe, juicy ones.
Martha give me apples!
I like!
[LAUGHS]
Shh!
Oh, to think.
[MOANS]
DR. VON NIEMANN:
She wants her cross.
Herman get.
Here.
Now that for Martha.
There.
Oh!
She won't let it
out of her sight.
A terrible experience.
To be attacked by a giant
bat is enough to shatter
Anyone's nerves.
She talks about it all the
time, how it flew in her face
And tried to sink its
teeth in her throat.
No, no, no, no.
Bats no do!
They soft, like cat.
They not bite Herman!
[CRIES OUT]
[INAUDIBLE] see
what you've done?
There, there.
There, Martha, there.
Shh.
[CRYING SLOWS]
She'll be all right.
If she isn't, let me know.
Thank you for coming, Doctor.
That's all right.
Goodnight.
Run along, Herman.
You can see Martha tomorrow.
Oh.
Ah, Dr. von Niemann.
Ah, Kringen, how are you?
Much better, thank
you kindly sir,
Since you prescribed for me.
That's right.
Go to bed, Herman.
Go to bed!
You shouldn't be filing
around the streets.
It's dangerous!
Oh.
I'm afraid.
Afraid?
Afraid of what, Kringen?
The bats, sir.
Big giant bats, with
wings like an eagle.
DR. VON NIEMANN: You
saw this bat, you say?
I saw it swooping
down the street.
It came directly
for my throat, sir.
When was this, Kringen?
Last night when they
came to take von Ilse.
It was a big, monstrous thing.
I saw it leap across the
alley and into a window.
I ran just as fast as
my legs could carry me.
You said nothing about this?
There's enough fear
in the village already.
Maybe I should.
Maybe I sh... I will.
I'll tell the Burgermeister.
Yes, Kringen.
That's the thing to do.
No!
Bats... bats good!
They not hurt Herman.
He plays with them.
You... you no tell!
No.
No, no, no, go to bed, Herman.
Go on.
Go on, go to bed!
You say he plays with bats?
His garret is filled with them.
He makes pets of them.
That's odd.
Very odd.
Maybe... maybe he's it.
Herman prowls around the
streets all hours of the night,
Just like an animal.
Maybe he's the vampire.
Now, don't start any
gossip with that, Kringen.
Heaven only knows
where it might end.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, sir.
There.
Now.
So nice.
There.
See?
What did I tell you?
Perhaps there's something
in what Kringen says.
Seems strange
that a human being
Should want to play with bats.
[GROWLS]
[LAUGHS]
He isn't human, I tell you!
He's in league with the devil!
Put it on.
There.
Now, go to sleep.
You'll be all right
in a few days.
The doctor says so.
Close the window.
Close the window!
I'm afraid!
The vampire!
He said leave them open.
But I'd have them closed.
Do you want the light?
Leave the light.
I'm afraid.
Well, I can't blame
you for that, either.
I'll turn it down a little.
Goodnight.
If you want me, just
pound on the floor.
I'll hear you.
All right.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Martha.
Ohh.
Herr Brettschneider is
here to see you, sir.
He's in the laboratory
with Miss Bertin.
Oh, thank you.
Ah, here you are!
Good evening, Doctor.
Good evening, Ruth.
How are you, Karl?
Well, I'd feel a
lot better if I could
Find the solution
to these murders.
You don't believe in
this vampire theory, then?
[SCOFFS] Of course not.
Do you?
There are many strange
happenings, my boy,
Many mysteries beyond the
power of the human mind
To comprehend.
Have you a theory which
might explain these deaths?
Well, I'll be pleased to
discuss it with you, but,
Uh, not now, now now.
I have some very
important work to do.
Well, tomorrow then.
Tomorrow?
Yes, perhaps.
Uh, we'll see.
Oh, this isn't so
important, Miss Bertin,
That you can't let
it go till tomorrow.
All right, thank you, Doctor.
Oh, uh, how about Martha?
Huh?
Oh, nothing serious.
Just a case of
nerves, after all.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Doctor.
Goodnight, Karl.
[FOOTSTEPS WALKING AWAY]
[CLOCK CHIMING]
[SCREAMS]
HOBB: Name?
SAUER: Martha Mueller.
HOBB: Age?
I don't know.
Cause of death?
Like all the rest.
A vampire.
Yes, yes, that's right.
When I said I was
going to tell you,
His eyes burned up
like coals of fire.
His hand reached
out toward me, as
If he were gonna sink
it into my throat.
And weigh this well.
He never works and
never bathes, and yet he
Appears well fed always.
That's so.
He does.
Well, what does
he live on, then?
I'll wager it's as Kringen says.
And my [INAUDIBLE]
was in Martha's room
Tonight, when Herman put
a flower in her hand.
Strange business if you
ask me, mighty strange.
I hate it when [INAUDIBLE].
Yes.
After what's happened tonight
I've locked myself in my room
And prayed God to protect
me from the devil!
[CROWD CHATTERING]
MAN IN CROWD: Dr. von Niemann!
Dr. von Niemann!
[SCREAMS]
Well, what do you
make of it, Doctor?
Are these two wounds
similar to those
Found in the other bodies?
Dr. Hobb can answer
that for you, sir.
Yes, they were the
same in every case.
This is a strange
condition, Karl.
So strange that I doubt
the evidence of my eyes.
What was your conclusion, Hobb?
I diagnosed the wounds as
having been made by needle
Sharp teeth,
punctures [INAUDIBLE]
Penetrating into but not
beyond the jugular veins.
Do you mean to
say that you also
Believe they could have
been made by teeth?
Frankly, I do.
Ha, you see, Brettschneider?
What kind of teeth, Doctor?
An animal of some sort.
It's hard to say.
The fangs of a wolf, perhaps.
A werewolf.
Could they have been made
by, well, a bat, for instance?
DR. VON NIEMANN: A
certain species, yes.
There are vampire bats.
Dr. William Garrison,
[INAUDIBLE] the perimeters
Of the upper Amazon, states
that bloodsucking bats do exist.
He further asserted
that the victims often
Become blood
drinkers themselves,
Citing a case in which he
saw a native [INAUDIBLE]
By his tribe brothers.
They swore he had
become a human bat.
And, states Garrison,
he confessed it.
KARL: Do you mean to say that
such a thing as a human vampire
Is possible?
Who can say.
Historic records would have
us believe that an evil soul,
Assuming there is such, can
take any shape it pleases.
So why not [INAUDIBLE]
that of a human being.
Eh, Karl?
Why not?
Have you any literature
on the topic, Doctor?
Yes, I have many interesting
volumes on my shelf
That might prove
very enlightening.
I'll be glad to
show them to you.
I don't mind admitting
that I'm up a tree.
Stumped.
Well, we'll see what
can be done, my boy.
No, no, no, Herman.
This is no place for you.
Go in, my boy.
Go in.
DR. VON NIEMANN:
Goodnight, John.
JOHN: Goodnight, Doctor.
DR. VON NIEMANN:
Goodnight, Hobb.
Uh, goodnight, Doctor.
DR. VON NIEMANN: In
the morning, Karl.
KARL: Thank you, Doctor.
I'm sorry to have dragged you
out at such an ungodly hour.
DR. VON NIEMANN: Oh, that's
all right, that's all right.
Ah!
Ahh!
A child, fleeing in horror
from the sight of death.
That was the vampire.
Arrest him!
Lock him up!
Kill him!
Has the entire
village gone mad?
Herman wouldn't harm a
baby, and you know it!
I've walk the streets of this
village for over 40 years,
But tonight's the end.
He knows that I've told
he plays with bats.
He knows that I saw
him sneak into Martha's
House just before midnight.
Perhaps he was taking her
another flower, Kringen.
The boy brought her one this
evening while I was there.
He killed her just like
he did all the rest!
And now he's gonna kill me.
Unless he's killed and a stake
driven through his heart,
I'm a doomed man!
He'll kill me!
I'm doomed!
I'm a doomed man!
He'll kill me!
Good morning, Mr.
Brettschneider.
What brings you to
Klineschloss so early?
You.
Fibber.
I heard the doctor tell
Georgiana he expected you.
I knew there was
something else.
You're a delightful
prevaricator,
Karl, but not a
very convincing one.
Oh, you don't mind me
using your stethoscope,
Do you, Doctor?
Not at all, Frau Schnappman.
What seems to be the
ailment this morning?
What's that?
Oh!
What seems to be the
ailment this morning?
Well, Doctor, I
am positive that I
Have valvular
disease of the aorta.
Or maybe it's the, um,
the right ventricle.
Hm.
Well, there's something
wrong with my heart.
I can hear it beat
thump, thump, thump,
Thump, just like the book says.
Well, if you didn't hear it
beating thump, thump, thump,
Just as the book says, I would
say there is something wrong.
What?
Without a moon?
You have a heart of stone.
All right then,
close your eyes.
Now.
Oh, so young lady!
It's too early in the
morning, Karl, much too early.
Oh, is it?
[GASPS] Oh,
there's Aunt Gussie.
Hmm, she would show up
just at a time like this.
Oh, oh!
[SIGHING]
Well, Aunt Gussie,
what's the matter now?
An [INAUDIBLE] of the
auricular, ventricular
Microvalves, to the [INAUDIBLE].
You mean your heart's beating.
Of course it's beating.
Dr. von Niemann
tried to assure me.
But I know, I know it's serious.
I'm liable to go just like that.
Did he prescribe for you, dear?
Yes.
[INAUDIBLE] chloric acid.
You mean salicylic
acid, don't you?
Well, silasalic or
salicylic, it [INAUDIBLE].
My heart is much quieter.
Hello, Karl.
Hello.
Oh, Karl.
You will be good to Ruth
when I'm gone, won't you?
Yes, of course I
will, Frau Schnappman.
Well, I'm not gone yet.
And you can't marry
her unless I say so.
Don't forget that.
Oh, my heart!
There, Auntie,
you'll be all right.
Just rest a while.
What you need is...
Rest?
Rest, dear, and quiet.
[GROANS]
Aunt Gussie has a heart
like a steam engine.
Karl! [LAUGHS]
[MEOWING]
Here, kitty, kitty.
Kitty, kitty!
Kitty-poo!
Come on!
Come on, kitty-poo.
Where are you, baby?
Come on!
Come on, kitty,
kitty, kitty poo.
Come on... [GASPS] Ew!
[INAUDIBLE]
Nasty little beast!
Oh!
Don't you know it's
wrong to steal?
[GASPS]
You'll cut yourself.
[INAUDIBLE] blood.
Ew!
Stop it, stop it!
No hurt me.
No hurt!
Oh, you poor thing.
Now, you wait right here,
and I'll run in the house
And get something
for that finger.
A subcutaneous wound
like that might easily
Result in a tetanus infection.
Tetan... tetan...
Tetanus Lockjaw.
Not that you need be afraid!
From the way you talk I
think you've got it already.
Look, here's a nice
juicy apple for you.
Mm!
[SIGHS]
Ah, this is it.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH] by
Augusta Dom Calimay in 1746.
Huh.
"Let us suppose that these
corpses do not actually"
Stir from their tombs,
that only the ghosts
Or spirits appear to the living.
Wherefore do these
phantoms present themselves
And what is it that
energizes them?
Is it actually the soul of
a dead man which has not
Yet departed to its
final destination?
Or"...
AUNT GUSSIE: [INAUDIBLE] Now,
how could a corpse buried
Under four or five
feet of earth get
Out to do any such foolishness?
I don't believe it.
It's a fair question, Doctor.
How could it?
Well, according
to accepted theory,
The vampire
dematerializes the body
And reintegrates it
outside the grave.
A good explanation
if you can believe it.
And while I'm standing here
listening to all this rubbish,
There's a poor man in
the garden in danger
Of a tetanus infection.
Now, what should I
do for him, Doctor?
Shall I apply [INAUDIBLE] or a
tube saturation of [INAUDIBLE]?
Well, either will do.
Get some gauze and
some material from...
Thank you, Doctor.
I'll wait here.
Difficult to believe, isn't it?
It's impossible to believe.
And yet it would explain
these deaths, wouldn't it?
Ah, Brettschneider.
Pardon our intrusion,
Dr. von Niemann.
But after what you
saw last night,
You'll be interested
in this as well.
What's happened?
Kringen was found dead an hour
ago, with the two punctures
In his neck and not a
drop of blood in his body.
And what's more, Herman
Gleib has disappeared.
What?
Now are you convinced that we
were right and you were wrong?
This ought to be proof
enough for anybody.
Kringen said Herman
would get him and he did.
Well, Brettschneider?
I appoint you my deputy.
Organize a searching party
and comb this countryside
From one end to the other.
Find Herman Gleib and bring
him in, but don't harm him.
You understand?
What good will that do?
He's a vampire.
There's only one thing for
us to do when we find him,
Kill him and drive a
stake through his heart.
Herman Gleib will be
tried by a court of law!
If the charge against
him is proven true,
The law will decide what
to do with him, not you.
Now get your men together
and do as I tell you.
That's a way to talk.
I'm going into town for
a little while, Doctor.
Would you care to come along?
Oh, I hardly believe so.
There's little to be done
till they find the boy.
If you need me then, I...
All right, thanks.
I'll let you know.
I feel as though
I'm going to faint.
There, Auntie, there's
nothing here to be afraid of.
[INAUDIBLE]
Run along now and take care
of that patient of yours.
Oh, heavens.
I forgot all about him.
Oh, my heart!
Oh!
Poor Auntie.
She's has every
ailment in the book.
Your [INAUDIBLE]
aunt, I'm afraid.
Particularly a palpitation
of the [INAUDIBLE] ventricular
Tricuspid and
microvalve, Doctor.
Well, I had to tell her
something to satisfy her.
[LAUGHS]
There, there, you
mustn't do that.
Now, where's that finger?
You good like Martha.
She give me apples.
Herman like you.
Are you Herman?
Me Herman.
You give me apple, Herman
give you nice soft bat.
[DOG BARKING]
[SCREAMS]
[BARKING]
[MOANING]
[SCREAMING]
[INAUDIBLE]
What is it, Georgiana?
I just found this
in Emil's room.
Well?
GEORGIANA: It belonged to
my friend, Martha Mueller.
Are you certain?
I gave it to her myself.
Martha died last night.
I find her crucifix
in Emil's room.
Doesn't that mean
Emil is the one
Herr Brettschneider was seeking?
This amazes me, Georgiana.
It's impossible.
It rained the
night von Ilse died.
There was mud of Emil's
shoes the next morning.
Have you mentioned
this to anyone?
I intend to tell
Herr Brettschneider
When he calls again.
I can't believe it.
Uh, leave this with me.
I want to talk to Emil before
you say anything to anyone.
The Burgermeister
should know at once.
Yes, all in good time.
Emil is going to
be too [INAUDIBLE]
For us to jump to conclusions.
Don't say anything
until I tell you.
And send Emil to me.
Very well, Doctor.
That's for the muritis.
And the [INAUDIBLE].
Is tougher than shoe leather.
And [INAUDIBLE].
That'll help if I
come into any harm.
And, uh, ginger... [BURPS]
that'll warm my stomach.
Now, a little
[INAUDIBLE] of soda.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Ooh!
[BURPS]
[MEN SHOUTING ANGRILY]
[DOGS BARKING AND HOWLING]
Come on, men!
We've got him!
He can't get away from here now!
Come on, he's around that way!
If he tries to get past
you, you know what to do!
[DOGS BARKING]
There he is, [INAUDIBLE].
Here, boys!
Herman?
You're going back to
the village with us.
Come on.
We won't hurt you.
No.
No, won't go!
Herman afraid!
Come on!
You're going with us, Herman!
No!
You're going with us!
Come on.
Come on!
Get him!
[DOG BARKING]
Come on, Herman,
we won't hurt you.
Come on, Herman.
No!
No.
[SCREAMS]
[DOGS HOWLING]
Come, [INAUDIBLE].
You've got to make certain.
I won't go down there.
Nobody asked you to.
I'll go myself.
Can you see him?
He's on a ledge
about 50 feet down.
I'll get a rope.
We've got to make
certain, I tell you.
You must be careful, Emil.
Very careful.
No.
It must be.
She's no better than the rest.
I've got to go on.
[MOTOR WHIRRING]
[BELL RINGING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Oh, it's you, Doctor.
Good evening.
I'm sorry to have to
disturb you, Doctor,
But we simply couldn't make
Georgiana hear the bell.
That's quite all
right, my dear.
Georgiana's becoming
careless, very careless.
Yes, I've noticed that too.
In my opinion, she
has [INAUDIBLE].
That's hidden sickness.
You know [INAUDIBLE].
At first I thought
it was [INAUDIBLE],
So I stuck a pin
in her leg to see.
And there was a splendid
reaction of the, uh,
Reflex motor [INAUDIBLE].
Why, Auntie.
Ha, you're shocked.
So was she.
Won't you join
me in some coffee?
Yes, thanks Doctor, we will.
There are a few questions
I'd like to ask you about.
About blood and murders
and vampires, I suppose.
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Well, so am I. Well, goodnight.
If such a thing is
possible I'm going to bed.
Won't you join us
too, Frau Schnappman.
Coffee at this
time of the night?
No thank you.
I'm going to stick
to my [INAUDIBLE]
Summer salad. [INAUDIBLE].
Goodnight!
What's the news in
the village, Karl?
Have they located Herman yet?
No, not a trace of him.
I hate to think of
that poor misfit
Being hunted down like a dog.
You know, I simply
can't bring myself
To believe in that
vampire theory.
Uh, would you pour, Ruth?
Certainly.
I know, Karl.
[INAUDIBLE] common judgment
tells us that such things can't
Be, and yet here, for instance,
in this ponderous tome
Are cited 1,0001
phobias and complexes
That human beings are err to.
Some of them are strange,
more untenable even
Than werewolves and vampires.
Uh, could I have
some more, please?
You drink entirely
too much coffee.
It's my one weakness.
And also my excuse for
tolerating Georgiana's
Laxity in other things.
She does know how
to make good coffee.
Thank you.
She brings it to me every
night at exactly 10 o'clock.
And when I've drunk it all,
then I know it's time to quit.
Yes, and eat breakfast so
you can have more coffee.
Oh.
[CHUCKLES]
Georgiana, you
mustn't lie like that!
You'll get yourself [INAUDIBLE].
G... Georgiana?
[SCREAMS]
That was Auntie!
Auntie!
Oh!
I'm all right.
I'm all right now.
Emil, help Frau
Schnappman [INAUDIBLE].
AUNT GUSSIE: [INAUDIBLE].
[SCREAMS]
It's OK.
Don't be afraid.
The same two wounds, Doctor.
And my last words to her
were angry ones, a petulant
Reprimand for being
late with my coffee.
What time was that?
About two or three
minutes after 10:00.
She's been then
about 45 minutes.
Bloodless, like the rest.
Passes all belief!
Ruth's aunt saw Herman Gleib
in the garden this morning.
Could it be that he...?
You were the first one here.
What happened?
I was in my room reading.
My door was open.
I must have dozed off
for a minute or so,
Because I awoke to hear
Frau Schnappman scream.
You say your door was open?
Yes, my room was very
poorly ventilated.
And you saw nothing?
Heard nothing unusual?
EMIL: Nothing.
Karl.
What is it?
This crucifix
belonged to Martha.
[BELL RINGING]
See who it is, Emil.
Can you positively identify
this as belonging to Martha?
Without a doubt.
I saw it in her room
the night she died.
How in the world
did it get here?
Herman Gleib was in her room.
He had that crucifix
in his hands.
And Herman was here today.
Maybe here now,
for all we know.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Who is it?
KARL: Karl:
Oh.
How is she?
She's had a real shock this
time, but she'll be all right.
I'm putting her to bed.
Leave her there.
Don't let her out of this room.
And don't you leave it, either.
Well, what do you mean?
It looks as if Herman Gleib
is the killer after all.
It's possible he may be
hiding here in the castle.
What makes you think so?
I'll tell you later.
Stay in your room and
keep your door locked.
Don't worry about that.
I heard every word he said.
And I don't think
there's any use
Of them searching for Herman.
They should look for a
dog, a human-faced dog.
Auntie, the doors and
windows are all locked.
There's nothing to
be afraid of now.
Well, who said I was afraid?
I'm not a bit afraid.
No, of course
you're not afraid,
But you must get some rest.
Rest in this awful place?
With dog-faced Hermans
and human-faced bats
And bloods and
murders and vampires!
Find anything, Karl?
There's an unbroken
cup over in that window.
If Herman did it, he
came through the door.
He must've.
And yet I don't understand
how he could find
His way up here
without us hearing him.
Yet Emil was asleep, and
I was in the library.
Yes, he could have done it.
The facts all point to it.
What was it, Emil?
The Burgermeister.
He has new for Herr
Brettschneider about Herman.
Huh.
Pardon the intrusion,
Doctor, pardon the intrusion.
I knew Karl was here and
I though you wouldn't mind
If I ran in to
tell him the news.
About Herman?
Yes.
He fell into the Devil's
Well in the cave.
KARL: He's dead?
BURGERMEISTER:
Dead as a doornail.
This ends our troubles, Karl!
The vampire's dead!
I can feel it in my bones!
Hmm.
Well your bones may be wrong.
What time did this happen?
BURGERMEISTER: Quite
early, about 9 o'clock.
The cave is nearly
two hours from here.
That's why we didn't
hear it sooner.
Well, it may interest
you to know that there's
Been another death,
after your vampire died.
Who?
Dr. Niemann's housekeeper,
right here in her own room.
Mother of mercy!
What are we going to do?
But a natural death wouldn't
kill a vampire, Karl.
You know the expected theory, a
stake driven through the heart.
Oh yes, that's the
theory all right.
But... but... but...
But what?
But they did!
They drove a stake
through his heart!
Good God, are we living
in the Middle Ages?
It wasn't through
my sanction, Karl.
Sauer did it.
He told me so himself.
Well, that ends the vampire
theory as far as I'm concerned.
Herman Gleib died in
the accepted fashion
For killing a vampire.
Oh no, there's some human agency
at work here, Doctor, a madman
Who kills to satisfy some
violent, sadistic urge!
Yes, you're right, Karl.
I've been a fool, a
superstitious fool!
Did they leave his
body in the cave?
Yes.
Yes, they did.
Well, in view of
what's happened,
Don't you think you owe
him a decent burial?
You're right.
In view of what has happened,
we do owe him that, Karl.
I'll see to it at once,
this very instant.
And I'll make arrangements
for Georgiana's removal
To the morgue.
Goodnight, Doctor.
Pardon the intrusion.
Goodnight, Gustav.
BURGERMEISTER:
Pardon the intrusion.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Well.
Here I am, just where
I started weeks ago.
There isn't a single
theory that doesn't
Lead straight into a stone wall.
I've jested about
this vampire business
Because my better judgment told
me it was a lot of nonsense.
Then I reached the point
where I was willing to accept
Even that, Because it seemed
to satisfy the equation.
All of it a bit superstitious.
I don't know which way
to turn, where to look,
What to look for!
Why should anyone
want human blood?
Why?
Why?!
Calm yourself, Karl.
Calm myself?
With all these unsolved
murders staring me
In the face and no
solution in sight?
How much blood is there
in a human body, Doctor?
About six liters,
approximately.
Can you think of any purpose
for which that amount of blood
Might be used?
No, not even in transfusions.
KARL: That's the
point which stops me.
There isn't any other
use for human blood.
Gah!
Murderers leave clues!
And these atrocities
are murders, Doctor.
Those simple fools
in the village
Can believe what they like.
But you and I are
sane, thinking people.
And you know and I know,
Doctor, that these are murders!
The last one was done
here, in this very house,
Right under this roof.
All right, I'll start here.
I'm going over every
foot of this place,
Both inside and out.
Nobody, sane or insane,
is clever enough
To get away with murder without
leaving a clue of some sort!
And I'm going to find that clue!
Come, come Karl, you musn't let
your nerves run away with you.
Here, these.
These will help to give
you a good night's sleep.
If there are any clues,
they'll be here in the morning
When your nerves are calm and
your... your mind is clear.
Take my advice and
go home and rest.
I imagined a
thousand demons were
After me as I came
down those stairs!
Ruth, didn't I tell you
to stay in your room?
Yes, but I wanted the doctor
to come up and quiet Auntie.
You know, it isn't her
imagination this time.
Of course, Ruth.
I'll come right away.
Take my advice, young man.
Go home and go to bed.
Goodnight, Karl.
Goodnight, Ruth.
DR. VON NIEMANN:
Goodnight, Karl.
Goodnight, Doctor.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
If his lights are on,
you must wait, Emil.
Wait until he has gone to bed.
Handle him as you
did the others, Emil.
You are strong, very strong.
I am waiting for
you, waiting for you
To bring him to the laboratory.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
You!
You're the one!
What mad thing are you doing?
Mad?
Is one who has sold the secret
of life to be considered mad?
Life!
Created in the laboratory!
No mere crystalline growth, but
tissue, living, growing tissue,
Life that moves,
pulsates, and demands
Food for its continued growth!
Ha, you shudder in horror.
So did I the first time.
But what are a few lives
being weighed in the balance
Against the achievement
of biological science?
Think of it.
I have lifted the babe.
I have created life, wrested
the secret of life from life!
Now do you understand?
From the lives of those
who have gone before,
I have created life!
I'll tell Karl!
You may, for tonight Karl's
name will be added to yours,
And all of those who
misachieved within mortal lives.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
I didn't take your
sleeping tablets, Doctor.
Emil brought them here.
He's the one who murdered them!
Stay where you are.
You'll have a chance to
tell everything, Doctor.
[THUMPING AND STOMPING NOISES]
I'll take care of von Niemann!
Get her out of here!
[GUNSHOT]
[CRASH]
You stay here.
[GUNSHOT]
Von Niemann and Emil.
Doctor!
Dr. von Niemann!
Karl, she mustn't see them.
Where is Dr. von Niemann!
I must see him immediately.
Aunt Gussie, you can't.
He's... he can't be disturbed.
Oh, but I must see him!
I simply must!
That hydrous magnesium
sulfate he gave me is, uh,
Affecting me most peculiarly.
You'll pardon me.
Hydrous magnesium sulfate.
Why, that's epsom salt!
[MUSIC PLAYING]