Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Why are they sending
so many soldiers daddy,
if it is only going
to be a little war.
Make those southern boys take us
seriously this time, my darlilng.
When they realize how much we want to put a
stop to their nonsense, they'll quiet down.
They'd better. Anyhow, when you get
there, you'll stop them won't you daddy?
I'll do my best dear.
We will miss you so.
I'll be back and we'll be together
again before you can say knife.
I can say knife a good many times
in a year.
At school, you'll have charming little
girls to play with.....
books to read, a pony to ride and
after all there will be Emily you know.
Yes, there will be Emily.
And she does look as though
she'd be an understanding
friend, don't you think daddy?
With that intelletual look, I'm sure of it.
- Not a very cheeful looking
school, is it daddy? - I'm
afraid nothing would seem very
cheerful to us at the moment.
Well, maybe it will be
better on the inside.
- Of course it will. I'm sorry sir.
- All right, get it out.
- The very idea of
delivering a thing like this
to the front door.
- Oh look daddy, my pony.
Your employer will answer to this.
Now take him away. Yes, far away!
- Oh no daddy.
- Oh, I say. Just a moment.
- You are Miss Minchin?
- I am.
I'm Captain Crew.
I'm afraid of caused you
no end to inconvenience.
You most certainly
have, Captain Crew.
- May I step inside and explain?
- Come in.
- Wait here, I'm returning.
- Very well Captain.
- I'm terribly sorry. I had no
intention of having the pony delivered
inside your house. - There are a
number of things besides the pony.
Parcels have been arriving here collect for
your daughter for hours. Follow me please.
Apparently you are not
aware, Captain Crew, that I
conduct one of the most
exclusive schools in London.
Yes, yes, I understood.
That is precisely the
reason why I brought
my daughter to you.
I would not have gathered
that, by your actions.
Really now,
I'm not entirely to blame.
You see Sara and I,
only just arrived from India.
Sara has lived there
practically all her life.
We no more than got here,
when I learned that my regiment was
to leave at once for South Africa,
so we had to act in a hurry.
But I wrote you and explained
that l do not take young
ladies without an interview
and impecable references.
I wrote you also, that at the
moment, I have no vacant room.
- Well in that case daddy, we may as
well move on. - This is a bit awkward.
You see, your letter never
reached me and I'm afraid it never
occured to me that any school
wouldn't welcome my little Sara.
If it is a question of my
social standing, my father
was Sir George Crew.
You've heard of him, perhaps?
And the best financial
references l can give you would
be the director of the South
African Holding Syndicate.
I'm the principal stockholder in the
syndicate.
My brother, Captain Crew, a
professor of dramatics.
- How do you do?
- Charmed, I'm sure.
- I say, isn't the
Eclipse Diamond mines one
of your holdings?
- One of the most important.
I'm sorry to appear casual Miss
Minchin, but the siutation is
quite distressing. I sail in an
hour to the east Indian docks.
I expect you'll just have to
take me to Africa with you daddy.
Well, well and what would a
little girl like you do in Africa?
Forgive me Captain Crew.
I'm afraid I've been over zealous. The
reputation of my school you know.
One has to be so cautious.
But after this interview, I can see at
a glance, she's a dear little child.
- It'll be a pleasure to have her with us.
- Does that mean I've got to stay?
Yes dear. You are to have that
privilege. You and your little pony.
- What a dear little pony.
- This is made out
to the school.
- Is it enough for the moment.
- Oh quite. - I should say it
would. Why it's stupendous.
- I beg your pardon,
but haven't I seen you
somewhere before?
- Quite possible my dear Captain.
Your face is most familiar.
Were you ever on the stage? I
seem to associate you with
one of the old music halls.
Musicals? My brother on the stage?
Ridiculous.
Ridiculous indeed,
you're quite right.
And now, shall we look at little
Sara's room?
Just a moment Miss Rose. This is
Miss Rose, one of my most capable teachers.
Captain Crew has done us the honor of
placing his little daughter Sara with us.
How do you do Miss Rose?
How do you do Captain Crew? We
shall do everything we can to
make your little girl happy.
Children, we have a new pupil.
Sara Crew. Say how do you do to her.
- How do you do?
- I'm very well, thank you.
Lavina, Jesse, that will do. You
may proceed Miss Rose.
- She's just like a little princess, isn't
she? - That's what she is, a princess.
I expect now, some people around
here won't think they're so smart.
Oh won't they? Wait and see!
Princess indeed!
Fortunately, the room has just been papered
and the fireplace has an excellent draft.
- But I thought you
didn't have any rooms? - I
didn't know then what a
dear little girl was coming.
Why does that make more rooms daddy?
Lady Bengiglis daughter has only recently
vacated the room. Our best suite of course.
Do you think you could brighten it up a
bit? I'd like it made as gay as possible.
Brought a few things from India. Perhaps
you could buy whatever else is necessary.
With pleasure Captain Crew.
- I'd like Sara to ride every
afternoon, if that is all right.
Of course. - Fortunately we
have a splendid riding master.
I expect you think I am
completely spoiling the child.
No doubt you're right,
but actually it's good for her.
She's much too inclined to
bury her cute little nose in a
book and keep it there until
someone lures her out of it.
You see Miss Minchin.
Sara has no mother and we've
never been separated for
more than a few days.
- How touching.
- This is going to be very hard for her.
Have no fear Captain Crew. I'm a
mother to all my little girls.
And now, I'll leave you to your farewells.
- How much longer have we got, daddy?
- Only a few minutes, darling.
- You know me by heart little Sara.
- No daddy, I know you by heart.
You're inside my heart.
We're going to be brave, aren't we?
I'll tell you what. Let's pretend we're
back in India.
And I'm going away with the troop
for a few days. Shall we?
We've fought this kind
of battle before, haven't
we? And you never cried
once when I went away.
- Remember?
- Yes daddy.
But this is going to be our hardest
battle.
- But we'll be good soldiers, won't we?
- Yes daddy.
- Shall we say good-bye,
like we used to at home? - Yes daddy.
All right then. Chin up, go to the
window and look out.
Say it as we used to.
My daddy has to go away, but he'll
return most any day.
Any moment, I may see, my daddy
coming back to me.
My daddy has to go away, but he'll
return most any day.
I can't do it this time. I can't do it.
- You're crying too.
- I'm afraid that we
aren't quite the good
soldiers as we thought.
Oh yes we are.
I can do it now.
My daddy has to go away, but he'll
return most any day.
Any moment I may see, my daddy
coming back to me.
I will do it! I will! I'll pretend this is
part of a war.
You be the enemy and you'll be my
trusty lance. Now ready, aim, fi re.
I guess we'll have to call in the
reserves.
- Good-morning.
- Misses speaks Hindu?
I've lived in India all my life.
Misses is going to live in England now?
- Until my father gets
through with making the
boars behave.
- Your father is a soldier?
Yes, my father is a captain. Captain
Crew. I'm Sara. What is your name?
I am Ram Dass. Servant to the
Honorable Lord Wickham and Lady Surani.
Ram Dass!
Why are you doddling here? Finish
with that bird and get on with your work.
Good-morning.
How do you do?
I'm up here at the window
almost every morning,
in case you want to
talk about India.
Good-morning Sara. Oh, good-morning.
Are you ready for breakfast my dear?
Well, I'm trying to be,
but I don't seem to be very
good at these buttons.
My thumb get lost in the holes.
Here, let me help you. Buttons are
a bother, aren't they?
I've never had to button things
before, but I'll learn.
Here, put your shoe up. Come in.
- Good-morning Becky.
- Good-morning.
- Has the young lady any boots to be done?
- Well,
only the pair I wore
yesterday, I'll get them.
I'll get them Miss. Oh I beg your
pardon Miss!
- Are you hurt?
- No Miss you mustn't be helping me Miss.
Just hold out your arms
and I'll pile them on.
Oh no Miss.
If Miss Minchin was to see.....
- Think you can hold two more?
- Yes Miss.
There. There we are. Are you all right?
- You take care of all those?
- And she does them beautifully.
- I thank you Miss.
- Thank-you for doing my shoes.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
Good-bye Becky. Good-bye.
Well, perhaps this isn't
going to be such a bad
school after all.
With you and Becky here.
Oh, we'll have to hurry dear. Miss
Minchin doesn't like anyone to be late.
Tell me Miss Rose. Do you think Miss
Minchin could be as cross as she looks?
- What will I have to do today?
- Well, after
breakfast,
you'll have a class of arithmatic.
Then English, then french, history
and geography.
I'm going to be a busy person,
aren't I? When do I get to ride my pony?
Later this afternoon. About 4 o'clock.
Children, our new pupil, Sara Crew
will be down shortly.
As you've seen,
Captain Crew is a very delightful
man and their family
is most distinguished.
I should expect you to treat her
accordingly. Now you may take your places.
- Good-morning.
- Ah, good-morning Sara.
- I'm so happy you feel like
joining us this morning.
Did you sleep well?
- No I didn't, thank-you.
Lavina, you and Jesse will move
down one place.
- Sara will be seated at
my right after this. - Why
Miss Minchin,
this has always been my place.
For this food,
and all thy bountiful gifts bestowed
upon us, we are duly grateful
and do now give thanks.
- Why are you putting salt
on your plate my dear. - Just
in case you plan on asking
me to have one of your eggs.
- Mr. Geoffrey. Shall I saddle
the pony for the wee lassie? - I
think not Sandy. We'd best use the
mare for her first few lessons.
What luck. The old girl allowed you
to come out.
Sara, this is Mr. Geoffrey Hamilton.
Miss Crew is our new pupil.
- How do you do?
I believe I am to teach you to ride.
And that means two bob extra to me.
- Is two bob a great deal of money?
- Values are comparative.
- In my present state, it's a fortune.
- Well,
in that case,
I guess I'd better be taught.
- Is my pony ready? -I think we'd best
start you off on something a little tamer.
Then hadn't I better explain things
to my pony. He might feel hurt.
Right you are. Ponies are very
sensitive creatures. Explain the
whole thing to him, thoroughly.
He's right there by the arch.
It may take me some time.
That's all right.
We'll wait right
here in the tac room.
Hello General.
Are you glad to see me?
Well if Mr. Geoffrey is going
to give me something tamer
than you, I'm afraid it's not
going to be much of a ride.
- Rose something's wrong. What is it?
- Miss
Minchin is taking away
my Thursday afternoons.
- But why?
- We must have been seen together.
- Well does that mean that I can
never see you alone again? Of course
not darling. - No matter what Miss
Minchin says, we'll find a way.
I can't understand the woman.
What is she
afraid of?
Why shouldn't we see one another.
Gossip I suppose.
She only lives for that school
the variety of the propriety
of the snobbisheness.
Fiddlesticks. She's afraid of losing
an excellent teacher whom she gets
for nothing. I won't stand for it.
I will have a talk with her myself.
No darling you mustn't do that.
She'd only discharge us both.
She may not have the chance if
things continue to pop in South Africa.
- You mean you might go? - Wouldn't you
want me to if they call for volunteers?
Of course darling you'd have to.
There is nothing to worry about now. This
poor rumpous will never get that serious.
I expect I'll have to make my visit a
little longer.
- Oh Mr. Brady is there
one this morning for the
little princess?
- We'll see my child we shall see.
Of she don't hear from
her father every so often
her eyes get that sad it
hurts me to look in them.
- Have no fear little one.
- There is a letter
for her this time.
Oh i'm so glad sir.
- A letter?
- It's from my daddy.
- Oh how nice.
- But it isn't.
- It's very bad news. Really?
- What's the matter dear?
He says the boys are not
behaving as expeted. And
he may not get here in
time for my birthday.
But that's months old. So many things may
happen before then. He can still come.
I'm writing Miss Minchin
to give you ar bithday
party such as I should
give you if I were there.
You are to go on a regular spree. Buy
anything and everthing your heart desires.
Now last and most important of all
my darling....
I want you to pause at exactly 2
o'clock on your birthday..
..close your eyes and send me a kiss.
For my eyes also will also be closed
and I'll be giving you a kiss too.
Isn't he the most wonderful man in
all the world?
- With one exception...
- Well Mr. Geoffrey is very nice.
What's that?
- Who are they Miss Rose?
- They are volunteers.
- Are they going to South Africa too?
- Yes dear,
they're going to relieve our
poor soldiers in Maefking.
- Is there something the
matter with our soldiers
in Mafeking?
- The boars have them all cut off.
We were unable to break through
their lines and ger help to them.
They're sick and hungry
dear and desprate.
They're holding out like
true British soldiers.
Miss Rose my daddy's at Mafeking.
Oh darling I'm so sorry. I didn't know.
Darling you mustn't cry. I'm sure
he'll be all right.
- Good afternoon Mr. Geoffery.
- Good afternoon
Madris.
Is Miss Sarah ready for her ride?
She'll be down presently. Thanks.
Oh, are we all ready?
The two most beautiful ladies in the world.
Why aren't you in your riding things?
- Oh i can't go today.
Ermegard needs extra
tutoring today.
- Oh will it take all afternoon?
I'm afraid so.
- I have to stay with
her until she can spell
Constantiniopel.
- Heavens that may take months.
You leave that to me.
Shall we go? Have you been
crying?
- But you have, there are still tears in
your eyes. - It's just this London fog.
Oh well if that's all,
lets be off shall we?
- Mr. Geoffrey.
Would you mind very much if we didn't
ride today?
- Not at all dear. But may I ask why not?
I'd like to talk to you.
It's about Mafeking.
Are the soldiers really
starving,
sickand cut off from everything?
- You see my father's there so I've got
to know. - Oh it's not as bad as all that.
They may not be having an
easy time of that, but they're
holding out. We're sending in
fresh troops everyday you know?
- Why they'll be leaving Mafeking
in no time at all. - It's
getting harder everyday to
pretend my father is safe.
Don't you worry. See here, I'll let
you in on at litle secret.
I enlisted today and while I
don't Miss Rose to know quite
yet, I'll be going over
there quite shortly myself.
- To Mafeking? Well then perhaps you
can help my father. - We'll get him out.
What the blazes are you doing
here? Answer me! What are you doing here?
- Don't be frightened Sara,
it's only my grandfather. - Don't you
believe him young woman.
I disowned him the day he was born.
- We're really very fond of each other.
Of course
we are.
- What?! We are nothing of the kind.
- As a favor to me,
will you please stop shouting at my best
paying pupil. - Pupil? Paying?
What are you talking about?
I am master of the horse in this
exclusive seminary of the young ladies.
You take advantage of
my absence to become a
riding master?
And next door to me own house?
- Where's your family pride boy?
- Well sir, one
must eat, and family pride
is a pretty thin diet.
Oh, blackmail eh?
You'll think I'll buy you off?
I hadn't thought of that,
but it's not a bad idea.
I'll see you hang drawn and
quartered for that. Wait till I see
the woman who runs this school.
I'll put a spoke in your wheel.
Do! She loved to know
that my grandfather is
Lord Wickham.
She probably raise my salary
- Miss Sara, Lord Wickham is coming.
- Then I'm going.
Insolent young pup! Just like his
father. Riding master! Bah!
- Maybe you're fond of him,
but I don't think he's very fond
of you. - Oh he's harmless.
His bark is worse than his bite.
I should hope so. Why is he so mad at you?
Oh he isn't really. He was angry with my
father. I'm mixed up in their quarrel.
What he really wants if for
me to come begging to him
for help. He'd be eating
out of my hand if I would.
I don't think I'd care for him eating
out of my hand.
- How would you like to
have me eating out of
your hand?
- You? Oh, that would be different.
Well I shall, if you do me a favor.
A very important one. Oh, could I?
I've got an idea that you are the
only one in the world who could.
I want you to get Miss Rose to go shopping
with you next Wednesday. Shopping?
Well, shopping is as good an
excuse for Miss Minchin.
Really? To Miss Rose?
And she said she would? Oh, that's
wonderful!
- No, not a soul. Not even Emily.
- Good girl! Now we've got to go.
- I must do some prelimanary shopping.
- You don't
have to tell me what for.
Something gold and shiny.
Right you are!
Come in.
- Come in. - Miss Minchin,
I wanted to ask you something.
- Oh, it's you. What do you want dear?
- I'm going to ask you a big favor. Yes?
Mr. Geoffrey leaving today for the
war, he's been so very nice to me...
I thought I ought to fill my
social obligations by doing
something nice for him.
That's what you teach us, isn't it?
When someone shows you a
kindness, you show them one in return.
Well doing something for Mr. Geoffrey,
scarcely
comes under the rules
of social obligations.
- But what is it that you want to do
for him? - May I have him for tea?
- Here? At the school? - Oh couldn't I
please? Since he's going away to war.
Well I suppose it would be for him,
since he was one of the teachers.
You need not mention this to
the other young ladies, however.
No Miss Minchin. Thank-you Miss
Minchin. Oh Thank-you Miss Minchin!
- We must eat something
after all the trouble little
Sara has gone to.
- I think she'll understand.
- You've forgotten your ring.
- No I haven't....see?
I'm always afraid I'll forget and
wear it in front of Miss Minchin.
I did yesterday and fortunately for
us, she didn't see it.
- Oh I'd love to tell the old girl.
- Can't do that yet darling. I know.
- Are you sorry you married me?
- As if you didn't know.
I only wanted you to tell me again.
Oh, my darling....
I'll be living this last week over
every moment I'm away from you.
We won't be separated, will we?
Because I'll be living it over too.
- I thought you were having Mr. Hamiliton
to tea? - I am, I mean I was but.....
- Who's in that room?
- Oh please don't go in there Miss Minchin.
- Miss Minchin, Miss Rose and I.....
- We were saying good-bye Miss Minchin.
How dare you risk the reputation
of my school in this manner.
Nothing has happened to damage
your precious school's reputation.
- As a matter of fact Miss Rose and I.....
- Geoffrey! For my sake.
- Oh please Miss Minchin, it was all
my fault. -Silence!
Since you are here to merely say
good-bye, please do so, now.
Good-bye Geoffrey.
- Good-bye Mr. Geoffrey.
- Good-bye dear.
- Sara, I shall expect an explanation
of this. - Yes Miss Minchin.
As soon as I can think of one.
- They've been cornered like
rats for 7 months. - I say send
more troops to Mafeking if it
takes every man in England.
- I'm with you.
- No! Nooooooooo!
Oh my boy, my boy, my boooooy....
They killed my boy.
I know soldiers are suppose to
stand a lot and my daddy is a good soldier.
But they've waited so long for help. Please
do something about Mafeking right away.
Or they'll all be lost and my daddy
won't come back.
Mafeking is set free. Mafeking is
set free.
Oh thank-you for being so quick
about it this time.
Get up, get up! Mafeking is set free.
Wake up everybody! Mafeking is
set free.
- Oh Mr. Bertie! Did you hear?
Mafeking is set
free!
- Yes darling, isn't it great news.
Oh Miss Rose, they're saved. My
daddy and Mr. Geoffrey are saved.
- What's wrong? Nothing is wrong.
- Nothing,
nothing, nothing!
Mafeking is set free.
Oh Miss Minchin, isn't it wonderful?
Can you hear the cheering?
- Oh Sara, I'm so glad for you.
- He's saved Becky! My daddy is saved!
Children, children! Attention please!
It is a happy circumstance that
Sara's birthday should fall on a day
that we are celebrating a glorious
victory for Her Majesty's Army.
Now Sara. Will you explain to the children
about your wishes for your birthday?
I'm very happy to have you
here and I thought I would
like to give presents today.
Not just receive them.
I want to show how grateful I am my father
has been rescued. Quiet children, quiet.
- Can we do the presents now?
- Yes, but your gift first Sara.
This is for you.
Oh thank-you Miss Minchin.
Now all I need is
to know how to sew.
And this from the entire school.
Here are pictures of your native India.
Oh thank-you ever and ever so much.
I shouldn't have to
pretend nearly so hard when I
want to make believe I'm there.
And now, would you like
them to have their presents.
Yes, if you please.
And your names are all on them.
Here you are Miss Rose. Oh, how nice.
Now would you help with the other presents?
- Here you are Miss Rose.
Oh, how nice. Now would you
help with the other presents?
- Oh how thoughtful Sara.
From one old trooper to another.
Me in younger and
happier days.
I was better known as Bobbling Bertie.
- Thank-you. We'd better keep this
present a secret. - Mums the word.
- Here this is from me. I hope you like it.
- It's just what I wanted.
Mums the word you know.
Here's my present Miss. Many
Happy Returns.
- Oh thank-you Becky.
- The material isn't new.
- Why you dear Becky, you made it all
yourself. - Yes Miss. I made it at nights.
I knew you could pretend, I said,
with diamond pins stuck in.
- It's beautiful Becky,
I shall love it. Oh
will you Miss?
- The material isn't all new.
- And this isn't so very new either.
- It's my present to you.
- Yes Becky, with my love.
- What is it Miss?
It's a scarab from Egypt. My daddy
gave it to me, because it brings good luck.
I'd rather you had it, than anyone
else I know.
- Oh my Miss. I think I'm going to faint.
- Oh no Becky! Not now.
I have lots more presents for you.
Two in my room.
- I don't know what to say Miss.
- You're sweet Becky.
Yes, yes, very nice.
- eg your pardon Miss. Yes?
Mr. Barrow of Barrow and
Skippo is here to see you.
- Today? I didn't send for him.
He seems very much upset about
something. He's waiting in your office.
- Miss Rose.
- The scarf is beautiful.
Miss Rose, remember to be sure
and tell me when it's almost 2 o'clock.
You know, I have a very
special appointment with my
daddy. He's going to be
thinking of me at exactly 2.
I'll watch the time.
Thank-you Miss Rose.
Oh Sara! Thank-you for the
handkerchiefs, they're lovely.
- Don't you think it's time to
cut the cake? - Oh yes, the cake!
- Please be seated Mr. Barrow.
- How much did you
advance for this party?
Quite a sum, I suspect.
What does it matter.
Captain Crew is a very
wealthy man.
His check will be here shortly.
- No Miss Minchin. There'll be no check.
- What? What do you mean by that?
The late Captain Crew..... The
"late" Captain Crew?!
Captain Crew is dead.
He was so reported in the
list this morning.
Moreover, he died bankrupt
- Bankrupt?! But his property, his mines.
- His
property and mines were
confiscated by the enemy.
You mean to tell me that
that child is penniless?
That she's left on my
hands with nothing?
She's certainly left penniless and
she's certainly left on your hands.
- She hasn't a relative
in the world that we know
of. - But her father's
account is overdrawn.
I was expecting a check, and advanced the
money for this party. So I understand.
Now you have to make a wish and
blow out all the candles with one breath.
My wish is that my father will come
back real soon.
Now take a big breath.
I haven't got very good lungs, have I?
- I'll turn her out on the
streets -Do you think that's
wise Miss Minchin.
The reputation of your school.
My school?
Well the report might get
about and it might not
sound well to the parents
of your other pupils.
Yes, that is so.
Of course, the child can
be made to serve in your
employ, until her
indebtedness is worked out.
- But that will take years. - Quite so,
but at least it is better than nothing.
Hurry children, your ice-cream is melting.
- Tara, it's almost 2 o'clock darling.
- Thank-you Miss Rose.
Oh daddy, I'm thinking of you.
And I know, wherever you are,
you're thinking of me too.
Oh Miss Rose. I felt him with me,
I really did!
Miss Minchin wants you dear. Oh,
all right.
- Children, you will leave your gifts here.
- Why? Where are they going?
- Why can't they take the presents with
them? - Because they are not yours to give.
- But I don't understand.
- You will later. Go to your room now.
- But Miss Minchin.
- Sara, go to your room.
All of you.
Now will you tell her what it's all about?
What has happened Miss
Minchin? Whatever it is,
you may want to let her off a bit easier.
Silence! Captain Crew is dead. His
name appeared on the list today.
He left the child a pauper. Oh Miss
Minchin. You had better tell her.
- Oh, I couldn't do that.
- You will do as you are told.
Oh Miss Rose. What's wrong?
Why did Miss Minchin stop the party?
Sara, I want to talk to you dear.
- Oh darling........
- Oh Miss Rose! What is it?
Sara, you're a soldier's daughter.....
and you know that
means being brave and
courageous, don't you?
No matter what happens.
- Oh Miss Rose! Is it something awful?
- Your father.....
But my father is all right. Mafeking
is set free. You heard them say so.
Help didn't get there soon enough
dear, for him.
His name appeared on
the list this morning.
- You mean with the wounded?
- No dear.
My daddy is...
Oh Sara, I'm so sorry.
It can't be! It isn't true! I won't
believe it! He isn't dead! He isn't!
- Have you?
- Yes.
You may go.
Come with me.
This is to be your room in the future.
I shall have to sell your
furnishings and clothes,
to pay part of the
debt your father owes.
Ordinarily,
you would go to a charitable
institution,
but I'm going to let you remain here.
There will be duties for you to
perform, of course.
I hope you appreciate my kindness
in not sending you away.
I was unable to fi nd a
black dress among your
things, but one of the
girls has given you this.
You'd better take off that party frock
and put this on.
I'll send up some shoes.
I don't believe it. I don't, I don't!
My daddy has to go away. But he'll
return most any day.
Any moment I may see, my daddy
coming back to me.
And Miss Minchin is going to sell all
her things.
It was beastly having to
give back all our presents.
How do you feel now
about your little Princess?
- Oh Miss. Is there anything I can do?
- No Becky, but thank-you.
Sara, I'm sorry.
Sara, from now on,
you are not to sit with us.
Return to your room and
smooth down those curls.
And then go to the kitchen. Run
along now.
Lavina, you may take your old
place, beside me.
- Mrs. O'Connel. - Oh, so the Misses
has sent you down to me, has she?
- Miss Minchin said that I am to
have my breakfast here. - You'll
do more than eat your breakfast
if you work for that one.
- I should be glad to help.
- You will eh?
Look at you! Look what you're
doing! For that you'll get no breakfast.
Min, you'd better make some more
toast for the Misses. Right.
Here's your breakfast. Take it over
there. We don't associate with royality.
- Let me wait on you Miss. No you don't.
- She can
wait on herself.
You can sit there and watch her eat.
Perhaps that will teach you a leson.
Please Mrs. O'Connel.
May I give my breakfast
to Becky?
I'm not that hungry this morning.
Give it to the cat if you like. Then
get to work and wash them dishes.
No Miss, I don't want it.
The mail just came.
My darling girl.
I have been half mad trying to
find a way out of you since
your letter reached me.
But it has come! My grandfather
has relented.
I pray him,
that this money and my love will
help you bear what lies ahead.
Geoffrey.
You say this girl's a
teacher at your school?
She was,
until I discharged her today.
We're not likely to hear from her again.
And I was prepared to turn over a
handsome sum to that boy when he got back.
I even made an ass of myself and
sent him a check.
Then I was right to withhold this.
He made it over to her.
- You're not very fond of the girl,
are you? - Hardly, under the circumstances.
- Are you sure the girl
has no legitimate claims
on him?
- I brought her up from a fondling.
Is it likely, she would not have consulted
me if their love had been respectable.
Ram Dass!
Yes sir? In future if any
letters or cables come
from Mr. Geoffrey,
they're to be returned, unopened.
As you wish sahib.
Come in Becky.
I'm glad you weren't asleep Miss.
It's one of the lonely nights.
I wonder where Miss Rose is?
I shall miss her terribly.
We're all alone in the world
now, aren't we Miss?
No, no, we're not alone.
There is my father you know.
- Your father? But cook said he......
- You
mustn't say that.
It isn't true. He's not dead.
He sick or wounded somewhere, or
he'd send for me. But he's not dead.
- How do you know Miss?
- Something inside tells me so.
And sometimes I hear him calling for me.
All alone Miss.
- Buford! You're smoking!
- As you see.
- Today my good woman,
the British army is behind
me. - That uniform?
You're not going to war.
Quite! To the very cannon's
mouth, if need be. But why?
Because old girl. I've had it
to the teeth with your bulling.
And your treatment of Rose and
little Sara is the last straw.
I prefer the less painful
horrors of the battlefield.
- Are you daring to critize me?
- Astonishing, isn't it?
But it proves that I am competent to
lead my men, into the very jaws of death.
- After this, you may never expect
help from me again. - I am quite calm.
For if the blood-thirsty
boar spares me, the
foot-knights will see
Bubbling Bertie once again.
- Buford, you wouldn't do that to me?
Oh wouldn't I? - Well, ta-ta old girl.
If you please sir? What is it lassie?
Were you at the seige of Mafeking?
- Aye, that's where I
stopped the bullet that
stopped me.
- Then did you know my father?
- Your father? What might his
name be lassie? - Captain I Crew.
- Was your father a Captain? - Yes. They
say he is dead, but I know it can't be.
- I've asked so many
soldiers about him. I hope
you can tell me.
- No lassie, I'm sorry, I can't.
- Why don't you ask in the hospital there?
- Maybe
they'll have some record of him.
Thank-you sir, I will!
- If you please sir.
- Well the little Princess as I live.
Why Mr. Bertie, I thought you'd
gone to war
No, Lord Roberts wanted
me to of course. But he
said: "Bertie old boy,
the wounded need you."
So you stay here and cheer up the brave
lads who have fallen in our dust corps."
So I'm practically in command of
this hospital.
- Oh Mr. Bertie. Can my father be in there?
- Your father Princess?
Yes, you see I know he isn't dead.
I've been looking and looking.
He could be among the wounded, couldn't he?
Yes..... I'm almost sure he is, somewhere.
If you're in charge, could I please look
for him in there? Well ah..... Pleeeeeease.
Yes, yes of course you may. Things
like that can happen you know.
Mr. Bertie,
why did you join the command here?
Well disipline in the
hospital is rather lax.
I say Major. They're waiting for you in
ward B. There is a lot of trash up there.
- Very good. I'll get one of my men to
attend to it. - Get one of your what??
Well then 2 of my men, carry on!
Portor! Sir?
- What's this child doing here before
visiting hours? - Well you see... Well,
well, well. If you please sir.
The Major is helping me find my father.
- The Major? - For her sir. You
see, we're old friends sir.
I knew her father, Captin Crew was
reported killed at Mafeking.
The child is sure there is some mistake, so
I'm helping her search among the wounded.
- Could you tell me anything about my
father sir? - Sorry my dear, I can't.
- Carry on, Major!
- Yes, sir. Thank-you sir.
This little girl's father
has been killed, but she
insists he's alive so I'm
letting her look around.
We'll try another ward.
- There's old Bertie.
- Give us a song mate.
Attention men! Attention! Official
inspection.
He isn't here either. But someone
might know about him.
If you please sir.
Were you at the seige of Mafeking?
I was that darling.
It's there I got bit by a bug.
It was no bigger than the seed
of a thistle and it laid me
low. Ah, the bugs down there
are worse than the bullets.
- Perhaps you didn't know my father?
- Afraid I wouldn't
have known me own father,
with the fever that was on me.
- Thank-you sir.
- It's all right darling.
If you please sir.
Were you with the troops at Mafeking?
Yes, yes of course I was.
That's where I ran away.
- Then did you know my father,
Captain Crew? - Yes, yes of course.
That's a fine looking officer, isn't he?
He ought to do well.
Well when did you see my father last?
Where is he now?
Where is who? My father.
Oh, one soldier more
or less, doesn't make
any difference you know.
I'm making thousands and
thousands for England. Fine
strong fellows,
who won't be afraid like I was.
I was afraid of the noise. That's
why I ran away you know?
- He says he knows my father,
but he won't tell. - He's been
living in a dream Sara,
he doesn't know what he's saying.
Don't go yet lad. Give us a song!
- How about it dear?
Shall we sing them a song to cheer
them up?
- Our old speciality. Not today Mr. Bertie.
- Oh come on darling.
Let's try and forget our own troubles and
do something for these lads, shall we?
- All right, I'll try.
- What about "The Old Kent Road"?
Yeah, that's the one.
Mackie will play for you.
- I'd be delighted Mac.
- Mr. Bertie, will it be all right
if I come again tomorrow? - I
shouldn't run away too often Princess.
You might get punished you know.
- I'll keep a sharp look-out
for whenever the wounded
come in. -You don't really
believe he come, do you?
Yes, yes, of course I do. I told you
missing men often turn up.
Then I'd better come. You might
not know him, if he's very much changed.
- All right dear. You come.
- Good-bye Mr. Bertie. Good-bye dear.
Are you hungry.
Poor little things. There won't be
any worms for you this morning.
Good-morning little misses sahib.
Good morning
Ras Dass.
Feeding your little friends?
- Yes, but I couldn't feed
them very much from my supper
last night. - It is difficult
for them when the snow comes.
Rani, Rani!
You look as though you are being
naughty and enjoying it.
- Her she is, on the bookshelf.
- Bookshelf?
Oh I forgot. I pretend it's a bookshelf
and fill them with beautiful books.
Well I'd better remove her, before
she ruins your set of Dickens.
This is your room Misses sahib?
It's so old and so high
above everything,
it's almost like a nest in a tree.
I can lie on my soft
sofa and look up into the
sky through that little
window on the roof.
- Sofa? - It looks more like a
soft sofa when it's made up.
Can you imagine it has down quilts
and lovely cushions to curl up on.
- There is a fire sometimes, of course?
- Well,
that is the hardest
sometimes, to imagine.
But it's lovely when you can.
The grate shines so when
it is polished and the
bright coals on the hearth.
Oh hurry Miss.
Cook is in an awful dither.
Oh my goodness.
Excuse me if I run.
I've got to go to the butcher. I'll get
my ears boxed if I don't hurry.
Listen to this: Hospital Ship Mercy
arrived with 1 200 wounded disembarked.
- Does it give any of the names?
- There ain't no list.
Oh I hope my poor Harry's among them.
A wounded
husband is better than no
husband at all, eh Min?
Oh Becky,
I've got to get to the hospital
before 9 o'clock when
they close for visitors.
Sara! You clumsy ox! For that
you'll whistle for your supper.
Oh Mame, Sara didn't get know lunch.
You put
things away before she
got back from the grocer.
Who do you think you're talking to?
You'll both go
hungry. Now clean up this mess.
Go on, get on with it!
There some sorry cases in this
batch, doctor.
Doctor, this man is an unknown.
His papers were lost.
Delerium following maleria fever.
- We're very much concerned about him sir.
- Heart
action, weak resperation,
well that's to be expected.
- He has no lucid moments.
- Temporary paralyzes
of some nerve center or
a blood clot possibly.
More likely to be the latter sir.
He received a nasty headwound.
- He repeated the call of this person Sara.
- You can't know who this Sara is?
No way of finding out sir, until his
identity is established.
- You'd better go now Miss.
- I'll finish up
for you. Thank-you Becky.
I'll have to fly.
Here hold your horses.
Where do you think you're going?
Miss Lavina want's some coal
for her fire. Hop to it.
Oh Sara! You look so tired and you
look hungry too.
- Are you actually hungry Sara? - Yes!
I am hungry. I'm so hungry I could eat you!
Put on plenty, my father pays for it.
Come back here and clean up that hearth!
I'd like my shawl. The pink one. It's
on my bed.
Cover me please. I find the room a
bit chilly.
Hello Princess,
what are you doing out so late?
I've come to see the new
soldiers that arrived today.
- Not tonight my girl. It's closing time.
- But I've got to. I ran away especially.
- Please let me in. I'm sure he's here this
time. - You're sure every time Princess.
I'm sorry. You run on home and
come back tomorrow morning.
That's a good little girl.
All right, good-night now.
He'll recover from the
effects of the fever,
but I'm convinced there
is brain pressure.
You advise an operation then?
Yes. Do you agree.
I do and Dr. McNesh
in Edinburgh is the man.
Prepare this man for removal to
Edinburgh tomorrow. Yes doctor.
Sara, where have you been?
- Answer me. You've been out, haven't you?
- Yes Miss Minchin.
- What do you mean by disobeying my orders?
- I had to, I had to look for my father.
All this ridiculous searching
for your father. All this
making believe and refusing to face
facts, it's indecent.
- I've had enough of it.
You must realize once and for all that
your father is dead. - Don't you
say that. He's not dead. He's not!
- And you can't stop me from
looking for him either. - How
dare you speak to me in
that manner you little......
I'll attend to you further in the morning.
I can't be a good soldier for much
longer. I'm cold and I'm hungry too.
Do you hear?
No, you don't hear and you don't
care. You're nothing but a
doll, a doll!
You've never had a heart to make
you feel. You're just a doll.
Your Highness, please forgive me,
but something has gone amiss.
There is an angry woman outside to
report a stolen kiss.
Tell her she must go away. Come
around some other day.
I have told her but she won't.
You must see her,
if you don't,
she'll scream her head off.
- Tell her to hush. She won't be hushed.
- Then
tell her to shush!
I'm afraid she won't be shushed.
I won't be hushed, I won't be shushed, I
know my rights and I know also what I saw.
- What did you see?
- I saw him.
You saw who? I mean whom?
I saw that lad steal a kiss, from that
shameless little miss.
Don't be fooled by all their shyness,
they're a wicked pair Your Highness.
The Law says in its shining,
that you should not kiss in this land.
There's a law I understand, against
kissing in this land.
There is a law that reads like this.
No one is to steal a kiss.
Ah but Princess, I've a feeling, this
isn't a case of stealing.
Silence fool. I know the law. What
I say I saw, I saw.
She's on a see-saw. What I saw,
you saw, he saw, she saw.
On a see-saw. On a see-saw. l
saw, you saw, he saw, she saw.
What she tells us may be true. And
if it is, what can we do?
If you ask me, we should listen, to
the lad who did the kissing.
Let him speak. Come lad this way.
Now then, what have you to say?
Please Your Highness, I confess.
When I saw such lovliness...
it was too much to resist. I just
thought she should be kisssed.
So I kissed her, kissed her twice.
It was very, very nice.
So he kissed her, kissed her twice.
There you see, he broke the law.
What I say I saw, I saw.
- Please don't start all that again.
- But he stole a kiss, that's plain.
Yes, it looks as if it's true and I'll
have to punish you.
No please. Let me say a word. It is
not the way you heard.
Please, he did not steal a kiss.
I gave it to him. Just like this.
There you see, I had a feeling, this
was not a case of stealing.
I'm not sure, it's not quite plain,
could I see that kiss again?
You were right, I have a feeling, this
was not a case of stealing.
Right! The law has been abused.
This lad has falsely been accused.
He's hers and she's hisn's, that old
witch should go to prison.
- You're a very wicked woman.
- Princess, I am only human.
Listen to the old grand-mommy.
You're a nasty peeping-tommy.
Banish her from here forever.
Never show your face here, never.
But what I say I saw, I saw. I know
my rights, I know the law!
Come and sit beside me here. Your
kiss has made things very clear.
Thank-you Princess.
Don't thank me. Was that kiss, that
set you free.
Now we're through with this arrangement.
Let us have some entertainment.
Bring the dancers, bring the singers,
bring the good old welting ringers.
- The new ballerina? She please you?
- She's
a very good dancer.
She looks familiar too.
What a nice dream. I feel quite warm.
I don't want to wake up.
I haven't waked up.
I must be dreaming.
I am dreaming.
I must be dreaming. But it feels
warm.
Becky, Becky come quick.
- Yes Miss?
- Look!
Oh no Miss. Do you see what I do?
- I don't know what you see. - But I don't
believe what I see. Well, I never.....
- Can you feel that? Yes Miss.
- What do you see? I see some fire Miss.
And a table with food on it, and a
rug and a lamp, and slippers?
I do indeed Miss. How did it all get
here? Did you pretend it into happening?
I don't know. I never pretended as
good as this before.
Look at these.
- If the little misses sahib
knew, she'd be
over here to thank you.
- Who wants any thanks?
- Oh Miss! You're beautiful! - Thanks
Becky. Now let's try this one on you.
- Isn't it beautiful? Oh yes Miss.
- It's perfect. And real satin too.
Let's try the slippers and see if
they're real.
- Do they feel like slippers to you?
- They feel soft and warm.
This feels soft and warm too.
They're as real as we are.
I don't believe it's a dream after all.
- Do you suppose the food is real Miss?
- Let us see.
- I can smell kippers, can you?
- Kippers and onions.
I wonder what this is? Muffins!
This tastes like a muffin. Is it one?
A muffin that ever was. It must be
the magic Miss.
Hadn't we better be quick before it
melts away?
- What sort of night did he have?
- He rested comfortably doctor.
Will we be able to
send him with the others?
Get him ready to be sent with group
D. He'll be leaving in about an hour.
I hear you're being punished. Do you
think we ought to offer her a chocolate?
- You must let her smell them. - Miss
Minchin surely couldn't object to that.
- Would you care to? - I don't want to
smell them, and I don't want to eat them.
- You don't!? Why not? - I've had much
nicer things than chocolate this morning.
- Listen to the Princess, pretending again.
- I'm not pretending.
I had the most wonderful things to
eat, that anyone had.
- Why you little liar. You haven't even had
breakfast. - Pardon me, but I really have.
Excuse me for saying so, it isn't
polite to call people liars.
- How dare you talk back to me.
- Was I doing that? My goodness.
So sorry.
You wait til I tell Miss Minchin on you!
Well, everything is still here Becky.
- Thank heavens it's stopped raining.
- Are you going some place Miss?
To the hospital. Becky, perhaps
everything is going to change for us.
Perhaps I'll find my father this time
and he'll take us away from here.
Oh no! It's the Misses.
Sara, how dare you......
- Why, what's happened to this room?
- That's what we would like to know.
When I woke up this morning,
here everything was.
Even to the food and the fire.
- Where did you get these things?
- I don't know. Maybe because
I dreamed such a beautiful dream
last night, that it came true.
These articles are rare and costly.
You stole them, didn't you?
Oh no Miss Minchin.
We didn't take these things.
I'll give you one more
chance to tell me the truth.
- But I am telling you the truth. - They
just came. Yes, they did indeed Mame.
You go to your room. This is a
matter for the police.
- Oh please Miss Minchin. Please don't call
the police. - Of course I'll call them.
- Oh we're prisoners sure enough
Miss, and the
police coming too.
- I can't be arrested.
- Those new wounded men
are at the hospital and I
got to get to them.
- I don't see how you can Miss.
Come on Becky, quick. Where are
we going Miss? Follow me.
- Oh I'm so frightened Miss.
I'm frightened this
time too.
- Come on Becky, give me your hand.
- Oh low Miss.
- Don't be afraid Becky.
- Ah, what game is this little
Misses sihib? - Can we please
go through your house?
We're running away from the police.
- And a very nice game to. Would you enter?
- We would like to, very much indeed.
- You seem in great haste Miss sihib.
Will you not stop for a
cup of tea? - Oh no thank you.
We're in too big of a hurry.
Oh, I see. You are still playing the
game of the police.
- I hope you escape in safety Miss sihib.
- So do I. Oh low Miss, police!!
- There they are! Stop them!
- Becky, run, run!
Sara, Becky! Stop where you are!
Go after the other one. I'll take care
of her.
Watch out Becky, don't slip. Becky,
where are you?
Wretched little beast.
You'll go to jail, both of you!
You'll never catch Sara.
Mr. Bertie will see to that.
So that's where she's gone.
Well did you find them Mame? Take this
little thief and don't let her
out of your sight till I return.
- Did you catch her?
She dodged her way into traffic. - I
couldn't find her anywhere.
Do you know where she's likely to be?
I do. Cabbie!
Harvard Hospital and hurry please.
He never stops calling for her.
Step aside a little bit will you? Ah,
ah, ah. You can't go in there.
- No visitors allowed for an hour.
- But that might be too late.
Now run along little girl, will you?
- I'm sorry sir. No visitors allowed
for an hour. - But we must go in.
Sorry sir. You can stand over there,
if that's all right.
- Have you seen Captain Marks? - I believe
he just went through the hall Miss.
- Sorry young one, but you can't
go upstairs now. - But I've got to.
I've got to see if my father is
here before Miss Minchin catches me.
Run along now. Do as you are told.
I say there. You come back here.
You can't go up there.
You can't go in there.
Let me go, let me go. I want to be
here. I will! I will!
Porter!!
What is it the child wants?
- Please, please don't let them
take me away. - What is it child?
My father. They say he was killed
at Mafeking, but I don't believe it.
He may be with the new wounded
men, but they won't let me look.
If they don't,
perhaps I'll never have another
chance.
Can't you make them let me look.
Colonel. Could you see that this
child is escorted through the hospital?
With permission, I shall accompany
her personally Your Majesty.
- What is your name?
- Victoria. What is yours?
Sara.......Oh Your Majesty!
Colonel.
I hope that you will fi nd your father
my dear. A thorough search Colonel.
- Oh thank-you Your Majesty.
- Good-bye my dear.
- Have you been through any of
the wards yet? - Not today sir.
I think we'd better cover this wing first.
We are searching for a patient.
Move right along dear.
- Is it all right?
- Thank-you darling.
- Miss Rose!
- Sara darling!
Oh Mr. Geoffrey. You're home, you're back
again. You can tell me where my daddy is.
Well Geoffrey didn't get as far as
Mafeking dear.
Then you don't know? You didn't
even see him?
No dear, I didn't. I'm sorry.
- Have you found him?
- Oh, no sir.
This is my friend Mr. Geoffrey and
his wife. Mr. and Mrs. Hamilton.
- Mrs. Hamilton.
- I'm afraid I can't introduce you,
because I don't know your name.
- I'm Colonel Gordon.
- This is Colonel Gordan.
He's helping me search the
hospital.
- Oh, don't bother. How do you do sir?
I'm very happy to know you both.
From Mafeking?
- No sir. An army mule, a British mule at
that. - That's adding insult to injury.
- Sorry sir, but it's time for the patient's
drops. - Well, I'd rather face that mule.
I'll come back later Miss Rose. Just as
soon as I've gone through the other wards.
- I'll wait for you dear.
- Good-bye.
- Be sure to come back Sara.
- I will.
Poor little thing. She'll never stop
hoping.
- I insist that you send for my brother.
- Very well
Mame, but you can't get in.
Brother or no brother.
- We will get in. My brother will see
to that. - I hope you're right Mame.
All filled now. This man will have to
wait until the next ambulance.
I think you'd better take
him into the waiting room.
These halls are much too drafty.
- I very sorry that you couldn't find your
father. - Thank-you just the same sir.
He may be on the next
convoy of wounded.
I wouldn't give up hope.
I won't sir.
- Good-bye and God bless.
- Good-bye.
I know that they were stolen.
That is perposterous!
I can prove it and I intend to
turn her over to the authorities.
She is in this hospital
and I intend to find her.
I insist that every
room be searched.
Sara...
Daddy...
Daddy, daddy! It is you! I found
you, I found you!
They said you were dead,
but I knew you weren't.
I knew you'd come back.
Oh daddy, hold me, hold me close.
You won't ever go away again, will you?
What's the matter daddy? Why
won't you talk to me?
Don't you know me daddy? I'm
Sara, I'm Sara.
- Where is my daughter?
- Oh daddy, something's happened to you.
Mr. Bertie! Mr. Bertie! Oh daddy,
you've got to know me.
Look at me!
You mustn't cry. You mustn't cry.
- We must be good soldiers you know.
- But I have
been a good soldier daddy,
but you don't know me.
- My little Sara never cries.
- But I'm Sara, I'm Sara!
Yes, yes,...Sara! Sara!
Sara, my darling. My baby Sara.
Sara my darling. My little Sara.
- Oh don't be ridiculous Amanada.
- Well then how do you account for
those silk covers, those robes and
those other things that are there.
Perhaps a little bird brought them in.
Perhaps they grew legs and walked
in. I don't know. One thing I do know
is little Sara wouldn't steal them.
Bertie! Yes?
Berties, what do you think has happened?
Little Princess has found her father.
She's found him!
- Captain Crew is alive?
- Of course he's alive!
How could she find him
if he wasn't alive?
- Oh Mr. Bertie, I found my father.
- Darling, I'm so glad.
Daddy, it's Your Majesty.
My daddy.