-Taxi!
-Charles!
-Ha, ha.
Maurice.
You're fat!
-And you are thinner.
-Ha, ha.
-Jeanette!
Jeanette!
Look!
-Charles!
Charles Wills!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-English, Mama, English.
-She loves you in French.
We all miss you in any language.
-He does not look well.
-That means she
wants to feed you.
You're away too long.
Almost two years, huh?
-Thanks, Maurice.
You remember.
-Bourbon straight,
water on the side.
You and Mr. Gamble!
Only people who
speak English would
put things like that
in their stomachs.
You're back on
business, perhaps?
-No, no, just to
see my little girl.
-Ahh, little ballerina.
She don't go back with you?
-No more for me, thanks.
-The world has changed.
-Uh, yes.
-It's not so crazy anymore
like it was after the war, huh?
You remember?
We had much laughter
together, eh, Charles?
-Maybe we had too
many laughs, Maurice.
[CROWD CHEERING AND SINGING]
-Maurice, how are you?
-Some big day, huh?
-This calls for a very big and
very cold bourbon and water.
No bourbon, no gin, no
cognac, no anything.
-How are you celebrating?
-For me I keep the Perignon.
-For you and me.
-That, uh, lady over there.
I do say, uh, she
gives you the eye.
-That one?
She's not even smiling at me.
-The eye without a smile,
is the most dangerous eye.
-Excuse me.
-Charles!
-Claude!
Ah, I knew you would make it.
CLAUDE: Ooh, but you--
I was afraid that--
CHARLES: Nah, don't you know
that bad characters never
die in war.
Excuse me I saw my
old friend and I--
-This is my dear
and crazy friend,
Charles Wills, Miss Ellswirth.
-Miss Ellswirth.
-Marion, please.
-American?
You've been here
all through this?
-Oh, we never left.
Dad, and I stayed on in
unoccupied France, Lyon mostly.
[THUMP]
-How do you know Claude?
-Oh, he was an observer
with our outfit.
Haven't seen him since
D-day in Normandy.
-Ha, ha.
I parted company with you at
[INAUDIBLE] after Saint-Lo.
CHARLES: Back into the FFI?
CLAUDE: With the
General de Gaulle.
-Um, quite a-- a
coincidence meeting here.
-Well, if I hadn't seen
you in the mirror-- uh,
I thought some stranger
was giving me the eye.
CLAUDE: But no, no,
I didn't see you.
-Am I interrupting
anything important?
-Well, uh, Marion and I are--
-Uh, you must have
influence around here.
You have a drink.
-Power of the press, ma'am.
Let's see what my influence and
lots of money can accomplish.
Maurice!
-I've got a better idea, let's
go to my Father's celebration.
-Well, where would he get
enough whiskey for a party.
-Ha, ha.
You don't know my father.
-To fathers!
-To men!
-To Frenchmen!
[GROUP SINGING IN FRENCH]
-We'll continue our celebration.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Bonsoir.
-Bonsoir, monsieur.
-Marion, ah!
You, my boy, you have a
thirsty look in your eye.
-Oh, does it show?
-It might go away
if you have a drink.
-Andre!
-And, uh, who have we here?
-Charles, Wills.
He's a reporter for the
"Stars and Stripes."
This is my father.
-How do you do, sir?
-A reporter?
We don't need a reporter,
we need a bartender here.
-Ha, ha.
-I invited him here
because it seems
to be the only place in town
where you can get a drink.
-And do you know
that all these people
came to precisely
the same conclusion.
[SINGING IN FRENCH]
-What is Helen doing here?
-Uh!
-Hi!
-What are you doing here?
Well, the fact of
the matter is--
-Your sister has
made me very proud.
We couldn't tell you the good
news before but Helen has
been expelled from
the university.
-What?
-If we're going to
have scene, either
ask this young man to
leave or introduce us.
-Marion, please.
-Helen--
-Ah, now look, let her alone.
After all, I was expelled
from Harvard, wasn't I?
Why shouldn't a girl follow
in her father's footsteps?
-Excuse me a moment.
I'll talk to you later.
-I have a feeling she'll
be talking to me, too.
-Ha, ha.
Name, please?
-Uh, Charlie something or other.
He, uh, says he's a bartender.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Ah yes!
-Charlie what?
-Uh, Wills.
I wish were a bartender,
a nice civilian bartender.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Oh, thank you.
-I told him we knew each other.
-Well, we do in away.
We were only
kissing an hour ago.
-We were?
Let me see now, you were one
of the ones at the Ritz bar.
-Ha, no.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-No!
-Ha, no!
-I know!
Near the Dingo Cafe.
-You do remember, ha, ha.
-Ha, ha, no, it's the only other
place I ran into more uniforms
today.
-Ha, ha.
-Are you rich?
-No, does that finish me off?
-No, but it does
slow us up a little.
We're not rich either,
we just live that way.
Daddy says it's the same
thing only it's much cheaper.
-I think I like him.
-That's good, because he'll
try to barrow money from you.
And I don't want him
to be disappointed.
-Ha!
-I like the way you kiss.
-Really?
-My dear, I'm afraid
I've underestimated
the alcoholic capacity
of our guests.
-I'll only be a few minutes.
-Uh, get the bartender
here to help you with it.
Say, Wills, Wills, are you
one of the wealthy Willses
from Maryland?
-No!
No!
-Ah!
-This way, Lieutenant.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, sir.
[CROWD SINGING "ALOUETTE"]
-Where are you from?
-Milwaukee!
-Would you help me?
-Sure!
Noted for good beer,
women with lovely legs,
and practically no
millionaires, ha, ha.
-Ha!
-And you?
-New York till I was twelve.
then Daddy moved us to Paris.
When the Germans
came in 1940, I was
sent to school in Switzerland.
That's where the loot's kept.
-No!
Ha!
-Daddy put it there so the
Germans wouldn't drink it.
-Very resourceful man.
-And lots of fun.
-Is he?
That's his eleventh
commandment, having fun.
Especially now.
He says that after
a war everybody
should always be
gay and have fun.
-Isn't your father a
little old for this war?
-Oh, he wasn't in this one.
He was in the 1918 War.
And he's been
celebrating ever since.
Now that the war in Europe is
over, what are you going to do?
-Try to stay out of
the war in the Pacific.
-That's very sensible.
That ought to be enough
to tame the tiger.
-Yeah!
[SINGING IN FRENCH]
-Charles, I was wondering
what had happened to you.
-Nothing, yet.
-Everybody's
waiting to meet you.
-Well, I've really
got-- got to report back
to the paper with
some sort of story.
-Oh, can't you stay
just a few minutes?
-I'm sorry, I've got a deadline.
-Oh, Lieutenant, don't
take the party with you.
-Oh, ha, ha.
-That's a nice laugh.
Do you think someday
soon you might be rich?
-Could you come back later?
-All right, I'll try.
-Uh, better yet, I'll meet you.
You call and tell me where.
-All right!
-Hello!
Who is this, please?
Who?
Oh, Helen, this
is Charlie Wills.
No, no, Charlie the bartender.
-The Army bartender?
CHARLES (ON PHONE):
That's right!
So just give Marion
a message, please.
Tell her that the
lights of Paris
go on tonight for the first
time since the war began.
Well, she wanted to meet
me, at the [INAUDIBLE],
right by the Shrine for
the Unknown Soldier.
Thank you!
[ANNOUNCER SPEAKING FRENCH]
[MARTIAL MUSIC PLAYING]
-Hi!
I thought that--
-Disappointed?
-No, but--
-The ordinary
unnerving, you know.
[CROWD CHEERS]
[CROWD SINGING]
[BELLS RINGING]
-Do that again.
-Thought you were asleep?
-Only my eyes.
-And my arm.
They're weakling,
your arm and my eyes.
-Mm, hm.
-Not worthy of us.
-Mm, mm.
They're not bad eyes.
-It's a nice arm.
-I'll take you home.
-Did you read Thomas Wolf,
"You Can't Go Home Again"?
-It's late.
-All right.
[BELLS RINGING]
[DISTANT CHEERING]
-Promise me something.
Promise?
Don't ever let the
celebration end.
-There will be
another celebration
when the rest of
the war is over.
-But it is over.
For us it's over.
I'm sick to death of death.
I want to enjoy
things and have fun.
And live like everyday
is the last day.
Wouldn't that be nice?
A lifetime full of last days.
Except there never really
would be a last day.
You're too serious.
Make that nice smile.
That's better.
I don't care if you're not rich.
[HORN]
-Chocolate!
[CHILDREN PLAYING]
-Hi!
-Oh, how wonderful!
CHARLES: Ha, ha.
-Look!
-Mm, mm.
You didn't have to this, my boy.
-Oh, yes he did.
He's trying to
make time with me.
-Ha, ha.
-Dad!
-What is it, animal
or vegetable?
-Powdered eggs!
Chocolate!
-You shall not go
unrewarded, my boy.
Come to think of it,
you're generosity shall
be repaid this very day.
Now--
-Good morning!
-Look, meat, eggs.
-About the powdered
eggs, you see
they look something like eggs--
-Never mind.
We'll cook them in sherry that
will make them taste like eggs.
-Helen, please!
I wish to make some small
token of appreciation.
-Charles, my boy.
A golden opportunity awaits us.
Now the question is, are
we equal to the challenge?
-Well, what is it, sir?
Benedictine in the
fourth race today.
He'll go to the post at 10 to 1.
At a mile and 3/8,
he can't loose.
-Why not?
-Um, it's a trade secret.
-Daddy means he has
a hot tip, right?
-Another hot tip?
-Look, we have less than
two hours to become wealthy.
-I think I can come along.
I'll make a phone call.
-Excellent!
Now, If we pool our
resources-- uh, what is
you're capital, my boy?
-Oh, about $40.
-Let's see that means if we
pool our resources we have $40.
-What a pity.
-Maybe I can barrow some.
-Don't you do it, Charles.
He'll keep you as
broke as he is.
-Opportunity, my
dear, is concerned
with the future, not the past.
Look, if it's collateral
you're worrying about,
I happen to own oil leases
in Texas that are worth,
uh, well, you know Texas.
-Oh, Daddy.
The oil leases
are a family joke.
Plenty of leases but
not one drop of oil.
-Charlie!
-What?
-I feel lucky today.
-I'll see what I can dig up.
-I have the utmost
confidence in the courage
and ingenuity of the
United States Army.
To horse, my boy, to horse.
Destiny hates a laggard.
Ah!
Uh!
[BELL RINGING]
-The paper said that--
-Don't be nervous.
Daddy's really very brilliant.
-Well, what could
possibly make me nervous?
If we lose the race, I'll
owe half a year's pay.
The money belongs to four
captains who bought their way
out of Bastogne with
their bare hands.
-We won't lose.
-Well--
-Did you bet it all?
-Every penny.
And at 12 to 1!
-Why did the odds go up?
-The suckers think that
Benedictine will lose.
What can you expect
of agnostics, my boy?
Over this way, what?
-Which one is Benedictine?
-Uh, Number 4.
He'll lay back for
the first half mile.
-He looks scrawny.
Lean, my boy!
Lean and ready and fit!
-Who gave you this tip?
[CROWD CHEERING]
-Where's Benedictine?
-Running beautifully.
-But where is he?
-Sixth.
In perfect position.
-Is Benedictine--
-Seventh!
He's outsmarting them.
-Helen!
-I think I'll buy a new dress
with my share of the winnings.
[SCREAMING]
-He won!
Benedictine won!
-Of course, he won.
-Why should that surprise you?
-He won!
-Not so much surprise as relief!
-You know at 12 to 1,
that makes your share--
-Maybe there's another
race fixed today.
If you could--
-Fixed, fixed race, my boy?
-You mean this
race wasn't fixed?
-You've been reading
too many crime novels.
[LAUGHING]
-There was no hot
tip either was there?
-Well!
-You just picked a crazy
long shot out of a hat!
-Intuition and
experience, my boy.
-But we could have
gotten killed.
-It's a wonderful way to
make a living, isn't it?
[LAUGHING]
ANNOUNCER (ON RADIO):
This is the American
Forces Network in Paris.
A pall of black
destruction and chaos
still hangs over Hiroshima.
Events are now moving swiftly.
The President--
-Hey, Maurice!
Leave it on!
-Did you hear the news?
-First things first.
MAN 1: It'll take more one
bomb to end this caper.
MAN 2: One will get you
twenty it's over in a week.
MAN 1: Will you cover
$60 bucks worth?
MAN 2: You got it.
-Don't do it.
Barney just came
from the office.
Japan offered to surrender if--
-What!
-Where!
-Who!
- --if we let the Emperor
stay in his throne.
-When are we going home?
-Yeah.
Charlie, what's the
dope on discharges?
-Well, if you start
right now you're
already behind
10,000 other guys.
I'll have to get right
back to the office.
-Why?
-I tried to phone you.
-Don't ever phone me if you
can possibly come yourself.
And don't ever leave
if you can stay.
-Maybe we can meet for
late supper or something.
-We'll see.
Is it really over?
The war?
Because I want to
buy you silk shirts
and silk socks and silk shorts.
Oh, darling!
[COIN IN PLATE]
-Taxi!
-What did you do
with my umbrella?
-I had it when I started over
here and stopped a second.
Must have lost it.
We've got a Special
Edition coming out.
-You had better hurry.
-I'll get you a taxi first.
Taxi!
-Now you stop fussing about me.
-Will you-- will
you wait for me?
-I think I'll go home early
and give Daddy a shock.
-But in this rain?
-I may not be able
to cook and to sew,
but I really can
find myself a taxi.
It's the first thing I
learned at finishing school.
Now you go on ahead.
-You're a girl
after my own heart.
-Make no mistake about it.
I'm after it, all right.
Taxi!
-Violet.
Merci!
Marion!
I phoned, and they said it
was all right for visitors.
Did she get my flowers?
-Every day.
-All my messages?
-Every one.
-Can I go in now?
-Charles!
-What?
-Hi!
-How do feel?
-Ha, the nurse answers
all the stark questions.
-The patient improves, but it
is required not to really hurt.
-Uh, I was going to ask you to
dance, but I guess that's out,
huh?
[LAUGHING]
-I was expecting a younger,
more attractive nurse.
-She's the fourth in two weeks.
Daddy's a pincher.
[CHUCKLING]
-For heaven sakes, get that
guilty look off your face.
-I lost your umbrella,
I gave you the flu.
-Don't be silly.
It was raining, I got
wet, so I got the flu.
And it's not your fault.
I was wondering how you
would look out of uniform.
Isn't bad.
-It's my fault.
-I would have
caught this, anyway.
I catch cold even from
weather forecasts.
Thank you for the
lovely flowers.
-Oh!
-What's the matter?
-I don't know.
You look so pale and
sweet and faceless.
-Remember, the nurse is
right outside the door.
Not that I'll call her.
-One thing I learned these
last weeks, I love you.
-You loved me the first day.
-I did?
-You sure did.
We should have told
each other then.
-Look at all headway
we could have made.
-For the first time in my life,
I wish I had lots of money.
Oh, money!
-Daddy says it isn't what
you have, it's what you owe.
-I don't even owe enough.
-And what are your
prospects young man?
-Prospects?
My old job on the
news at 65 a week.
-Please!
I'm only suppose to
think beautiful thoughts.
Doesn't DuPont or General Motors
need a president or something?
-Well, the Paris office
of the Europa News Service
needs a reporter.
-Paris!
-It doesn't pay as much
as the New York job.
-But you don't need money
to have fun in Paris.
-Yeah, yeah.
Well, I've been
working on a book.
I should get back to the States.
-Why can't you write
your book here?
Oh, Charlie, darling, please
marry me and let's stay here.
Please?
-Oh, it sounds so wonderful.
But isn't it a little crazy?
-Yes, it is crazy.
If you had any sense, you
would walk right out that door
and never see me
or call me again.
Maybe send back my
umbrella and call it quits.
-But I haven't any sense.
No sense at all.
-You have no sense, I have
a one degree temperature.
If I were 98.6, this
would never happen.
[DOOR CLOSING]
-Forgive me, but, uh,
I'm rather enjoying
playing the anxious father.
After all, it's Helen's
first marriage, you know.
-Only marriage, sir.
-Tut, tut!
No arrogance, please.
Helen tells me that you are
a very serious-minded person.
You know, both feet on
the ground, hard working,
industrious.
-Well, I try to be, sir.
-I tell you frankly,
these are not
the qualities I'd hope
for in a son-in-law.
I'll uh, go even further.
They're, uh, not the
qualities to make Helen happy.
-Oh, well, sir, I uh-- I'm going
to work on a Paris news agency.
I'll be surrounded by carefree,
irresponsible characters.
Some of it is bound
to rub off on me.
-Hm.
Well, let us hope so.
Tell me, do I uh, do I strike
you as being an unusual father?
-You certainly do.
-That's a very
straightforward answer.
Try to overcome this tendency.
You understand,
of course, that I
can't afford to give
you a large wedding.
-I don't care for one, thanks.
-Care for a drink?
-Oh, yes.
I'd love one, thank you.
-Oh, it's too bad.
You know, I'm getting a little
low on this stuff and I was--
-Oh, that's all right, I'll--
-Here you are.
-Oh, thank you.
-Do you know what you're
getting for a wedding present?
-Well, Helen told me
what not to expect.
-My dear, sir, you are
getting the old family joke.
4,000 acres of
invaluable oil land.
-Thank you, very much, sir.
-Not at all.
You know, after all it's
not bad being an oil baron,
even if there's no oil, uh?
[LAUGHING]
-Well, did you give
Helen your permission?
I had to give her my permission.
-Huh?
-Claude has asked me do be
the mother of his children.
-Really?
That-- that-- that seems a
bit irregular, doesn't it?
Huh?
-Dad, Claude has asked
her to marry him.
-Oh!
Well, then I suppose
I must kiss you.
Hm?
-Do you, uh, say best
wishes to the bride?
Or congratulations to the groom?
Or which way is it?
I've forgotten.
-You just go ahead
and kiss each other.
-What did you put
into that kiss?
-Well, why don't you
come here and find out.
-Helen, getting married,
Marion getting married.
A father abandoned
in middle age, ahh.
Hmm!
What man could ask for more.
[TYPING]
-Give me a rewrite
on that, will you?
-How you feeling?
-Pretty good!
-Good, good.
That-- that beard looks good.
-Ah, Charlie, if you're getting
around to asking for money,
not a chance.
I haven't got a franc.
If I had any, I wouldn't
give it to you anyway.
-The prices aren't going
up here like in the States.
-Neither are the--
-Fellas, please!
I've got a wife and baby
waiting in the hospital.
I need 500 bucks to
get them out of hock.
-Why don't you leave them there?
It's the healthiest in town.
-Ah, you can make jokes,
you're not a father.
-Oh, I don't know.
All the returns aren't in yet.
[BABY CRYING]
-Ahh!
How about it, Your Highness?
There's nothing like a hot tub
after a long day's hollering,
is there?
Ahh, there.
Ha, ha.
Look at those legs, will you.
A regular man-killer.
Forgive me, Your Highness.
This is not the
Follies Percheron.
-I beg your forgiveness.
-What can you expect from
the common herd, my lady?
Huh?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Claude!
-Charles!
-Well!
-I have good news.
-Fine, fine!
Where's Helen?
HELEN: Charlie?
-OH!
Oh, how's Marion?
-She's fine.
-Oh, that's fine, fine.
Hiya, fatso.
-[SIGH] Fatso is right.
Look at me, bulging
out of my own clothes.
-I happen to be insane
about each every bulge.
Where's Vicki?
-Being bathed.
-Mm.
I just can't help it.
You look so pretty to me.
Of course, I've been looking
at my editor all day.
-Oh, did you hit
him for the bonus?
-Mm, hm!
I got, too.
Only it's not a
bonus, it's a loan.
I sent it right off
to the hospital.
So you can tell your
daughter to come out now,
she's all paid for.
--[SIGH] I'll never,
never be a size 10 again.
-Vicki will be exactly like you.
Then I'll be surrounded
by beautiful women.
-That compliment and a martini
would just about square you
for putting me in
jail for nine months.
-Mm, martini coming right up.
-Charles?
-Yes, Claude.
-I was appointed to the
prosecutor's staff yesterday.
-But what about your
private practice?
-But this is more important.
There are many collaborators
must be brought to justice.
-Sure.
And the lawyers who
defend them will get rich
and you'll get
convictions and be broke.
-Ta-da!
Gentlemen, the Queen.
-Ah,
-Ha, ha.
-Hello, Highness.
Well, what happened to her hair?
She had some yesterday.
-Wishful thinking, that's all.
-You know, she's not
bad for a first try.
-You had better be beautiful.
A genius and terribly rich.
-The beauty she got
from my daughter.
The genius she
inherited from me.
You had better get busy with
your contribution, my boy.
-The last nine months
I've devoted to you.
Now, I'm going to have fun.
What do you say, sweetheart?
Whee!
-Hey!
[LAUGHING]
-No guts, eh?
-Ah!
[TYPING]
-I was wondering if you
could uh, uh-- Thank you!
I uh, trust you're keeping a
record of these loans, huh?
Goodnight!
-Goodnight!
-Goodnight, angel.
[TYPING]
-Sure you won't come along?
You hate me for not holding your
hand while you have your baby?
-If you held my hand, the
next thing I'd hold yours,
and the next thing,
I'd kiss you.
And the next thing, uh--
-Mm, I like that.
-You're a glutton.
-Coax me not to go out.
-I can finish this
thing tonight.
-Please, it's not a thing.
It's a great American novel.
Charlie, will you still
worship me when you're famous?
-Well?
Say it.
-It's even better
than the first book.
It's beautiful.
It's too good for them.
Let's send it off tonight.
-Come on, wake up.
Spit on it for good luck.
That a girl!
ANNOUNCER (ON RADIO):
This Christmas night, it
is five years since the
end of World War II.
Veterans everywhere
pray that peace
will come with the new year.
[MUSIC, "OH COME ALL YE
FAITHFUL"]
Vicki: Daddy?
Daddy.
Daddy?
-Well!
Ah.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-English, darling, English.
Oh!
-I had a bad dream.
-Grownups have
them too, darling.
I'll get you of milk, huh?
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[SIGH]
-One kiss for the road.
-Ha, ha, you're not Ben Hur.
You lost the race.
-I need consolation.
-Hiya, Charlie.
I lost the race and your
wife won't console me.
MAN: Hi, Charlie!
-Next time win the race, huh?
-Goodnight!
-Look, see here.
-Mm!
-I didn't forget.
-Ah!
-Goodnight, everybody.
Hi!
-Hi!
[SHOUTING]
[PARTY MUSIC PLAYING]
-Charlie!
You're not Charlie.
Where is Charlie?
-You haven't told her yet, huh?
-Why spoil her fun?
-Why let it spoil yours?
-I'm peculiar, that's why.
I used up a year of my life
trying to write a book.
For some unaccountable
reason, I thought
somebody would
want to publish it.
-My boy, you're not
in the least peculiar.
You're merely naive.
Now I knew a publisher
once, and he made it
a rule never to
read a manuscript.
Oh, he would smell it and weigh
it and feel it and taste it.
But read it?
No.
Now, if this manuscript smelled
and weighed and felt and tasted
like garbage, then
he published it.
Would you like to know
the secret of success?
Mediocrity, my boy.
To be a rich writer, you've
got to remember your three
R's, riches, ruffians, and rape.
[SINGING "AULD LANG SYNE"]
-Hey!
Hey!
"Saturday Evening Post" bought
my serial, 15,000 bucks!
-How about that!
-Yeah!
-Goodbye!
-Thanks, thanks.
Uh,uh, uh.
Farewell, hacks, forever.
MAN 1: $15,000, tax-free too!
MAN 2: He could have at least
thrown a party for everybody.
-Merci beaucoup.
Charlie, uh, run down to
the police station will you?
-What for?
-Oh, some crazy American dame.
Seems she held up
traffic by taking a dive
into a fountain at noon, today.
-Not much of a story is it?
-No, but you know how
Americans in Paris
love to read about
Americans in Paris.
-Oh, all right, what's her name?
-Helen Wills.
[LAUGHING]
-That's my girl.
-No use acting as if
you didn't know me.
I'm your wife.
In sickness and in health,
in dry clothes and damp.
-You know how you
are with colds.
You had better go
home and change.
-We can't go home,
Vicki's at the Dingo.
-Again!
-Isn't she better off in a
nice respectable bistro then
all alone at home?
This gonna get in the papers?
-One more crazy American
jumping into one
more beautiful fountain.
That isn't news any more.
Is that why you did
it, to get into print?
-I guess it was
silly and stupid.
But it was fun.
-Was it?
-Well, almost fun.
On the verge of being fun.
-Only it never is, quite, is it?
-No, somehow it never is.
I don't know why.
Maybe it's something about
Paris, or me, or the times,
or something.
It's as if you gotta hurry up.
Hurry before-- it's like
you're trying to find out
something terribly
important only--
-Only you never do.
-Oh, come on now, you always
laughed at these things.
It took a little
time but you laughed.
-It isn't that.
Campbell just sold a
serial to the "Saturday
Evening Post" for $15,000.
-And you hate him for it?
Oh, darling I think that's
wonderfully human of you.
[LAUGHING]
-Finally?
[DANCE MUSIC]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-What's he saying,
he's talking so fast.
-This is Marcel.
-How do you do.
Who are you?
-He says he's going
to immortalize me.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-What?
Are you running for
office or something?
-Oh, you me.
Always good for a
couple of laughs.
MAURICE: Mrs. Wills, it's a
good thing to make people laugh.
-Don't I get anything?
I paid the fine to
get her out of jail.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Papa!
-Anglais, sweetie, English.
Papa, I have been
waiting to show you,
this morning-- [SPEAKING FRENCH]
-No, Vicki.
Not half and half.
All English.
-Watch, Daddy, watch.
-Hold it!
I haven't been kissed yet.
Ha, ha, ha.
-Hey, Charlie.
-Barney!
You want to see something great?
Go on.
Ha, ha.
Oh!
-Pretty young to be hitting
the bottle, isn't she?
It's the floor, darling.
Even Pavlova couldn't
dance on a floor like this.
Are you all right?
-I'm sorry.
-Say something nice.
-It's swell kid, great.
The boss wants me on an
interview at the Royal France.
I can't handle it,
got a heavy date.
Cover for me, will you?
Uh, the woman's name
is Lorraine Quarl.
-Who's Lorraine Quarl?
-Cafe society.
So long, kid.
You got a great act there.
Great!
All it needs is a finish.
-Oh, oh.
You've got the right finish,
haven't you, sweetheart?
Right into my arms.
Ha, ha.
-Mr. Wills!
-Mrs Quarl!
I am Wills from the
Europa News Service.
-I hate to be late.
I'm sorry.
And I need a drink.
Leon!
-The same, Mrs. Quarl?
-Please!
You can skip the usual.
Paris is beautiful.
American women love French men.
French men love American women.
Prices are too high.
I haven't picked out
my next husband yet.
Might be the bartender,
at least he has talent.
-You've been interviewed before.
-The last time, an hour ago.
He wasn't very young
or very attractive.
The interview was
very, very short.
But then, take your time.
-Oh.
First trip to Paris?
Oh, no, no.
First divorce here, that's all.
-Why did you choose Paris?
-I get saddle sores
in Reno, and I
lose too much
money in Las Vegas.
-According to our files,
you were married four times.
-Three.
Annulments don't count.
Leon!
-Is something wrong?
-Is something right?
-You-- you really can't tell one
of my marriages from another.
But that's the problem.
Husband number one, for love.
Failure.
Husband number two for money.
Failure, except for the
money and the name Quarl.
-Ha!
LORRAINE: Husband
number three, annulment.
He forgot to tell me
he already had a wife.
Husband number
four, a bullfighter.
Four times I bet,
haven't had a hit.
-Any children involved?
-No.
And that's my only
contribution to humanity.
I told you I was a failure.
Mm, shouldn't you be
writing this down?
-Oh, the interview
stopped long ago.
-Thank you.
I'm hungry.
What about dinner?
-Uh, I am not an
expense account.
I'm just a struggling
newspaper man.
-Oh, well, stop struggling.
The dinner is on
my four husbands.
I'll change and
I'll be right down.
-But what about the--
-Please, Mr. Wills.
At home my enemy charges $50
an hour to listen to me talk.
[CHUCKLING]
-Hey!
That's my taxi!
-Charles!
-Hello, Claude!
I'm glad to see ya.
How have you been?
-Fine.
-You look fine.
How are ya, Marion?
-Fine.
-You look fine.
I'm fine, too.
Ha, ha.
Oh, excuse me.
Uh, my sister-in-law, Mrs.
Matine, Mr. Matine, Mrs. Quarl.
-How do you do?
-Uh, Claude's with the
Prosecutor's Office.
-Oh?
I hope we haven't
done anything wrong.
[CHUCKLING]
-Uh, Mrs. Quarl just
arrived in Paris.
I'm, uh, interviewing her.
-How's Helen?
-Fine.
Fine.
Oh, and you should Vicki.
She's, you know, we really
should see more of each other.
After all family and--
-I'll get in touch with
Helen in the morning.
Goodnight, Mrs. Quarl.
-Goodnight.
-Charles, I really would
like to see you again.
Goodnight.
-Goodnight, Claude.
Thank you.
-How is Helen?
-Oh, now what's one little
wife among all your husbands?
-I'll imagine you'll catch
it when you get home.
-From Helen?
Not Helen.
She's the most wonderful,
most understanding--
do you mind if we don't
go on with the interview?
Somehow, I'm
suddenly cold sober.
And it's awfully late.
And if I don't get back to
the office and do this story--
-Can I go with you?
To the office, I mean.
-Why?
-I don't know.
We'll probably never
see each other again,
and I-- I'd like to drag
the night out a little.
And I should see that story.
-Oh, that office
is awful cold and
dingy at this hour
of the morning.
-You would be surprised how
often I feel cold and dingy.
I'll be simpatico.
-Well, good morning.
Now what's the matter?
Oh, Charlie, how could you?
Don't Charlie me, sister.
What about you?
I'm sick and tired
of you sitting
around these crummy cafes
day and night, the darling
of every phony, petted by
writers who don't write,
adored by painters
who don't paint.
And what do you write?
Interviews with
useless, sloppy women.
Well, at least I don't
jump into fountains
and lap up all the
liquor in Paris!
Well, why don't you
ask me why I drink,
why I jump in the fountains?
That's right, blame me.
Blame me.
Did I want to stay in Paris?
What right have you
to criticize me?
You're suspicious?
You?
Ah!
That's a laugh!
Now you just listen to me!
-Morning, darling.
-Helen.
Do you realize what time it is?
-Mm.
Mm, does it matter, darling?
-It's 8 o'clock in the morning!
-Mm, it's your turn to
take Vicki to school.
-Do you realize I've
been out all night?
-Mm, poor darling.
All right, I'll
take her to school.
-Well, don't you care I've been?
-You look awful!
Was it a tough assignment?
-I was interviewing a woman.
-Mm, that's nice.
You have much better
copy than that.
-She was a rich,
beautiful, exciting woman.
She was interested in me.
Well, don't you even care?
-What are you trying
to say, Charlie?
-I'm trying to say
that I love you.
-What kind of a woman
did you say she was?
-How many kinds are there?
-Was she really pretty?
-I'd lie about it,
but Marion her, too.
Yes, she's very pretty.
-Marion?
-Oh, we ran into
Claude and Marion.
She'll probably try to build
up into something, but--
-Just how rich and
how pretty was she?
-Oh, shut up!
-Mm, that's nice.
[PHONE RINGING]
[SIGH]
-I don't hear a thing, do you?
[PHONE RINGING]
-I'll be back in a minute.
-Hello, Marion.
What?
Say that again!
-It's a lie!
You know how Marion
has never liked me.
-Charlie, we're rich!
We're rich!
-Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
-You old fraud!
Why didn't you tell us?
-I am not old.
I couldn't tell you
last night, because I
was celebrating last night.
I stopped by Marion's on
my way home this morning
and had breakfast.
And then told her then.
-How much are we worth?
Marion said that you said
that we're stinking rich.
-Oh, Marion always
editorializes.
Money has no odor.
-Oh, especially lots of it!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-English, Vicki, English.
-Are we millionaires?
-Insanity, there's a
wide streak of insanity
in this family, Vicki,
on your mother's side.
-We have hit an oil gusher!
-We what?
-Oil, darling!
It's about to put
Texas on the map.
-You mean, those worthless
oil leases of ours?
-A generous wedding
present from me,
which I trust you'll
remember and keep in mind.
-How rich are we?
-Well, there's this
state law about only
pumping out 80 barrels a day.
Now at $2 a barrel, that's, uh--
-That's only $160 a day.
-Seven days a week?
-Of course.
Oil is an act of God.
-That-- that's $1,100 a week!
-And 27 1/2% tax-free.
-What if we sold out?
-My thoughts exactly!
A capital gain.
-But if we didn't sell out,
we'd have an income for life!
-Is everybody from
Milwaukee cautious?
-Sensible, just sensible.
-Well, we'll decorate
everything from top to toe.
Me too.
I'll have my hair cut.
We'll take Marion's
room and turn
it into a writing room for you.
Do you suppose we really could
run through $50,000 in a year?
-Well, we could try.
-We?
-Oh!
Mm.
-You know what?
-Of course, we could
drill another well!
-Marion never said a word about
running into you last night.
-Mama, what's oil?
-Oh, Vicki!
Oh!
Ah, ha!
-Ha, ha.
[WHISTLING]
-How do you like it?
It's mine, all mine!
[HORN]
[SINGING A DIRGE]
-Open the shroud.
No more deadlines,
no more journalism.
The job is dead.
Lower away.
-Catch it!
[CHEERING]
-That's wonderful.
-What are you gonna
do now, Charlie?
-Now?
Now I'll finish my third novel.
If this one doesn't
get published--
-It'll get published.
-I got no money worries,
I got no job worries.
What would I use for an excuse?
-If you got enough money,
no excuses are necessary.
Good luck with it, Charlie.
-Thank you.
-Good luck, there.
-That will be 5,000
francs, please.
-Oh, I should like to
do more for charity.
Oh, well, that's nice.
-Helen.
Uh, pardon me once,
s'il vous plait?
-Uh, 6,000 for another kiss.
-I'm really worth
much more, you know.
-But--
-I never expected to see
you at a charity event.
-Neither did I.
-Something wrong?
-Yeah.
-Vicki?
-No, Charlie.
Look, he hasn't moved
from his room all day.
He's still there.
He won't eat anything,
he won't say anything.
Just sits there in
the dark, alone.
-Charlie?
What's the matter, darling?
Have you had dinner?
Do you want me to fix something?
-Go away, Helen.
Let me alone.
-Is it something I've done?
Please, Charlie, whatever it--
-All right, I'll admit it.
You're a good wife.
You're devoted and loyal.
You've done your duty.
[SIGH] Now please go back to
your party and let me alone.
-I'm only trying to help.
-Help what?
-You, me, us.
I don't know.
-Help what?
This?
Can you help another rejection?
Can anybody help that?
-Why?
Because some publisher
turned you down again?
-Yes.
Again!
Again, Helen.
And again!
Can you help it that
I'm stupid enough
to spend five years
writing three stupid books?
Can you help it
that I'm no writer?
-But you are!
You're wonderful.
They're the ones that
are stupid, not you.
-Dear Mr. Wills, we regret
to inform you-- I'm no good,
Helen.
Go away and let me alone.
-Oh, Charlie!
-Please!
I can't explain
my failure to you.
Now be a good girl
and let me alone!
-But you're not a
failure, not to me.
-When I was 20, I used to think
I would write great books.
I would be able to do this,
because I was different.
I wanted perfection, and
that made me different.
Well, I'm not 20 anymore.
And it's too late now.
HELEN: But we'll try again.
-No!
I just don't have what it takes.
All I need to do now is
get used to the idea.
I'm rich.
For the price of a
few drinks, I could
buy fame and friends,
or something like them.
Why spend years writing?
I can hold court
in some noisy bar
and criticize writing and
talk about writing and--
-You'll never make it, boy.
-25 bucks says I do.
MAN: Stop this.
-We've already got 75 bet.
-Make it 100.
-All right, 100.
Sucker.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Charlie.
-Oh!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Watch this, baby.
-Come on, Charlie!
Pull, pull it, Charlie.
-Aha!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MAN: Hey, Charlie, you beat me.
-Viola!
Ah!
-That a boy, Charlie!
[PLUNKING PIANO]
-All right, Charlie.
-Winner, and still champion.
And this is the arm that did it.
Ha, ha.
-Take me home.
Waiting for the car.
It's getting souped
up for the race.
-Race?
-Sports car event.
Monte Carlo to Paris.
[WOMAN SINGING IN FRENCH]
-Take me home now, please.
-That's what I thought you said.
[WOMAN SINGING "THE LAST TIME I
SAW PARIS"]
[TYPING]
-Uh, anybody phone?
-No.
[SIGH]
-Kind of quiet, isn't it?
-It's nice, though, isn't it?
-Why hasn't Vicki come
in to say goodnight?
-Your daughter is in a
compete state of crisis.
One of her front teeth fell out.
-How's she taking it?
-Oh, life is completely
over for her.
She says she'll come
in if she doesn't
have to smile or open her mouth.
-Sure.
I know a big, dramatic
situation when I see one.
-You don't really mind
staying in tonight, do you?
-Of course not.
-How's it going?
-Uh, it's not easy
getting started again.
-But you promised.
-And I'm trying.
-And you'll make it.
-Poor little ballerina.
Ugh!
Ha, ha.
Ha, thank you, very much.
Not a bad kiss at
all considering.
When will you smile again?
At least can you
give me an estimate?
Teeth grow back in a
few months, you know.
But by that time, those
muscles will be all set hard
and you won't be able to smile.
They say you're the
wickedest woman in Paris.
You know what I'll
look like pretty soon?
-Ha!
Daddy!
[KNOCKING]
JAMES: May I borrow
a pair of cuff links?
I can't seem to--
[CHUCKLING]
-Both of you put your
upper plates back in,
you're making me self-conscious.
-Can I dance for you, Grandpa?
-In the morning, my dear.
-I have to get up
at 6:00 tomorrow.
-Well, now that
will work out fine,
because I should be
getting in by then.
-Goodnight, darling.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Bon oui.
Milk, literature, what's
the meaning of this?
-I'm supposed to be working.
-Your idea?
-It's a fine idea.
Don't you corrupt him.
-I wouldn't think of it.
But we will miss
you at the Wilson's.
Can you imagine throwing
a white tie party simply
because it's Thursday?
-Couldn't we go?
-Oh, Charlie.
-Really, it would
be good for me.
And tomorrow morning, I'll
chain myself to that chair.
Please!
[SIGH]
-Why do I always end up saying
yes when I really mean no?
-By the way, I'm
bringing a friend.
He's an international
tennis bum.
Paul.
Now don't worry about
him at the Wilson's, he's
invited everywhere.
Come to think of it, that's,
uh, how he makes his living.
-You mean he gets paid
for being a guest?
-No, no.
Uh, he steals the silverware.
-Charming.
-Paul, my, uh, my daughter and
Charles Wills, my son-in-law.
-How do you do?
-Anchante.
-I hear you played in Rome.
-I play all the tournaments.
-How do you make out?
-Brilliantly, until
the second round.
Then invariably some
young Australian
or American school boy beats me.
-But nobody beats him
in jumping over the net
and congratulating the winner.
-I'm the champion
graceful loser.
Forgive me, but you're
the lady in the fountain
in the Cafe Dingo.
Why, it's my favorite painting.
Whenever I'm in Paris, I
go there to stare at it.
-Well, you're in luck.
Now you can stare
at the original.
JAMES: Come with me, Paul.
-Until later.
-Sort of appealing, isn't he?
-What?
-Appealing.
-Yes, in a revolting
sort of way.
Anchante!
-Well, my dear, it was the
funniest thing you ever saw.
All those gangsters on
the television and it's
DuFour asking all
those questions.
Nobody in New York works at all.
-What?
-What did George
Bernard Shaw die of?
-Mostly old age.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-You're going to drive
in this race yourself?
-Certainly.
-What do you get if you win?
-What do you get?
You get to be winner,
that's what you get.
-Well, what do you know.
It's my wife.
Hiya, wife.
All right sporting blood,
run along to the locker room.
-Come back in a
few minutes, Paul.
It's only his guilty conscience.
It won't take long.
-Hey, what kind of a wife are
you, dancing with other men?
-The average kind, neglected.
-Oh.
Whats with Mr. Tennis and you?
-Oh, we're Paul and Helen now.
-Mm.
-He's sweet and attentive.
Doesn't think it's terrible
at all that I'm married
and have a
seven-year-old daughter.
-Maybe he just wants
to be mothered.
Ha, ha.
-Not exactly.
He's made several conjectures,
but that wasn't one of them.
-Well, let me know
how he makes out.
Lorraine!
Lorraine Quarl!
You've forgotten me?
-Oh, believe me, the only
thing I've forgotten about you
is your name.
-Wills, Europa News Service.
-Charlie!
Ha, ha!
Oh, it's so good to have
my arms around you again.
-Oh, well, you've got me
confused with somebody else.
We never got that far.
-Why not?
-You get married again?
-Of course.
And I'm embarrassed
now to get rid of him.
Are you still married?
-Yes, of course.
LORRAINE: To the same woman?
-To the same wonderful woman.
I have to say that, 'cause
she's standing right here.
May I present my wife,
Helen, Mrs. Quarl.
-Oh, it's Mrs.Johnson now.
Oh, but not for long.
How do you do?
-I'm not quite sure.
-You're much prettier
than I expected.
-And you're much less beat up
than you have a right to be.
[CHUCKLING]
-Uh, is it all right if
I, uh, come back now?
-Oh, Paul Lane, this is the,
uh, temporary Mrs. Johnson.
-The best mediocre tennis
player in the world.
-I've seen you around my hotel.
-Oh, I always stay
at the Royal France.
-Tennis anyone?
-Yes!
CHARLES: Your hair is like wine.
It keeps you drunk.
-Charlie, I'd like to go home.
-Home?
What's the matter?
-Nothing.
I'd just like to go home.
-Does that sound
reasonable to you?
Uh!
-Are you going to take me home?
-Oh, I would, but I can't.
I promised to show Lorraine
how fast the car would go.
Ha, ha.
-Do you mind if
Paul takes me home?
[SIGH]
-Paul?
Paul, who?
-Paul Anybody.
A party like this,
there must easily
be six or seven Paul's around.
[SIGH]
-You can't hold a serious
discussion with her.
I can get up to 60 miles
an hour with this baby--
in second gear!
[LOWLY WHISTLING]
[DOOR SLAMS]
-I've been up for hours.
-Well, that-- that's a habit
you must try and grow out of,
kitten.
-Why do grownups drink milk
when they have all 32 teeth?
-Well, develop butterflies
in our stomach,
and milk seems to
quiet them down.
-How do they get
in your stomach?
-They usually hide in
the bubbles of champagne.
-But--
-It's a well-known
fact of hydrodynamics.
Goodnight, my dear.
-Goodnight.
[BANG]
-Get you coat, Vicki
-Can Daddy come with
us to the de Beaune?
-We're going to church first.
-Is it Sunday already?
What happened to
Friday and Saturday?
-Run along, Vicki.
-Are you coming, Daddy?
-I'll meet you at
the de Beaune later.
Church on Friday?
What happens at
church on Friday?
-The usual thing.
Well, as long as you're
in that sort of mood,
can I expect a little
sympathy for this head?
Heads?
HELEN: Very little.
-What did I do?
-That, I'd be very
interested to hear.
-I'd like to go for a
ride on that thing myself.
How about it?
Must you look so grim?
-I'm waiting to hear
the end of the midnight
ride of Paul Revere.
You got the car up
to 103 miles an hour
and then started back, right?
-Right.
-Then what?
-Then nothing.
I dropped Lorraine at her hotel,
or she dropped me at the house.
I forget which.
-You sure that's all
you've forgotten?
-I'm sorry to disappoint
you, but nothing
happened last night.
-Tonight's another night.
She'll be beautiful again.
You'll be full of wine again.
-And nothing will happen again.
Who took you home last night?
That tennis player?
He didn't exactly take me home.
-Oh!
-He asked me back to his
hotel for a nightcap.
I went.
-Did you have to
fight your way out?
-Oh, there was a
battle, all right.
But it wasn't Paul I had a
fight with, it was myself.
-Did you win?
-Now you listen!
I'm under the same strains
and stresses you are.
I live in Paris, too.
And I'm bored, too.
And all that time,
I had a picture
in my mind of you
and that woman.
And don't underestimate Paul.
He's charming and attentive
and-- and I'm so unhappy.
Charlie, let's go home.
-All right, as soon as
Vicki finishes with--
-I mean really home!
America!
Home!
-It won't work, running home.
-Charlie, let's go back,
before we crack up.
Please.
If you love me,
let's go back home.
-You used to say, let's
live it up a little.
And you were right.
There's lots of time to go home.
Plenty of time for everything.
-Suppose time runs out on us.
-You're just having
a bad day, darling.
Tomorrow will--
-I've been having a
bad day for a year now.
Maybe I'm growing up.
-It's too late to grow up.
-I'll tell you what.
Come racing with me.
We'll go to Monte Carlo.
-Why is winning a
race so important?
-Oh, I don't know.
Maybe I could do a short
story about racing.
Why not?
Oh, all right, all right.
I get a kick out racing.
It's fun.
The culture illustrious father.
Nothing is more
important than fun.
Does that make me sound stupid?
Is that what you want me to say?
Come with me, Helen.
-No, Charlie.
-Well, maybe I'll
take somebody else.
Wouldn't that be reasonable?
-You'll find a reason
to make it reasonable.
Look out for Vicki, will you?
-Well, where are you going?
To do something
important-- buy a new hat.
[ENGINES REVVING]
-Can we stop for a while now?
Please?
[THUNDER]
[WOMAN SINGING]
Cognac, quickly, two of them.
-Mr. Wills.
-Mrs. Wills, is she here?
-This ought to be good.
-Well, look who's here!
What's the news from
the racing world?
-I called you at the
house, you weren't there.
-Of course not.
I'm here.
-That's not funny.
-You haven't been at
that house for a week.
I didn't think that
was very funny either.
Now i think it's
very, very funny.
You remember Paul, don't you?
No?
Well, that's sort of funny, too,
because I remember Lorraine.
-Uh, will you join
us for some dinner?
-Ah, shut up!
-I'd love to join you.
-The times that you drink
champagne with me are slipping.
-We've already done that.
How do like him?
Don't you think he
makes me look drunker?
-I hope you don't mind a
harmless little dinner.
HELEN: Oh, come on, Paul.
You can do better than that.
You could tell them to go away,
for instance, leave us alone.
-Not me, dear.
He's your responsibility.
-Oh, please.
We're all very civilized, no?
-No.
-That's my boy.
-Touch me again and
I'll take a poke at ya.
-I wouldn't do that,
Charlie, because then I
would have to take
a poke at Lorraine.
[LAUGHING]
-What's so funny?
-Why, you, me, all of us.
Very funny.
[SCREAMS]
-Please stop, Charles.
Please.
[RAINING]
-Wiseguy!
The world's full of wiseguys.
Helen!
[SIGH]
Oh!
Oh, Helen!
-You're beautiful.
-And married.
-And exciting.
-And rich, too.
Ah, love, old soul.
-Of course, I love you.
-Love is never, of course.
Is it?
-Please, I'll never
let you be lonely.
-Paul?
-Hm.
How are we going to tell him?
-Tell him?
Tell him what?
-About us.
That you love me.
I'm not going back to him.
-Why, that's silly.
Well, of course you're
going back to him.
Well, if you don't
go back to him,
well, he'll spoil
everything for us.
You can see that, can't you?
-Of course, darling.
I stay married and
keep you on the side.
And when I'm lonely-- ha!
Oh, brother!
PAUL: The idea wasn't
invented just now.
(SCOFF) It's done all the time.
Half your crowd
have arrangements.
-Is that what you
expected of me?
-Helen, listen.
What's the matter with you?
-Suddenly, I've
got very cold feet.
[DOOR UNLOCKING]
-Charlie.
Please, Charlie.
Do you want me to go away?
Is that what you want?
[DOORBELL RINGING]
-Coming, Ma.
-Helen!
-I am sorry.
I couldn't find a taxi.
I-- I couldn't--
-Doctor.
-Run and see Wells.
He's never been warned.
Fetch him.
-He's outside.
-He can't see her.
I won't let him.
-(WEAKLY) Marion.
You took my umbrella.
-I'm sorry, darling.
So sorry.
Please forgive me.
-Shh.
Take care of Vicki.
Don't let Vicki make
the same mistakes.
I'll always love you.
-Please, Mr. Wills.
-Leave us alone.
-Mr. Wills--
-Get out.
-You'll have to leave here.
Now, Mr. Wills, this no way to--
-Get out of here!
-Out in the hall, Doctor.
-But Doctor, [INAUDIBLE].
-You had better go, son.
Vicki's alone.
[CRYING]
Charlie, what are
you going to do, son?
You've got to talk to Marion.
If you don't, you're
going to lose Vicki.
She's going into
court today and going
to ask for custody
of Vicki, charging
you are unfit as a parent.
-She's right.
I'll hurt Vicki,
just as I did Helen.
-What will you do?
-I want to go home.
All the way home.
[WOMAN SINGING IN FRENCH]
-A thing of beauty, huh?
-Oh, Maurice.
I'm sorry, I'm late now.
-Americans!
Always in a haste.
And the rich American,
it's even worse.
-Not rich anymore, Maurice.
-What happened to the, uh-- oil?
No?
-No, Maurice.
It changed back to
salt water a year ago.
-Oh, that's unfortunate.
-Maybe not.
-You must dine with us tonight,
like old times, Charles.
-I don't know.
It depends.
-Jeanette will be
very disappointed.
You have many things
to remember together.
Come back, Charles, please.
-Oh, I'll try.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
-Charlie.
Hello, son.
-What happened?
-Oh, a slight stroke.
-When?
-Eight or nine months ago.
-But you never
wrote me about it.
-Oh, it wasn't serious.
Mostly old age.
Charlie, I read your book.
It's good.
Very honest.
-Thanks.
-Yeah.
I liked it.
I liked it, fine.
-Uh, here.
For you, Havana cigars.
The kind you like.
Shall I open them for you?
-Oh, later.
Uh, doctor says when
I'm better, huh?
-Where's Vicki?
You've come for her?
-If I can get her back again.
-Good.
Good.
-Daddy!
Daddy!
-You're taller.
-Daddy.
-What?
-You're not grey.
I told everybody at
school you'd be grey.
-Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, here.
-Thanks.
-Claude!
Welcome, Charles.
I'm very happy to see you.
-Thanks.
For everything, thanks.
-As soon as I got your telephone
message, I went to school
and got Vicki.
VICKI: Look, Daddy!
Look!
-Uh-oh!
Oh!
It's wonderful, as usual.
-Daddy!
-What?
-Could we go to de Beaune?
Remember the rainbow train?
-Well, I--
-Oh, please?
Please?
That was the very first thing
I wanted to do when you came.
-You've got about an hour
till Marion comes back.
-I'll wear my new coat.
-OK.
How is Marion?
-She's fine.
-I want to know, Claude,
how much I appreciate--
-Oh, I didn't do anything.
I showed Marion your letter.
She couldn't stop you
from seeing Vicki.
-I was hoping she would
let me have Vicki back.
I've got to have her, Claude.
I need her.
-Yes, I think she
needs you, too.
VICKI: Daddy!
Daddy!
Hurry, Daddy!
The hour is almost is almost up.
-I bought your book.
And about Marion, if we are
careful, if may be all right.
-Daddy?
-What?
-What's wrong?
-Why, nothing, darling.
Why?
-You didn't even look at me.
You didn't even wave at me.
-Oh, ho.
Will you give me another chance?
You get back on that
train and I'll--
-Daddy, may I sit
out the next ride?
-Oh.
-I'm really getting too
old for that sort of thing.
-Ha, ha.
-Don't you think so?
-Yes, you're really old now.
[CHUCKLING]
-Darling, do you ever
think of your mother?
-Oh, yes.
-I don't want you to forget her.
-I have a picture
of her in my room.
Grandpa says I look like her.
Do you think, so, Daddy?
-Yes.
Very much like her.
-That's lucky for me.
Daddy?
-What?
-Why don't I live with you?
-Oh, I-- aren't you happy?
-Yes.
But not perfectly happy.
Do you know what I mean?
-Yes.
I know what you mean.
-Then I can come
and live with you?
-I don't know.
I don't know.
-Don't you want me to?
-Oh, of course, darling.
-Oh, Daddy!
If you really love me, please
let me come and live with you.
Please!
[SIGH]
We'll see.
-Say yes, Daddy.
-Yes.
-There, you see?
It wasn't so hard
to say yes, was it?
[DOORBELL RINGING]
-Hello, Uncle Claude.
From de Beaune we went to
Ernay's and we bought something
for you, Uncle Claude,
and for Aunt Marion.
And something for me, too.
It's a wonderful store
and a wonderful day!
[CHUCKLING]
Oh, Aunt Marion!
You ought to see what
we bought for you.
It's a surprise.
Look!
-You're late for your nap.
VICKI: But I thought today--
MARION: Go on up to your room.
-Don't you want to
see your present?
-Do as I say, please.
-Hello, Marion.
-Hello, Charles.
-It's good to see you again.
I'm sorry about getting
back so late with Vicki.
-Oh, well.
She would have been too
excited to sleep anyway.
-And it's very important.
-You've done a wonderful
job with Vicki.
She's grown up.
-How do find Paris?
-Well, most of the
old crowd is gone.
[SIGH] Funny, I dropped
in at the Dingo bar
this afternoon, just
to see how it looked.
There wasn't a man I knew.
-I should think you've
had enough of bars.
-As I wrote you, I take
one drink every afternoon,
but no more.
And I take that
drink deliberately.
Just so the idea of taking
a drink won't get too big.
CLAUDE: Of course, Charles.
We understand.
-Sometimes I forget and
don't take the drink.
But, well, I went to the
Dingo to see how it looked.
I went to a few
other places, too.
Places where, uh, Helen
and I-- look, Marion.
I just can't keep on talking.
I'm all tied up in knots here.
Marion, can I have Vicki back?
-I don't know.
It's all very well to talk
about one drink a day,
but what guarantee
have that-- well,
when I-- I think of
those wasted years.
-But I think about them too!
I'm working hard now, Marion.
I've, uh, got a contract
for several short stories.
And I'm-- I'm starting
on another book.
And my sister's
coming from Milwaukee
to-- to keep house for me.
I want Vicki.
Please, Marion.
If we wait much longer,
I'll-- I'll lose her childhood
and my-- my chance for a home.
I-- I just can't lose
her, don't you see?
It would be almost
like having Helen back.
-Marion.
-I can't help it.
I'll never, in my life, be able
to forget that morning when
Helen, soaked and--
and shivering.
You locked her out!
CLAUDE: Marion!
-But you only
remember one night.
How long are you gonna make
me pay for that one night?
What about those years Helen
and I loved each other?
-I don't want to hear about it!
-Marion, you're not
gonna let me have Vicki?
-No.
-Marion, please.
-I don't want to talk
about it anymore.
-I'm sorry, Charles.
-What will I do?
-We'll see.
[SIGH]
Thanks.
-I'll get dinner started.
-Marion.
-There's no use
talking about it.
He's not getting Vicki.
Not now, not tomorrow, never!
-Why?
Do you hate him that much?
-Yes.
For what he did, yes!
It's true.
He committed an unforgivable
crime, against you, personally.
He's guilty of never
knowing you loved him.
You found him, but
he married Helen.
And yes, he's
guilty of that, too.
And being guilty, of
course, he must be punished.
The penalty?
What would hurt him most.
Take away what he loves
most, his little girl.
My poor darling, we can't
have everything we want.
Take me.
I wanted all your love.
I wanted our own child.
A child out of our love, not
out of your disappointment.
[WOMAN SINGING]
-Charles.
May I see you
outside for a moment?
[WOMAN SINGING IN FRENCH]
I-- I don't Helen would
have wanted you to be alone.
-Daddy!
Daddy!
[WOMAN SINGING IN FRENCH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]