[THEME MUSIC]
-Morning, stranger.
-Hi, old timer.
Guess you don't remember me.
-Can't say as I do.
Yet there's something
mighty familiar about you.
-Well, Jake, I guess it's a
long time since you taught me
how to trap coyotes
and ride rocks.
-Jerry Mason, as I live.
Well, well.
Man, how you've grown.
Why say, you're a regular
mountain, ain't you?
Heh.
Sit down here, and
let's talk it over.
-Well, there's not
much to tell, Jake.
I finished college, and--
-True to your
dad's last request,
you've come to
live with me, huh?
Huh?
-That's right.
-I can't tell you how
happy I am to see you.
-And I'm happy to
be here, too, Jake.
How about the ranch, the cattle?
-There ain't no cattle, son.
Rustlers got most of 'em,
and I sold what was left.
-Well, can't we
stock it up again
or start in some other business?
-Itching to get to work, huh?
Well, I was figuring on
opening up the blacksmith shop,
but-- what do you say
we fry us a chicken
and gargle some coffee?
What do you say, huh?
-Sounds like a good idea,
especially that chicken.
[LAUGHTER]
JERRY MASON: Well, no wonder
this horse was limping.
COWBOY: Well, got him fixed up?
-Yep.
Your horse picked
up a sharp rock.
No, no.
There ain't no charge.
Looks like you've been
through plenty of water.
-Oh, yeah.
Tried a shortcut about 12 miles
back yonder and got stuck.
-Oh.
-Had to come right down through
the middle of the creek.
-Hmm.
-And that's where he went lame.
-Well, good luck to you.
-Come on, Bruno.
-Hey, I just picked this
up at the post office.
-I'll bet I know who it's from.
Heh, I was right.
Heh, heh.
It's from Betty. [CHUCKLES]
Well, I was right.
It's from Betty.
-Betty?
-Yeah, my granddaughter.
Didn't you know I
had a granddaughter.
-I certainly did not.
-Yes sirree.
I'm her only living relative.
I've been sending her college
for a couple of years.
But she'll soon be
here to live with me.
Let's she what she's got to say.
Dear Grandy, I just
received my monthly check,
and thank you so much.
I can't wait until
school is over
so I can come and live with you.
Gee, just three months more, and
I'll be keeping house for you.
Please write me a
nice, long letter.
I do so enjoy hearing from you.
Lovingly, Betty.
Heh.
She's a fine girl, Jerry.
And I'm going to do everything
I can to make her happy.
Well, hello Friday. [CHUCKLES]
-Hello.
-She's the town dog.
Everybody feeds her.
[CHUCKLES]
-Ah, so you want to play, eh?
Say, Jake.
-Huh?
-Take a look.
That's that piece of quartz that
came out of the horse's hoof.
It's gold.
-Say, there's a
stringer in there
bigger than a 10-penny nail.
-If we only knew
where it came from.
-I do know.
That prospector said
he was forced down
the middle of a
creek 12 miles out.
Well, there's only one
creek out there, Jerry,
and it'll be a cinch
to backtrack it.
-Well, we're on our way right
now, and if we find anything,
I know a dog that's
going to have
a porterhouse steak
and a home for life.
-You said it.
-Right there's where
he left the crick.
Wait a minute.
Look at that.
-Say, that's the
real stuff, son.
According to this pan,
the crick's full of color.
-Hello.
Hello, Benson.
What can I do for you?
-In the first place,
you fellows buy gold?
-Certainly.
That's part of our business.
-Well, weigh this up, and
let's see what we got.
-Say, that's the pure stuff.
It's good as I've ever seen.
They've made a great
strike somewhere.
Let's see.
At $16 an ounce,
that'll come to $848.
-OK, we'll take
that in currency,
if it's just the same to you.
-OK.
All right, Joe.
-Now, listen.
We expect to bring in
many times that amount.
We think we've got rich strike.
But we don't want anybody
to know anything about it.
-But you'll tell us, won't you?
-We're not telling
anybody, Harris.
But when we do get ready to
let the location be known,
you'll be the first
ones in on it.
-Thanks.
-Come on, Jake.
We got to go buy a dog
a porterhouse steak.
-They've made a rich strike,
and it's up to us to locate it.
I wouldn't mind having old
man Benson's ranch either.
He used to run cattle.
Huh.
Of course, he doesn't know
it, but I got most of them.
-You know, Jake,
it's a good thing
we didn't file on that claim.
It'd have just tipped the
whole town off to the location
and confined our operation.
As it is, we can
work the whole crick.
-Yeah.
Your idea of
crossing Windy Flats
and entering the town
from the other side
sure had them puzzled.
Heh.
-It sure has.
They've been back-trailing
us now for two months,
and they always get
stuck at Windy Flats.
They think this mine's out
in the middle of the desert.
-Why don't we take
a little rest, son.
Just a few more days,
and Betty will be coming.
-Well, don't you think we better
be getting back and getting
some of this dirt
out of our hide?
-Yeah, I reckon you're right.
You know, you want to sure
look your best. [CHUCKLES]
-Hiya, Pete.
Well, well.
-Hello, Hank.
How's your old woman?
[CROWD CHATTER]
-She's all washed up, boys.
No pay dirt this time.
[DISAPPOINTED CHATTER]
-Hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
I tell you, we didn't
get a bit of color.
-What?
All the way there,
and you're coming
home claiming not
a bit of color?
What, are you crazy?
-Hold on now.
Wait a minute.
Tell you what I'll do.
I give you every nugget
you find in the pack.
[EXCITED CHATTER]
Yeah, go on ahead and search it.
-Here comes old Benson now,
and Mason isn't with him.
-Good.
Are the papers all ready?
-Everything.
-Hello, Jake.
-Hi.
-Afternoon.
-Well, what luck this time?
Not too bad.
Heh, not so bad.
[CROWD CHATTER]
-Let's see, at $16 an
ounce, that's $2,335.
How you having it?
In coin or bills?
-Well, bills is
easiest to carry.
-All right, Joe.
Sit down, Jake.
I've got to have your
signature this time, Jake.
The government demands
that I get a receipt
for all monies paid
out for all gold.
-Sure.
-Uh, Joe, stamp the
date on that, will you?
-There you are.
-And here's your money.
-Thanks.
Give me my canteen, will you?
I'll be seeing you
fellows again mighty soon.
-Goodbye.
Well, we got the
deed to the ranch,
and when he
eventually disappears,
we'll have this recorded.
Let's see what we
made on the nuggets.
-Well, how did we get this time?
-$2,335.
-Woo.
-I'm g hold our $500 of that,
pay on this blacksmith shop
tomorrow.
You know, Jerry,
I got an idea this
is going to be a
valuable corner someday.
And we ain't gonna let go of it.
-I think it's a good
investment, Jake.
-Hello, dad.
Say, you got a couple
of bucks you can spare?
-Gambling again, eh?
-Well, that's about all there
is to do around this town.
Gee, I wish I had a job.
-So do I. And remember, you
can't keep this up forever.
There's an end to everything.
-Hey, Al.
Come here a minute.
If you don't kick through
that dough you owe me,
I'm telling the town everything.
That'll just about throw
your old man out of office.
-Where am I going to get it?
-That's not up to me.
I don't care where you get it
or how you get it, but get it.
-Mr. Williams in?
-Yes, Jake.
You'll find him in his office.
-Come in.
-Hi, Mr. Williams.
-Hi, Jake.
I'm glad to see you.
-I want to pay off my debt
on the blacksmith shop.
-Well, that's fine.
Sit down.
I'll give you a
receipt for your money.
We'll put it into escrow.
You'll get your
deed in a few days.
-All right, Mr. Williams.
-How's the claim coming?
-Oh, still coughing
up a few color.
We won't be working it again
'till next spring, though.
-Howdy, sir.
-Hello, Higgins.
[CRASH]
-You better send for
the doctor, sheriff.
It's too late.
You've killed him, Jake.
-I killed him?
-You're not trying
to deny it, are you?
Didn't I hear you fighting?
BANK CLERK: You were the
only one in here, Mr. Benson.
-Somebody must have come
in through the back door.
That's the only way it
could have happened.
-Well, don't worry, old timer.
I'll have you out
of here in no time.
-This is Mr. Benson's
ranch, isn't it?
-Why, yes.
Are you Betty?
-And you're Jerry Mason.
-Well, why didn't you let us
know you were coming today?
-Well, I wanted to
surprise Grandy.
Why, where is he?
-Oh, uh-- well, uh-- you see,
when he gets out in the hills
prospecting, why, uh,
well it's pretty hard
to tell when he is coming back.
Won't you come in?
-Oh, gee, you don't know
how glad I am to be here.
[GIGGLE] But I just
can't wait to see Grandy.
-Well, I'm gonna ride out and
see if I can't locate him.
-Oh, I hope you find him.
-Now, just make yourself
comfortable, Miss Betty.
-Well, thank you.
And-- and I'll have dinner ready
for you when you come back.
-Well, that'll be great.
-Goodbye.
-Well, got any news, Jerry?
-Nope.
I'm just going to give
this bank a once over.
-Well, uh, this may
not mean anything,
but, uh, Al, the
Sheriff's son has
been flashing a roll of bills.
Now, I know he hasn't
done anything to earn it.
He just paid me for
a horse I sold him.
Hmph.
-Did Al Miller give
you this money?
-He sure did.
-Where'd you get
that money, Miller?
-Well, I don't think that's
any of your business.
-Well, I'm making it my
business because that's
part of the money Jake
Benson paid the banker.
Now just where did you get it?
-As I told you before,
it's none of your business.
-Oof.
[AGITATED CROWD CHATTER]
[CROWD SHOUTS AND JEERS]
-Miller, tell these boys
where you got that money.
-None of your business.
-Oh, no?
-(STRAINED) I did it.
Ah, I did it.
Let me go.
-You hear that, boys?
-Yeah.
[SHOUTS OF APPROVAL]
-Stand up.
What do [INAUDIBLE], boy?
-[INAUDIBLE].
TOWNSPERSON:
[INAUDIBLE] get away!
-There he goes!
Hey!
[SHOUTS]
[SHOUTS OF CONCERN]
[CONCERNED CHATTER]
-Jerry'll get him.
He's [INAUDIBLE].
-He's got the best
horse of the two.
-I tell you, Sheriff,
Jake is innocent.
[CHEERS OF SUPPORT]
-Wait a minute then.
If what you say is true and my
boy is guilty of this crime,
I'll see that he gets the
full penalty of the law.
-Say, here comes Mason now.
-Yeah, there he comes.
-Halton Miller, I arrest you for
attempted murder and robbery.
And I'm going to do
my duty in helping
to exact the full
penalty for your crimes.
-I'm sorry, sheriff, that
it had to be your son.
[CROWD CHATTER]
-I'm sorry, Benson.
-That's all right.
I know just how you feel.
-Here's the rest of the
bank's money, Sheriff.
[CHEERS]
-[INAUDIBLE].
Glad I'm out.
Heh.
Never keep me caged up
in one of them things.
[CHEERS]
TOWNSPERSON: We knew
you wasn't guilty, Jake.
-It's a mighty good
thing you're out,
because guess who's
home waiting for you.
-Betty?
Well jumping Jehoshaphat.
-And maybe you think
I wasn't worried.
BETTY: Grandy.
-Betty.
Well, well, well, well.
Heh heh heh.
-Never going to see you.
-Thought so myself for a while,
but thanks to Jerry, here I am.
-I have dinner
all ready for you.
-Yeah, and I'm sure ready
for dinner. [CHUCKLES]
Crikey, that's the best
dinner I've had in years.
-And that goes for me, too.
-Well, I can see it
isn't going to be
very hard to please you two.
-Well, son, we won't
be working the mine
again 'till next spring.
You know we can't afford
to miss meals like this.
I think I'll go out tomorrow
and hide the sluice box.
In fact, I'll stake out
three claims along the crick,
and you can file on them.
After all, you know,
better be on the safe side.
-And while you're gone, I'll
take Betty around the ranch
and who her the town
and our blacksmith shop.
-Yeah.
And you can figure on me
being here for dinner.
BETTY: All right, Grandy.
[CHUCKLES]
-This town is located
about 6 miles up--
JAKE BENSON: --a few minutes?
-Pardon me a moment, Betty.
-[INAUDIBLE].
-You know they're taking young
Miller over to Cedar City?
-Is that so?
-Yeah, and I thought you
might like to know that Banker
William is going
to pull through OK.
-Well, that is good news.
-Is Jake Benson around?
-Why, no.
He went to his
claim this morning.
But he'll be back
this afternoon.
-Oh, thanks.
Benson's out at
his claim, and he
won't be back 'till
late this afternoon.
This is just what
we've been waiting for.
-Friday, there's some
nuggets that Jerry
don't know nothing about.
Ha.
Won't he and Betty be
surprised when they hear that.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on, Friday.
-Guess we got here just in time.
[DOG BARKS]
-Drop your hands, Benson.
We've decided it's about
time you were tipping us
off to this gold field of yours.
-Oh, so that's your game, eh?
Well, Jerry and me
found that gold for you,
and we ain't tipping
it off to nobody.
[DOG BARKS]
[GUNSHOTS]
-He's done for.
-Yeah.
There's a canteen on that pouch.
Come on.
We've got to catch that mule.
-Here's the canteen,
sure enough.
[SNORTS AND GUFFAWS]
[DOG BARKS]
-Get him, boss.
No use, Harris.
I can't get it.
-Well, come on.
We've got to get out of
here and get back to town.
We can't afford to be seen here.
Get your horse.
-Now listen, Friday, I
want you to go get Jerry.
You understand?
Go-- go get Jerry.
Go get him.
[CROWD CHATTER]
-I think he's hurt.
-Why, that's Grandy's
horse, isn't it?
-It sure is.
-Say, here comes his pack.
-Yeah?
TOWNSPERSON: Here it comes.
BETTY: [INAUDIBLE].
[CONCERNED CHATTER]
-What do you suppose
has happened?
-I don't know, but
I'm going to find out.
[CONCERNED MURMURING]
-What's all the
excitement about?
-Why, o Jake's horse
and his pack came in.
-Is that so?
-[INAUDIBLE].
-[INAUDIBLE]?
-Yeah. [INAUDIBLE].
He never did this before.
-Friday.
Friday, where's Jake?
[DOG BARKS]
-You better go
back home and wait
'till you hear from me, Betty.
-All right, Jerry.
-What's the matter, old timer?
Are you all right?
-Oh, I'm only a
little bit dizzy.
I'm getting better every minute.
They only nicked me.
-What are you talking about?
Who nicked you?
-I'll tell you all about
it on the way home.
Come on.
Remember now, son,
not a word to Betty.
-What happened, Grandy?
Oh, you're hurt.
-Oh, it ain't nothing at all.
Horse throwed me, and I
lit square on my head.
What I need's a good feed.
-Oh, well I'll run
right uptown and get
you something nice then.
-Well, don't tell anyone
that your granddad is here.
-All right.
-Hey, son.
Open up that trunk and get
out my makeup case, will ya?
-Makeup case?
-Yeah.
-This it?
-That's right.
This here will stop it bleeding.
-Well, what in the world's this?
-Oh, heh.
That's just a souvenir of
my old theatrical days.
-I didn't know you
were an actor, Jake.
-Yep.
I wore that when I played in a
show called "Charlie's Aunt."
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-Well, what the heck is this?
-Son, that's the
thing that helped
make Anna Held and
Lillian Russell famous.
-Oh, I see-- up
here like this, eh?
-No.
[LAUGHS] You durn yearling.
You got it in the
wrong spot. [LAUGHS]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Hello, Mason.
Has Benson come in yet?
-Not yet.
If he doesn't get in by night,
I'm going looking for him.
I reckon his horse threw him.
-We just called to
find out when we
could take possession
of this ranch.
-Take possession?
I don't understand.
-Well, maybe Benson
didn't tell you,
but we bought this
ranch a few days ago.
-Well, that's strange.
Funny, he didn't tell me.
You got a bill of sale?
-Why, certainly.
It's at the office.
Well then I'll have
Jake drop in tomorrow,
and he can advise you
when he's getting out.
-Well, that'll be fine.
We're anxious to get started on
the improvements on the place.
-Hey, what are
they talking about?
I ain't sold no ranch.
-Have you signed any
papers lately, Jake?
-No, I don't think so.
Wait a minute.
Yes, I did.
I signed a receipt for the money
we got from them last nuggets.
-Well, did you
look at it closely?
-No.
-Well, that's it then.
You probably signed a bill
of sale for the ranch.
That's why they were
trying to get rid of you.
They figured they could
claim the ranch then,
and nobody could deny it.
-Well, that dirty,
low down pole cat.
But we'll get 'em.
You wait 'till my
headache's better tomorrow.
We'll give 'em the
surprise of their life.
Hey, but you gotta go
file on them claims.
Take that canteen of nuggets,
and leave it at the bank
this time.
Here's the location
of them three claims.
Now, there's one for
Betty, you, and one for me.
-All right.
You better lie down and
get some sleep, Jake.
-Don't you forget yourself.
Remember, I'm
supposed to be dead.
-Aw, I ain't forgetting.
-There's Mason.
-It's that old Jake's
canteen on the saddle?
-Let's go see.
-He must have taken it off
the burro before we got there.
-[INAUDIBLE] there, boys?
-Oh, hello.
Hello.
I--
-Uh, you see, Sheriff.
We recognize this canteen It
belongs to old Jake Benson.
Whenever Jake brought
in his nuggets
to us, unknown to
anyone else, he
brought them in this canteen.
And we thought it
was kind of funny
that old Jake's disappeared
and Mason should have this.
-Well, where is Mason?
-He went in the courthouse.
-Pete, go in there and
see what Mason's doing.
I reckon he can explain this.
-He'd better be able to.
[HUMMING]
-He filing on a
mining claim, Sheriff.
-Huh.
Probably old Jake's claim.
-Well, we'll just wait
'till he gets here.
-Howdy, boys.
What's all the pow-wow about?
-Just how did you come to
have this canteen of nuggets.
-I don't care to answer
that question, Harris.
-Who's claim were you
just filing on, Mason?
-My own claim.
-Do you know anything about
Jake Benson's disappearance?
-Yes, I know he
hasn't come back.
-I'm sorry, Mason,
but I'll have to hold
you until we can locate Jake.
-That's fair enough.
When do I get my
preliminary hearing?
-First thing tomorrow morning.
-You better take charge
of those nuggets, Sheriff.
[CROWD MUTTERS]
-What are they going
to do to Mason?
-They think he killed old Jake.
-They do?
-What's happened?
What's wrong?
-Mason's up for murder.
-Murder?
-Yes.
-Sheriff, may I please have
a moment with Mr. Mason?
-Well, yes.
I guess so.
Go ahead.
-Thank you.
Oh, Jerry.
-Now listen, Betty.
They think I've
murdered your granddad.
Now don't say
anything to anyone,
but hurry home and
tell Jake that I have
a preliminary hearing
in the morning,
and for him to get there
without being seen by anyone.
-All right, Jerry.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
-[GIGGLES] So long.
-Grandy, they've got
Jerry locked up in jail.
-What's that?
-They think he murdered you.
Now, Jerry says he's due
in court in the morning
and for you to be sure and
get there without being seen.
-I understand.
Heh.
Will I be there-- and how.
[CHUCKLES]
-So we're in the loop.
-A couple of weeks
ago, [INAUDIBLE].
-Yeah.
-Pardon me, gentlemen, but I'm
looking for the courthouse.
-You're standing
right in it, madame.
-Oh, for goodness sake.
I do love murder
trials, don't you?
But if I were a murderer, I'd
much prefer the electric chair
than to have a rope around neck.
Wouldn't you?
-Listen lady, we're
not interested.
-Hmm.
But you're going to be.
[CROWD CHATTER]
-Well, here comes the
sheriff and Mason now.
-There he is.
-Yeah.
-My goodness, what big feet.
[LAUGHTER]
[CROWD CHATTER]
-Just a minute, boys.
Check your hardware.
-Come on.
Let's get in here.
This thing is just
about to start.
Come on.
Get in here.
The show's about to start.
[BANG OF GAVEL]
BALIFF: Hear ye, hear ye, hear
ye, The court of Sonoma County
is now open, Judge
McGill presiding.
Everybody be seated and
come to immediate order.
-Your honor, before you
proceed further with this case,
there's a few words
I'd like to say.
-And what is your name, madame?
-Veronica Mehitabel Benson.
-Any relation to Jake Benson?
-Oh, yes.
I'm his dearest relative.
-What do you want
to say, madame?
I wanted to say that
I've known the accused
since he was a babe in arms.
[LAUGHTER]
[BANGING OF GAVEL]
-Quiet, please.
-As I was about to say,
I knew him years ago,
and he was the sweetest thing.
[LAUGHTER]
[BANGING OF GAVEL]
-Come to the point, madame.
Well, I know who
shot Jake Benson.
[MURMURING OF CROWD]
The men are In this
court, your honor,
and I advise the sheriff not
to let anyone leave this room.
They tried to steal his mine.
They tried to steal his ranch.
And they shot him
down in cold blood.
[SHOCKED MURMURING]
-How do you know this, madame?
-Because I was there when
it happened, your honor.
[SHOCKED MURMURING]
-Sheriff, swear Miss Benson in.
[LAUGHTER]
-Order in court.
[BANGING OF GAVEL]
-Please, put down your dress.
-I ain't no lady.
I'm Jake Benson.
And there's the two
coyotes that shot me.
[SCREAMS]
-Come on, Benson.
There he goes!
-Try not to [INAUDIBLE].
-How do you run this durn thing?
-I'll do the driving.
[CROWD CHATTER]
[CRASH]
[COUGHS AND SPUTTERS]
-All right now, folks.
That'll look fine.
Now, just a minute.
Relax for a minute.
Now, here we g You must remember
that I've spent most all
of the afternoon trying
to get you in position.
Now hold it, just like that.
Still-- hold it.
Hold-- hold it.
Ready now?
[THEME MUSIC]