- That's fine. Here you are.
- Thank you.
Gee... that's swelll photography.
Well, we better get back to the hotel
and get our things packed...
because the boat sails
at 12 o'clock tonight.
Not for me, it doesn't.
What do you mean?
I've decided to stay a while.
In fact, if my plans work out right...
I may never go back!
Oh, we have to go back or we'll lose
our job at the fish market in Des Moines.
So what?
There're plenty of fish markets
here in Paris.
- Garçon!
- Oui, Monsieur?
Another glass of milk
and two fresh straws.
You know what? I think you're hiding
something from me.
Oh... Roses are red, candy is sweet...
This is something I sent you to eat.
Ollie.
That's so funny!
But the flowers are beautiful.
Candy!
Who is he?
He's the American guest in number 4.
We must not ridiciule his generosity.
Really he's been very kind.
Mr. Hardy!
Yes, Ma'am?
- I want to thank you for your photograph.
- You're welcome!
And for beautiful flowers...
Oh, shucks. It was just a thought...
...and the delicious chocolate!
Well, I thought you might want
sometning to nibble on...
...while you were smelling the flowers.
What are you so happy about?
Stanley, can you keep a secret?
Sure!
I'm in love!
You don't tell me! Who is it?
The most gorgeus
creature in the world.
Georgette, the innkeeper's daughter.
Well, I don't blame you.
She sure is a swell dish.
- She certainly...
- Yes, sir!
Don't call her a dish.
She's the girl that I'm going to marry!
Get a load of this diamond ring.
Boy, it sure is a load.
Yes, sir!
Say, when are you going to get married?
Just as soon as I ask her.
Why don't you ask her now.
Then, we can all go out and celebrate.
That's just what I intended to do.
We'll get cleaned up
and I'll go down and pop the question!
That's a good idea!
I'm sure we'll have
a lot of fun now!
You sure can pick 'em!
I never saw anything like you get...
What are you doing with that cushion?
Well, I keep on bumping "me" head.
See?!
Move it in front of the the window
were you can stand up.
How anyone can be so stupid to stand there...
and continually bump their head
is beyond me!
Why you didn't stand by the window?
Why don't you mind your own business?!
What is all this?
Holler... Yes I'm sorry.
Papa... it's this.
The girls think he's funny.
Yes, it is funny yes...
But remember Georgette,
you are a married woman...
and François's little bit jealous.
Oh... papa.
He's not serious.
It's just the American way of having fun.
Oh, yes., yes. Might be.
Well... run along... girls...
Come, come, come...
François!
François.
- It is so good to see you.
- After such a long time!
Why didn't you let us know you were coming?
I wanted to surprise Georgette.
Where is she?
George... Georgette!
Yes, papa.
François!
My darling Georgette! I've waited every day...
every hour... every minute.
My poor François!
I was worried about you,
way out in that lonely post in Morocco!
It was lonely, terribly lonely.
But that's all over now.
I've got great news for you.
I made arrangements for you to join me
when I go back.
Oh, darling. I am so happy!
You must be hungry.
I'll get you something to eat.
Well, how about a nice cold drink?
That's great.
It'll just put me in the mood.
Yes, sir.
Throw it over your shoulder.
What can I do for you?
My friend and I would like a bottle of wine.
And bring three glasses.
Three glasses?
We thought maybe you'd like to join us.
You know I feel as fidgety as a jitterbug.
You do? What's the matter?
Well I'm nervous!
You know, Stanley, this will be the first time
I've ever been married.
- Say... now is a good time.
- Shhhhh!
Go on now. Why, don't you?
Go on, tell her.
What's the matter, you scared?
I'll tell her for you.
I know just how you feel.
- Let me fix it for you.
- I can fix it. Just leave it...
Say... He got something to tell you.
- Something to tell me?
- Yes, he is "nuts" about you.
- "Nuts"?
- Just plain nuts!
Oh, oui!
No, I don't mean that...
I mean he's crazy about you!
He's going to marry you!
Aren't you, Ollie?
Go on, start talking.
You want to marry me?
That is, if you don't mind.
Monsieur, youn make fun of me.
No, he's not kidding.
He's on the level.
Aren't you, Ollie?
Why... certainly.
I was never more sincere in my life.
That's very nice of you, I'm sure.
But that can never be...
Won't you give me one chance,
Georgette?
Go on... why don't you?!
Is there someone else?
Yes, very much so.
I'm so sorry.
Well, that's that!
No use crying over split milk.
Well, I guess we better be going, eh?
Come on...
You, go ahead.
What's the matter?
Aren't you going out with me?
I want to be... alone.
Don't be long, darling.
No, darling but it's absolutely necessary
that I report to Headquarters.
- You'll be back right away?
- Just as soon as I can.
Don't worry about it,
you'll get over it all right.
To think...
that this would happen to me.
Just at the time in my life...
when I needed something real.
Something wholesome...
something tender...
Why don't you try a nice fat, juicy steak?
That would make you feel better,
if you have something to eat.
You don't understand.
Get me some smelling salts.
That better now?
Get... get...
...won't come out!
Get... get this off!
Put some water on my head.
Get a towel!
That. Now, is that better?
Make it wet.
Is  there anything else I can do for you?
Yes! Leave me alone!
Don't talk to me like that
after all the hospital I've given you.
I tried to give you a candy...
A nice fat, juicy steak.
I've waited on you with your hands and feet.
Tried to tell you that there's plenty more girls...
You don't have to worry about that...
If I felt as bad as you,
I'd go and drown myself.
- Stanley, you've given me an idea.
- What?
- I'm going to follow your advice...
- Good.
...and drown myself.
Oh, wait a minute now. Listen...
I was only kidding.
This is no time for kidding.
I know, but don't you think you ought
to think it over?
Have you ever been drowned before?
I have thought it over... and since Georgette
has given me the air...
I have nothing left to live for?
Oh, don't be silly.
What do you mean, "Don't be silly"?
This is a far, far better thing I do now...
than I have ever done before.
Stand up.
- Well... Goodbye, Ollie.
- Goodbye, Stanley.
Good luck.
Where are you going?
Well, I don't want to get my name
dragged into this.
What...?
- What's this for?
- Now, when I count three, we'll both jump in.
What have I got to jump in there for?
I'm not in love!
So that's the kind of guy you are...
After all I've done for you...
let me jump in there alone.
Do you realize that after I'm gone...
that you will just go on living by yourself?
People would stare at you
and wonder what you are?
And I wouldn't be here to tell them.
There'd be no one to protect you.
Do you want that to happen to you?
I never thought of that.
I'm sorry if I hurt your feelings, Ollie.
I didn't mean to be so dispolite.
That's all right, Stanley.
Let bygones be bygones.
This is going to be easier than you think.
Now, move this over here for me.
Don't do that.
Are you ready?
- Goodbye, Ollie.
- Goodbye, Stanley.
One... two...
- Ollie.
- What?
I just thought of something.
Listen, you remember once
you were telling me that...
when we passed away we'd come back
on this earth in some other form?
Like a bird or dog or a horse or something?
- Oh, you mean reincarnation.
- Yeah, yeah, that's it.
Well, now that we are going to go,
what would you like to be
when you come back?
Well, I don't know.
I've never given it much thought.
I like horses.
- I guess I'd like to come back as a horse.
- Huh!
What would you like to be
when you come back?
I would like to come back as myself.
I always get along swell with me.
You can't come back as yourself!
Now come on and stop wasting my time!
Are you ready?
- Goodbye, Ollie.
- Goodbye!
One... two...
Ollie?
Just thought of something.
Do you think the water is deep enough?
Maybe you might bump your head, if...
Well, I never thought of that.
Termites.
Hey...
We can't jump in there.
There's a fellow watching us.
What are you trying to do?
Talk me out of this?
I came here to jump in this river
and that's what we're going to do!
Now you quit this horsing around,
or I'll jump in without you!
Don't leave me, Ollie!
Well... are you ready?
All right.
- Goodbye, Ollie.
- Shut up!
One... two...
Pardon me, gentlemen.
What seems to be the trouble?
Well, if you don't mind,
we're going to jump in the river.
But why to commit such a foolish action?
Surely your troubles can't be
as bad as all that.
Well, that's what I have been
trying to tell him.
All because he fell in love with a dame.
Now, isn't that silly?
- No woman is worth that.
- I should say not.
You haven't seen her!
If you knew her as I know her.
I understand. But don't forget.
There are plenty more fish in the sea.
He is not in love with a fish...
It's a girl.
- That's just an expression, my friend.
- Oh.
I realize perfectly how you feel,
but you've too much to live for.
Sure, you got your dog and there's me...
Life is too precious to throw away on account of...
of some woman who probably
isn't worthy of you.
He is right, Ollie.
She is worthy, all right.
But there was another man...
and if I could meet him face to face,
what I'd to him would be nobody's business.
Yes, sir!
Well, advice is cheap.
Maybe if you'd listen to my
suggestion your problem would be solved.
What is your suggestion?
Join the Foreign Legion.
- What for?!
- To forget.
Say, that's not a bad idea, Ollie.
Better than jumping in here...
We could forget all our troubles...
You're right, Stanley.
- Thank you, mister for telling us.
- It was a pleasure.
- Goodbye and good luck.
- Goodbye.
Gee... that's great, isn't it?
- No we don't have...
- Say, we can't join the Foreign Legion.
We gotta to be back in Des Moines
on the 17th.
Well, you ready?
- One...
- Just a minute, Ollie.
Hey, mister!
If we join the Foreign Legion,
how long will it take him to forget?
No time at all.
Just a matter of a few days.
- Well, that's swell.
We'll have plenty of time. - Great.
Now we don't have to worry about it.
- Say, we won't need this, will we?
- No.
Right shoulder... arms!
Present... arms!
Order... arms!
Take command, Captain.
Lieutenant, close order drill.
Prepare the platoon.
Positive.
These clothes sure don't fit you
very well, do they?
Oh, they'll be all right for now.
We only use them for a few days...
until I forget.
That's right too.
Left time.
Left!
Right shoulder... fire.
Walk left... march!
Left flank... march!
Turn around!
Right flank... turn around!
Column... turn around!
Pardon us.
Well, look who's here!
Hey, Ollie. Look.
Well, blow me down.
Ha, ha, ha...
What a small worldl!
Well, we followed your advice.
Yeah, but nothing has happened yet,
has it, Ollie?
- Show this men to the Commandant.
- Yes, sir!
- Well, we'll be seeing you. Goodbye.
- Yeah, take good care of yourself.
- Don't he look good?
- Sure he does.
Hey, hey...
When're you gonna have dinner?
- Attention!
- Goodbye.
Good morning.
I will now assign you to your duties.
Revelie at 5, you dress quickly...
make up your bunks
and get ready for inspection.
Inspection until 7.
10 minutes till breakfast.
You drill until until 1
and march until 4.
What about lunch?
You'll have that while marching.
You'll have inspection until 6.
15 minutes for mess,
kitchen duties until 10...
inspection at 11, then taps.
That is all.
If we have to do all that,
you won't have time to forget.
Why don't you tell him?
Uuuh, how much do we get
for all this work?
100 centimes a day.
Well, that's not bad.
Uh, how much is that
in American money?
Oh, American money?
It's equivalent to about 3 cents a day.
Of course it varies
with the rate of exchange.
Well, how much do we get
for overtime?
There ain't gonna be any overtime.
If you think you're going to get
that much work out of me
for 3 cents a day, brother...
you are crazy.
- Is that so?
- Absolutely!
Yeah, and that goes for me too.
Cause we don't work for less
than 25 cents a day.
Do we, Ollie?
Uh-uh, uh-uh-uh...
Come on, get to work!
What do you think this is?
Get back to work!
Haven't I got enough trouble
without you making it tougher?
Well, it's your own fault.
If you hadn't fallen in love with
Georgette, we wouldn't be here.
- Wouldn't that...
- Will you stop reminding me of that?!
Here I am trying to forget and you
keep talking about it all the time!
Now here's another day wasted!
Well, maybe you don't try hard enough.
If you can't forget,
why don't you try to pretend to forget?
How can anybody pretend to forget?
Well, I know if it was me,
I'd sit down and relax.
I would close my eyes and concentrate
and I'd think of nothing.
Wouldn't be long then.
That's what I'd do.
Say, I think you've got something there.
I know I've got something.
Why don't you take a whirl at it?
Now don't think of anything.
I won't.
I know it's tough to forget
a swell girl like that.
Gorgeous hair and lovely eyes...
beautiful teeth...
Ruby lips...
Gorgeous!
I can see her now.
So can I.
Will you shut up?
How can I concentrate when you
keep talking about her all the time?
Now keep quiet.
Let me alone!
Now sit down!
- Hey, Ollie...
- If you don't stop bothering me,
I'm going to punch you in the nose.
Didn't I tell you... to quit that?
You'll hear about this later!
Hey lads.
When you get through with that washing...
the cook wants you to manicure
them vegetables...
for tomorrow's stew.
I beg your pardon?
You heard.
Well, can you beat that?
How does he think that we're gonna...
- Stanley, I feel something coming over me.
- You do?
A miracle has happened.
- What?
- I've completely forgotten.
- You mean you've forgotten Georgette?
- Who is Georgette?
Gee, that's swell!
Now we can finish the washing
and we can go home.
Finish nothing!
We are going now.
Now you're talking!
Absolutely.
And I found them asleep.
When I told them to go back to work...
they threw wet laundry in my face!
Oh... they did, eh?
I'll show them what it means
to disobey my orders!
- Goodbye... goodbye.
- Bye, bye.
- Gee, I'm sure glad to get out of this joint.
- Me too.
- Have you got everything?
- Uh-huh.
Now we'll go to that commandant guy
and tell him we're through...
and at the same time,
I'll give him a piece of my mind.
I don't blame you.
3 cents a day, ha!
Left time!
Left!
- Turn out the guard
and place them both under arrest!
- Yes, sir!
Say, what's a big idea
of keeping us waiting?
- You know what? - What?
- He's not here.
Well, of course he's not here!
- Well, let's go look for him.
- Look nothing. I'll leave him a note.
Oh, I wouldn't bother to leave him a note.
Just leave him a P.S.
Good enough for him.
Now he can put that in his pipe
and smoke it.
Maybe he doesn't smoke a pipe?
Well, whatever he smokes.
Well, you've gotta to be careful
about those things.
What did you say in the note, Ollie?
I said plenty and if I could've spelled raspberry
I would have told him a lot more.
- That will learn him.
3 cents a day. - Right!
Never during my army career have
I been so grossly insulted!
Just wait until I get my hands on them.
Attention!
Shine on, shine on
harvest moon...
up in the sky...
I ain't have no loving
since January April...
June or July...
Snow time...
t'ain't no time to stay
outdoors and spoon...
Shine on, shine on
harvest moon for me and my girl.
- I wonder what time the train
leaves for Paris?
- The sooner the better for me.
Say, which way to the depot?
- Just around the corner.
- Thank you. - Godbye.
- Let no one pass through the gate
no matter what happens. - Yes, sir!
Come on.
Say, we're not going to take a plane,
are we?
Ha! I should say not.
I wonder what keeps them up?
I don't know but I know
what keeps me down.
Me too.
Good old terracotta for me anytime.
"Tomesceously".
Georgette, darling.
Now I'm so happy.
At last I'm here with you.
- Have you missed you?
- Every day has been a year, darling.
I'll bring the car for you.
You wait here just a moment.
Could you tell us
the way to railroad depot?
- Mr. Hardy!
- Georgette!
So, you've changed your mind?
Darling, I forgive you everything!
Say, I though you said
you'd forgotten her.
Don't be silly! How could I forget
my little Georgette?
Oh, Monsieur, I...
I understand.
- Stanley... We wish to be alone.
- Come on.
Come on, go on...
Please, please.
Mr. Hardy!
What's the big idea?
The idea is that this lady
happens to be my wife.
Oh, is that so?
Your wife?
Yes, you would be home wrecker!
François, please don't hit him.
He wouldn't understand.
Honey, step into the car.
I want to speak to this gentleman alone.
Now once more I'm going to give you
a piece of advice.
Keep away from my wife.
If I ever see or hear of you
being in her presence again...
I'll see to it that your worthless carcass
lies sizzling in the desert sun...
at the mercy of the vultures.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
Hey, mister, you don't have to worry
about us. We are leaving right now.
- Aren't we Ollie?
- We certainly are! - Yes, sir.
Fall in!
Who's he talking to?
What do you mean "Fall in"?
We're through. Didn't you get our note?
Yes, I got your note and when you signed it,
you signed your own death warrant.
You're under arrest for desertion.
Now fall in!
- Call them at the jail and have the guard
to keep a close watch on them. - Yes, sir!
Fall in, march!
Halt!
Two deserters.
Deserters, eh?
Come on, I'll show you to your suite.
Get in.
Hey, come on...
Don't push me.
Revolution, eh?
I'll see you at sunrise.
I'll learn them. I'll show them
where they get off at.
- But what did we do?
- What did you do?
Why you...
Get in there!
- Hey, mister?
- What?
You forgot your key. Look.
Why don't you keep your mouth shut?
The prisoners have been found guilty...
and will be shot at sunrise.
Here's a nice pickle we're in.
Shot at sunrise.
I hope it's cloudy tomorrow.
- Say, Ollie.
- What?
Do you still want to come back
as a horse?
I don't care if I never come back.
I'll play you another one now.
Shut up!
Go to sleep!
Put that thing down!
Well, I guess we better get some sleep.
- What?
- Get in there.
- What for?
- Shh... never mind what for. Hurry up.
Come on, get in.
You could let the fellow know...
Here, take this candle.
Say, where are we going?
This tunnel leads to the outside wall.
We're making our escape.
Are we allowed to do that?
Go ahead!
"Are we allowed to do that?"
In this fog...
I just don't know where we are.
It sure is, I'm dying with laugher.
- Go ahead!
- Don't you hit me!
See what you've done?
Now we've got to dig our way out.
Go back to the cell
and get those tin plates.
I don't want to go back to the cell.
Will you hurry?
This is our last chance.
Why do I always have to do everything?
Always me, me, me...
Put your head down.
Never you, you...
- Bring the prisoners!
- Yes, sir!
All right, come on you. The sun's up.
Come on.
- They're gone! Escaped!
- What?
Give me the Commandant!
Sir! The prisoners have escaped.
What? The prisoners have escaped?
Than find them!
Yes, sir!
I want both of those prisoners
brought back, dead or alive.
Call out the entire post, if necessary.
I wonder what time it is?
Now how do I know?
We should be beyond the wall by now.
- Seems like we've been working...
- I guess you're right.
- We better start digging up.
- That's a good idea.
Oh, stop all this nonsense now.
- Don't you dare go back to Paris again
and leave me alone. - Darling.
- Oh, uh, bring up a bottle of that special
vintage wine from the cellar, will you?
- Yes, sir.
Will you get out of here!
I'm trying to get dressed.
You're starting to annoy me. Now go!
I wonder where we are.
Maybe some saloon outside the fort.
See if the coast is clear.
I don't want to see
if the coast is clear.
Go ahead.
Maybe someone is...
Troops, pay attention!
Make a search straight for the barracks!
Georgette, may I come in?
- Georgette.
- Yes, dear!
Are you all right?
Yes, fine.
At a time like this,
you had to do that.
Quick. Help me get her on the bed!
Get her feet.
Quick, get me a glass of water!
Look out.
Don't do that!
What is the meaning of this?
What will we say?
You think up your story.
I've got mine.
Now pay strict attention all of you!
The men who were to be shot
this morning have escaped.
Make sure all gates are closed
and make a thorough search
of the entire barracks.
Whoever brings them back...
will be given a reward
of six weeks furlough.
That's all.
Let's cover up the hole.
- Hey. - What?
- See if they've gone?
Yeah, we've given them the slip.
Good. Now let's get out of here.
Hey, Stan. Look!
I'm over here!
Well, here's another nice mess
you've gotten me into.
Ollie, is that really you?
Of course, it's me.
Gee, I'm glad to see you.