[MUSIC PLAYING]
-You made good time, Yak.
-How long you wait?
-Oh, I got here last night.
What'd you find out?
-Two man gonna hold up
stage, Coyote Canyon.
Much money on stage.
-Well, it looks like we're
gonna have our hands full.
-More trouble, more fun.
--[LAUGHS] Well, that's
one way to look at it,
but there's been two sheriffs
killed at Little Rock.
And it's our job to
find out who did it.
-We [INAUDIBLE].
-Well, I reckon we
better get started.
Beat them [INAUDIBLE].
-Gentlemen, I've
called this meeting
that you may all know Al David.
He's to be sworn
in this afternoon
as sheriff of this country.
[APPLAUSE]
Mr. Davis, I feel that we should
acquaint you with the face
that this vicinity is being
terrorized by a band of outlaws
ruled by a man whom
they call The Shadow.
He's a very clever man.
Many traps have
been set for him.
And he always evaded them.
Our cattle are stolen
night after night.
He has absolutely no
regard for human life.
Stage coaches are
held up and robbed.
And the drivers shot.
-Well, it looks
like we won't get
through this time, [INAUDIBLE].
-You stay out of
sight and follow me.
-[INAUDIBLE].
-Don't look back.
Drop that gun and keep driving.
-[INAUDIBLE].
-You meet me in town.
MAN: Throw down that bag.
DRIVER: You're too late.
A lone rider beat you to it.
MAN: Yeah?
[GUN FIRES]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
-Hey, look boys.
Something's wrong.
[INAUDIBLE CHATTER]
-Better get him
to a doctor, boys.
Quick.
-Where can I find Mr. Matlock?
He's my uncle.
-I'll get him for you, Miss.
-Thank you.
-Well Miss, you had
quite an exciting ride.
-I certainly did.
-And gentlemen--
-Matlock!
Matlock!
Stage was held up.
Joe's dead and Dave was wounded.
There's a girl on the stage
claims to be your niece.
She's asking for you.
-So you are?
-I'm Anita, Uncle Matt.
-My dear, this is certainly
a pleasant surprise.
Tell us.
What has happened?
-Well, I don't know exactly.
I was heading for town
when I saw the run away.
And I happened to be
close so I caught it.
This young lady can probably
tell you more than I can.
-Well, first we were
held up by a lone rider
and then shortly after
two men held us up again.
And they shot the
guard and the driver,
and then the horses ran away.
And this gentleman caught them.
And I'm mighty grateful, too.
-And so am I. You
see, Davis, it's
things like this that
happen every day.
[GUN FIRES]
-Look.
See that smoke.
-The bullet came straight
on, but from where?
That's just the way the
other man was killed.
-I reckon this is
end of law and order.
Won't nobody run
for sheriff now.
-If it's just the
same with you folks,
I'll take this job as sheriff.
You say you can see
the whole street?
-Hmm, me hear shot.
Look quick.
See no one.
Only smoke.
-[INAUDIBLE].
-I'm sure those are the
hombres that held up the stage.
Wait here.
[MACHINE SPINS]
VOICE ON OTHER SIDE OF WALL:
You needn't explain, boys.
I know everything
that has happened.
Keep your eyes on
this new sheriff.
Watch every move and report
to me in the morning.
-Cover my trail, Yak.
I'm going back to
the money bags.
-[INAUDIBLE].
-It's the stage bag.
Do you suppose he just found it?
-I don't know.
But here's we get it.
And him, too.
-[INAUDIBLE].
Two men follow.
Look through glass.
-Ah, well I figured as much.
Here, take my horse and meet
me at the express office.
Keep this money.
[GUN FIRES]
-It's empty.
-Where did he go?
-I don't know.
-Look!
-I know we got him.
He can't get far.
Come on, let's find him.
-Oh, you stay here and watch.
Reckon the express company will
be glad to get this money back.
-[INAUDIBLE].
-We trailed him and saw
him pick up the money bags.
Park here shot
him off his horse,
but we couldn't find him.
VOICE ON OTHER SIDE OF
WALL: He just rode in town
and went into the
express office, probably
with the dough.
This is twice you've
gummed things up.
Another fluke like this and
you two guys keep riding.
It's 10-1 he knows
who followed him.
So you'd better get
back to the hide out
and stay there till
I send for you.
-All right, Yak.
Let's find out where
they'll lead us.
-The loco Frank.
He'd cut a man's
throat for $1.00.
And [INAUDIBLE].
A lifer from Walla Walla.
And there's [INAUDIBLE].
He's wanted in every
state on the border.
And Slippery Williams
and Spike Morgan.
[WHISTLES] What a
nest of hornets.
And Matlock's ranch
only two miles away.
Wonder if he knows
what's near him.
-Maybe we tell him.
-No, it might spoil our
chances of getting them.
-Well my dear, what do
you think of the ranch?
-Oh, fine.
But I haven't seen any cattle.
-There are no cattle.
They were all stolen
several weeks ago.
That's why I've tried to bring
law and order to this valley.
Seems useless.
Three men have been
mysteriously shot down.
And the outlaw
activity continues.
-Well, can't you appeal
to the government?
-The ranch men have
written repeatedly,
but nothing has happened.
-Oh, where is the
foreman and your boys?
-They were in with the rustlers
and left with the cattle.
-And you live here alone.
-Yes, except for
old Jake the cook.
-I'm going over to Matlock's.
Now you stay here and keep
an eye on whoever passes.
-Under the circumstances, I
think we should try and dispose
of this ranch, or at least
let me buy your half.
This is certainly no
place for a woman.
-Oh, I quite agree with
you there, Uncle Matt.
I didn't expect to
find it like this.
-How many for
supper, Mr. Matlock?
-Just the three of us, Jake.
-Thank you, sir.
-Oh, here comes
someone, Uncle Matt.
-Well, it's our new sheriff.
Come right in, Mr. Travers.
-How do you do?
Miss Matlock.
-Just wanted to tell
you about my good luck.
I found the express money
near the scene of the hold up.
-Well, that is good luck.
Did you see any
sign of the robbers?
-Well, uh, I can't
make any promises
right now, Mr. Matlock.
But I hope to have the Shadow
and his gang behind the bars,
in a very few days.
-Well my boy, I
certainly wish you luck.
But I'm afraid that
never can happen.
The Shadow is clever.
His men are the most desperate
criminals ever banded together.
-How do you know?
-Why, uh, the cold-blooded
manner in which they operate.
-Oh, I see.
But I still think I can do it.
-Well, I certainly hope you do.
Will you excuse me a moment?
-I suppose you're glad to
be home again, Miss Matlock.
-Well, this isn't
exactly my home.
In fact, it's the first
time I've seen the place.
You see my father and
Uncle Matt own this ranch.
And two years ago
dad was killed.
I inherited his half.
Uncle Matt has
offered to buy me out.
He says this is no
place for a woman.
-Oh.
-He says strange things
happen here at night.
And there are only
the three of us,
old Jake, Uncle
Matt, and myself.
I'm almost afraid.
-Hello?
VOICE: Sheriff will soon
be leaving Matlock's ranch.
Wait for him at the crossroads.
There's a girl at the ranch.
No harm must come to her,
but scare her away tonight.
-[INAUDIBLE].
I'll have the boys attend to it.
-And don't be afraid to use it.
-I won't be.
-Won't you stay for
dinner, Mr. Travers?
-No thanks, I have to be going.
I'll see you in the morning.
Good day, Miss Matlock.
-Good bye.
A fine fellow, isn't he?
-Yes.
It's too bad that he's Sheriff.
-[INAUDIBLE].
Big fun.
-You boys been a
little too careless
with your shooting irons.
So we'll just send you
up for attempted murder.
-We'll be outta here
by noon tomorrow.
-Yeah?
Well, thanks for
the information.
There must be a secret entrance.
I distinctly heard
a third voice.
That's a funny place for a safe.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[KNOCKING ON WALL]
Here it is.
It's a fake safe.
This must be where The
Shadow gives his orders from.
[BANGING SOUNDS]
YAK: [INAUDIBLE].
TRAVERS: Well, this
is interesting.
It's a tunnel.
Come on.
Let's see where it leads.
Well, what do you think?
They've hollowed
out this old stump.
This is where those
mysterious shots came from.
Through this hole
a man could cover
the entire northern
part of the street.
We've got work to
do tonight, Yak.
The first thing is to
find cross-cut saw.
[ANIMAL SOUNDS]
[SCREAMS]
[GUN FIRES]
[MAN SCREAMS]
-Good morning, Anita.
-Good morning, Uncle Matt.
-Did the disturbance
bother you last night?
-Oh, not a bit.
In fact, I rather enjoyed it.
You should've seen
these so-called ghosts
run when I opened fire on them.
-Did you do that shooting?
-I certainly did.
And I intend to
keep on shooting.
You know Uncle Matt,
I've decided not to sell.
I think I'll stay right
here and fight it out.
-Well, I, I admire your spirit
and if that's your decision,
I'm with you.
But you breakfast is ready.
I must hurry to town.
-Good bye.
MATLOCK: Good bye.
-Morning, Sheriff.
-Morning.
-The ranchers are all
here as you ordered.
-Good.
Ask them to stay of the
main street until I'm ready.
I gotta surprise
in store for them.
-OK, Sheriff.
We'll be waiting.
-Come on, Yak.
Let's go.
Come on out, partner.
Don't worry, it's empty.
Yak, watch the street
like I told you.
Come on, get going.
I'm warning you.
Now do as I say or
take the consequences.
Now listen.
VOICE ON OTHER SIDE
OF WALL: You're late.
What happened last night?
He had men covering his trail.
We couldn't get near him.
VOICE ON OTHER SIDE OF WALL:
Well, he's in his office now.
Get him out in the
middle of the street.
[INAUDIBLE]
At 11:00 this
morning I personally
will head the boys into town.
[INAUDIBLE] will be under the
straw that cover the wagons.
We'll cover one end of the
street and the boys, the other.
We'll take the bank
for a cleaning.
You'll take your
position in the stump.
Get going.
-Take off your hat.
Put this one on.
Take off that scarf.
-You're not gonna send
me out there, are you?
-You guessed it.
But I got the stump covered,
so I guess you'll be all right.
Get moving.
Get the boys.
Come on.
-Come.
Sheriff say keep eye on stump.
-Take it easy, Parker.
Don't move.
[MEN YELL]
-Listen up you, you got
just one chance to live.
Who's The Shadow?
-Oh, don't shoot.
I'll tell.
It's--
[GUN FIRES]
Oh!
-Boys, we just
missed The Shadow,
but he's coming back,
he and his gang.
They have a machine gun and they
intend to wipe out the town.
What's to be done?
[MEN YELL]
-All right.
They must never reach town.
We'll surprise them
and head them off.
Pick up all the men you can
and let every rider wear
a white cloth around
his head so we
can distinguish ourselves
from the outlaws.
Get your guns and we'll
all meet at [INAUDIBLE].
Men, I was sent here
from Washington.
I'm swearing you all
as deputy marshals.
Today [INAUDIBLE] United
States government.
Everyone raise his right hand.
You solemnly swear.
-It just doesn't seem possible.
-But it's true, Miss Anita.
The night your dad brought
your uncle from the east
was the night this man and
his gang raided the ranch.
Both your dad and
uncle were killed.
He took all your uncle's
papers and his clothes,
and passed himself off
in town as Matt Matlock.
The sheriff must know
about this, Jake.
I'm going to tell him right now.
-Yak here will signal
us from that mountain
when they're coming.
We'll let them get by us and
then attack them from the rear.
Now everybody scatter
and stay hidden.
-Are the boys ready?
-Yeah.
-Well, there's no time to lose.
-Who's that coming?
-It's that fool girl.
Stop her.
Take her to the hide out.
Put her in the
wagon, [INAUDIBLE].
I reckon the sheriff
won't do much shooting
with her in there.
Stand ready with
that machine gun.
-Stand ready, men.
They're coming.
[GUNS FIRE]
[MACHINE GUN FIRES]
[ANITA SCREAMS]
-All right, boys.
Let's go.
BOY: Daddy, daddy.
Daddy, [INAUDIBLE].
-Well now, what's happened
to you, young fella?
-[INAUDIBLE].
[YAK SINGING NATIVE AMERICAN
CHANT]
-Yak and papoose
have [INAUDIBLE] fun.
-You'll get a lot more
than [INAUDIBLE] fun
if you don't leave
our child alone.
[MUSIC PLAYING]