Radio Pictures presents
Ann Harding and Leslie Howard in
The Animal Kingdom
Produced by David O. Selznick
Screen Play by...
Horace Jackson
From the Play by...
Philip Barry
Directed by Edward H. Griffith
Hello Tom, hello Harry.
Hello
Hello Jay.
-Hello Dave, how are you?
-Good.
Hello, Meyer.
-Hello, Tom.
-How are things?
-Fine, fine.
-Good.
The book is ready.
- It's not.
-I put it on your desk.
Oh, come on now, let's have a look.
Ah, now that looks all right.
I say.
Well,
lovely.
Congratulations, Meyer.
Glad you
like it, Tom.
And you had
I think this calls for a celebration.
I-I brought some champagne in the car.
I got it for tonight, but if we drink it up, well my guests can drink beer.
Harry, get some glass.
And you take that, Meyer.
Tom's never been on time for an appointment in his life, he has
absolutely no consideration for other people.
You're not awfully fond of your son, are you, Mr. Collier?
Cecelia, if you'd spent the time and money and effort I had,
to make that young man realize who he is and
what he ought to be doing in the world,
you haven't known Tom long.
No.
Owen, perhaps some longer experience might enlighten her.
Well, I presume what Mr. Collier means is that,
in ordinary terms, Tom doesn't seem to have gotten very far.
He's wasted his life in the cradle.
It must have been pathetic to see him wasting in a tree.
I assure you his genius weren't shown even then.
I sent him to Harvard and he last two years there.
I sent him to Oxford and he commutes from Paris.
I put him into the bank and he...tsk
the whole world at the feet of that boy, the whole world
and all he's ever done is to run from it.
Well, you know, Tom has his own ideas of what he wants to do with his life.
Yes, Wiggin?
A radio message came by phone from--
Oh, thanks. You can leave it here. I'll take care of it.
Right.
All right.
Everything satisfactory?
Uh, yes, quite thanks.
-Comfortable, miss?
-Quite, thank you.
Blanketry?
-Anyone?
-No, no, no, we were talking!
-That's all right, go right ahead. Make yourselves at home. I'll be right along.
The butler?
He's charming.
He looks like a prize fighter.
He was.
There, there now. Tom will be here any second now.
Mm, if what I think is true, I hope he never comes along.
What?
Well, I'll tell you what's in my mind.
Heaven knows I don't want it there.
That girl he's been living with for the last three--
Uh, just a minute, Sir.
It's all right.
Good gracious, there's no secret in it.
Who is she anyway? What is she?
She's an extremely nice girl.
Hard working, talented.
She draws for one of the fashion magazines.
Very successful.
She left three months ago for her magazine's Paris office for an indefinite stay.
Oh, maybe she's coming back...
What of it, Mr. Collier?
What of it? Everything of it! He's likely to marry her!
Ha, I'm surprised he's missed it as long as he has!
Well, I've stood for his rowdy
friendships, I've put up for his idleness, his ill-mannered incidents--
-Sorry, Mr. Collier.
I'll have to ask you to let it go at that.
Hmm? Why so?
Because it so happens that
I am fine we're here.
How is that?
It's me Tom's going to marry.
And I've heard enough against him for quite a while.
Ce, what are you talking about?
Marrying.
-I say I thought--
-On June 1st to be exact.
He asked you out here to tell you.
And I imagined to receive your good wishes.
My dear!
My dear, I congratulate Tom, and myself,
and I hope it will work out for you.
I hope he won't be out of the impossible as a husband,
he has been at everything else I wanted him to do.
I don't agree with you.
Tom's the most interesting, most
attractive man I've ever known.
I consider myself shot with luck.
Oh, very loyal.
Not at all.
I simply believe in him.
Now in his so called path, perhaps.
I'm not quite a fool.
But certainly, in what's to be!
Well, faith is a beautiful thing.
I think so.
Well, if you can make a respectable citizen out of Tom Collier at this rate,
you have nothing but praise from me, my dear.
Seems not to occur to you,
when Tom has someone who really understands him,
to work and care for--
-Understands him?
Yes, completely.
Why, he'll make what you call
a respectable citizen of himself.
Oh, you think so?
I know.
And if what you laughingly refer to as my "faith" isn't very used to it...
Mm, love will conquer all.
Oh, yes, yes, of course, but forgive me a few doubts.
Oh, how is that so?
"Darling, I'm coming back.
Arrive on Paris at 8 tonight. Much love, Daisy."
Well,
I know all about her.
Did you know she was returning tonight?
No, not at all.
Owen, I'd like a few words with you, if Cecelia will pardon us.
Certainly.
Owen!
I meant to tell you on the over,
then I couldn't.
Ce, how did it happen?
Very suddenly. Very sweetly. Yesterday.
I am sorry. You asked.
If you'll excuse me, I--I think I'll see what Mr. Collier wants.
-Hello, Harry!
-Hiya, Tom.
Oh, uh, are they here yet?
-They are.
-Good.
Darling.
Tom!
Take my hat, will you?
Thanks. Now get out.
Uh, I just wanted to tell you that...
later...
but there's a--
-guest!
-a radio message come for you!
Oh, get out.
Hello, darling.
No, you're late! I'm furious with you!
Late?
Yes, is that all right?
It's terrible. I've taken off with a thrifty spinster.
That's all you deserve.
Well, where are they? Father and Owen?
In the other room.
Tell me darling, did you really say you'd marry me?
I'm afraid I did.
Oh, heaven help us both.
Just this one marriage, please.
You know, I haven't been very good about marriage.
I was exposed to a very bad case of it as a baby.
We must make a grand go of it.
Oh, we shall. Never you fear.
Well you just do everything I say, and it'll be all right.
With pleasure, Sir.
Ce, darling, what a marveling object you are.
Oh, I feel good.
-So do I!
-Do you?
My lovely Ce!
Oh, stop it Tom, you're embarrassing me!
Why?
I feel quite naked.
You look marvelous.
-You look--
-We'll have dinner in a couple of minutes, Tom.
Get glasses with ice, and run all the way!
Right. Did you get your radio message?
What message?
Goodbye.
Don't tell me if you don't want to.
But I do.
I'd always intended to at the first opportunity, anyway.
And suddenly it seems, here it is.
Well, Ce,
for a long time, I've known...
known intimately...
a girl who's been very important to me...
Yes?
Daisy's done more for me than anyone in this world.
She's the best friend I've got, and I believe she always will be.
I'd hate terribly to lose her.
It's been a queer sort of arrangement.
Well no arrangement at all, really. There's never been any idea of marriage between us.
Well,
-Is she attractive, Tom?
To me, she is.
I don't believe you'd like me half so well if
Daisy hadn't knocked some good sense into me.
Someone's done a good job of it.
I'll tell her that.
I sent her a long cable this morning, all about us.
Of course, she never got it, because this,
this came from the boat.
She lands tonight.
I see.
Ce, we've--well, we've been everything possible to each other, of course, but...
-Yes, Tom.
-At the time, as free as air. I mean, there's never been any feeling of...
conventional responsibility towards each other's involvement.
I can understand that.
Can you see?
'Cause I never could.
Anyhow, that's how it's been.
We haven't been, what you call... in love
for a long time now.
Does she know that?
She knew it first.
Well, I don't know what else there is to be said about it, except that
-that there's no need for you to be worried.
You won't, will you?
Not if you tell me I needn't.
Well I do.
And finally,
I think she ought to know the news about us pretty promptly.
Yes, probably.
Well, is anything I do about that all right with you?
Of course.
Thank you, Ce.
Oh, hello father. How are you?
-Good evening, Tom.
-Good evening.
You said five o'clock, and it's seven. I think--
-Oh did I? Is it?
Listen you and Owen, I want to tell you what this is all about.
We know. We've heard.
He was abusing you, so I had to tell him.
It didn't discourage you?
On the contrary...
Aww, sit down Tom.
Why, thanks very much Sir, but I think I am the one to be congratulated.
Yes, indeed we are.
I'm sure we shall be.
Hello, Red, there you are. That's my boy.
Uh, that's my father over there.
Oh, glad to meet you, Sir.
-And my fiancée, Miss Henry.
Your...
Good boy!
Okay, thanks very much.
Well, here's how and why and wherefor.
And you know where marriages are made.
Is-is it all right?
Swell.
Well, splendid, then. We're all satisfied, aren't we?
Uh, yeah, just a moment Red,
did you put the car away?
Say, how many hands have I got?
Well don't. I shall need it.
Father,
I fear I'll have to ask you to do the honours at dinner.
But, why?
I found I have to go straight back to town.
-Now you listen to me!
Seems to be extremely important that I should do it at once. In fact, I can't do otherwise.
You have the upfrontery, the colossal bad taste
on the night of celebrating your engagement to a fine, trusting, loyal girl,
to go from her, your fiancé, to your--your--
same old difficulty about words, ay father?
Never mind, none of them apply to Daisy.
Well, I suppose you know better.
-You leave here tonight…
-Yes, much!
Much better!
Until tomorrow.
My poor child.
I'm sorry, Cecelia.
Oh, I think it is exactly right.
Beautiful thing, faith.
A beautiful, beautiful thing.
-Tommy!
-Daisy.
I was looking for you at the dock.
I am so sorry. I didn't get your message in time.
Well, come in.
Oh, hello you dear Tom.
Hello Daisy.
Now it seems as though I hadn't been away at all.
Mmhmm.
Oh, come sit down. I have so much to tell you. It'll take hours.
Tom,
two of the most exciting things have happened to me! Not one, two!
Really? What, really?
Oh I'm bursting with them!
-Darling...
-Daisy, I--
No, no. You tell me. Come on.
Well, my heavy sledding ought to be over in a few weeks.
The first of June, anyway.
What have you got on the fire, much?
Yes, a good year.
-It is I--I--I…
-We'll work day and night until the first of June, and then,
come to Mexico for a month with Daisy.
Oh, I'm dying to go because,
first of all,
-What?
-I feel like such a fool.
Promise you won't speak word of it to anybody?
Tom, I think I can paint.
Haha, well that's no surprise. I've always thought you could paint...
Well then, you've always been wrong because it's just been within the past two months.
I believe that if I work my eyes out and my fingers to the bone,
one day I may really paint.
But don't be hard on me now. No parties, no playing around; just work.
You mustn't let me show until you know I'm ready to, is that agreed?
All right.
You got a funny instinct about those things, and I'm counting on you.
That's the first thing.
So, the second thing
-What?
You know what? Suddenly, I feel shy with you.
Oh I don't like it.
I don't like it a bit.
It's been a long time, Daisy.
Too long.
Gosh, I better wait to tell you the second thing.
No.
Tell me now.
Oh my dear, what's wrong with us?
Come here to me.
That's better; I don't feel it as much now.
You're a free man, you know, Tommy. With me, no questions asked.
So please, Mexico in June together, because listen!
No, don't look at me. Look the other way.
On the boat coming over,
the sweetest small boy, about two,
and I got crazy about him, and I want one.
I want one badly.
So will you please be good enough to marry me?
Or you've always said you've wanted to, but I wouldn't let you,
but you can be terribly serious.
Not a life sentence you know. Just a little while if you like.
Would be such a dirty trick on him if you didn't.
Then after I get my stuff through for the July issue.
Mexico for a month together.
Oh I love you so much! I was a fool to ever think I didn't.
Now, come on, Tommy, be a good sport
and give me a cigarette.
Alright, never mind. Let's forget all about it.
That is a foul necktie you've got on--
What is it? Oh, you're going to tell me something terrible.
What is it?
I-I'm going to be marrying Daisy.
To be...
Listen, listen, my darling!
It happened very quickly--
Yes it did. A month ago we hadn't even met.
-It was if...
-You can spare me the details. Please.
I don't even want to know who she is.
Who is she?
Cecilia Henry her name is.
Behold the bridegroom comer,
and no oil for my lamp as usual.
A foolish virgin me.
Foolish anyway.
When is it to be? Soon?
About the first of June, we planned.
June? Oh well...
If well in that case, then Mexico would be out.
But I never dreamed...
Ugh, I feel so awful.
Remember me, Tom.
Daisy, there is to be no nonsense about not seeing each other again
as friends, or any of that, you know?
Oh, but there will be that nonsense.
Oh yes, it will be that all right.
I-I don't understand. I don't see why we shouldn't.
I thought for a long time, we'd been out of danger, so far as...
well so far as...
Why didn't you let it go
Well have we?
See for yourself, Tom.
You too dazy, you
Well it's true. That side of it was never so much to as to not in comparison not,
well, not after those first crazy months.
But, I-I thought that was natural.
I was even glad.
Glad that it was all the needs that held us together.
So closely.
Not a claim. Never a claim, but so closely.
Tom? Tom, do you have to marry her?
I want to marry her.
I thought that maybe you just wanted it--wanted it most awfully...
No, no, no. It's more than that. Much more than that.
W-well, I don't see how you can quite
tell that. For all that big talk, you know, we do still belong to the Animal Kingdom.
-If you knew her, Daisy--
-Yes, well I don't.
Listen Daisy,
there's no one like you. There never will be. I know that.
But this, it-it
I don't know. I can't tell you.
Don't try. Don't try. Don't try.
Goodbye, you Tom Collier.
Goodbye?
Until when?
Doomsday, my darling.
What are you talking about?
-Just that.
-Now, you listen to me.
If you think I'm going to allow two people that mean as much to each other as you and I do,
To be separated by this forced ridiculous
notion, that's your mistake, and just you try it.
Tell me goodbye.
I'll do nothing of the kind.
Oh yes you will. You must.
You have to!
Sharp, decent, and clean. No loose ends between us two.
But it's not decent! It's soft, it's sentimental, it's the kind
of thing you'd never have any use for--it taught me never to!
-Goodbye.
-I will not say it!
-Goodbye!
-Goodbye
-No!
-You must!
Listen to me, Daisy, please!--
I have some things of yours that are here. I want you to take them along with you, please?
I got me a new maid just before I landed. I let Harriet go when I left.
Well, the new maid had a swell hunch about us, she did.
Some shirts and things of yours that were here,
she wrapped up in a nice little bundle.
Well, she gets the gate for it--the big suite.
I don't believe in this! I don't believe in any of it!
Come on, get them, will you?
Fetch, Thomas!
It's quite a neat, tidy little bundle.
If it stays around here, well...
I don't quite see myself crying into an old shirt, do you?
I work to do my son a great deal of it.
No? Come on, fetch!
Then, kindly permit me to.
And you will say "goodbye" to me.
You've said it so many times, so brightly.
Say it this time, sadly.
You will, won't you?
We'll make it an unmarried ceremony.
Keep everything quite regular.
You must take my hand in yours, one splendid gesture.
Murmur, "Goodbye, my Daisy".
Thanks very much
for charming association
and may we never, never meet again
so long as we two shall live!
Here's the wash bag.
Now do as Daisy says, and
There you are.
Thank you.
My dear, I congealed.
I can't say I envy you and your husband the trip into town.
It is not my idea
Well, why do you do it, Cee? It's so grim...
Tom wants to.
Such loyalty.
It's her first showing,
and he thinks for some reason that we should be there.
Who is she anyway?
An artist. Sage her name is.
Tom says she's good.
Oh well. I suppose puppies just have to hobnob
with all sorts of queer people.
We see few people of any description anymore.
Yes.
Don't tell me about the hermit life you live.
I think the least you could do would be to come to my Sunday breakfast every now and then.
Tomorrow's will be such fun! Do see!
-Perhaps we shall.
-Well, not if you're going tonight.
Perhaps, we shan't go in tonight.
Oh ho, so that's the way it is.
Well, well, well,
Ahh, with us again!
With you again, yes.
Cee, don't you think we'd better be getting on the way, dear?
Oh, we've got hours.
I read the new book you published last week, Tom.
Oh yes? What do you think about it?
Superblative, my dear i was simply ravished.
Well, that's something, isn't it?
Isn't he beyond words?
You're the world's funniest man.
You couldn't possibly be funnier.
Ahh, you don't know me.
Oh, yes I do.
Don't you adore it, Cee?
The book, I mean?
I like it very much.
In fact, I'm afraid it was I who made Tom take it.
And I'm afraid that I still think it the worst
Try to banned the prohibition.
But my dear!
Everyone's simply devouring it!
Well, there will be lot of sickness this winter.
You're so foolish about it Tom.
You'll make enough on that one book to bring out ten he really cares for.
Yes, I suppose that's the way it works.
Oh, well, Father called today.
What'd he want?
He wants us to dine with him on Wednesday and spend the night.
Oh, come on darling. Get us out of it, won't you?
-Again?
-Mmm.
-How can I?
I don't know. Tell him I'm up to eyes in work or anything
else he won't believe.
Tell him the old car is frozen stiff.
Well I could easily send you in a closed car.
Gabby and I might even join you.
Oh, thank you. We-we cannot accept your sacrifice.
Really, he's extraordinary. He defeats me.
Well, I guess I'll be barging along as they say.
I, uh, I'm sure it's getting colder by the minute.
Yeah, it's almost cold enough to--
You know, I-I think we best bring the brass monkeys in tonight, don't you?
The, uh, he he...
Goodnight, Cee.
Goodnight, Grace.
Must you really?
Well, uh, yes. I'm afraid I must.
Oh, now don't forget. You're coming to my Sunday breakfast tomorrow.
We're having the most amusing people.
Of course that's just what Sunday breakfast needs, isn't it Cee?
I knew that the coffee must be very hot as well.
Goodnight.
I think that--
Good evening.
I think that desperate butler must embarrass you to death!
Not much longer.
Tom's promised to fire him tonight if he isn't completely insensible.
Good evening, Red.
G'evening
Hey, yeah. You'd better get to bed, haven't you?
That's where I'm headed.
Okay, just a moment, Red.
Now,
Alright, bring a couple bottles of beer, will you?A
Aye.
What did you say to Regan?
Regan?
He never drinks on duty.
Why shouldn't he have the right to get slightly "mellow" on his one day out?
Slightly mellow?
He can hardly stand!
When I said "good evening" to him, he didn't even answer!
Well, maybe he couldn't speak.
All he did was to bow, like
this, with a foolish grim. So
low, he nearly fell over.
Well, you know, it's--it's pretty hard to gage a bow under those conditions.
Tom!
I think it's selfish of us to keep him.
Selfish?
Well, we're certainly depriving him of any chance he ever had
to make anything of himself.
Hang on, Cee. He broke his hand, so he'll never fight again.
I don't mean fighting.
Well, these are hard times. I don't know what else there is for him.
I'll leave it to you. Do as you like about him.
And, you know, I feel somehow--
I feel somehow that Red's good luck for me.
I don't know. We understand each other. I'm awfully fond of him.
You must be.
To ruin what other chance he might have in life.
I wouldn't do that to Red. You know I wouldn't.
You're doing it, though.
What possibly could be more degrading to a man than housework?
Well, I don't know. I wouldn't like to tell you, darling.
Of course, you know you're making a regular Simon degree out of me.
Cee, where's my whip?
No.
It's just that in your delightful, casual way,
you've never thought of his side of it.
I wouldn't do that to Red. I really wouldn't.
Ring for him, Cee.
Me? I've nothing to do with it.
Do you have to change? Or are you ready?
Seems to me that you were unnecessarily rude to Grace.
I have to change.
Now we've got to go to her breakfast in the morning!
Honestly, Cee. All my life, I've been trying to get away from her kind of people.
Takes all kinds to make a world.
Yeah, then what have we got?
Come on, darling. You go get dressed.
I suppose you feel that we must go into town tonight.
Of course. Why?
An exhibit lasts several days, doesn't it?
Yes, but I want to be there tonight. Tonight's the opening.
Besides, they'll all be there tonight.
Have you, uh, seen any of your old friends lately?
No.
Why not, dear?
Oh and the girl?
Daisy, the one who's exhibiting tonight!
Have you seen her?
No.
Why not?
I thought you felt her friendship was important to you?
She won't see me.
-Won't see you?
-No.
Come on, Cee. Be a good girl. You go on up and get dressed.
Oh dear.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Dear, what is it?
It's just this blasted headache.
I had it all day.
Oh, it's a shame. The cold air will fix that up.
It was that that gave it to me.
Honestly Tom, I don't think I can face it.
Why not send her a wire?
"Best wishes"? That's enough, isn't it?
-Isn't it?
-No, no, no. That wouldn't do.
I'm sure she'd be every bit as glad to have a telegraph.
Cee, darling, listen, Daisy's been working for years for this.
A telegram wouldn't do at all. I've simply got to be there.
There's no particular reason why you should go. I could go alone
I'll come-hmm
Uhhh. Put them done there will you?
Right.
Tell him now.
Alright.
And wait a minute. What's the rush?
Stick around.
Certainly.
Listen Cee, if you feel tired, you go to bed.
No, I'll come.
Well, drag a chair, Red.
One more's about all I need.
Y'know the smaller of all the bedheads in the world
were put together in a row
my head would'a got up and sneered at the rest of em'
Well, here's how
How!
Ah that's the stuff. Haha that fills you up eh?
Yo!
-Ah
Hey.
Have you seen this one?
I don't think so no.
Tell me where to stop and remember the card.
Right, got it?
I got it.
Where is it?
Gone alright
Feel in your pocket
Not this time
No?
No.
Is that it?
Marvellous!
I paid 5 dolla's for that trick
I'll let it go for $2.98
Sorry, not interested
Red!
Was it cold in town today?
I don't envy those guys sellin' apples on the corners.
Oh, not much of a job then, eh?
Womens work!
Pretty tough times, alright, eh?
Say, look here Tom.
- What?
If I...nothin'.
If you're ever hard up, though, you know where to come
It goes both ways
Red, I might just as well tell you right off.
What?
Nothing.
Say, how's your father these days?
Never better, thank you.
Red. Do you ever think about your future?
I guess where I'm going will be plenty hot.
I mean...
- Oh you mean here?
Now that's a funny thing, because, listen Tom...
I...I'll let it go.
No, but what?
Fill er' up, will ya?
Not much of a future in Buttling, eh Red?
Oh, well...
No, I...I'm certainly grateful for all you've done
Ah, be still will ya?
I am.
That's fine, from you
I'll never forget when I was
and you...well...I'll never forget it.
Put it there, old boy.
You're the top, boy.
I don't know what you would think of me when I...
When you what?
When I...
Well, well what would you say for instance if I...
Nope, it's no good.
Here, you're not in any trouble there are you?
Trouble? Me? What trouble?
Well then, look here Regan
Well, Chief
Don't call ya for president, the peoples choice!
Now now Listen to me!
- Wait, wait Tom. I just gotta tell ya...
Don't hold it against me, but I'm...I'm quittin ya.
I've took another job.
What?
- Oh I know what you'll say...
Holy Cadsmith...
I couldn't stand it any longer; she don't like my ways
I mean the missus. I get on her nerves.
Last week, Mo Withers told me he wanted to open a country gym.
And would I run it with him
And you would
But with a little bar attached.
Heaven help me, I...I gave him my word.
I see.
Well, what's in it for you, Red?
Aw, Don't put it that way, Tom.
I really want to know
$200 a month and a smell at the gate if anything
Alright, sounds like good deal.
Let it go, I'll phone him
When do you start?
He wanted me last Wednesday.
I've been trying all week to get up the nerve to tell you but
Well, but...
- How long will it take you to pack?
Well there's my hat trunk, and my shoe trunk...
And a trunk for my fancy dress ball clothes...
You leave by noon tomorrow, not a minute later! You understand?
Ok, Chief.
I'm sorry you had to take it that way.
Don't be a fool, I'm overjoyed for you.
Fact?
- Absolutely! Here's to the new job.
Take it from me, boy, you're the goods!
You're the goods.
Well, you've got your points too, you know.
Anyhow,
Anyhow!
Well, you'll explain to the missus?
Yes, of course.
Tell her I'm sorry
hope no inconvenience
I...I'll explain really
So long, Tom.
Goodbye Red.
I'll...I'll give you a ring, how it goes.
Yes, yes you do that.
Keep your bib clean
I will, old boy.
Good luck, Tom.
Tom,
Oh hello
Ready?
Not quite.
Did you tell him?
You know I...I'll miss that guy
I'll miss having him around.
Oh I know, darling.
But it's for the best.
I'm sure of it.
I feel somehow...that my luck's going with him.
I'm your luck, darling.
See if you're good
Do I dear?
You haven't any clothes on.
Go along, now dress. Dress quickly, we've got to run.
Come and help me.
No, you'd best not.
Ce!
Do you remember this nightgown?
I came across it in the bottom drawer.
My spine simply loved it.
Quebec?
Yes.
Come here.
You'll make us late
Well why don't we do that.
We're late already, we'll miss it.
Well,
What if we do?
Oh darling...
You're the limit...
10 minutes ago you said
Tom.
You go in alone.
I decided to stay here
You did what?
Yes, it's too cold.
I will tuck myself in my warm bed and read
Good night
I'll miss you
Look here, I'll stay!
Good night.
You'd better take your heavy coat
Keep warm.
Ah, Hello?
I want to send a telegram.
I would have an exhibition, wouldn't I?
I'm to believe the critics ought to be painting sign boards.
There are no judges of ones work but ones self these days
I wonder who that is?
- I'll answer.
Hello Frank.
Hello Tom
Is Daisy in?
Yes
Hello
I think I'll run along Daisy
No don't go Frank
Yes I must go, goodbye Tom.
Well, uh, speak to me somebody. Am I a leper?
What would you like me to say?
Oh, uh. Take off your coat, Collie, and stay awhile.
Thanks I think I will
Well it is, nice of you to ask me over.
Yes but I didn't, you see.
Well it was nice, anyway.
Whatever made you think I wanted to see you?
Nothing
Except that I wanted to see you
How's eh..how's it coming?
how's what coming?
I mean the job
Job?
Oh, the job. I gave that up last winter.
A trifle, can we say, Quixotic
Shall we?
How's Joe's book doing?
Haven't you seen him?
No.
Joe's book is doing fine, thank you.
Course it can't compare with the magnificent value of
being brought out by your vapid press.
Indian summer
Oh what on earth made you take those things off?
Oh, I don't know...money?
Ah but Daisy, I've reformed!
You wait till you see the Bantom's new lists.
I'm waiting.
Well, I hear Frank's a hit?
She is.
I uh, saw your exhibition today.
Oh did you really? Funny, I missed you.
What'd you think of it?
Well,
Oh tell me.
Daisy, I don't think you're ready to show yet.
How were the notices?
Appauling.
I suppose their reasons were all wrong?
Yes, of course they were. What were yours?
Well, you've been painting less than a year
yet you had about thirty canvasses to show.
Thirty-two!
An awful lot of paintings.
Saying it like it is.
Oh yes. The one I loved,
that one with the milk bottles on the doorstep, you know...
I'd like to buy that one.
That's number 7. Sorry, not for sale.
But your drawings are marvelous.
Only what, Sir?
Well it depends on what you want to be. I
thought it was a painter.
So did I.
Doyer's drawings were always pretty good; he painted all the well too, I always thought.
The first year, I doubt it.
I wasn't aware that it took a death to make the kind.
And living in cities all your life...
Oh I suppose I should
I don't think it would hurt a bit.
Well if you can show me a purer cobalt blue
than of a winter sky over the east river in the afternoon at four o' clock,
Now you're just being bull headed.
Bull headed! Me?
Me? Bullheaded?
Well, what more teacher?
All I've said, and all I'm saying is that you
can't expect the first crack out of the box
you've got to work this.
Work?
Now he's telling me to work!
Great Heavens what have I done else but?
Much differently with such pains
than turning out too much newnote
Maybe.
Maybe anything is too much.
Now, don't soften on Miss daytime.
Well I do believe that's it.
I think I've the old story: still hung over from the old job.
You should have pressure all the time.
Still rushing countless sketches through against a magazine's deadline.
Anyhow, I guess some deadline.
Easy, darling.
Oh, but you Tom.
Oh but you and strangers, honest of me ever.
Daisy,
do you miss me Daisy?
You? Well, I'll tell you about that. See, it's this way...
Much?
Constant.
God...
- Oh, now you...
No, nonsense this is ridiculous.
We need each other, we do.
Terribly, I'm convinced of it.
Never worse such friends, you and me.
You see it's wicked to give that up.
To lose anything so precious for no good reason.
Why you of all people for shabby low down
question of convention?
It'd only be considered by shabby, low down...
Oh well now, wait a minute!
A hundred times, I'd have give my eyes to see
just to talk to you.
Well here i am!
Face it.
May I come and see you just now then?
If you like, just now and then.
- Oh, Sweet dear, thank you.
But no "sweet dear"
That belongs to another life, years and years
and years ago.
I see.
There are to be rules, are there?
One or two.
Some very definite ones.
Never secrets, never hidden.
Why should a friendship be hidden? What's there to hide?
Well, it does get misunderstood.
It can't, it won't or the whole world grumbles.
You did pretty right for a long time Tommy.
Tommy.
Oh darling, how grand it is.
Kiss the boy, Daisy.
No, you've got to go!
I won't really take long
All as before.
Yes, except for one thing.
- What?
We're not in love anymore.
Now run.
Hold it!
How about lunch tomorrow?
Lunch?
- Yes.
The old place.
I'd love it.
- Fine
-- And this guy John Donovan...
Yes, he's opened a new place on 48th street.
Alright.
- Yes, now lets see, Wednesday is the next day...
I said I'd drive out and see Pat Atkins.
Oh poor dear
He's better now, come with me Daisy.
Oh, Wednesday...
- Thursday, and if it's a fine day we'll take a picnic.
Oh, you...
- Thursday, Thursday I'm at the press all day...
but Friday...
- Oh now wait a minute,
You said...
- How about 4 o' clock on Friday?
Will you be here?
Oh, I suppose so.
Haha, good bye then darling.
Till tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
- What about this afternoon?
- What?
Yes.
Yes, what about - how about a cocktail at Gene's place, 5 o' clock?
Oh, the...Alright.
Good bye, then.
Sweet dear.
5 o'clock.
Ten minutes to 5.
Frank!
What is it, you frightened me?
Frank I'm scared.
But Daisy, wait!
Oh Frank, don't ask any questions: I need your help.
I know you've been holding your tongue Frank,
But what is not my business...
- It's Tom.
I'm going away, a long way away.
I love him, Frank.
I love him more than I ever did.
Think Daisy, wait, are you wise?
I'm going alone.
Yes, that is wise.
And nobody is to know where I've gone, either.
No, of course not.
No mess Frank, it's too
avoid why I'm going.
But it's your place to be calm
- Oh I can't!
Does he love you?
I don't know!
I don't think he knows.
Oh Frank, he's so slim and
Now snap out of it Daisy.
He'll always be like that, I know he will, even when he's old.
That funny way he stands, all stiff, with his feet turned out.
What they call "Duck-footed", eh?
No, certainly not.
Perfectly natural way to stand.
It's a fine, strong way to stand!
Yes, but don't forget your water colours.
Huh? oh.
Frank. Maybe if I wait?
Maybe I better see him once more and
explain.
- Daisy, if you want to go at all: you must go tonight.
Yes, I guess you're right.
Come along, come along.
Yes now...
Look.
- Yes?
You know that painting of the doorstep, the one with the milk bottles, number 7?
Well...
Will you wrap it up?
And take it to him for me with my love?
Take it?
Oh yes, yes you're having cocktails with him at Gene's in one hour.
At 5 o' clock.
5 o' clock?
Ten minutes to 5.
And Frank?
- Yes darling?
- When you see him...
kiss him for me!
What?
Kiss him for me.
Kiss him for me...
Daisy...
Hello! How are ya?
Fine, thank you.
Glad to see you.
Grab yourself a chair, I'll tell the missus you're here.
You're too kind.
Ha, ain't seen ya since I've been back.
No.
You're back. Gee it's swell.
I daresay.
Will you have some tea, father.
No, thank you my dear. No thank you.
By the way, his
birthday is on the 23rd.
Think it would go well to have it a surprise party.
Have all his old friends
give him a chance to realise he's outgrown them.
And I hope you may be able to persuade him to move into town this winter.
Must be uncomfortable to you out here?
Father, I'd so love being in town with you. But
you know how Tom feels.
I'm very contented here.
Hmm. There's something besides contentment.
How did that...that desperado Regan get back here?
Oh Tom ran into him somewhere.
Seems a new job didn't pan out. Regan
was ill,
so Tom asked we might bring him back.
I said he might.
Oh, why not just give him something. Anything to get rid of him?
Don't worry, father.
I'll work it out somehow.
I have the greatest confidence in you, my dear.
Thank you.
Well, I, I guess I must be getting back into town.
Good bye.
- Good bye.
Operator? Long Distance.
I want to get the number of Miss Daisy Sage, in New York.
Yeah?
Just a minute.
Connecticut, calling you.
Oh this is miss Sage.
Oh yes, miss Sage.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Mrs. Thomas Colliard.
Mrs. Thomas Colliard?
I am so sorry we haven't met.
Oh, isn't it a shame.
All of Tom's friends here abouts have so regretted not knowing you.
I called to tell you
his father and I are giving a surprise party for him here on the 23rd.
You'll possibly remember it's his birthday?
Why no, I uh...
We'd so love having you and Miss Schmidt
And Mr. Fisk, to the party.
And if possible, spend the night.
The 23rd...
Oh no, now isn't that too bad.
Oh I'm terribly sorry, but
I just couldn't possibly make it on the 23rd.
Oh...I'm frightfully disapointed.
We must try again, sometime,
soon.
Yes.
Good bye.
Now what was that?
What?
Mrs. Thomas, Thomas mind you, Colliard.
Wants to know if I won't surprise her - surprise Tom - on
his birthday and spend the night with him in the country.
Going to ask you and Frank too.
And what did you say?
You heard me didn't you?
Look Daisy,
every since your trip to Nova Scotia, you've made Tom feel as though you don't want to see him.
And so he's cut himself off from
well, from all of us.
He's only trying to do what he thinks you'll wish.
Well I don't propose
Mrs. Thomas Colliard,
invited me down there for some very good reason of her own.
Well don't take it out on Tom.
I think it'll do him a lot of good.
He needs it. He needs us.
Well if he's so weak...
Oh, he isn't. Just bewildered.
If he could get back,
just now and then, with the right people
it might help him get a decent point of view again.
Oh, Joe, I love that boy.
With all my heart.
- Then don't go.
I would like to find out something I think is true, is true.
I certainly would.
May I look up the number for you miss Sage?
Oh thank you so much, Mr. Fisk. I think
by making a tremendous effort, I may be able to recall it.
Long distance please.
Brandy mam?
How about some backgammon?
Oh fine, grand!
Hi Red.
No thank you.
The boss has got you reading his new book?
- Uh huh.
Forget it, join the party.
You might get some laughs.
Oh it's a nice party.
Not like we used to have though
I don't know hardly anybody here.
Don't you Red?
Aw, Red, why don't you get Tom to introduce you?
Of course I know very little about music but uhh...
I know what I like.
That's for the boss.
Oh. Sorry.
We're so anxious to hear you play, Miss Schmidt,
I am sure you're better than the radio.
But I didn't bring my cello.
Oh what a pity.
Perhaps we could get one?
She's used to her own fiddle.
Yes, but is there any difference?
Yes, I suppose there is.
Look what baby brought ya.
Well he is quaint.
Indeed.
He never spanks me.
McFinch!
But it's about fight time
Cheerio.
Listen, you're a pretty good actor.
Try and act like a butler.
Right Sir. I knows me place Sir.
Don't lay it on, Meadows.
Oh No, Sir.
Say,
How's it feel to be 32 baby...uh...
Sir?
I...I'm bearing up.
Brandy Sir?
No thanks.
Try it, I did. The results were very satisfactory.
No thank you.
Get out.
Very good Sir.
Oh Joe.
This is awful tripe.
What?
This uhm, rotten egg about to be laid in the Bantam press.
Yeah I know.
But it'll make money.
Is that all he ever thinks about nowadays?
Apparently so.
I have an idea he thinks he's doing me a favour in publishing my book.
Oh he doesn't, he couldn't.
Well, he kind of gave us a work certificate.
Oh I imagine he rather gathered we didn't approve of it.
We don't.
Gotta do something about it Joe.
Yeah, but...
he kinda hinted that he might hook up with those pirates, Williams and Marne.
Oh no!
Yes!
Why do you suppose she asked us out here anyway?
Just to prove we don't belong?
She isn't a bad sort.
You know I have quite a long talk with her tonight.
And she seems like a very nice attractive woman.
So did Delila.
Ah, Miss Sage,
I wondered where you were.
Joe Anderson Fisk.
I suppose you've made a good plot tonight
I...
Uh, Did I make any plots tonight?
Oh no, not so far as I know.
Well, I, I mean for your new novel?
Oh, oh yes.
Oh, I know you writer men...
I bet you're going to use us all for characters.
Oh, well that's a very good idea.
Come on, everyone's playing games.
Oh I'm still reading this thing.
Isn't it too divine?
I think it's going to be a sensation!
I'm practically a collaborator on it
Yes, Grace is my reaction agent.
She submits to tests.
I love to!
Yes, she's my little guinea pig.
Uhm shall we go play backgammon mr. Fisk?
Oh yes, I-I'd love to.
Well how're you getting on with the book?
Look, is this on the Bantam list you told me to wait for?
Don't you like it?
Well it seems awfully
bright.
Bright things seem to sell.
Yea.
Look at those great publishers Williams and Warren, they sell millions of copies
in drugstores.
What difference does it make
where they sell?
None
except if you want to keep your integrity you.
You-You can't go in for mass production can you?
I-I mean you can't just become a..
a little cog in big machinery.
Can you?
Don-Don't let's argue about that.
Oh why not?
Daisy listen..
Never mind, never mind..
I just shouldn't have said anything at all until I had read it all through.
That book will make money.
Money?
Is that so awfully important?
I haven't got any but you know
I fee-I feel quite alright.
Well..you're not a married man.
No, I..
I suppose that does make a difference.
Daisy..please read the thing through and give me you're opinion.
I-I'm not quite sure about it.
You will won't you?
Oh yes Tom.
And..And just bare in mind that eh
Well you can't please everybody.
Why did she come?
Who?
A woman?
Well, I thought you asked her.
First she said she couldn't and then
she telephoned back she would.
Well...
Well, I'm not the least bit jealous anymore.
In fact I'm inclined to like her.
That's big of you Ce.
I suppose that Joe's one of hers, too.
How do you mean?
Oh, sweet innocent.
How's that?
I should think you'd know by now that she's just a
promiscuous little -
oh, well.
You're a strange girl, Ce.
Pretty cruel one, too.
Not at all.
In fact, I don't see why Tom and she shouldn't be just as good friends as
well, as you and I are.
Their history is a little different.
Why? Don't you like our history?
What there is of it.
A trifle uneventful, don't you think?
Or shall we simply call it
'lacking in excitement'?
You've been so strange, lately.
So remote.
I wasn't aware of it.
Refusing to help us sell Tom's press to Williams and Warren.
But Tom - Tom doesn't want to be helped.
I do.
Good heavens, darling, I've told
you a dozen times I'm counsel for them.
They do exactly as you tell them.
Hang it all, Ce.
Tom doesn't want to sell the Bantam!
Tom doesn't know what he wants.
Just one little word from you.
Well, you know, there's a thing called 'legal ethics'.
There's a thing called 'friendship'.
Oh, and
'lacking in excitement', you said. For you?
For you, I meant.
And I suppose you're the judge of that, too?
Well, I don't know who else.
And of course, you couldn't possibly be wrong.
Could I?
And I'm not a human being at all,
of course.
Ce - Ce!
You will do this one thing for me?
One word to Williams and Warren?
Owen,
Yes.
Darling.
Oh, Miss Sage.
Owen and I have been discussing something that might interest you.
He's promised to use his influence to have
Williams and Warren take over the Bantam press.
Isn't that splendid?
Did Tom -
Is it all settled?
Owen's arranged it.
See, he's their lawyer.
Isn't that nice of him?
Well, if there's any credit due, i"m sure it's Cecilia's.
Oh, yes, I'm sure it is.
Will you excuse me? I was just looking for Miss Schmidt.
Frank, Jo -
Look, do you mind going in tonight?
Buy why?
We were supposed to spend the night!
Yes, I know we were, but
I've just got to get out of this house.
But Dais-
No!
We are going.
Get your things together.
Okay.
Okay gee, when the part's getting good.
I'm sorry, Mrs Collier, it just can't be helped.
Are you ready, Joe?
Yes.
Goodbye - thank you very much.
Goodbye, Tom.
Goodbye.
I must say, your leaving seems very strange.
We so loved having you.
You were very kind to ask us.
Goodbye, Tom.
'bye.
Goodbye, Mrs. Collier.
Goodbye
Come again when you can really stay.
Thank you.
I'll see about the car.
Well, all so solemn.
I know you don't like my friends.
Your-
They are, however.
I know you don't like the book I'm publishing.
Tom, I pity you with all my heart.
Pity me?
What are you talking about?
I came to find out, and I found out.
Now I'm going.
Found out what?
Pity me, why?
Do you mind?
Daisy, I-
Give us a kiss, Daisy.
Hey, Daisy -
Hurry up or we'll miss the train.
C'mon, here's your coat, get in.
You must give us a ring sometime, Tom.
Right.
I'll wait for you outside.
Goodbye, Tom.
Once I wouldn't say it, would I?
Once you wouldn't.
Well, goodbye.
This time you do.
Goodbye.
Well, goodnight my dear.
I had a lovely time.
I'll miss you.
Good night Tom.
Goodnight.
Good night, father!
Well?
Oh, yes.
Why you declined to spend the winter in town with your father is-
Is what?
You must simply wish to be disagreeable.
That isn't true.
Aw, come on, Ce, now, let's forget that.
As if that was so easy.
I suppose you refused to sell the Press.
Even if Williams and Warren are willing to pay twice what it's worth.
I don't know.
Can't we talk about something else tonight?
I'm afraid not.
Oh, hello, Ce.
You're frighteningly late, darling.
I stopped at the bank.
What made you do that, silly?
I don't know. I just went to think.
Try to clear my mind with a vision of...
vision of millions and millions of people.
Williamson's recital of the glories of the machine age.
I stopped with the press.
It went alright, didn't it?
Oh yes perfect.
In fact it's settled.
- Not already?
- Yes...
Yes they've signed.
All I have to do now is dig out a notary in the village...
Write my name under theirs.
- Are you pleased?
Aren't you?
No, I think something's happened to my nervous system.
I feel awfully light.
Of course you're famished.
Come and eat.
You like to eat in my sitting room?
Alright.
I'll call Regan.
- Ce.
- Yes.
Yes.
I think it's time we had a child or two Ce.
We'll talk about that.
We must.
They're all ready Tom.
I thought it would be so cozy us dining here.
What's the matter?
Honey.
You know, the lighting this way, it reminds me of some place
What?
Hmm.
Champagne, is it?
Don't you feel like celebrating?
Very well.
A little wine, won't hurt you?
The little more and how much it is.
Fill 'em Mr. Regan
Infinite riches...
In a little room.
You got the quote badly.
The little lamb who made me.
Regan doust though know who made me.
Easy to remind, you know?
And his little morals.
The discrete withdrawal.
I've seen that before too.
I know the florentine.
A private room at the Florentine.
What's that?
It's a hotel...
run by a woman called Flora Carniver
Sounds wicked.
It used to be the best place in London.
Place, what sort of place?
Twenty guineas.
Twenty guineas?
On the mantelpiece.
What are you talking about?
In advance at that.
Well expensive, isn't it?
Well, I went to Florence to celebrate.
Food was good, waiter discreet, the wine excellent.
Lady...most artful.
I don't care to hear about it, thank you.
See your eyes are so bright.
Ahh... eat you.
Seeing things.
- Ce.
- Yes dear.
You know, little love is no love.
Meaning what, precisely?
Wasn't necessary to lock your door against me last night.
But I didn't.
I mean, not against...
Then why?
Tell me instantly why it was.
That an order?
Tell me.
You mean... Why I didn't near me?
Yes.
You've been constantly disagreable, that's all.
About what, what wanting Regan back?
- That's one thing.
- Well what else then?
Your father chiefly.
What are you going to do about your birthday check Tom?
Well... oh that... well.
Well, I...
I don't know whether to send it back or just not to cash it.
Of course you simply can't allow yourself to show any graciousness towards him.
No.
It's a way of telling you how pleased with you he is.
He gives you a small check and you have the extraordinary bad taste...
What?
Good heavens.
I can't believe it.
There it is.
There isn't that much money in the world.
In father's world there is.
He fells he can afford it to get us to come and live with him.
Of course I can't understand your attitude about that either.
- Don't you Ce?
- No.
He knows how inconvenient it is here in the winter.
And having that great huge lovely house in town is...
perfectly sweet and natural of him to ask us.
Well to us.
Yes you to preside night after night at his deadly dinners.
Me to listen eternally to his advice on what to do and how to live.
To give up what little integrity I have left.
Taught to allow him to own us.
Of course he's willing to pay. He always is.
How can you be so hard about him I don't know.
- Why we are thinking of the perfect... br&gt; - Hold it.
Oh let's stop it Ce.
Very well. We shall.
Now you're gone from me again.
What you care.
Oh Ce, my lovely Ce. Where are you? What's become of you?
The thing you call your integrity...
That's the word.
It is no use talking.
Is this what you call be disagreeable I suppose?
Yes. Very.
How to be other wise then.
Possibly by being the fine, kind, generous man you ought to be.
Accept the cheque with thanks, and go and live with him.
It's only for a few months.
I think to refuse his presence would be extremely bad manners.
Just about in a class with those of your ex-sweetheart.
Why I'm sorry. I didn't mean.
Nevermind.
Ce. Suppose I should do what you say about father.
Oh, Tom.
You'll be the darling, I know you are.
Would you like me better?
Much.
How much?
Oh, very much.
No...Lock doors anymore.
Not one ever.
That was the most inviting.
Darling.
And suddenly I'm beginning to see with awful clearness.
What?
How stupid you've been.
Well, I am too.
Yes.
Well you are going to be nice again.
You'll see.
I want to feel, I don't know. Together again.
As we used to.
You're very pretty, you know?
Oh, thank you sir.
Very exciting too.
I don't know if it's you or the wine speaking.
Oh me... me through the wine.
Shall we have a little more?
I think so.
It's a party then.
It's a party!
We'll have another small bottle.
There's some here.
- Sometimes you're so thrilling Tom.
- You think?
You think?
We shouldn't. You know we shouldn't.
Uh... we seem to be.
All at once.
I feel terribly naughty, somehow.
You know, I suppose you're one of the most
Prettiest girl I have ever seen.
So nice of you to think so, sir.
So very attractive.
I like to be attractive.
So very alluring.
There, that's enough.
A strange woman.
Your lips drop honeycomb.
Your mouth is smoother than oil.
Now why are you pouting?
Ah, the discreet waiter returns.
Come in.
Give the lady some waiter.
You leave the bottle on the table.
That'll be all.
To the...pleasant ways of life.
Such pleasant ways.
It's good, isn't it?
So good.
I'm beginning to feel it a little.
That's what it's for, right?
It must be.
Champagne, the friend of lovers.
No. Not yet.
Artful child.
You think?
Lovely endearing thing.
I like you too.
It's pleasant here, isn't it?
So pleasant.
You're not taking any?
No.
It makes me see most too clearly.
Oh. Take a little more, everything will get so...
So lovely and vague.
The way I feel now.
A good feeling, is it?
Delicious.
Oh, Tom.
One last toast.
Do we dare?
Come on...
But to what?
What to?
You name it.
To love
and darling . . .
Yes?
You are going to be an angel aren't you?
You'll see
I knew you would
I'm so happy
I want you close to me
Don't be long
Come in
- See here Red.
- Never mind.
All I mean is, well I'm out for good this time.
Why?
I just don't like it here, that's all.
When you want to go?
As soon as I can
Tonight then.
That's alright with me.
I'm packed.
Wait downstairs.
Oh Red!
Have you got a fountain-pen?
Thanks.
Don't let me forget to return it.
On the mantlepiece.
Oh here you are Red.
Thank you
Well
Goodbye.
Go get in the car
I can walk to the train alright
Bring my hat and coat.
You bring my hat and coat, please?
What's the idea?
Light please.
Now then
I can walk I tell you.
Not at all, we are driving.
We will?
I'm going back to my wife Fred.
To your?
My wife I say