The Screaming Skull
is a motion picture
that reaches its climax
in shocking horror.
Its impact is so terrifying
that it may have
an unforeseen effect:
it may kill you.
Therefore,
its producers feel
they must assure
free burial services
to anyone
who dies of fright
while seeing
The Screaming Skull.
Welcome, Mrs. Whitlock.
It's lovely, Eric.
You looked disappointed
for a moment.
I did not.
It's really lovely.
Oh, look.
I bet that's the den there.
That's right.
Is that a bedroom?
- Yes, it is.
- It's gonna be ours?
It'll need some fixing first.
It was her room, wasn't it?
Yes.
Come on along. I'll show you
the rest of the house.
It's rather forbidding
now, I suppose,
empty like this.
But it was usually this way.
Shortly after Marion
and I were married,
she removed all of the furniture
her parents had left her.
"This is our home,"
she used to say,
"and we must choose
everything carefully."
Well, we didn't get very far
before she died.
But now that you are here,
it's gonna be lovely again.
I'll get the things
out of storage tomorrow.
They're all in town
at the warehouse.
And I'll take care
of that, too.
You have candles?
Sure.
It'll be twice as romantic.
Speaking of being romantic...
I forgot to carry you
over the threshold.
I love you.
- I love you.
- Oh, Jenni.
I thought life
had died out for me.
What's that up there?
Oh, that's where Mickey
keeps his gardening things.
- Who's Mickey?
- The gardener.
He's kept it up for
two years I've been away.
- By himself?
- That's right.
He must work awfully hard.
Oh, he and Marion
would spend hours on end
working here in the gardens,
and up in the greenhouse
back there.
See, he loved it very much.
Sometimes, I used to wonder
who she was,
my wife or Mickey's
nursemaid.
You know, I don't think
he quite believes she's gone.
I think he expects her
to show up
one of these mornings
and scold her
for neglecting the gardens.
You still love her,
don't you?
No, I'm not jealous.
I'm grateful to her.
I think to have loved once,
really loved,
is to learn
how to love always.
Learning it from her,
you give again to me.
I wish there was some way
to thank her.
- Who's that?
- I don't know.
And they're driving
around the back.
Come on, come on along.
- Eric.
- I see Eric. Hi.
We stopped by
to meet your new wife.
Oh, Eric, this is
a wonderful surprise.
- It's been a long time.
- It has.
- Reverend.
- Good to see you, Eric.
Jenni, this is Mrs. Snow.
I'm very happy to meet you.
Jenni, this is
a lovely surprise.
And the reverend, Mr. Snow.
Hello, my dear.
- Oh, she's sweet, Eric.
- I know.
I happened to be going into town,
I ran into Mr. Mauer.
He told me you were
getting back today.
And we thought
we'd just drop by
and bring you something
for your dinner.
- How nice of you.
- Well, it'll save you
all the bother of shopping while
you're trying to get settled.
Then, why don't you stay
for dinner?
- Oh, no, not tonight.
- Oh, no, no.
We wouldn't think of that.
- Oh, now, please say yes.
- We'd like for you to.
- It would be like old times.
- All right.
On the condition
that I do the cooking.
You don't have to.
You know, I know that,
but I'd love to.
Well, there's Mickey.
Excuse me, honey.
Mickey!
Oh, poor Mickey.
He keeps this place up
like a shrine.
Eric told me
how he loved Marion.
Mickey's father
was a gardener here
when Marion's mother
was alive.
Mickey and Marion
grew up together here.
Jenni, this is Mickey.
How do you do, Mickey?
I hope we'll be good friends.
Well, Mickey?
Thank you, Mickey.
- Well, shall we all go inside?
- It's a good idea.
Mickey, remember,
you promised me
some of those rose cuttings.
Nice seeing you again,
Mickey.
I'm going to have to get you
down to the barbershop
one day very soon.
Excuse us, Mickey.
All right, that's done.
Oh, god. Please, be careful!
Oh, Edward, now,
don't break your neck.
You're doing great,
reverend.
- Don't worry.
- Good heavens.
Honestly, the two of them
are just like children.
That doesn't look
too bad, Eric.
Jenni, I hope you have more luck
in getting your husband to mind
than I've had with mine.
You know,
you've got to admit,
it does make the room
look better.
It went very well, Tarzan.
For penance, you can come
help me with dinner.
Now, come on.
Edward, you keep
Jenni company?
Yes, dear.
No, Marion, no...
Send them away!
No.
Oh, she's so very nice, Eric.
- Jenni?
- Yes.
- Isn't she wonderful?
She's not at all like Marion,
and I think that's for the best.
You know, so many men,
when they lose a wife,
they try so hard
to deny the loss,
they marry someone
exactly like the first wife.
It hardly seems fair
using the living
to bring back the dead,
does it?
No, I suppose, it doesn't.
We make a prison
for ourselves out of the past,
at least, our sentimental
wished-for past.
- Mrs. Snow.
- Yes, dear.
There's something I must
tell you and the reverend.
Well, of course, Eric.
What is it?
You see, Jenni has not had
a very happy past.
- Oh?
- And talking about it,
or about something that might
strongly remind her of it,
she's very impressionable.
Is there something
wrong, Eric?
No, not really.
You see,
she lost her parents
many years ago
in a very tragic way,
and talking about
unhappy past only...
She's very impressionable.
See, I want her
to be happy, Mrs. Snow.
Of course you do,
and so do we all.
Now, how did she lose them?
Well, I'm not prying, dear.
It's just that Mr. Snow
and i can help better
if we know something
about it.
They drowned in an accident.
Jenni saw it all.
Who's Mr. Mauer?
Mr. Mauer? Well,
he's a lawyer in town.
I thought no one knew
we were coming.
You said you heard
from Mr. Mauer?
Well, Eric wrote him.
He takes care of the estate
or what's left of it.
Oh, that's right.
Eric has to see him tomorrow.
Well, Eric's co-executor
of the estate,
along with Mr. Mauer.
You see, Marion's death
was so sudden
that, well, all that
was left to Eric
was the house and these grounds.
Mr. Mauer told me
that Eric had found
someone very sweet
and very kind,
and with whom he is
very much in love.
He didn't say enough.
How did Marion die?
Didn't Eric tell you?
I think the subject's
rather painful to him.
I don't like to make him
talk about it.
Would you mind telling me?
I'd like to know.
It was a rainy day.
She and Mickey had been working
up there in the greenhouse.
She left him to go back
to the house for a few minutes.
The way we pieced it together
after the accident is that...
While she was coming
down this path,
apparently, it began
to rain very hard.
She must have run along here.
We don't know, of course,
what happened then.
Perhaps she slipped
on a leaf.
They said her skull
was smashed.
It was thought
that she hit her head
on the edge of the cement wall
where we're sitting,
and she fell in there.
She died in the water.
That's where Eric found her
10 minutes later.
Marion.
Marion...
You said...
You said, "Mickey, wait here.
"I'm going down to the house
for just a minute.
"Wait here, Mickey,"
you said,
and then you went away
in the rain...
And you didn't
come back to play.
Marion!
Why didn't you?
And don't forget that you
and Eric are coming for lunch
the day after tomorrow.
We'll do better than that.
We'll come to church
on Sunday, as well.
Oh, getting Eric to church
is like moving a mountain.
He'll come.
Come along, my dear,
it's getting late.
Eric, thank you very much
for bringing Jenni
into our lives.
Thank you for the dinner.
It's a pleasure. Thank you.
- Good night.
Edward, did you know
that Jenni's very wealthy?
Well, yes, Mr. Mauer
told me in town today.
But she's not at all
like Marion.
You know, she's so gentle
and timid as if...
As if she were afraid
of something.
I knew you'd like
my friends, dear.
Hey, what's this, huh?
Just happy, that's all.
- Oh, come here.
- I'm so happy.
Come on.
How are the cots?
Fine.
What are you reading?
Something Mrs. Snow
sent over.
Interesting?
It's called
Beast in the Jungle.
It's all about a man
who waited all of his life
for something great,
wonderful to happen to him.
He had only one good friend,
it's a woman
in whom he confided.
And she died.
At her grave,
he suddenly realized
that she was the great
wonderful thing
that he'd waited for
all of his life.
But it's too late then.
And his memory is like...
Beast in the jungle...
Rise up out of the past...
Overwhelming.
Oh...
Poor fellow.
He doesn't know what
he missed.
Eric?
Jenni!
What are you doing here?
The window was blowing.
Where were you?
I thought I heard
someone moving about.
Now, what is it?
What is that?
Is that water?
A lily pad?
I don't think Mickey
looks for her in the pond.
Jenni, now, stop it.
I can't help it, Eric,
that bad feelings come back.
I forbid you
to talk about it.
She looked like that, Eric.
My mother looked like that!
Oh, Jenni, Jenni.
I can't help it, Eric.
Darling, you're just
talking yourself
into those same old fears.
I've got to talk
about it, Eric.
I have to talk about it!
I forbid you
to talk about it now.
What?
Just that with you beside me,
I'm alive again.
I don't wanna be
sick anymore.
Honey, look.
Now, you mustn't go on
thinking like this.
Besides, how could a very
poorly-done self-portrait
upset you so much?
I know it's only
my own fear.
It's my own guilt
that I can't get away from.
Eric, I'm sorry.
I want you to listen to me,
and I want you to believe me.
Now, you were sick once, yes,
but you were cured.
Mickey caused this.
You may as well know.
He does look for Marion
night after night
down by that pond.
And he probably
comes here afterwards.
I'm gonna speak to Mickey
in the morning.
Now, don't you see
how simply it's all
explained away?
But if I also heard
a scream, Eric?
Before I went
to the hospital,
I was hearing things.
I'm hearing them again.
What did you hear?
It was a high,
strange scream.
High, strange scream?
Like a peacock's cry?
What's that sound like?
Come here.
Sound like that?
You see?
It's all very, very real.
I'm such a fool.
You feeling better now?
Yes.
Good night.
Ah, we won't be bothered
with any of Mickey's
nightly visits anymore.
I've forbidden him
to come into the house.
I was just nervous
last night.
I wish you wouldn't
take it out on Mickey.
No, he's a child.
He must be disciplined.
I'd like him to feel
I'm his friend.
Why don't you do
some gardening with him
while I'm in town?
If he sees you're
interested,
you'll win him over
quickly enough.
Wait a minute.
I made a list, staples mostly.
Are you sure you don't
wanna come in with me?
You'll get more done
without me.
I got to see about the lights,
the phone, the bank,
and the warehouse people
about that furniture,
you know, that couch
has just about broken my back.
Don't forget
to see Mr. Mauer.
I have to see him
this evening.
It's a bore, but I'll
have to see him.
Will you be home in time
for dinner? I'll wait for you.
Now, if I'm not,
don't you worry, darling.
Getting out of
Mauer's clutches
sometimes requires
an active guard.
I love you.
Hello, Mickey.
Oh, look out.
You almost cut him.
He's a handsome one,
isn't he?
So cuddly and warm.
When I was a little girl, I used
to wanna be a caterpillar.
So, I was a very
little girl!
There you go.
Marion must've loved
the gardens.
We'll keep them lovely
for her always.
You know what I'd like
to do, Mickey?
I'd like to pick some
of the nicest flowers
and take them to her.
Would you like that?
Yes.
Eric told me
she was near here.
Could you show me where?
Is that all right, Mickey?
I'm sure it was a great loss
to all of you, Mickey.
She cries.
Cries?
- In the night.
- Dead people don't cry, Mickey.
I heard her.
Heard her?
Mickey?
I don't think he quite
expects she's gone.
She cries.
She cries in the night.
I think he expects her
to show up
one of these mornings.
She died in the water.
The base of her skull
was smashed.
She didn't wanna die.
She died in the water.
Eric?
Jenni?
Jenni? Honey?
Honey?
- Eric!
- It's all right, darling.
It's all right,
I'm right here.
Just lie back, that's
right, just lie back.
It's all right.
When you found me,
what else was there?
What do you mean what else?
A skull?
Jenni?
I know there was no skull.
Of course not.
Mickey says
Marion cries at night.
Why, that childish,
stupid...
Don't blame him.
We both heard the peacocks.
He, out of his love
for Marion,
wishes the cry to be
from her.
I, out of my sickness.
Now, darling.
We've been all through that
nonsense last night.
Don't you see?
I've never imagined
seeing these things before.
To just stand there and see it,
if it turned out to be not...
Eric...
I want you to call Dr. Anne
tomorrow in New York.
I want you to take me back.
No, Jenni.
Now, it may sound selfish,
but don't you see,
having you to love,
I'm happy, too.
I don't wanna lose that.
Now, in the morning,
Mr. Snow will be here,
and we'll tell him...
He's very comforting.
And I think
he'll agree with me.
About what?
I think it's Mickey.
You see, he hated me
from the first.
Marion was his friend,
and while I married her,
he thought I was taking
her away from him.
And now that she's dead,
taken away from him forever,
I suppose in that
childish mind of his,
I'm responsible for that.
And now, because you're my wife
and in Marion's house,
he hates you, too.
I don't think
Mickey is responsible.
He's not quick enough
or clever enough.
Then who?
Myself.
It's all in my own mind.
We do need
somebody else, darling.
We need somebody
outside of the confusions
of our love for each other.
Now, the reverend Snow
will be here in the morning.
It was in there.
Well,
this much is real anyway.
Look here, Jenni.
You see, this is how
you gouged your hand.
And you say, you threw
the skull down here
where Eric is looking?
Yeah.
Did you find anything, Eric?
Nothing yet.
Surely, Jenni,
you must agree with me
that anything
as fragile as a skull
would've been smashed
to bits down there.
And Eric has found nothing,
and to assume that the skull
would move of its own
all the way from there
to the driveway door...
Come now, Jenni,
there's no reason for that.
Don't you see?
I agree with you.
Did Eric tell you
i spent over a year
in the sanitarium?
Well, Eric told Mrs. Snow
that you are
very impressionable,
but that's all.
I know lots of people needing
a rest go to sanitariums.
This wasn't quite
that kind of sanitarium.
You see...
I grew up loving my father
and hating my mother.
Well, she never knew it.
Something I kept to myself.
She was very beautiful,
very gay, like her.
Very much.
And I knew she resented
that I was not more like her.
I used to lie awake at night
and wish she were dead.
Well, that isn't
very unusual.
I understand many children
go through such a period.
I was no longer a child.
One day...
I got my wish.
They were both drowned.
I could still hear
her scream.
I was all alone
on the little beach.
And all I could see
was the overturned boat
on the top of the waves.
And I kept trying
to reach them,
and the waves kept
throwing me back.
And then...
I could hear
her cries no more.
And then, hours later,
the men came and searched
for the bodies.
They were never found.
And that's when these
bad feelings started,
this feeling that if
I really wanted to,
I could've saved them,
but I didn't.
That I really killed them.
No, Jenni, you tried.
You tried your very best.
I didn't.
But thinking, and begging,
and praying couldn't make
this feeling go away.
That's when they took me
to the hospital.
But they told me
I was cured.
Jenni.
They told me I was cured.
Mickey!
All right, you go on.
I'll be there
in time for lunch.
But where do you think
he's gone off to, Eric?
Who knows about Mickey.
He might be hiding.
You looked at
Marion's grave?
Mickey?
Mickey!
Eric, did you find him?
No.
Where's Jenni?
She's with Mrs. Snow
on the patio.
Eric...
I think I should tell you
that Jenni has confided in me
about the sanitarium.
Oh, did your wife know?
I told her Jenni
was impressionable,
but not that...
Well, I haven't said
a word to her.
Mr. Snow,
you can do both Jenni
and me a great favor
by forgetting
she ever told you that.
But, Eric,
if it helps explain...
It explains nothing.
If I were you, Eric,
I'd take her away.
If she's so impressionable,
and that house
frightens her so much,
why subject her to it?
Look, I can't do a thing
like that.
It'd be the worst
thing for her.
Mr. Snow, it would be
admitting she was sick again.
I want her to be happy.
We'll stay here.
Perhaps you know best, Eric.
See, I've got a simple
and old-fashioned
piece of philosophy.
The only cure for her fear
is to teach her she's loved,
I mean, really loved,
and I love her so much.
God bless you for that, Eric.
She's a very fortunate woman
having someone like you
to care for her.
It'll be night soon.
Oh, Jenni, Jenni...
I'm sorry.
Darling, you've got to believe,
it will not happen again.
Ever.
Mickey!
Eric.
Eric!
- Eric, stop it!
- All right,
what are you trying to do
with that skull?
Eric, stop it,
it wasn't his fault!
- Where did you get it?
- Leave him alone!
I'll take care of this,
Jenni.
I know you never
liked me, Mickey.
I know you're doing it
to get us to leave here.
Idiotic attempt to scare us,
as if we were children.
It was you, wasn't it?
Wasn't it?
No, not me, not me.
Ah, get out of here!
Get out of here!
I wish you'd apologize to him.
You know as well as I do
it's not his fault.
It's all in my own mind.
Jenni, I'm gonna do something,
and you're gonna help me do it.
- What's that?
- That portrait upstairs
reminds you of your mother.
Yeah.
You were fine until
you saw it.
Now it has you all preoccupied
with memories of the past.
We're gonna burn it.
That's precious to you, Eric.
The picture means
nothing to me.
I want you to be happy.
We can't be until this fear
is out of our lives.
All right, Jenni.
Go on, Jenni.
Let's go back in now.
It's only the peacocks.
Fire's almost out.
Yes.
We can't let those ashes
stand overnight.
The brush in this hill
is a regular tinderbox.
You wanna help me?
All right,
you feeling better?
It's as if I destroyed her
with my own hands.
She'll come back, Eric.
She'll come back.
Darling, if you go on talking
that way,
you destroy the whole purpose.
Now, the thing is out
of the house, and it's over.
You just give it half a chance,
and you'll begin to forget it.
And if you'll just spread
those ashes out a little for me,
I'll get the water to it.
That's it.
Eric!
What is it, darling?
That skull!
It's the skull!
Darling,
there's no skull there.
There's no skull there,
darling.
There is no skull there,
Jenni, darling.
There's no skull there.
There's no skull.
We'll be able to catch
a plane tonight?
When we get into town,
I will call Mr. Mauer.
He'll arrange
a midnight plane.
I thought there'd be
more time.
Time for so many
wonderful things.
It's gonna be all right.
Of course.
It's just me.
It's gonna be all right.
Good evening, my dear.
Mrs. Snow's hens thought
you might like some fresh eggs
for your breakfast
in the morning.
Hello, Eric.
This is a surprise.
Those hens labored mightily,
as you can see.
Fine, I'll take them.
If you'll excuse me, dear.
Of course.
What is it, Eric?
I've got to take Jenni away.
That hospital
she was in before.
It happened again?
I thought it would help her
if we got rid of that portrait.
- You know the one.
- Yes.
And we burned it.
She saw a skull in the ashes.
You were there?
I saw nothing, of course.
Of course.
And I thought it was Mickey.
But when I was there myself,
and I saw her...
Mr. Snow, there's something
I've never told you,
I've never told anybody,
but when Jenni was put away
in that hospital,
she tried to do away
with herself.
I'm terribly afraid.
You think she might
try it again?
I know she will.
Unless I get her back
to that hospital.
When are you going?
Tonight.
We shall miss you.
Mrs. Snow and I have grown
very fond of Jenni.
Yes, and she of you.
I don't suppose you'll be
coming back here again, Eric?
No.
Never.
I'll miss him and his wife.
He's very kind.
Yes.
And I said goodbye to him
just now.
He tried to talk me out
of what I saw.
How?
He said he felt the skull
was real.
He's gonna bring
some men in the morning
to search the estate.
Where?
Everywhere.
He's just talking,
trying to be kind.
I suppose.
I'll go upstairs and pack.
You wanna come with me?
I'll be up in a minute.
Mickey!
All right.
Where's the skull at?
You saw me put it in the pond,
- you must have. Where is it?
- I don't know.
- Don't lie to me!
Don't lie to me.
Where is it?
- I don't know!
- Tell me the truth.
Who took it?
Tell me, tell me.
- Tell me!
- I didn't take it!
- Who?
- Not me, not me!
Who?
Marion! Marion, took it!
Marion took it.
You and your Marion!
All right!
Oh, Edward,
in the name of heaven.
Mickey, where
did you find this?
Pond.
Well, who put it there?
- He did.
- Eric?
He did.
Then, there was a skull.
But Eric said that he didn't
see it when Jenni saw it.
I know.
Oh, but why would Eric
lie like that?
Mickey, those other times
with the skull,
did you do it?
No.
Mickey, you've never
lied to me before.
Lying is a sin,
you understand that?
You must not lie to me now.
Did you do it, Mickey,
all those other times?
No.
I simply do not
understand that.
If it wasn't Mickey...
And it wasn't
her imagination...
But why would Eric
do such a thing?
I don't know,
i just don't know.
Well, what do you think
we should do about it?
We're going back there
to that house.
All right.
Mickey?
Eric and I are leaving,
Mickey.
I'd like to say goodbye.
I'd like to leave
as your friend, Mickey.
Mickey?
Eric! Eric!
Eric!
Jenni?
Jenni!
What happened?
Jenni,
Jenni, are you all right?
Oh, Jenni?
Eric...
Eric tried...
- Shh, oh, don't, don't.
- Where is Eric?
I don't know.
- I don't know.
- I'll find him.
It's all right.
Edward, now, be careful.
It's all right, darling.
Oh, it's all right.
All right, come on.
Eric?
Please answer me.
Eric, where are you?
Eric?
Eric.
Why did he do it?
Your money.
The question is now,
did Marion die in an accident?
I suppose we'll never know.
They're gone.
Rest.