THE DEVIL'S BATTLE MOBILE
All Heathville loved Paul
Carraters, his kind rural doctor.
Nobody suspected that in his
home laboratory on the slope.
The hill overlooking the magnificent
Martin Heath mansion ..
The doctor found time to conduct
some secret experiments -
Strange, terrifying experiments.
Ah, my friend ..
Our theory of glandular stimulation ..
With the help of
electrical impulses was true!
A couple of days ago you were
small, like your kindred.
And now - just look at yourself!
Hello? Says Dr. Carruthers.
This is Heath.
Today, Henry Morton and I are
having a small party at my house.
We want you to come.
You are very kind.
I am very grateful to you.
But I'm very busy, working on the
formula for a new after shave lotion.
Oh, doc, this is my daughter's idea.
She is very disappointed
if you do not come.
Refuse do not accept.
Make him come.
You see, there's something like
a special occasion here ..
Ready to argue - Mary is going
to announce her engagement ..
With this young shot, Don Morton.
Tell her I'll come. Bye.
Well, everything is arranged, he will come.
He will be surprised to learn
that a special occasion.
This is giving him this
check with a bonus.
Five thousand dollars ..
Good.
You did not forget.
You hate this strange eastern
flavor, even in a dream.
Just as I hated him before
I made you big and strong.
Now, if you find this fragrance in
the night, when you are awake ..
You will attack!
Yes, you will attack .. to kill!
The dock is delayed.
He must have been called to the patient.
I'll phone him ..
Roy, Tommy, do not forget ..
You do not have to say
anything to the doctor
about this check until
your father gets it.
And you warned those two doves?
Probably better to warn.
"I want to warn both of you."
"Do not say a word about the check."
While you yourself do not spoil them.
His father will show it to you, Mary.
Why do not you arrange a grand
opening, like for a statue?
Then we could all be there.
You know, I think it
would be better to seal
the check in a bottle
and run it to him.
It must have come to
you from the bottle.
"Well, that does not come."
"What a nuisance!"
He was too carried away by this new
formula and completely forgot about us.
He would forget about
the formula if he found
out about the check for
5 thousand dollars.
Why do not we go to him
and give him a check?
Oh no, I would not do that.
He does not like guests who
come when he experiments.
- Roy can take him a check.
- Of course, I could.
Should I make a speech
when I hand it over?
No, actually, the check
itself speaks for itself.
Yes, and says a lot.
Sonny, tell us that we are very
sorry that he could not come.
Of course, we understand
how busy he is.
Good.
Just a minute, Roy, now I'm free.
All is ready.
So, what can I do for you?
We are all very sorry that
you could not come today.
Yes, but, you see, I'm busy.
"Something important, very important."
Oh sure.
Mr. Morton and my father prepared
a little surprise for you.
Surprise?
"He's right here."
"Well, let's see what it is."
Five thousand dollars ..
What is it for?
Just a small sign of friendship.
Oh, I understand.
Bonus.
Well, that's very kind of you
from your father and Mr. Morton.
"Tomorrow I will thank them in person."
"I'll tell them, Doctor."
And you are not interested
in my new formula?
Of course, interesting, but I
did not want to seem curious.
- What is it?
- A new after shave lotion.
Smell it.
"A pretty strong smell, is not it?"
No no..
The odor will erode
shortly after use.
Try a few drops.
Now rub it in the soft
tissues of your neck.
Softens, does not it?
Yes..
When will it be ready for sale?
Oh, he's still in the experimental stage.
I first want to test it
on several people ..
And see if it works.
If you want, send me a bottle,
I will gladly test it for you.
Thank you.
Good night, doctor.
Goodbye, Roy ..
Nice check, is not it, doctor?
They are rich - at your expense.
You made them rich, doctor.
It was your formula!
Today they gave you five
thousand dollars ..
And wanted you to come to their
home and thanked them for it.
It was your money, what they gave you ..
As if throwing the
ball obedient dog.
You must be very grateful,
doctor, very grateful.
Thanks to you they are rich and happy.
And what did you get, doctor?
You have to work hard this night!
It's time for you to go!
But Mary, now that our families are here -
It's time to announce the engagement!
Listen, Don, I've loved you for a
long time, ever since we were kids ..
But I'm afraid, more like a sister.
Well, I...
I did not think it was that way ..
Something happened to Roy!
Roy!
"I'll call Dr. Carruthers!"
Faster please!
I can not help you.
"Do you want to say that he's dead?"
Yes. I'll call the coroner.
"Do you think this is a murder?"
I do not know.
I've never seen this before.
His jugular vein is torn.
Call Johnny Leighton to me!
Well, what have I done now?
Who wants to fire me now?
Nobody, for now.
But the day has just begun.
It came from Heathville.
Mysterious murder.
The son of the old Martin Heath.
- Who is Martin Heath?
Tell me, did you ever go
on a date with a girl?
With a girl? Oh yeah,
with the girl .. It
seems that one day I was
walking with a girl.
"Well, did you smell good from her?"
Yes.
Of course, it smelled good.
As with most girls.
This is because of the limited
series of cosmetics Martin Heath.
He does all this stuff that
women put on their faces,
when they do not want to wash
themselves with water and soap!
Ah, I understand, he's a big man, right?
Yes, and a great supplier
of advertisements.
Take the photographer and
drive to Heightsville!
The coroner is conducting an investigation.
Find who actually killed
the son of old man Heath!
OK, McGuinty, I'm on my way!
"Chief Wilkins?"
- Yeah.
I'm Johnny Leighton from
the Chicago Registrar.
Nice to meet you.
And this is my photographer,
Shooter McGuire.
"Hello, Chief."
- Hi.
Look, we're here about
Heath's murder,
but from the coroner's investigation
we did not get much information.
I thought - maybe you can help us?
Well, I'm always ready to
cooperate with newspapers,
provided that they will
cooperate with me.
This is the policy of my newspaper.
I'll tell you the truth - I myself
did not understand this too.
Here's something that might interest you -
it's a snapshot of the victim's wounds.
With this glass you
can see better.
Are there scratches on
the neck and shoulders?
Yes, but we can not
determine what they did.
For the nails are too deep, and
for the knife - too superficial.
More like claws.
The same thing was said by Dr.
Carruthers during the inquiry.
Wild animal?
Is there a circus lately?
No.
And there was no escape
of animals from the zoo?
No.
Or maybe this is one of those
African leopard people?
"They use steel claws."
"This is not Africa."
OK, chief, I was just trying to help.
Chief, you do not exactly hold any
clues found during the investigation?
Well, since you're going to
work with me on this case ..
There is a clue.
But very strange.
The pathologist said that such
wounds could have been inflicted ..
Claws of a large bird.
Birds?
But in the district there are no
birds large enough to attack a man.
How about an eagle?
"But we know that it was not a bird."
How do you know?
Because we found a few hairs on
the shoulders of Heath's cloak.
Ah, Sherche la fem!
"This is not human hair."
"And whose?"
Well, it may seem stupid,
but laboratory tests showed
that they belonged to a mouse.
But who and when heard about the
mouse, so big to kill a person?
Listen, in bats, wool
is like a mouse ..
The only bats that are found
here are no more than a sparrow.
From the wounds came a strange smell,
but he was so weak and elusive ..
That the police chemist
could not identify him.
There is already something to work on.
Well, the smell could be evidence,
but it's destroyed - it evaporated.
Listen, Chief, do you mind if I
make myself something up here?
Of course not, roll.
And if I can help...
You can.
It seems that Miss Heath was
nearest to the murder scene.
I'd like to talk to her.
Can you arrange this?
I think I can.
Dr. Carraters refused
to talk to us.
We tried this morning
during the investigation ..
Do not worry about Dr.
Carruthers.
He's one of the best people in Heathville.
He just thought you were
interested in the tragedy of Mary,
to print a sensational article.
I will arrange an interview.
Thank you, chief, I'll
be in touch with you.
Good.
4-8-J.
Miss Heath, do you know if
your brother had enemies?
No, everyone in the village loved Roy.
And what did he do in the factory?
He was the head of the research
bureau, developing new products.
And here is Dr. Carruthers.
Hello, Doctor. "Hello, Mary."
I walked from my lab a short
way through the garden.
You met Dr. Carruthers this
morning at the inquest.
Yes.
Mr. Leighton, I hope you will forgive
me if I seemed slightly rude.
But I love Mary,
and mindful of the test, through which
she already had to go through ..
I wanted to protect her from a too
long experience of this tragedy.
Of course, you were right.
Now we are working on this
matter together with the police.
Yes, I understand, Chief Wilkins told me.
If there is anything I can do to help,
just give me a call.
Thank you.
"You will not sit down?"
"Shall I serve dessert?"
No, Maxine, I myself.
You can go. "Ui, mademoiselle."
"The Sahara, Mr. McGuire?"
"Oh, no, ma'am, for nothing.
Actually, I do not even need tea.
If I may be absent,
I'll look around.
Perhaps I'll find a clue.
Mr. Leighton, how do you like the theory
of Dr. Carruthers about a wild animal?
Frankly, I do not think so.
I would not blame you for that.
I, as a scientist, consider
many things from those,
what a simple man could not overlook.
For example?
The ragged edge of the wound,
The speed with which the
killer disappeared,
scratches from the claws
of a hare or beast ..
When an animal attacks a person -
there must be a lot of noise.
You heard the testimony of Miss Hit -
there were no sounds of struggle.
No.. Only these terrible cries.
All this is very mysterious,
very mysterious ..
Doctor, when you last saw Roy -
did he look worried,
nervous or gloomy?
No, not at all, on the contrary -
he was in a great mood.
Well, it's time for me to go back to the
village and start writing an article.
With your permission..
If you find it necessary to talk
again - you can come at any time.
Tonight, if you do not mind.
I would like to stay here for a while.
- Yes, I do not mind.
- Thank you.
"Good-bye, Miss Heath."
Bye. "Goodbye, doctor."
"A little more chiffon, baby."
But I do not understand..
Oh, you know what I'm talking about -
a little more stockings.
- Like this? Like?
- Of course! And who would not like it?
And now - do not move.
It will take a little time ..
Got to shoot - shoot!
Now, Johnny, I'm just
trying to focus.
Done, and - not bad!
I'll be back in a minute, Frenchcoats,
and do not worry about these werewolves,
because when I'm around -
nobody will hurt you!
You helped Maxine
feel so calm ..
My big brave journalist!
In my understanding this is called -
sit back.
Sit here and wait for the animal
to help us write the article.
Just look at this moon!
And I had a date with a French jacket ..
Yes, enough to complain.
We are supposed to solve the murder!
You, the "big brave journalist".
For the first time I was invited somewhere.
And ask not to shave until I go there.
I would like to watch your reaction
when you experience lotion.
Now understand..
I want the lotion to be perfect before
you transfer it to you for sale.
Here ..
Slightly harsh .. But customers will
decide that they are paying for it!
Oh, how nice! Very soothing.
I do not think that you will
ever use something else.
Well, we do not sell goods that
we would not use ourselves.
It smells so good that it can
practically be used instead of cologne!
Oh, what's up, doc?
Do not like your own lotion?
I have a terrible dislike for perfume.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Nothing, Tommy.
"Good night, doc."
Goodbye, Tommy ..
Hey..
What is it? "Where?"
There, something is moving ..
Get out of there, whoever you are!
What are you doing here, Miss Heath?
I thought that you would not be harmed by
the company. Maybe we should sit down?
You know, after what
happened, you should not
be wandering around
the garden at night.
- Yes, and you, too ..
- Well, my job is this.
Me too. Roy was my brother.
Careful, in my opinion, it's Tommy!
- Hey, Tommy.
- Hello. - Hey, Tommy.
How are you, sis?
Mr. Layton wanted to sit in the
garden for a while, and I joined him.
Do not tell me that you
are waiting for this
animal, about which Dr.
Carraters spoke.
"So you do not believe that either?"
Of course not. What an absurdity.
Someone or something killed your brother.
And, I believe, you are practicing theory,
on which the murderer always
returns to the crime scene?
Maybe.
This is not for me.
Listen to my advice, Mary -
leave these gentlemen to
guard, and go to bed yourself.
Personally, I'll do it.
Goodnight.
Good night, Tommy.
I do not think your brother
likes my presence here.
Do not pay attention to Tommy.
We are all terribly annoyed.
I know.
Help!
"Tommy!"
- Faster!
For help!
But I'm telling you, McGuinty -
it was a bat!
I saw how she killed Tommy Heath!
Listen, Johnny, I want you
and Shooter back home.
Or I'll fire you both!
I'm not going back,
and Shooter, too.
He will stay here to take a
picture of this diabolical bat.
Listen, great will be the headline -
"The devil bat attacks again."
Listen, do not tell me this nonsense.
Maybe for you to send a van
with bars on the windows ..
And with strong guys
with straitjackets?
Listen, Joe, did I ever lie to you?
Many times.
But this time I'm not lying!
If it becomes known that I invented
this story about the devil's bat
I can not get a job
even in a rural weekly!
Print the article, Joe.
God swear, it's all true!
Okay, I'll type it.
But I do not believe in it,
until the Shooter takes a picture
of this diabolical bat in flight!
Do not worry, he will make it.
Bye.
You, my friend, will take a picture
of a diabolical bat in flight.
Who am I? How?
Have you not noticed
that there is a
workshop of a stuffed
animal in the village?
You're not suggesting I go there
and stuff a stuffed bird, right?
Shooter, how could you think
what I'm offering you ..
To persuade the village jelly.
To make you a pretty
big bat for a picture?
In addition, the bat -
it's not a bird, it's an animal!
And what did not you just say?
Where is this bird feller?
Ah, the manager of the cottage!
A mysterious diabolical
bat killed Thomas Heath!
Flying death strikes
another blow at Hithville.
The villagers live in fear
of the diabolical bat.
Thomas Heath fell victim to the monster.
Who will be the next victim
of the diabolical bat?
The villagers tremble with
terror in front of the killer.
Aftershave. Experimental.
The devil bat attacks again.
A winged monster kills a
new victim in Hatville.
That's the idea, Frenchies - you keep
the bat while I'm cooking the camera.
When I raise my hand, you
will push the bat well -
and she rushes, as if in flight.
And I'll have a great
shot for the boss, okay?
Ui. I'm smart, are not I?
No. But hold the bat
until I raise my hand.
Cher, are not you hurt?
What did it take you to
break my devil's bat?
I'll make you pay for it!
And I'll put you in jail until
you explain it! Come on!
"You can not do this to me!"
"But I do, do not I?"
We just did a little experiment,
trying to understand how the
devil bat is committing murders.
I'm sure that McGuire was not
going to do anything wrong.
He's just too fanatical
in his work.
Yes, but the whole city is on ears.
And everyone with horror thinks, whether
he will become the next victim.
I do not need unnecessary problems,
even with an artificial bat.
You'd better go back to the hotel.
I want to talk to the chief privately.
"Can I go, Chief?"
"Yes, but be careful from now on."
Have you ever met a similar smell?
Yes! It's the same substance that was
on all the victims of the devil's bat!
"Where did you get it?"
Found in the bathroom of Don Morton.
Find out where Morton got it?
No, I did not raise suspicion
with unnecessary questions,
until this piece is analyzed.
Do you think this has anything
to do with the murders?
It occurred to me, but I
could not figure out which.
I immediately call a police chemist.
I'm poking around, maybe I'll
find out where he's from Morton.
Perhaps, from the cosmetic factory Hit.
My people are working on a hypothesis,
that the crimes committed by an
angry employee of the factory.
Certainly, it is not
a coincidence that,
that all the victims were members
of the Morton and Heath families.
Yes .. It seems like a
conspiracy to destroy them all.
I would like the remaining
of them to leave the city ..
Until the crime is solved.
You're worried about Mary, are not you?
Yes, I insisted that she leave, but
she will not go without her father.
And he persistently wants to stay here and
help with the disclosure of the crime.
And worse, neither Heath nor Morton ..
Did not allow me to
send them bodyguards.
I guess we'll have to wait
until something happens.
"Good night, Chief."
"Good night, Johnny."
Boy, I have a picture that
will dump McGuinty dead.
Meet the devil bat!
And what about this wire? It
looks like a bat on a trapeze.
I have not worked on it yet.
When I'm done with it, this
bat will look like this,
There is nothing around
her except for nothing.
OK, Rembrandt, you won.
Says your radio
commentator Walter King.
Today we are reporting from a
small village of Hittsville,
Where are the victims of the
supposedly devilish bat ..
For the last six months
there were three people.
You noticed, I said
"supposedly diabolical bat".
This, ladies and gentlemen, because
your correspondent is very skeptical ..
Refers to the possibility of the
existence of this monstrous creation.
Today I have a guest in my studio -
Professor Percival Garland Raines,
Perhaps the world's best
specialist in the animal world.
I'll take Professor Raines's
interview on an infernal bat.
Our audience can draw
their own conclusions.
Professor Raines, first let me
ask you a direct question -
Do you believe in the existence of
a creature like a diabolical bat?
I do not believe.
"He's an insolent fellow!" This!
In the forgotten centuries, when
men and women lived in caves ..
There could be
bats of this size.
But not in our days, not in this century.
How would you comment on
the fact that Mary Heath,
two of whose brothers were
victims of the diabolical bat,
and reporter John Layton claim to
have seen this incredible creature?
Sometimes, under the
influence of experiences,
our brain can play
a joke with us.
Hey, does he mean you
saw a little bat?
Shut up.
And what about the photograph
of the devil's bat,
published in the newspaper of Mr.
Leighton?
I studied this picture under
a strong magnifying glass.
I declare that this is a fake.
Whoever created this strange monster -
he forgot to cut the label from silk.
From the silk used
for the left wing.
The label says "Made in Japan".
Order an urgent call to Heathville.
I want to talk to Johnny Leighton!
He lives in a hotel in Hithville.
- One attempt - who could it be?
- Yes, MwkGinty.
Come on, get out.
So you slipped me
a fake shot, huh?
You're fired, both of you!
And I'll make sure that you can not get
into any newspaper while I'm alive!
"Made in Japan"..
And tell Strelka McGuire that he will
have to take pictures in the madhouse!
Come back here both and
get your calculation!
Oh no, we will not come and
we will not get anything.
Well, we're fired -
but still remain here.
I saw this bat!
We stay here to catch this
mouse, and when we catch it -
I'll bring her and shove
you in the throat! Bye!
"Well, we're fired."
Yeah, again.
Now he calls to apologize.
Scare him right!
There's no point begging us to
work for you again, McGeady.
You fired us - so be it!
Oh, Mary ..
I thought it was someone else.
Johnny, why did you turn
such a tragedy into a joke?
Mary, I was not going to
turn anything into a joke!
I was just trying to make an article!
I suppose "making an article for you
means" publishing a fake picture".
This is a deliberate deception!
Now the whole district laughs!
Great job, Johnny, but, strangely
enough, I did not appreciate it.
"But I can explain this picture!"
"And do not try, Johnny."
"Made in Japan"..
I'll take off your living hide
and slay her to the barn door!
This is a chemical analysis
of that shaving lotion.
I see you could not identify
one of the ingredients.
Yes, the chemist said that perhaps it is an
element with which he is not yet familiar.
We will not go anywhere
until we identify him.
In this city there is only one
person who could help us.
Dr. Carruthers.
Yes, Carrateres could help us.
I found out that it was he
who created the lotion.
If you suspect Carraters -
you're barking out the wrong tree, Johnny.
He is the last person in this
city who would harm someone.
That's why everyone loves him.
Maybe..
But here's what I've dug up.
Heath and Morton made states on the
formula of a non-soiling cream,
developed by Dr. Carraters.
So what?
All that the doctor got for this was
$ 10,000, and others made a fortune.
Well, everyone knows
that he chose money,
although he could become
a partner of the firm.
However, on each victim there was
this substance from his laboratory.
Johnny, maybe you're working
too hard on this thing?
Well, I just want to see
his reaction to this.
If he denies that he knows something.
Then it is somehow connected.
I think you're crazy.
Just to show you that I'm
checking all the options -
We'll talk to him.
Pour it into another bottle and do not say
that we would know that he created it.
And ask him to analyze it.
Doctor, I hope we did not interfere with
your work here so bursting into you?
Oh no, not at all!
I can not wait to help
solve these crimes.
All the victims were
my close friends.
Here is a sample of the
substance that was on
the younger Morton and
the two sons of Heath,
When they attacked
the devil's bat.
Of course, I do not understand why
a bird should attack only people,
using this particular substance.
The bat is not a
bird, it's a mammal.
Whatever the case, our police chemist could
not identify one of the ingredients.
We thought - suddenly you can.
And how! I created it myself.
This is a new shaving lotion,
with which I experimented.
An ingredient that your
chemist could not identify,
I discovered many years ago in Tibet.
And why did you decide to
use it in shaving lotion?
Lamas used it in one of their
religious rituals as an incense.
The smell is very pleasant and
competitors can not imitate it.
But why would Morton and the
two sons of Heath use it?
Oh, this is the policy of our firm -
experience any new product
before you put it on sale.
Well, that cut down our theory in the bud.
Yes..
We hoped that an unknown ingredient
might prove to be a clue.
This is not the bottle
I poured it into.
But I suppose your chemist poured
it when he did the analysis.
Yes.
Can I help you with anything else?
"Tell me, did you hear Professor
Raines on the radio last night?"
Yes, it was very interesting and exciting.
Do you mean you believe
that the devil bat exists?
Why not? You saw her, did not you?
"Of course I did!" And Mary saw!
Then why worry about what
one scientist is saying?
Because of this one scientist I was fired.
You mean your newspaper
threw you out?
- And there is.
- What a pity..
So you will leave when this
mystery is not yet revealed?
I'm afraid not. I'm going to stay
here and work with the boss.
If you're going to stay here...
I would like you to experience a
new lotion and say if you like it.
"And you, too, chief."
"No, no, it's not me, Doc.
If my wife smells on me perfume -
she will start to suspect me.
Well, Mr. Leighton, I understand
that you are not married ..
Well, I'll test it in the
morning when I shave.
"I think we should go, Chief?"
"See you later, doc."
"For now, Dr. Carruthers."
"Good-bye, Mr. Leighton."
What's the matter, what's the matter?
This smelly shaving lotion
plunged you into a dream?
Why did you tell Dook that you
use it if you think it's stinky?
I do not know, probably, I was ashamed for
the fact that I suspected the old dock.
Well, I like him, I'll tell him so.
What time is it now?
"It's past midnight."
"Midnight!"
There's no point in waiting here longer.
It must have been a
night out for the bats.
- You heard?
- Yes!
Prepare the camera!
Bend down!
You did it! Listen, Johnny ..
I'll make this bird for McGinnie,
and I'll feed him myself!
The reporter killed the diabolical bat!
The monster is shot.
The end of the mouse power of terror.
The reporter killed a bat
looking for a victim.
Scientists are surprised
at a huge bat.
It is believed that this creature -
the last of its kind.
I was still skeptical when I
arrived in Heathville today,
To investigate the body of the
so-called diabolical bat.
But after I saw her personally
and carefully studied ..
I came to the conclusion
that this creature.
Relic of the species
of giant bats,
which in huge numbers existed
in the early Neolithic period.
Maybe I should explain to
some of our listeners ..
That the Neolithic Age is a period
commonly called the Stone Age.
Imbecil. Pompous ignoramus!
I'm sorry, McGuinty, but we and Shooter
are not interested .. in your pricing.
- Of course, if you add twenty ..
- Thirty!
Tree dollars plus a good
bonus - we could think.
You are extortionists!
I will not allow to be robbed!
As you wish, McGuinty, whatever you like,
but .. we have a mouse corpus delicti
and photos are a real bomb!
Of course, I have an
eyewitness account,
which is already waiting
for two syndicates.
And do not forget - you have to pay
us for the time that we were fired!
That's better.
Well said, boss!
OK, we're working for you again.
We will finish something and in a
couple of days we will arrive.
Bye.
Sign in.
- Hello, Johnny ..
- Mary!
Johnny .. I came to say that I
regret what I said last time.
You think .. I do not know how to say it ..
Of course.
Miss Heath, do you think -
the Frenchwoman will
apologize to me if I visit her?
I'm sure!
Wonderful!
You will be even more than
your unhappy predecessor.
You're furious, are not you?
Excellent!
I'm also furious.
Today I'll call Henry Morton -
and you will destroy it!
Henry, the lotion was even
better than I had hoped.
I want you to experience it.
Leave it here, doc, I'll try
it tomorrow when I shave.
It smells good, does not it?
Yes, but is it not too strong?
No, no, evaporation will quickly bring
it to the desired level of smell.
Spread a few drops on your face ..
I'd rather wait to shave.
Then my skin will be more tender
and receptive to the lotion.
Well, a little bit, here ..
The skin here is always very gentle ..
I'll drop a little on your arm.
I hope you are right, and the
smell will quickly erode.
I smell all the way to heaven.
Perhaps this will be the
secret of his success.
In this business you never
know what can happen.
Can you believe me, Henry -
you do not have to worry.
Yes, I can believe that, doc.
All your formulas are very successful.
I looked through the company's
annual profit reports.
The income was a million dollars.
Not bad, eh?
Do you remember where we started?
With the unfortunate ten thousand
dollars for your formula.
You should not have taken
all the cash, Doc.
If you decided to join us,
you would also be rich.
Although, perhaps, you are more interesting
in your laboratory, with your experiments.
To invent something new ..
You're a dreamer, doc.
Dreamers are harmful to
have a lot of money.
Therefore, you try to pay me flattery,
telling me that I am a dreamer.
Well, I really dream ..
And you will never guess - about what.
I'm afraid you got nervous, doc.
Calm down, pull yourself together.
You worked too hard
on your formula.
Formula..
For a great scientist,
it's like a child's play.
Your brain is too weak to understand
what I achieved in the world of science!
Doc, you've made some great
scientific discovery.
What kind?
Henry, when you learn it -
it will be too late for you.
Come on, Doc, come on.
You can not pretend that you
control the fate of a person.
I have already proved this three times.
I apologize.
Perhaps you are right, Henry,
about the fact that I overworked.
I think I'm a little tired.
I'll go home and rest a bit.
Of course.
Sleep will do you good.
Good night, doc.
Goodbye, Henry.
36 J
Hello? "Is that you, Martin?"
Yes, Henry.
I want you to ask Chief of Police
Wilkins to come to you immediately.
- It is very important!
- The boss now has me.
Do not let him go until I come.
And what happened?
I think I found out who
committed all these murders.
Maybe I'm wrong..
But if my suspicions are
at least half true,
then this is the most diabolical
plan ever invented by man.
What's the plan?
Speaking of the scattered professors -
I forgot my hat.
Henry, what are you talking about?
I'll tell you everything
when I come to you.
I hope I did not interrupt
the personal conversation?
No, nothing important.
I hope Henry was right
about his suspicion.
But why did not he tell
me more on the phone?
When I began to insist on this -
he changed his tone, as if interrupted.
I'm afraid that someone could hear him.
"What is this scream?"
"Ah, just one of the nocturnal sounds."
Help!
The partner of the devilish
bat kills Henry Morton.
The second flying monster kills
the resident of Heathville.
The village is horrified by
the appearance of a new bat.
Henry Morton - the fourth
victim of the devil's bat.
Horror resumes after
a new monster attack.
Mr. Heath, it became much easier for
me when you asked me to live with you
don't kill this
new diabolical bat.
I'm worried about Mary.
What prompted you to think
that Mary was in danger?
Only the next ..
I'm convinced that someone
is using this bat,
To completely destroy the
families of Hits and Mortons.
As a scientist, I can assure you that
the thought of a man controlling a bat.
The idea that a person
controls a bat is fantastic.
Be that as it may, no villager
was killed or even attacked.
You forget that Mr.
McGuire was attacked,
and he does not belong
to any of this family.
Well, I'm already practically
a member of this family.
I'm going to marry
Miss Mary's maid.
Really?
Well, boys, I'll tell Maxine
to escort you to your rooms.
- Thank you.
- And I'll go home.
It's high time for me to sleep.
Good night, gentlemen.
"Good night, Martin."
"Good night, doc." "Good night, doctor."
Good-bye, Mary.
Come again.
"Maxine?" "Uwe, mademoiselle?"
You poured me something new
in the perfume bottle?
Oh no, mademoiselle, I
never touch your perfume.
Strange, I do not recognize him ..
Probably, my father
poured, as a surprise.
He always does this with all the new
spirits that he plans to release.
Anything else?
"No, Maxine, that's all."
Goodnight.
"Good night, mademoiselle."
Mary, what happened?
She tried to break through the window -
Big Bat!
Oh, how awful it was!
Mary, I want you to tell me
everything that I did ..
Before this bat tried
to get inside.
Well .. first I took a
bath and combed my hair ..
And Maxine came to check the mosquito net.
And the hook on the grid somehow
turned out to be uncoupled ..
Yes? Continue, what next?
Well, then we talked about new perfume ..
Someone poured it into the
bottles on my dressing table.
Dad, did you pour new
perfume into my vials?
No, I did not.
- This?
- Yes.
Johnny, smells like ..
"Hush, wait!"
I have a guess that
I want to test.
But only everyone should cooperate.
"We will do our best."
Of course!
"What phone do Carraters have?"
48 J.
Operator, connect with 48 J, please.
Hello, Dr. Carraters?
This is Johnny Leighton.
And there is.
With Mary something terrible happened.
You can come?
- I'm coming.
- Good.
Johnny, I'm fine, I do not need a doctor!
That's the point and it
came to cooperation, Mary.
You have to pretend that you
have a nervous breakdown.
Mr. Heath, you and Shooter have to help ..
Hold Dr. Carruthers
here as long as possible.
Where are you going, Johnny?
I'll go hunt for bats.
The devil bat tried to
penetrate this window.
She suffers from fright.
I'll give her a sedative.
"Where's Mr. Leighton?"
I guess he's in the garden,
hunting for the devil's bat.
Layton is a very brave young man.
Let's Miss Heath one
tablet every half hour.
"Uwe, doctor."
"It will calm her nerves."
But the doctor, maybe you'd
better stay until she calms down?
By morning she will recover.
Hey, doc, I do not feel much myself.
Do you mind measuring my temperature?
You look perfectly healthy, Mr.
McGuire.
You should look at my tongue, it
looks like a squirrel tail, look!
Try calomel.
Today we can have guests.
And for me it can be dangerous
if they find you here.
"Hi, Doc, I hope I'm not interrupting?"
No, not at all.
I heard that you went
after the devil's bat.
Successfully?
No, but I thought
you could help me.
I do not see how I would be mon,
but if you offer anything ..
You could give me a little of your
mixture, this after shave lotion.
But how does this help
catch the devil bat?
I still adhere to the insane idea
that this can attract a killer.
I do not see what kind of
connection there can be,
but there is a bottle
of lotion on the table.
Thank you.
You see, Doc, I figured something out ..
On all four of the dead was this lotion,
when the diabolical bat attacked.
My plan is to sit in the garden, and
when the assassin dives - I'll kill him.
Leighton, I'm afraid all these
murders have affected your mind.
Doc, maybe you want to come
with me and become a witness?
I'm sure I'll waste my time, but
I'll be glad to see your experiment.
Excellent. I knew that I
could count on your help.
I tell you, Layton, to wait for the
bat to smell the lotion-stupidity.
I think I'd better go.
Sit down, doc .. Bat
today just lingers.
You are not very talkative today, doc.
What's the matter?
The weapon always makes me nervous.
Oh, I thought maybe you should
not sit too close to me ..
In case the
diabolical bat appears.
Based on your theory, the
assassin will not attack me.
I do not have this lotion.
Now there is, doc.
"Why did you do it?"
To make the probability 50 to 50, doc.
Now sit down and do not try
to throw out any trick.
Is not it fun when your own
jugular vein is in danger?
Is not that so, doc?
I .. do not understand
what you're talking about.
Perhaps you made a mistake,
when today released this your
diabolical bat from the attic.
Do not be afraid that the bat will kill
you. I will save you for the gallows.
Tell me, Doc, how did you
grow such a monstrous bat?
You would not understand
this scientific theory.
Oh, chief, what are you doing here?
Young man, do not think that
only you worked on this case.
And you were lucky that I was here.
Thank you.
Did you kill the devil bat?
No, she flew away.
Well, here's a bird that
did not fly away - and
this is the killer that
we both were looking for.
Quick, shoot!
- Where's she?
- Disappeared.
And the doctor, too.
"Did you kill the bat?"
What happened?
Doc Carraters is a murderer, and
he hides somewhere in the garden.
You return to the
house and guard Mary.
Come on!
Doctor! Dr. Carruthers!
Doctor!
Is something wrong with Johnny?
Is he hurt?
He was taken to my house.
You'd better go with me.
It was Mary!
Are you all right, Mary?
Help Dr. Carruthers, he's over there!
Mary, this diabolical bat
belonged to the doctor.
He created it to commit
all these murders.
Well, it's too late to help.