[MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, I remember this.
[HORN HONKING]
- Taxi's here.
- Already?
- You wouldn't want Marcy to
miss the train, would you?
- Yeah, I would.
Wouldn't mind it a bit.
- Oh now, Sam.
Get your feet out of the way.
- Just listen to
that meter ticking.
Shut off your meter.
She'll be right down.
JOHN (OFFSCREEN): Good
morning, Mr. Lewis.
- Oh, hello, John.
- You're losing Marcy today, huh?
- She's not dying, you know.
She's just going to Chicago.
- Sam, stop shouting.
[CHUCKLES]
- That's the year she
wanted to be an actress.
Pretty good, too.
Oh, my robe.
Remember the summer she won it.
Most popular girl
at Camp Watahami.
[MUTTERING]
- Oh Mother, you're an angel
for helping me with all this.
I'll finish it.
Just sit down, talk to me.
- No, I'll help.
- How I'm going to get
all these clothes in here
I'll never know.
- Does this go?
- Yes.
- Did he already leave?
- Yeah, he wanted to come
down to the train, dad,
but I thought that was silly.
It's a working day.
- He's a nice boy.
I think he's- - Enough, Sam.
Bring the things from
the dresser, will you?
We've all agreed that if this
is what Marcy wants to do,
she should do it.
- Well, I just thought maybe
it wouldn't be a bad idea
if she stayed and married him.
Where do you want these?
- Here, I'll take them.
Oh, he's sweet, dad,
but it's strictly
a business arrangement.
- Oh, that's too bad
because I think that-
- Go- go sit down, dear.
- I gave him an idea
for his canning factory
to can whole family dinners.
They come in sets, everything
from soup to desserts.
- Gee, that's a wonderful idea.
- It's working out, too.
- Darling, doesn't your head
ever get tired of these things?
- Mine does.
- Oh, before I forget.
I ordered the stove and if
they don't bring it on Monday,
you'd better call them, Mother.
- Will do.
- Let me see.
I canceled my speech to
the advertising club.
just say no sir and yes sir.
When the gardener
puts in the dahlias,
tell him not to put them
so close to the fence.
- Well, that's your department.
- Oh, and before I forget,
we've got a credit
of $3.50 at the meat market.
If you go down there,
Mother, ask for Marty.
- Marty?
He must be new.
- Yeah.
And I was thinking, Daddy,
when you buy your new suit,
ask him to show you
some pinstripes.
I think they'd look good on you.
- Oh, you do?
- Mm-hm.
And guess where I put
your pipe cleaners?
- Where?
- In your top desk drawer.
- Well, it'll be nice having
them where they belong.
- Well, now you two take care
of yourself while I'm away.
- Ah-
- We'll be all right.
- Be all right.
- Guess that's it.
- Well, we'd better set out.
The taxi's waiting.
- Well, what's the hurry?
The taxi can wait.
Oh, we're going to
miss you, honey.
- I'm going to miss you, too.
I might be back.
Maybe they'll turn me down.
- No, they won't, but let
me give you some advice.
Don't give them a million
suggestions your first day.
You know, don't take
over all at once.
They've probably been getting
along fine up until now.
And when you go in
for your interview,
- I had a friend who was one.
Will you remember that?
- Yes, sir.
- How do you do?
- I'm Marcy Lewis.
- Sit down, Miss Lewis.
- Thank you very much, Mr. Wells.
- I thought you wrote a
very impressive letter.
So you're from
Havenville, Indiana?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you like it there?
- Where did you go to school?
- Havenville.
- Oh.
Um, tell me about your parents.
- They're living.
- Tell me, um, what
made you decide
to become an airline stewardess?
It's- it's a home in the air.
- I see.
- She-
- Yes?
- She likes it.
- You know, Miss
Lewis, sometimes girls
who are very well
adapted to other things
aren't quite suited
to this kind of work.
Oh, it's no reflection
on the individual.
95% of our applicants
are rejected.
- You mean I'm not accepted?
- I'm afraid not.
- Yes, sir.
- You see, we're
looking primarily
for girls who like to meet
people and take care of them.
A stewardess is the greatest
salesman an airline can have.
We've got to be very particular.
- But you're absolutely
right, Mr. Williams.
If you had a girl
who was tongue tied
and couldn't take
care of people,
you'd have the passengers
at each other's throats.
And I love meeting
people and I love flying.
You know, an airplane is more
than just a piece of metal.
- You mind if I take
the one next to yours?
That might be a wonderful
slogan for our company,
your home in the air.
If you don't like that
one, Mr. Williams,
I've got a lot of other slogans.
I've wanted to be an
airline stewardess
ever since I can remember.
Aviation is the most
exciting thing in the world.
You know, God didn't mean
people to be strangers,
and with commercial aviation,
people all over the world
are becoming neighbors.
Let me tell you
about my uncle that
used to fly in the last war.
He was my mother's brother,
but you won't believe this.
When he started to fly-
- June, you go to dormitory DC3.
That's the first room.
- OK.
- Hello.
I'm Marcy Lewis.
- I'm Anne White and
this is Miss Well.
- Hello, Miss White.
Hello, Miss Well.
- Hello.
- You're assigned
to dormitory DC6.
That's the second room down.
- Thank you.
- Think you'll find
everything you need there.
- Thank you very much.
- Joyce Davis.
- Hi.
My name's Jan Baker.
- I'm Mary Lewis.
- Welcome.
- I'm exhausted.
I wonder which one's mine.
- Take any bed.
I feel like an old timer.
I've been here 10 minutes.
- No.
We're probably the
oldest friends here.
- Hey, he's cute.
Is he yours?
- Mm-hm.
- "To Jan with my
highest esteem."
- Roger's not very emotional.
- You know, I haven't found
what I've forgotten yet.
Oh.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- I'm Alice Raymond.
I'm from Memphis.
- I'm Jan Baker.
- That's cute.
- And that's Marcy Lewis.
- Hello, Marcy.
Hi.
- I declare.
Isn't this cozy?
Sleepy, honey?
- Hello.
- I think I belong here.
M- my name is Kathy Hunter.
- Hi, Kathy, honey.
This is Jan.
That's Marcy.
- Hello.
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): Hi.
- Help yourself to a bed.
- Oh, thanks.
I can sure use one.
I'm dead.
- Can I have your
attention, please?
Will you get your things
unpacked immediately
and report to Miss
Wiley in 15 minutes.
- Oh, they do things
fast around here.
- Ah.
Ah.
Since the general motion of the
atmosphere in the United States
- Airline service involves
safety, capability, efficiency,
and courtesy.
A stewardess must not only
make a good first impression,
but a lasting one.
Now, your first duty
is to go directly
to the cockpit, where you'll
clean the captain's earphones
and radio mouthpiece
with Exuberol.
I'll show you how that's done.
A little on the cotton,
it's very simple.
[SNEEZES]
- On a Convair,
you'll work alone.
On a DC6, there are
always two stewardesses.
All right, Miss Wells.
- Oh hi.
There's nothing to this at all.
Oh!
- I hope I didn't flunk
that meterology test.
Marcy, what's the- Marcy!
- Hm?
- What's that rule
about air masses?
- Oh, Alice.
I can't believe it.
is toward the east, the
polar and Arctic air masses
ALL: Generally move
toward the southeast.
- Is that it?
[LAUGHTER]
[SNORING]
- Well, girls.
I came here today
to congratulate you,
but after looking
you over, I think
I should congratulate
our passengers.
[NERVOUS LAUGHTER]
- There's a lot of hard work
ahead of you and a lot of fun.
I won't keep you
from it any longer.
In case you're mildly curious
about your assignments,
they're in the next room.
[SCREAMING]
[CHATTERING]
- Memphis?
But I became a stewardess
to get away from Memphis.
- Well, this time tomorrow,
we'll be on our own flights.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Attention, please.
Flight 485 leaving for Nash-
- Oh, that's me.
- Don't worry, Kathy.
You're not going
to an execution.
- I know, but I'm
afraid I'm suddenly
going to forget everything.
- Oh no you're not.
You're not nervous.
- I'm not?
Well then why are
my knees shaking?
Oh, Jan.
Goodbye, Marcy.
- Goodbye.
- Take care, Alice.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Attention please.
American Airlines Flight 576 for
Cleveland now ready at Gate 11.
- That's me.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
All aboard, please.
- Now- now you're both
going to be all right.
You don't- don't let anybody
know that you're nervous
and don't let anybody
know that you're scared.
I guess I better get aboard.
Goodbye, Jan.
Goodbye, Alice.
Now take care now.
Bye!
- Don't you want your suitcase?
- Oh!
- That's right, honey.
Don't be nervous.
- I'm not.
Goodbye.
- Let Cleveland be nervous!
They're expecting
a tornado, sir.
- Cleveland tower calling
American operations.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Yeah.
Yeah, OK.
Point killer.
283 is on the ground, Joe.
- All right.
- As I was saying, it was
the most beautiful two wing
job you ever saw.
I had smooth air all
the way and was all
set for a two point landing.
- What happened?
- Her mother walked in.
- Oh, great.
- Stewardess Marcy Lewis
reporting for duty.
- Meteorologist Hawkins.
- Flight Dispatcher Brown.
- Williams, charge
of crew schedules.
- Allison, radio operator.
At ease, men.
- You're not going to
fly in this weather?
- But it's beautiful here.
- Ah, but you're not flying here.
You're going to
fly to Nashville.
What's the weather in
Nashville, Mr. Hawkins?
- I don't know, sir.
I'll look in the paper.
- But I love tornadoes.
I've been out with the
operations crew in Chicago.
- Uh oh.
- Welcome to the club.
- Hello, fellas.
- You check in at
a downtown hotel
until you can find an apartment.
- Thank you.
[SINGING]
- You'll go out on flight 783.
-783.
- Report back here tomorrow
morning at 11 o'clock sharp.
-11 o'clock.
- Synchronize your watches, men.
We're expecting
big things of you.
- Roger.
Over.
Out.
Bye, fellas.
- If you put the
jack under the axle,
I think you'd get
a better leverage.
- Yes, but this was
a bumper jacket.
- Well, will you please hurry?
I've got to be at the
airport in 10 minutes.
- I'm going as fast as I can.
- I don't think there's
enough of a fulcrum.
- Look, lady, I've been jacking
these cars up all my life.
- Oh, I'm going to be so late.
Gives you a feeling that
you're, well, indispensable.
- Are you going anyplace
near the airport?
- Yeah.
Can I give you a lift?
- Oh, wonderful.
Here.
- Oh, thank you.
- I still say you've
got the wrong jack.
I've never been
late for a flight.
- No?
- Oh, I'm a stewardess.
You see, a stewardess
must not only
create a good first
impression, but a lasting one.
- Oh, really?
- Would you mind driving
just a little bit faster?
- Oh no.
- An airline service involves
safety, capability, efficiency,
and courtesy.
Do you do much flying?
- Only a little.
- Do you like it?
Me too.
No other way to travel.
You know, I'm not
really happy unless I'm
in the air taking care of
my passengers and crew.
- You know, I never realized that
a stewardess was so important.
- Planes don't fly without us.
- How about, um, pilots?
- Chauffeurs.
Well, I can't thank you enough.
- Well, I wouldn't have missed
it for anything, Miss, um?
- Oh, Lewis.
Marcy Lewis.
- Marcy Lewis.
- Maybe we'll meet
again sometime.
- I hope so, Miss Lewis.
- All right.
Thank you.
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
Chauffeurs.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Attention please.
American Airlines Flight 183
from New York and Buffalo now
arriving at Gate Five.
- Number one.
Sterilize captain's microphone.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Miss Virginia Invy.
We have a message for you at
the Capital Airlines ticket
counter.
Attention.
Attention please.
American Airlines Flight 783
leaving for Nashville now ready
at Gate Four.
All aboard, please.
[SNIFFS]
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Good morning.
- Thomas Beckett.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Attention please.
American Airlines Flight
783 leaving for Nashville
has been cleared and is ready
for departure from Gate Four.
All aboard, please.
- Your clearance slip.
- Oh, thanks.
- Have a nice trip.
- Wait a minute.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Um, I- I'll write to you.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
[CHATTERING]
- Your name, please?
I'm terribly- what
are you doing here?
- What is your destination?
[CHATTERING]
- Oh, son, you'd better sit down.
What's your name?
- Kevin.
- Where are you going?
- Nashville.
- Fasten your seat belt.
- Your name, please?
- Mary Elizabeth Brown.
- Just a moment, please.
Destination?
- Nashville.
- What can we do for you?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- Oh, well- well I'm afraid
that I don't- I don't speak
whatever it is that
you're speaking.
- [SPEAKING_FOREIGN_LANGUAGE]
[BELL RINGING]
- What's keeping that stewardess?
- Would you hold
the baby, please?
- Oh yes.
Isn't she sweet?
- It's a boy.
- Miss, how about
something to eat?
- Oh, well thank you very much.
I just ate.
[BELL RINGING]
[GASPS]
- Oh, I forgot.
Um, take the baby, please.
Don't anybody go away.
Oh!
And everybody fasten
your seat belts.
Hurry!
[CHATTERING]
- It's about time.
- Yes.
- This plane's flying
on a schedule.
When you get a clearance
order, bring it to me.
- Yes, sir.
- Magazine?
- I work here.
- You didn't tell me you work-
- You didn't give me a chance.
- Well, I'd like to explain
about this morning.
- Well, maybe we could
go someplace and chat
over a cup of coffee.
- Well, I'd love to,
but we have to fly.
- Oh.
That's what's been on my mind.
Now I remember.
The- the tower has been
asking me to take off.
Now then, if it won't
inconvenience you,
I'd like to leave, hm?
- All right.
- Weren't you a
little rough on her?
- That one needs a lesson.
- I think she's kind of cute.
- She's darling, fellas.
Now how about moving that ship?
- Magazines?
- Yes, please.
- [SPEAKING_FOREIGN_LANGUAGE]
- May I have a pillow, please?
- Oh, yes.
Wouldn't you like
to take your hat off
and be more comfortable?
- Thank you so much.
- Miss, if it isn't too much
trouble, I'd like some lunch.
- Well, of course.
I'm going to serve right away.
Here's something
for you to read.
I couldn't have.
Radio back for instructions.
- Time's lunch?
- That's what I
wanted to talk about.
Well, you see, there was so
much excitement and confusion,
and then one of the
passengers said he was hungry,
and then I went to look-
I forgot to check-
- You forgot the food?
- Yes, sir.
- What?
- Oh, of all the stewardesses in
this country, I had to get you.
What I'd like to know
what have I done to-
- I'm sorry.
- (MOCKING TONE) I sorry.
A stewardess's job is to
make a good impression.
Now, of course, I'm
only a chauffeur,
but what I'd like you to know is
what an impression you've made
and how indispensable
you've been.
- Well, you know how
it is, schedules
Those passengers have to be fed.
You know what that means?
- Flight 783-
- That means we have to
go back to the airport.
That's 15 minutes lost.
Then land, that's
10 minutes lost.
With any luck, we'll get
off a half an hour late
and then we can
start all over again.
It's an hour lost
and you're sorry.
- Maybe we won't have to-
- We're back.
- But you didn't write.
- I suppose things like
this happen often.
- I've never seen this happen
before, but don't judge by me.
I've only been with the
company for 15 years.
- Are they terribly upset?
and all that nonsense.
Look, if this airplane ever
reaches Nashville, Mr. Thomas,
the operations chief there,
is very anxious to see you.
- He is, huh?
- Well, goodbye again.
- Where do they get
dames like that?
She's a menace to
commercial aviation.
- Take it easy, Mike.
You're like a flying busboy.
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER
(OFFSCREEN):
Fellas, your lunches are packed.
Would you like to make
your airplane fly now?
We have other planes to land.
- Here she comes.
Hey, fellas.
- Hey, Joel.
What did you say her name was?
- Marcy Lewis.
- Is Mike really sore?
- Sore?
He wanted to land
in my parachute.
- Thanks for everything, Marcy.
Goodbye.
- [SPEAKING_FOREIGN_LANGUAGE]
- It was nice, and don't
you worry about a thing.
- We enjoyed the trip.
Goodbye.
- Well, I don't know, Mike.
This is a pretty serious thing.
We can't just overlook it.
- Well, I'm not asking you
to overlook it, Tommy.
I just hope that you won't be
too hard on her, that's all.
Sure, she was excited.
It was her first flight.
She's great with passengers.
- Well, I'll see.
- Thanks, Tommy.
I promise you, you
won't be sorry.
- Mr. Thomas?
- Yes.
Come over here, Miss Lewis.
- You know who I am?
- The whole airline
knows who you are.
Aviation stocks are tumbling.
- I said I was sorry.
I tried to take care
of all the passengers.
I did everything I could
to make them feel at home.
Maybe I tried too hard,
but- anyway, I tried.
Well, I don't mind.
I can go back to Havenville.
Furthermore, I'm going by bus.
Goodbye.
- Miss Lewis, you'd better
check your schedule.
Your next flight
goes out in an hour.
- My?
Oh.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Thomas.
- I hope not.
You're flying with Mike Jamison.
- Oh.
Well, anyway, thank you.
- Don't forget the lunches.
- No sir.
Captain Jamison.
- Oh.
- You'll be disappointed to
know that I'm not being fired.
- Oh, you don't say?
- Mr. Thomas was
very understanding.
He felt it could
have been worse.
- Yes.
You could have
forgotten the airplane.
- Come on.
I'll buy you some coffee.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Flight 617-
- Thank you so much
for a wonderful trip.
- Goodbye, Mrs. Fleming.
You tell your husband to
get you that new goat.
OK, now watch the step, please.
- Bye, Miss Lewis.
- Goodbye, Mr. Saunders.
I'll give your
daughter the message
when I get back to Nashville.
- Thank you, honey.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Watch the steps, please.
- Hey, Marcy.
- Hi, Willie.
- Your transfer came through.
- No.
- Yeah.
You're assigned to the
Chicago Los Angeles run.
- Oh, Willie.
- That came through for you, too.
- Oh, thanks.
Well, this is from my roommate.
We're going to be on
the same run together.
She's going to
meet me in Chicago.
- Better get started.
You're scheduled to
leave at three o'clock.
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER
(OFFSCREEN):
- OK, Mike.
- Me too.
- Anything the matter?
- No, nothing.
I- I just got my
apartment furnished.
- I'll see you before you go.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
United Airlines Flight 617
leaving for Milwaukee, Denver,
and Los Angeles now ready
for departure at Gate Two.
All aboard, please.
- American Flight 396,
Chicago Midway tower.
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER
(OFFSCREEN):
Chicago Tower, go ahead,
American Flight 369.
- American Flight 369
in range of shoreline.
Go ahead with
landing instructions.
- Well, let's start with me-
You're number three
to land on Runway 22L,
wind southwest five.
Call on-
- American Flight 369.
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN): Incoming
passenger aboard Flight 369.
- Marcy!
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
Please come
to the information
counter, American Airlines.
- Oh, Jan!
- Hi, Marcy.
- Oh, you look wonderful.
- So do you.
- Is everything all right?
- Just fine.
- Oh listen, I've got
so much to tell you,
I don't know what to- I
don't know where to start.
- Start anywhere.
- OK.
- Top of the bottle
came off and spilled
all over the microphone.
- This way.
- Well, I knew I had
to do something,
so I took my perfume
out and put that on.
- Oh no.
- I told you what happened
on my first flight.
- Didn't have to.
Everybody talked
about it for weeks.
- Oh, this is darling.
- Mm-hm.
- Who have you been flying with?
- Well-
- And aren't the
pilots wonderful?
- Absolutely.
- Have you been having any fun?
- Well, I- - Hm?
Hm?
- Oh, I guess so.
- Oh.
How is Roger?
- Well, he hasn't married
anybody else yet.
- That's romantic of him.
You know, you and I may have
to do something about this boy.
- Yeah.
Hey, Marcy.
Do you realize that
tomorrow, we'll
be flying the Mercury
run to Hollywood?
- You'll love Hollywood, Jan.
It's a wonderful place.
Everything out there is
touched with a kind of magic.
- Gee, it sounds wonderful.
When were you there?
- This'll be my first trip.
- Oh honestly, Marcy.
- What?
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN): United
Airlines mainliner service
Flight 608 from Los Angeles
now arriving at Gate Two.
(WHISPERING) Where is he?
- I'm going to turn
the oven off, Jan.
- OK.
Number three?
- Mm-hm.
Did you take a look at all
the passengers on board?
- Mm-hm.
Why?
Did anybody leave?
- No, but there's a man
named Michael Lawrence
I've got a feeling about.
- What kind of a feeling?
I need two milks.
- Nothing, except I
think he's a VIP.
- The list didn't say anything
about a very important person.
- Well, he isn't listed.
It's just a feeling.
- Sort of an intuition?
- Yeah, sort of.
- Think it's too early
to get the desserts out?
- Are you ready to serve?
- Now, Marcy, these
intuitions of yours.
- Up front.
- His head looks fine.
I'll take his dinner
and let you know.
- Thank you very much.
Here's your dinner,
Mr. Lawrence.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Did you enjoy your
dinner, Mr. Lawrence?
- Yes, thank you.
- Did you have enough?
- Would you like some
more hot coffee?
- Mm-mm.
- What?
- No thank you.
- This plane is going
to be 48 hours late.
- That's nice.
Did you know that the
Big Dipper scoops up
- Hello.
- Oh good.
You're awake.
- Oh wow.
So am I. Wh- what's your name?
- Natalie.
What's yours?
- My name's Mike.
- Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Did she disturb you?
- Oh, that's all right.
She got lonesome, I guess, and
needed somebody to talk to.
- Don't you think you'd
better go to sleep, now?
- I'm not the least bit sleepy.
- Oh, why don't you let
her sit there a minute?
She's- over-
- Are you sure she
won't disturb you?
- No, no.
- Don't you think
Mike is handsome?
- Well, I- yes, I- I do.
- Thanks.
- Wouldn't you like me
to tell you a story?
- I don't think so, thank you.
- Have you ever flown before?
- Oh yes.
I love to watch the stars.
- You do?
Well, there's the
Big Dipper out there.
See it?
And there's the Milky Way.
If you had a house
on the moon, you'd
all the milk that
passes through the sky?
- Did you know that, Mike?
- Well, actually, the Big Dipper,
or Ursa Major, as it is called,
is used very little
to scoop up milk.
For many years, the
sailors have been
using it to find
Polaris, the North Star.
That's the beacon light
that guides them safely
home from voyages
all over the world.
You see that group
of stars over there
that resemble a big chair?
That's Cassiopeia.
It's known as the seated lady.
Further south, just out
of sight of Pleiades.
Long ago, the Babylonians called
them the many little ones,
the ancient Greeks called
them the seven sisters,
and to the American
Indians, they
were known as the
seven brothers.
- Do- do you know about
the man in the moon?
- I don't think Mr. Lawrence
can answer that question
unless Mr. Lawrence
has been to the moon.
- I can tell you a little
about the moon, Natalie.
I've been there in a telescope.
I'll just get her a pillow.
never have to clean it because
there's no dust up there,
and you wouldn't need
any glass in your windows
because there's no rain
or wind to keep out.
And you can't hear
any noise up there.
- That would be nice.
- Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Don't you think you
ought to go to sleep now?
- I think I could if
I had my dog with me.
- Oh, where is he?
- He's up in front
with the suitcases.
- Oh.
Well you see, Natalie,
I'm afraid the company
can't allow animals back here.
- What's his name, Natalie?
- Poochie.
- Poochie?
Well now, isn't
that a coincidence?
Only dogs named Poochie
are allowed back here.
- Oh.
- I'll go get her.
- Thank you.
She's very pretty, isn't she?
- She's very what?
NATALIE (OFFSCREEN): Pretty.
- Oh, yes, I guess she is.
- Here he is, Natalie.
- Hello, Poochie.
- Come on.
Let's go back to your seat, hm?
- Can I stay with Mike?
- Oh, why don't you
let her stay here?
There's plenty of room, really.
It's no trouble.
- Is it all right?
- Sure.
- Is it all right? -
Sure. - Sure. - Well, fine.
- Sure.
- Well, fine.
All right.
- Blanket.
Tuck her in there.
There we are.
All right, Natalie,
now go to sleep now,
just like you're at home.
- There.
- Get the blanket
tucked in there.
There we go.
- That's right.
Good night.
- Good night.
Sweet dreams.
- Got your hot chocolate.
- Oh good.
- For a minute, I thought I
heard you bring a dog in here.
- I did.
- What?
- I brought a dog in.
- You read the rules lately?
- Yeah, I've read the rules.
Cookie says we have
to use our heads.
There was a little girl
who couldn't sleep.
Now she has her dog and
everybody can sleep.
What's the harm in that?
[SCREAMS]
- All right, everyone.
Don't worry about it.
It'll be quite all right.
[CHATTERING]
- Wish I'd gotten a chance
to say goodbye to Mike.
- Who?
Oh.
Your VIP.
- This looks like something
left over from Halloween.
Wonder what that is?
You know, I can't believe
we're in Hollywood.
- I bet Kathy's
rented us a bungalow.
Hope it isn't too fancy.
Just a nice little place
with a little backyard
where we can lie out in the sun.
- Are you sure?
- Oh, here it is.
I have a feeling this is going
to look better in the dark.
- Going to get a key.
- Wait a minute.
Oh no.
- Oh no what?
- Oh, Jan.
- Now, don't be silly.
Come on.
Well, isn't a
penthouse apartment.
We've got to go in.
- Why don't you
turn the lights on?
- OK, I will.
You keep your eyes closed.
Oh, Marcy.
Her friends kept trying
to drop in all night.
- This room needs something,
but I'm sure it isn't us.
- Where are the closets?
- Look, you've lived
here as long as I have.
Oh, here's a door.
See where that leads to.
- What is it?
- The bedroom.
- Well, let me see.
- Oh, no, no.
Stay right there.
I'll bring it to you.
[LAUGHING]
- Did you sleep at all?
- Nope.
I stayed up counting
light bulbs.
You know, I could
make a fortune.
All I need to do
is find a quiz show
that wants to know
how many times an hour
Rick's sign goes on.
The answer is 900.
- Oh, that's awful.
- I didn't mind that.
What made me mad was that
at 4:17, the sign went off
and I didn't have a thing to do.
- I had the craziest dream.
I dreamt all night long people
were knocking at our door.
- You weren't dreaming.
Seems that the former
tenant of this dungeon
was an exceedingly popular
girl named Bubbles.
You see, I was- yes, Miss Hale.
- Well, why didn't you wake me?
- They wanted Bubbles.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- I'll get it.
Bubbles doesn't
live here anymore.
- Yes, I know.
Are you Marcy Lewis?
- Yes.
- Telephone for you
downstairs in the hall.
- If I'm not back in an hour,
there was no phone in the hall.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yes, this is Marcy Lewis.
Who?
Oh, I see.
- Who is it?
- Miss Hale.
Yes, Miss Hale.
Oh, dear.
- Something wrong?
- If you'll wait a minute,
I'll give you a full report.
- Then let your time.
- But it was my fault.
Jan had nothing to do with this.
- I can well believe it.
Yes, I understand.
All right.
I'll come in this afternoon.
Goodbye.
- You're in trouble, hm?
- How do you spell catastrophe?
- Let me see.
- Guess who's been
grounded for a week?
- Oh no.
- Yes.
Poochie had to pick a
woman who collects cats.
She reported me.
- Well, I don't know
what we're going to do.
- Well, you're going
to do anything.
- I certainly am not.
This is on me.
It hardly seems fair.
- Well, I'm not worried, Jan.
What I did was right, it
just turned out wrong.
- Certainly did.
- I'm just afraid they're
going to find out
they can fly without me.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- This business.
Yes?
- Surprise!
[CHATTERING]
- Come on in and sit down.
I'm sorry the place
is such a mess.
We're just having it landscaped.
- Oh, I know it's terrible,
but honestly, Marcy, I
couldn't find anything better.
- You mean this isn't a joke?
- Well, we all live
in jokes like this.
There's a housing shortage.
an interest in a small child.
You know, last night,
she wouldn't come in
until I turned the lights off.
- I've got it.
- She's got it.
- Well, there goes
the housing shortage.
- I don't know why I
didn't think of it before.
There are four of
us, and if we pool
what we're paying
right now, we could
have a lovely little house.
- That sounds wonderful.
- What do you say?
- Oh, I say yes.
- Yes, indeed.
- Now we can invite more-
- Listen, let's talk
about it over lunches.
- Oh, there's a
wonderful restaurant
where we all hang out.
- Oh good.
Well, let's go.
- Marcy!
- What?
- Where's your hat?
- I'll get dressed in a hurry.
Come on.
- Gee, this is a cute place.
- You'd never mistake the
cooking for mother's, but prices
are reasonable.
- You'd mistake it for my mother.
She's an awful cook.
- Look, let's order right away.
I can't wait to start
looking for a house.
- Where is the best
place to live?
- We're going to have to
take anything we can get.
- You know, Alice and I
have to fly this afternoon,
so if you'll drop us off at the
airport, you can take the car
and pick up a map,
and then good luck.
- Good.
- It's a shame about you
being grounded, Marcy.
- Well, that's what
I get for taking
I flew to Chicago to attend
a research conference.
- You should get a look
at that small child.
- Oh?
- Well now, it's not
what you think at all.
He's some kind of a scientist.
He communes with time
and space and things.
- Sounds just like a cousin
of mine from South Carolina.
They finally put him away.
- What does he look like?
- Oh, he was a cute
little old kid.
He was fine.
- Quiet, Alice.
- Oh, I don't know.
He's, um, he's tall.
He has light hair.
Jan.
- Well, looks like your scientist
also communes with spirits.
- Excuse me.
Don't stare.
- Hello.
- If you don't recognize me,
it's because I'm out of uniform.
- You're out of
uni- oh, of course.
You're, um, Poochie's friend.
- Yes, let's not go into that.
I want to talk to you.
- Must be this apron.
As soon as I put it on,
everybody wants to talk to me?
- What are you, a
flying bartender?
- Oh that.
No.
- Well, there it is.
- Do bartenders have
research conferences?
- Oh, no.
The university sent me back.
I do this because,
contrary to public opinion,
graduate research
students have to eat.
That's what I am,
graduate research student.
- I see.
I'm awfully glad.
- Why?
- Oh, just confirms a
feeling I had about you.
- What kind of a feeling?
- Oh, just a feeling.
I'll be seeing you.
- What is that?
- Old Oak Road, Old Oak Lane.
- We seem to have misplaced
Sunset Boulevard.
What does it say on the map?
- And it says we're lost.
- Let me see.
- You have to drop everything and
leave for London by tomorrow.
- Right, Mike.
Tell them I'm adding a whole
new advertising campaign.
I want you to report to me as
soon as you've met with Henley.
- This new campaign
of yours is great.
They're going to love it.
- I hope so.
- You'd better get going.
- What is this?
Old Oak?
- Mm-hm.
- OK.
- Good.
- Hm.
Now, let me see.
I have to- left,
I have to turn.
- Thank you.
What's the matter?
- Battery's dead.
- Oh no.
- So are we.
OTTO (OFFSCREEN): I don't
know where I'm staying yet.
I'll cable you as
soon as I get there.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): OK,
have a good trip, Otto.
OTTO (OFFSCREEN): Thanks, Mike.
- Oh, there's a cab.
Hey!
Hey, hey, wait a minute.
- Huh?
- He got away.
- What's the matter?
- The battery's dead.
- We need a push.
- You sure it's the battery?
- I think so.
- Is there gas in your tank?
- Yeah.
- Maybe your starter's stuck.
Step out.
I'll take a look at it.
- All right.
- Your battery's dead.
- Isn't it nice to
have a man around?
- Will you give us a push?
Get in the front seat, honey,
and turn the wheels that way.
We're going left.
- OK.
- Turn the ignition
on, put it in second,
push your clutch in, and let it
out, and we start to roll OK?
I've got a hunting license.
- Well, can't you
push any harder?
[CAR STARTS]
- Oh!
Did you hurt yourself?
- No.
I'm fine.
- Oh.
Oh, well wait a minute.
Here.
Thanks a lot.
Th- thanks a lot.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
[BELL RINGS]
- Oh, there goes the
call of the wild again.
- That room.
- One's as bad as the other.
- It's a good thing this
isn't a night flight.
They'd both be
baying at the moon.
[BELL RINGS]
- Wish Roger were a wolf.
- What?
- I do.
Mother taught me how to handle
a man who didn't treat me
like a lady, never one who did.
[BELL RINGS]
- Want me to get it?
- No, I'll handle it.
- Oh boy.
- Hey-
- Just a minute, please.
- Good salesman never gives up.
Now, look.
For the tenth time, why won't
you have dinner with me tonight
in Chicago?
- Well, I'm sorry.
I never eat.
[BELL RINGS]
- Excuse me.
- Well now, look, honey.
- Well, what do you say, baby?
I got some pretty good
connections in old Chi.
Instead of sitting in that
little old hotel room looking
at those little old
walls, you and me
could be having lots of fun.
[BELL RINGS]
- Excuse me.
- Oh no wait a minute.
- Don't bother with that.
Here's the key to my suite.
I'll expect you around seven.
We'll have a little drinky,
hang on the old feedbag,
and you and I will
go on the town.
How does that sound, hm?
- Oh boy.
- How about that
little celebration?
What-
- All right, you win.
Seven o'clock.
You can help me to spend
that dollar you gave me.
- May I have your baggage checks?
- Here we are, three of them.
- Yes, sir.
- Hi, Marcy.
- Hi, Bud.
- Pardon me.
Haven't we met before?
- No, we haven't, and
that line's had it.
- How's your battery?
- You must be the gardener.
But you're not a gardener.
I'm sorry.
I didn't recognize you dressed.
- You didn't?
- I mean, um, dressed up.
If you're not a
gardener, what do you do?
- I'm in advertising.
My name is Mike Tracy.
- Mike?
- Mm-hm.
- Well, I'm Marcy Lewis.
- Hello, Marcy.
Say, look.
Um, if you didn't like
"haven't we met before,"
you're really
going to hate this,
but it happens to be true.
I have to take an important
client and his wife
to dinner tonight and my
date is at home with a virus.
No really, honest.
Would you, um, like to join us?
- Oh.
- How do you do, Mr. Bellemy?
Well, I believe you, but,
um, I'm sorry I just can't.
- Well, that's too bad.
Maybe some other time.
- All right.
And thanks again for the push.
- Bye.
- Hi, Jack.
- Hi, Marcy.
- I missed your last two letters.
- I don't know why.
- You must be Roger.
- Oh, you must be Marcy.
- I knew it was you
because it's Chicago.
In California, it's Bill.
- Bill who?
- Marcy, what are
you talking about?
- Or is it Tony?
I don't know.
I forgot.
[CHATTERING]
- Tony?
What is it?
What's going on, Jan?
- Well, I've checked us
out, so I'll be seeing you.
- Oh, you're not
going to leave now.
- Oh, yes I am.
I have a date standing
right over there,
so you kids, um, have fun.
- Just wait 'til I get you alone.
- Jan, I want to talk to you.
- Oh, you silly-
- Oh, that's fine.
Here we go.
Thank you very much.
- Mr. Tracy?
- Hm?
- I found out that I haven't
anything to do tonight.
- Oh?
- Would you mind dropping
me by the public library?
- I'd love to.
- Ah, good evening.
- Seven minutes late.
- Clock watcher.
I'd like to present Miss Lewis.
Mrs. Bellemy, Mr. Bellemy.
- It has everything- color,
appeal, educational value.
- I'm afraid it's my fault.
I had to get out of my uniform.
- Waiter?
- What branch are you in?
- Miss Lewis is an
airline stewardess.
- Oh.
I had her down to the Navy.
I've ordered
champagne cocktails.
- I hope you like them.
- Yes, I do.
- Well, here's to Mr.
Bellemy's Gardenia soap,
which brings us all together
on this pleasant occasion.
- Oh, no.
I think we ought
to, um, make a toast
to Michael's lovely young lady.
- Thank you.
- Do you like being an
airlines hostess, dear?
- Oh, yes.
I love it.
I can't remember seeing
you or Mr. Bellemy
on any of my flights.
- Well, you young ones
can have the airplanes.
I'll stick to the ground.
- But I thought you were so
interested in selling soap.
- What's that got to do with it?
- Well, does our
airline use your soap?
- I don't know.
- Well, you should know.
You're letting a big
customer get away.
- That's very true, my
dear, but right now,
selling to one customer
isn't our problem.
We need to map out a
whole campaign, one that's
just as effective
as the last one.
- Mr. Bellemy, I think I have it.
- Yeah?
- That's the way
girls should talk.
- Go on.
- Well, we run a series
of ads going back
to the origins of soap, show how
they made soap in the old days.
We can use posters
of the pioneers,
contrast these posters with
the modern Gardenia soap plan.
- I like that.
- That stinks.
If I want to educate people,
I'll build a college.
- All right.
I'll find another approach.
- I have an idea.
- I have a better one.
Let's dance.
- All right.
Excuse me.
- Certainly.
- Sorry we got
involved in business.
- Oh, I didn't mind.
Mr. Bellemy likes you.
I can tell.
- That's one thing
about old Bellemy.
He's got a tough exterior, but
inside, he has a heart of rock.
- He was a little
rough on your idea.
You know, I have an idea.
- And so have I,
and it has nothing
to do with gardenia soap.
You're a wonderful dancer.
- You make me look good.
The art of flattering
men seems to be lost.
Women can't seem to lie
the way they used to.
- Oh, we do all right.
You know, I really
think I know what
would appeal to Mr. Bellemy.
- Honey, honey, look,
the office is closed.
Look, if you're so eager
to sell gardenia soap,
why don't you
write him a letter?
- I'm sorry.
- That's the girl I've
adored all these years.
You see, if two people
really love each other,
these little spats
can be patched up.
- Yes, Mike.
- I'm awfully glad the
battery in your car ran down.
We should celebrate every
anniversary in a garage.
Um, where would you
like to go from here?
- Oh, I don't care.
Anyplace you like.
- Maybe we should get
home to the children?
- Oh, I think the governess
could take care of them all.
- Oh.
How many do we have?
- Six.
- Oh.
- Drinky?
- Gee, I hate to leave you
alone with all this stuff.
With the other
kids flying too, I
don't see how you can handle it.
- Well, at least
they'll have time
to load their things in
the car before they leave.
- Yeah, once the trunks get here.
- Well, old Mother
Necessity will find a way.
Look, you'd better
get out of here
before your passengers
have to serve themselves.
- OK, OK.
I- I'll see you tomorrow
at the new house.
- OK.
- Oh, and Marcy,
that's my best suit.
Don't put it on the
floor of the car, huh?
- All right, all
right, you know me.
I don't make any mistakes.
- Yes, I do.
Bye!
- Bye.
Now.
- Hi, how do you do?
- Good morning.
- You're new, huh?
- Yes.
- Well, I guess you'll
be wanting milk.
- Well, not right now.
Would you do something for me?
- Sure.
What?
- See the box up front?
- Yeah.
- Would you mind taking that out?
- No trouble at all.
- It's heavy.
- I'll watch them.
- Morning.
Moving in?
- Good morning.
Yes.
- I'm your new baker.
- Oh.
Well, there are going
to be four of us.
We're going to eat
a lot of bread.
- Yeah.
- Say, would you give us a hand?
- Pleasure, lady.
- Thank you.
- Marcy!
- Hi, Mike.
- I'm late.
I went down the wrong street.
- Oh, gee.
You're an angel to
come over and help.
- I think we can manage.
No neon signs?
- Whoa.
Hey, that's quite a
mansion you've got there.
- Well, Mike, what
are you doing here?
- I just flew into Boston,
ran into Jan at the airport.
She told me you were having
trouble, so here I am.
Troubleshooter
Tracy, they cal me.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
This is Mr. Lawrence, Mr. Tracy.
- Yeah?
- How do you do?
- Well, what's the problem?
- Well-
- Simple logistics.
We move these from
here to there.
For you.
- Oh.
- Careful.
That one has got glass in it.
- Yeah.
OK.
- Hey.
Got any room for a [INAUDIBLE]?
- Mike!
When did you get in?
- I got transferred
to the Mercury run.
- Why, that's wonderful.
- Hey, what are you, a
one woman moving company?
- Well, not exactly.
- Gee, you look good.
- Oh, thank you.
- Well, with Captain
Jamison on the job,
your trouble's over, ma'am.
[WHISTLING]
- Oh, thank you very much.
- Oh, not at all.
Tomorrow, the milk
will be on the house.
- Thank you.
- I'll leave a cake for you
when I come by in the morning.
- Thanks a lot.
Oh, I- I'm terribly sorry.
Mr. Lawrence, Mr.
Tracy, Captain Jamison.
- How do you do?
- Listen, Mike.
- Yes?
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): I
got the curtains up,
- Oh dear.
Maybe we'd better go inside.
- They're canning
everything these days.
Even some family
dinner, everything
from soup to dessert.
- Friend of mine cans those.
- Really?
Speaking of eating, Marcy,
I have the evening off.
I thought maybe if you
weren't busy tonight-
- Oh, I'd love to, Mike, I would.
[CRASH]
- Well, wait a minute.
I'll be right back.
- It's that tomcat again.
I told you we'd have
to get rid of him.
- Careful.
- Whoops.
- What'll the children say?
- Say, do you really
want six kids?
- Yes.
- Miss Lewis, in many ways,
you're a very remarkable girl.
Why don't we talk about
it at dinner tonight?
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Marcy!
- Um, you'd better go
back to breaking dishes.
Yeah?
Yes, this is she.
but I- there's a couple
pieces left over there,
kind of little.
- Oh, well those
are the tie backs.
Here, I'll do that myself.
Come on down, skipper.
- Oh, thanks.
Altitude was beginning
to get me anyway.
Tiebacks, huh?
- Mm-hm.
- Well, I don't know
much about that.
But there's a lot
that I do know that I
want to talk to you
about at dinner tonight.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Can I
rest for a minute, Mommy?
- Why, sure.
- Mommy?
- Oh yes.
We have s-
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Marcy!
- Yeah, Mike?
- What else goes in the kitchen?
- Well, there's one more carton
and I know just where it is.
Oh, Mike?
- Yes?
- Yeah?
- Oh dear.
This will never do, will it?
- Nuh-uh.
- Well, um, you'll be Mike,
um, Mickey, and Michael.
Mike, Mickey, and Michael.
How's that?
- Why can't he be Mickey?
- Because I'm Michael.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
- [GASPS] It couldn't be.
- What's the matter?
- I'm on 24 hour reserve.
That must be the airport.
They're the only ones
that know the number.
Hello?
Tiebacks, huh?
Oh yes.
All right.
I'll be right out.
Thank you.
I have to fly to
Dallas in 40 minutes.
[ALL OFFERING TO HELP]
- Well, I have a car
outside, thank you.
Now, let me see.
Flight bag.
What did I do with my uniform?
Talk to one another,
will you, please?
Oh, Mike.
- Yeah?
- I am Mike.
- Would you please unhitch
the trailer for me?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Well.
- I guess I'll be running along.
- Oh, you fellows have
been so wonderful.
Gee, I'm really
going to have to go
in the back door
with this uniform on.
I'll be grounded for good.
Thanks a lot, fellows.
Goodbye.
- So long.
- Keep your flaps up.
See ya'.
- Look, this interior decorating
is just a hobby with me.
- Nice seeing you.
- Yeah, likewise.
- Michael.
- I'm Mike.
- Oh, Mike.
This is wonderful.
Did you do all of
this when you were-
- How was Dallas?
- Well, the flight was
canceled because of fog.
- Oh no.
- I, um, haven't
eaten yet if you'd
still like to have dinner.
- I don't think so.
- Where are you going?
Seems all I do is mix drinks.
I'm a scientist.
- Well, I know
you're a scientist,
but what's the matter?
- Let's examine it
scientifically, huh?
- All right.
- Premise.
You needed some help.
Argument.
You got it.
- Well, I appreciate it.
- That phone call from the
airport was very convenient.
Kept things from
getting too complicated.
The coast clears and you're
back with some convenient fog.
Conclusion, I think I'll
stick to my test tubes.
- But-
- Bye.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[LAUGHING]
- Never been in a chemical
laboratory before.
- This is it.
- So this is where you work.
- Yep.
May I present Marcy
Lewis, Dr. Hardy.
- Well, this is very interesting.
You know, I didn't know-
- Would you mind turning
out the light, Marcy?
- Turning out the light?
- It has to be dark.
- Dark for what?
Now, look, Professor-
- There we are.
- Professor, what is it?
- Living bacteria.
It's called bioluminescence.
Isn't that pretty?
- It's beautiful.
Would you mind
explaining it to me?
- I wouldn't mind,
Marcy, but I don't
think you'd understand it.
- Now, don't be a smug male.
Tell me.
- Very well.
What I'm doing is an
experiment with intensity,
which varies in proportion
to the velocity of reaction
of the oxidated enzyme
sipheros accompanied
by lucipherine,
which is a substrate.
Well, I warned you.
- I must have missed something.
- All right.
Let me explain it another way.
Bioluminescence is a cold light.
- Am I interrupting anything?
- Oh, Dr. Hardy.
Come in.
- How do you do, Dr.
on your lap for five minutes,
it seems like five seconds.
- How do you do?
- I feel as though I know you.
We used your books in
my science classes.
- That's a dirty trick
to play on the young.
- Science became my
favorite subject.
- Well, you've got a pretty
fine instructor right here.
He was the guest lecturer at the
research conference in Chicago.
- He didn't tell me.
- I suppose you didn't tell her
about the Bricker Fellowship
either.
- Oh, I don't think Miss Lewis
would be interested in that.
- Oh, but I am.
- Really?
- Course she is.
The Bricker Fellowship is
awarded only once a year
to an outstanding scientist.
It's based on achievement
and character,
and this year, Mike is
one of the nominees.
- Well, that's a great honor.
- Oh, it's very
flattering, I think, too.
I- if I win, it means
a teaching job here,
and I can go on
with my experiments.
- I hope you do.
- I do, too.
- Do you think he will, Doctor?
- I'm not allowed to say.
I'm on the selection committee.
Would you like to hear
my relativity joke?
- Oh, Doctor.
- Yes, I'd love to
- All right.
- Ask me to explain the
theory of relativity.
- All right.
Will you explain the
theory of relativity?
- Well, when you're sitting
in a dentist's chair for five
minutes, it seems
like five years,
but when you're
holding a pretty girl
In that way, you become
projected into the future.
- I see.
- Oh.
When Einstein tells it,
he gets belly laughs.
- He never gives
up on that story.
- Well someday, you'll see.
- You bet.
Someday, it'll be one of
the school traditions,
talk about Dr. Hardy's
relatively joke.
- You love all of
this, don't you, Mike?
- You mean the lab?
- The lab, the campus, your work.
It shows in your face.
- It does?
- Mm-hm.
- I'm afraid I'm just
a teacher at heart.
- Well, that's wonderful.
- Now you're being polite.
- No, I'm not.
- You mention the word
"teacher" to anybody,
and right away, they think
of a little, underpaid absent
minded Mr. Chips character
wearing an alpaca jacket
and surrounded by dusty books.
They don't understand, but
teaching is just about as close
to immortality as you can come.
You know, in every
class that you teach,
someone will remember
something you say,
and because of it, his life
will be changed a little,
and he'll changed
someone else's life.
- Learned about bioluminescence.
I'm lecturing, and you're
not even registered.
- I'm registered, Mike.
My mother was a teacher.
- Really I didn't know that?
- Mm-hm.
You'd like mother.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN):
Oh, I'm sure I would.
You're not at all like
I thought you'd be.
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): I'm not?
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Uh-uh.
Not at all.
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): I was brought
up in a little college town.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Really?
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): Mm-hm.
I love this life.
Some people think it's
sheltered and unimportant.
- Oh no.
- It's terribly important.
- I think so too.
- And very exciting.
- Mm-hm.
- Mike?
- What?
- I'm so glad we met.
- So am I. Well,
if you don't mind,
Doctor- oh, I guess he doesn't.
- How was your date last night?
- Oh, we had fun.
He's a very
remarkable young man.
- What did you do?
- You want some coffee?
- Mm-hm.
- What'd you do last night?
- Yes.
- Oh.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
- I'll get it.
- Do you want some coffee, Jan?
- Mm-hm, please.
- JAN (OFFSCREEN): Hello?
Oh, yes.
That's it.
- It's Mike.
- Hm?
- Oh.
Thanks.
- Did you hear what she
learned last night?
- Good morning, professor.
How are all the test tubes?
Oh, Mickey.
Well, how are you?
Um, what happened?
Well, I didn't-
- Shh.
- All right.
I'll come down this afternoon.
All right, I'll come
down right away.
All right.
Goodbye.
- I seem to be in trouble again.
- What did you do?
- He didn't say, but I did it.
Hm.
Oh, take this upstairs.
Worry myself to death sometimes.
- You know, maybe she shouldn't
have learned about bi-
- Alice, finish your breakfast.
- I can't eat.
Honey, I spent 30
minutes on the phone
- Miss Lewis, Mr. Tracy.
- Hello, Marcy.
This is Mr. Tanner, Mr. Osgood.
- How do you do?
- Mr. Parker, our
photographer, Mr. Hamilton,
head of our art department.
- How do you do?
- Gentlemen, this is
our little Marcy.
Won't you sit right
down over here?
- We've certainly got to
hand it to you, Miss Lewis.
- You do?
- It's all right, Marcy.
We know all about it.
We've heard from Bellemy.
- Oh, how is he?
- He's fine, like a kid,
full of enthusiasm.
He's got the greatest
advertising campaign
in the history of
his company lined up.
- Well, that's wonderful, Mike.
Is it yours?
- No, yours.
- Mine?
- Didn't you write him
a letter giving him
an idea for gardenia soap?
- Oh, yes.
Remember that night we
were dancing in Chicago,
you told me to write him a note?
- Uh-huh.
- Well, I did.
- You did?
- Mm-hm.
Did he like it?
- He's insane about it, and I
use the word "insane" advisedly.
He's talking bonuses.
- CJ, don't let's
forget to call Bellemy.
this morning listening to
him rave about this idea,
and I don't even
know what it's about.
- Well, it's a wonderful idea.
- It is?
- Um, Miss Lewis, could you be
a little bit more specific?
- Well, of course.
- That would be nice.
- Well, the idea is this.
You've seen pictures of
actresses, socialites,
and athletes endorsing
different things,
and I was thinking, why
not airline stewardesses?
I know people are
interested in us
because they're always
asking me about our work,
and if you use pictures
of airline stewardesses
all over the world, it
would tie in with the idea
that Gardenia soap is the
same under all conditions.
You like it?
- Like it?
Like it?
Honey, I think it's great.
It's just great.
- It's fine.
- Osgood, I want you to
get an exclusive tie-up
with the airline.
We're going to use 24
sheets all over the country.
- Right.
- Hamilton, give me a layout for
a series of radio commercials.
Use the marriage angle.
Airline stewardesses
have gotten married.
- Oh, but they don't fly
after they're married.
- Then strike the marriage angle.
We'll keep them single.
- Mike!
- Yes, good idea.
- Parker, I want you to
use a different stewardess
for every layout.
We'll make it a Gardenia
girl of the month.
get your girls to
start shooting art.
We could use backgrounds
all over the world,
but wherever they are,
they're using Gardenia soap.
Got it?
- Got it.
One thing.
- Yeah?
- Who's going to be our
first Gardenia girl?
[CHUCKLES]
PHOTOGRAPHER (OFFSCREEN):
All right now, Marcy.
Hold it.
Good.
One second now, Marcy.
Got it.
Hold it.
Ah, that's good.
Now let's have one
for the road, huh?
You can relax a second.
- I'm comfortable.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- Come in.
- Hi, kids.
How's it going?
- Hello, Mike.
Just finished.
There you go.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Got it?
- All right.
- You know, this is fun.
- Well, this should
make it even more fun.
All of that for me?
- All for you.
Say, um, how about having
dinner with me tonight?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I have to take a flight out.
- Oh.
- Ooh, and I'd better
get my clothes changed.
- All right.
I'll see you as soon
as you get back.
You and I are due
for a long talk.
- American Airlines Flight
455 calling Douglas
to request weather.
MAN (ON RADIO):
American Flight 455.
This is Douglas Radio.
Tucson, thunderstorm
overhead moving east.
Douglas overcast,
visibility five miles.
- American Airlines
Flight 455 off.
- Coffee time.
- We're setting down at Douglas.
- Two sugars.
That's your- you can't do that.
I've got a dinner
date in Los Angeles.
- Now, ain't that too bad.
Better get your
passengers ready.
- And don't give him any.
but, um, I guess I
can accommodate you.
- Well, the passengers
are all taken care of.
The bus just took
them into town.
- I just checked with the hotel.
They've got room enough
for them, but that's all.
I'm afraid the crew
will have to sleep here.
I've got a cot back there that
you're welcome to use, Miss.
- Well, thanks anyway.
I'll stick with the troops.
- Um, you mean to tell me that's
the only hotel around here?
- Well, there's the Adobe
Inn, but that's no good.
They're closed for the season.
- Well.
- Wait a minute.
Old Hawkins is still there.
Oh, I forgot.
Phone's shut off.
If you want to take a
chance, my car's outside.
- What do you say?
- It's fine with me.
- Well, let's pick up Benson.
We'll go around,
take a look at it.
- All right.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
See you later.
MAN (OFFSCREEN) All right,
all right, I'm coming.
Hold your horses.
- We're sorry to intrude
on you like this,
but, um, our plane ran
into a little weather.
- Well, the hotel is
officially closed up,
I, um- I'd better go get
started on your rooms.
You folks, um, want a room?
- Two rooms.
- Well, shouldn't be
any trouble. [CHUCKLES]
You have 50 rooms
to choose from.
Come on in.
- Thank you.
- Flyers, eh?
- Yeah.
- I'll, um- I'll have to
pick you up some fresh linen.
- Um, could we get
something to eat?
- Oh.
Oh, I don't how.
Um, I won't even
eat my own cooking,
and I ain't very particular.
- Have you got any food?
- Oh sure, lady, we've got food.
- Well, if you show
me the kitchen,
I'll fix you something.
- Oh, I- I love to eat.
Come right this way.
- Hey, she cooks.
- Well.
- Some more coffee, Benson?
- Mm.
I've had it.
My compliments to the chef.
- Thank you.
- I better check on the weather.
- It's a good idea.
- Can I get you
anything, Mr. Hawkins?
- Oh, no thank you.
I- I couldn't eat another bite.
- See you.
- You know, that's
the best meal I've
had since the hotel closed up.
Now- now you leave
everything right here,
and I'll- I'll clean
it up in the morning.
My old man found out about it
and whaled the tar out of me,
- It's a nice old guy.
- Yeah.
There are only
two pancakes left.
Surely you can eat them.
- Oh no, no, no.
Gosh, I thought cooking
like this was a lost art.
- I love to cook.
- Ah, this is nice.
Do you realize
we've never really
had a chance to
talk alone before?
- I know.
I can remember the
time when you weren't
very anxious to talk to me.
[CHUCKLES]
- Remember the first day
when I gave you a lift?
- When I forgot the lunches?
- Oh.
- I still can't figure out why
you didn't let them fire me.
- Well, it was something
you said in the car.
- Something I said?
- Mm-hm, that first day.
- About pilots being chauffeurs?
- Oh no, no.
No, about not really being
alive unless you're in the air.
- Oh.
- I've felt that way
ever since I was a kid.
- How long have you
been flying, Mike?
- Mm, I took my first flying
lesson when I was about 15.
- Really?
- Mm-hm, an old crate with wings.
but it was too late.
I think you're
running to something.
- Why?
- Well, I got hung up on a cloud.
I ran away from home and
joined an air circus,
barnstormed all
over the country.
Had my own airline for awhile.
- You didn't?
- Yeah.
- I just had one airplane
and two engines.
Then the war came
along and I joined up.
You know, most people get
tired of traveling around,
but traveling affects me
like- like some people are
affected by money.
The more I get, the more I want.
- I know.
- Sure you do, but a
lot of people don't.
- You know, you and
I are alike, Marcy.
We both come from small towns
where people live and die
and never travel any farther
than the corner barber shop.
That can never satisfy me.
People at home don't
seem to understand.
They seem to think I'm
running away from something.
- Oh, I don't think
you're running away
from anything, Mike.
Now what did I do?
- Hey, that's it.
Exactly.
You know, Marcy, this is a
great, big world we live in,
filled with many languages,
and I want to hear all of them
before I die.
I want to meet as
many people as I can
and find out what makes them
tick, what they talk about
and what they think about.
I don't want to miss anything.
- That's the way I feel, Mike.
- Hi, Joe.
- Someone in the
office to see you.
- Who?
- Only CR Smith,
president of the airline.
- CR?
- I've arranged for you
to get a nice bonus, see?
Well, thanks, Joe.
[ANNOUNCER SPEAKING SPANISH]
- These are good.
Have you seen them?
- Yes, fine.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- Come in.
- Hi.
- Hello, Marcy.
- Hello, Mike, Mike,
Mr. [INAUDIBLE].
- This is CR Smith, your boss.
Marcy Lewis.
- Hello.
- How do you do, sir?
- Miss Lewis, I'd
like you to explain
why I pay a high price public
relations department to do
a job that you've knocked
off in your spare time.
This campaign of yours is great.
Sensational, I
think is the word.
- That's the word, all right.
- You like it?
- He's crazy about it.
- It's the biggest
thing that's happened
to us since the
reversible propeller.
- Here, Marcy.
Wait 'til you get a
look at these pictures.
Aren't they just wonderful?
- Oh, there's one shot of
you that I'm crazy about.
[CHATTERING]
- Oh, Mark, these are wonderful.
- Look what I had to work with.
and wanting to.
- A bonus?
- Uh-huh.
- Oh, thank you.
- Now, how would you like
to spend some of that bonus
on a fellow who hasn't
got a thing to do tonight?
- I'd like it.
- You're all welcome
to join us, of course.
- I'd love to.
Oh, I forgot.
I've got another appointment.
- Isn't that too bad?
Thank you, men.
We'll see you all later.
Come on.
- Marcy, will you
tell me something?
- What?
- What are you doing
as a stewardess?
- I like it, Mike.
- Oh sure, it's great, but not
for the rest of your life.
- I hadn't planned on being the
oldest stewardess in the world.
- You are a most surprising girl.
Does anybody ever
remember to tell you that?
You don't fall into any of
the ordinary layout patterns.
You're wonderful to look at.
In advertising, that's impact.
Most read, that's
having you in sight.
Most remembered, that's
not having you in sight
- Mr. Bellamy, would you
excuse me for a moment?
Marcy, you know, I think you'd
like the kind of a life I live.
It's almost like another
world, the constant excitement
of seeing your ideas
come alive and start
all kinds of wheels
moving all over the earth.
You get an idea today,
and tomorrow, it
influences millions of
people you'll never even see,
people in South America,
Bombay, England.
There's nothing to
match it, Marcy.
- You make it sound
so wonderful, Mike.
- More wine?
[CHATTERING]
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): Yeah?
- Certainly.
- Dr. Hardy, you're not
having a good time,
and I don't think you
know Captain Jamison.
- How do you sir?
- Captain.
- Now sit down.
Be comfortable.
- I'm having a
particularly good time.
I'm supposed to be
at a faculty dinner.
Mike and I have just
finished our experiments
in bioluminescence.
- Really?
- Yes.
- What?
- Bioluminescence.
- That's the emission of
light from living organisms.
- Oh, I see.
- Well.
- Pardon, pardon, pardon.
- Must be very interesting,
being a pilot.
- Oh, we get around.
I don't like to be
tied down, myself.
That's for the kiwis.
- The what?
- Oh, that's what we
call the stewardesses
when they get married
and can't fly anymore.
It's named after an
almost extinct bird
in New Zealand that can't fly.
Oh, Mr. Osgood, have
you met everyone?
- Yes, I believe I have.
Say, this is quite a party.
Real impact.
- That's an advertising phrase.
It means balanced eye appeal.
Oh, the cheese.
I'll be right back.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
- Hello?
Oh, yeah, just a minute.
Marcy!
- He said he needed an extra
picture tonight to send east.
- Telephone.
All right.
Don't get up, Doctor.
Hello?
Yes.
Oh, no, Mack.
Well, we're having a- oh.
All right.
I'll be down in 20 minutes.
Goodbye.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have to leave
for a few minutes.
- What's wrong?
- That was Mike
Tracy's photographer.
He needs one more picture to
airmail to the east tonight.
I'll only be a few minutes.
- I'll drive you to-
- Now, look, you to stay
and enjoy the party.
I'll slip out the back way.
Goodbye, Doctor.
- Goodbye.
- Kind of a funny time to be
taking pictures, isn't it?
- I don't like it either.
- Where'd you put my briefcase?
- Oh, it's upstairs-
- Where's Tracy?
- You don't think that-
- I wouldn't put it past him.
- Hem um-
- Evening, Mickey.
- I'm Michael.
You're Mickey.
- Forgive me, Michael.
Evening, Mike.
- How are you?
- Where's Marcy?
- Don't you know?
- Should I know?
- Didn't you tell
your photographer
to call her to work tonight?
- Parker?
Did he call her?
- Yeah.
- I'll bet he did.
- Don't you trust him?
- I wouldn't trust him
with Whistler's mother.
- Oh you wouldn't, huh?
- No.
- No?
- Hm.
- Fix you a little drink, Marcy?
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): No thanks.
- Not even just a
little teeny one?
MARCY (OFFSCREEN): No.
Don't know why I
have to wear this.
All the other pictures
were taken in uniform.
- Yeah, I know.
That's why I thought we'd add
something different you know?
A little variety.
- Yeah, different,
what there is of it.
- Wowie.
You look great.
- But will I sell soap?
- Honey, you could sell mud.
Anybody ever tell
you that you're
a very unusual girl, Marcy?
- Look, Mack, if you're
in a romantic mood,
go to the movies.
I've got a house full of
people waiting for me.
Now where do you want me?
- Ah, ah, ah, take it easy.
- I, um, have known a
lot of girls in my day,
Marcy, but when I tell you-
- Are you sure you asked me
down here to take pictures?
[DOORBELL BUZZING]
- Well now why don't you
sit down here and relax?
I've got a couple lights
out- - Your doorbell.
[DOORBELL BUZZING]
- Yeah.
Just about one second.
I'll set this-
- There's somebody
at the door, Mack.
[DOORBELL BUZZING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
- Wait here.
- Yeah?
- What's the matter, buddy?
Marcy!
What are you do- come
on, get your clothes on.
I'm getting you out of here.
- Why did you hit him?
- What did you expect?
- Oh, you're just about that.
You're one of the primitives.
- Marcy, what are you doing?
- I'm taking pictures.
[ARGUING]
- I'll remedy that right now.
Come on, Marcy, I'm
taking you home.
- Listen, I'm not-
- Now, look.
I don't want to fight.
- I'll bet you don't.
The phone's been
ringing all morning.
- Why should I?
- Fellas, now stop it.
You stop it!
- Because I did a little
boxing at college.
- Come on, get on your feet.
- Marcy, I'm taking you home.
- Oh you are, huh?
MARCY (OFFSCREEN):
Mike, stop it.
You're going to hurt- Mike!
Oh.
Look out for the props!
You'll have the whole
neighborhood in here
if you don't behave yourselves.
Mike, you lean on me
and I'll take you up.
If you two don't stop it,
I'll never talk to you again.
- I thought so.
You let go of her.
- Oh no!
- Look at you.
Where are your clothes?
- What did you have
to hit him for?
I was just bringing
him to- Mack.
- I'm going to get
you out of here.
- Mack, come on.
- Is this your coat?
MARCY (OFFSCREEN):
Yes, and see if you
can't stop these-
stop it, fellas.
Now stop it.
Stop it!
WOMAN (OFFSCREEN):
Photographer's studio scene
of Sunset Strip brawl.
Hm.
- Well, this ought to sell
a lot of Gardenia soap.
- Boy, what a brawl.
- How can you joke about this?
wouldn't have gone down
there in the first place,
Mike Lawrence has
been disqualified
for his fellowship, Mike
Jamison has been grounded,
and Mike Tracy lost
the Bellamy account
and I've been suspended.
- I'd say you've had a busy day.
- But honey, worrying about
it isn't going to help.
- I'd just like to unscramble it.
- Darling, if you don't
mind a suggestion,
why don't you let them all alone
before you get them all hanged?
- Hm.
- Anyway, one good thing's
come out of all this.
- What?
- Roger saw the
paper this morning.
He's informed me that we're
to be married right away.
- Oh, he woke up.
- I'm glad that's settled.
- That's wonderful.
- Oh, I'm so happy for you, Jan.
Just great.
- Anybody want some more coffee?
- Mm.
- Alice?
Hold your cups up, please.
Kathy?
KATHY (OFFSCREEN):
Mm-hm, a little.
JAN (OFFSCREEN):
How's the toast?
- I realize the fellowship
depends partly on character,
but Mike has one of the finest
characters I've ever known,
Dr. Hardy, and that's
what makes me feel so bad.
If he didn't care
about people, he
I issued the order myself.
and he wouldn't be
in all this trouble.
If he didn't care about people,
what kind of a scientist
would he make?
Why would he want to
devote his entire life
to working and teaching to
make life easier for all of us?
Please, don't take this
opportunity away from him.
It wasn't his fault.
He had no idea
this would happen.
It isn't fair for you to
take your account away
from Mike because of this.
He's impulsive.
That's what makes him a creator.
If it weren't for that,
he wouldn't get ideas
like the Gardenia
girl campaign, which
is still great advertising.
I don't have to tell
you how lucky you
are to have a man like
Mike working for you.
Look at his record.
You can't dismiss that.
Mr. Smith, Mike Jamison
is the best pilot
you have for the simple
reason that flying
is the most important
thing in his life.
If he weren't adventurous
and courageous, he-
he just wouldn't be
Captain Mike Jamison.
- This used to be such a quiet
business before you came along,
Marcy.
- I'm on suspension.
- I know.
- This is important.
It's none of my
business, but, um,
what were you doing
in that sarong?
- Posing for the Gardenia ad.
- Oh, I wondered.
- Then the I started
and I had to-
- Yes, I read the rest of it.
Look, if you can find something
a little less colorful to wear,
like our regulation
uniform, you and Mike
can go back to,
um, cloud hopping.
- Um, what do you mean
by cloud hopping?
- Well, that's up to Marcy.
- Oh, she- she and Mike
were getting along very well
on the ground.
- No, that's not what she needs.
She needs a guy like Mike
who's creative, impulsive.
She told me so herself.
- Mr. Bellamy, you
just heard Miss Lewis.
She admires a man of courage.
- Oh no, she admires
a man of character.
- Now, wait a minute.
[ARGUING]
- I have to disagree with you.
- Gentlemen.
- She needs a pioneering spirit,
a man who will direct her-
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
American Airlines Flight
Four, the Mercury, for
Chicago and New York
now boarding at American-
- Hey, Marcy.
- Hi, Mike.
- Oh, now wait a minute.
- No, I want to talk to you.
- I've got to get aboard.
I-
- Mike, I have to leave.
- Look, not until
I've talked to you.
- That's my flight.
- Look, Marcy.
I- I don't know how
to say this, but-
- Marcy!
Marcy, I- I've got
to talk to you alone.
Excuse us, please.
- Now just a minute.
- Look, I've got to say
this before you leave.
- If you don't mind.
- Jan told me you were leaving.
- I am.
- This is important.
- Well, I'm- I'm
glad I got here.
- Well, I have-
- Look, Marcy.
I never thought I'd have to
propose in front of a crowd,
but Marcy, will you marry me?
- Oh, Mike.
Remember what we said about
the world being filled
with wonderful people
talking strange languages?
We could listen
to them together.
We've got the whole
world to fly around in.
We could be awfully
happy, Marcy.
I-
- Marcy.
Marcy, that's wrong for you.
You and I are not
going to watch history.
We're going to make it.
It's ideas that move
the world, Marcy.
That's what your excitement
is, the same as mine.
Besides, those six
kids need a father.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): Marcy!
- Yes, Mike?
- He lights up.
- There's not much
more I can say.
All this sounds
pretty wonderful.
- Then why are you here, Mike?
- Because I love you.
Oh, Marcy.
You don't have to say anything.
Being married to
a teacher wouldn't
be very exciting, and-
- Oh, you're going
to be surprised.
- What?
- Hello, Mr. Chips.
- Mr. Chips?
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN): Final
call, American Airlines Flight
Four, the Mercury, now
boarding at American Airlines-
- That's us.
- What's us?
- We have to go.
- Where are we going?
ANNOUNCER (OFFSCREEN):
All aboard flight-
- Oh, Mike.
Mike.
- Are you sure, Marcy?
- Oh yes.
It's simple bioluminescence.
- It's what?
- Lights up?
- Goodbye.
- So long.
- Bye, Marcy.
- Marcy, here's your
clearance slip.
Hey, that's an extra passenger.
- He's with me.
- I'm with her.
- Hey Marcy, you can't do that.
It's against the rules.
Marcy!
She can't do that.
It's against the rules.
- Rules weren't made for Marcy.
- They sure weren't.
- Well, we got each other.
- Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
that you have to
be your own boss
- and I have repeat
customers all year round.
My gross sales for a whole
year were close to $300,000.
SMC definitely changed my life.
I feel free.
I don't have to
work for somebody.
I don't have that pressure.
I make a lot of
money and I find out
to help you succeed.
and go out there and have fun.
I feel really good about that.
- SMC gives you the
best of all worlds.
You can start a business of your
own, part time or full time,
from the comfort of your home
or office or retail outlet,
or at festivals and swap meets
with an initial investment
as low as $25 or less.
Best of all, it's your business,
but it's awfully comforting
to know you don't
have to go it alone,
that you have the full
support and resources
of a multi-million
dollar company
with more than 50 years of
experience helping people
like you start
their own business.
- I think anybody
going into business
for the first time needs help.
More than anything
else, they need help,
and SMC is committed to giving
them all the help that we can.
So we give you a
personal business coach
for your first 60 days,
and it's that coach's job
I mean, there were no
income coming any place,
They're going to help you figure
out what the best marketing
program is for you, they're
going to help you figure out
which products you
should be selling,
how much you should charge.
Their job is to make sure
that in your first 60 days,
you're putting money
in your pocket.
A lot of people who have
been really successful at SMC
have never sold anything
before in their life.
In fact, they'll tell
you that they still
don't know how to sell, and
yet they're selling every day.
It's because
really, they tell me
the products sell themselves.
They just show their catalogs
or they show their samples,
and they get orders.
There's really not a
lot of selling involved.
Plus, we have marketing programs
that run the gamut from swap
meets and flea markets
to internet sales,
mail order sales,
where you might never,
ever meet any of your customers.
I think it's everybody's
dream to be able to make money
at home, have time to
spend with the family,
really have control
of your life,
and SMC has really allowed a lot
of our members to do just that.
- I worked 27 years
for this company
and had the rug pulled
out from under us.
The whole plant went down.
- SMC shows you nearly
a dozen different ways
so I just thought it
would be good to help
my wife in her business, then.
- Our goal became to
survive, but the coffee shop
wasn't going to
make enough money.
You just can't sell
enough cups of coffee
to support two people.
- Anyway, I contacted
SMC, and that's
how we got into the business.
- With SMC, the amount
that we put into it,
we saw it come back quickly.
Sold a few items, saw that
money come back, now we
have more cash, put it out
again, and we're making money.
The customers love the
quality, and they always
comment on our prices,
how good the prices are,
and they keep coming
back very often.
- It's not hard to
sell SMC because there
is such a great variety
of items that they offer
and it's good quality.
The merchandise sells itself.
SMC was a great
thing to get into.
I love my job.
to make money with
small business,
You can order in huge
quantities or as little as-
each detailed with step
by step instructions.
They support you
with rock bottom,
below wholesale prices on
more than 3,000 high profit,
high demand products selected
by an expert buying team.
Take this charming
birdhouse, for example,
with a delightful
Noah's Ark design that
welcomes all feathered
friends aboard.
This high demand item
retails for $24.95,
but your cost with
SMC is only $8.30.
That's a profit of more than
$16 on every one you sell.
Another hot selling item is
this high quality tool set,
135 piece handyman's
helper, and a must for every
fix it project around the house.
It'll help you build
up profits too,
because it retails for $69.95,
but your cost is just $23.30.
So with a margin
of over $46, you
triple your money with each one.
SMC prices are so
low, many members
earn a nice income by
simply providing products
to other wholesalers.