Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes
You're awfully quiet tonight, Janie.
I've been trying to think
of just the right way
to ask you to turn around
and go back.
On this road?
Can't do it, sweetie.
I mean it, Allen.
I'd like you to turn around, please.
What's the matter, Jane?
I tried to tell you before
we left home...
I just don't like being patronized,
that's all.
I don't think I could take
another evening of it.
Patronized? Oh, sweetheart,
Ralph is one of the nicest guys...
You know it isn't Ralph.
It's his diamond studded wife.
Looking down her nose at me
like a big ugly house up there
looks down on Hollywood.
Please, I'm just not going.
Slow down and find a place to turn.
Oh, Jane, you're crazy.
Alice likes you.
Please, Alan, I mean it.
I'm just not going.
What are you trying to do?
Send us off the edge?
All right, we'll turn around.
I told them we'd be there
but we'll turn around.
That guy almost hit us.
Alan, he threw something.
It's in the back.
- Feels like there's paper in it.
-  Paper?
Yeah, feels like it.
Open it!
- They threw it in?
- Yes.
- Maybe it fell in.
- Alan, open it.
Quick, Alan, get in!
Alan, get in!
He's after us, Jane.
The bag was intended for him.
Jane, what are you trying to do?
We've lost him.
Slow down, I'll take the wheel.
You almost killed us doing it
but we got away from him.
Now what happens?
Hasn't it hit you yet, Alan?
The money was literally
thrown in our laps.
No one in the world knows we have it.
Get a hold of yourself, Jane,
will you? It's a bag of dynamite.
That was a payoff.
Probably blackmail.
We'll turn that bag over
to the police or the...
Don't stop, Alan.
He's almost a block behind.
- What are you two so scared about?
- Who's scared?
You are. Didn't you ever
get a ticket before?
It's supposed to be
a big secret, officer.
But we're on our way
to Las Vegas.
We're the old-fashioned kind.
We're eloping.
You're still gonna get a ticket.
The next time
you make a turn, signal.
You think you can remember that?
I'm afraid my mind
wasn't on my driving.
You're nervous, Mac.
It's the bride
that's supposed to be jittery.
Get going.
All right.
What's the matter with you, Jane?
What were you planning
on doing with that?
I...
I don't know.
You had a chance to give up
the money. Why didn't you take it?
I was just asking myself
that same question.
We'll take it up to the apartment.
I wanna look at it.
I don't see him, Alan.
What about Kathy?
I wonder if she came home yet.
I think she went to a show.
Hurry.
Just call me Dracula.
I'm afraid you did startle us a little.
- Did my sister come in yet, Pete?
- No, I don't think so.
Hey, uh...
You folks been away?
Oh, no. Just some things
Mr. Palmer had in storage.
- Did you lock the door?
- Yes.
Well, that wasn't very smart.
It'd be a great time for Cathy
or someone to come in, now, wouldn't it?
You said you wanted
to look at it, Alan.
Look at it.
Fifties and twenties.
There must be thousands here.
Probably a hundred thousand.
It's a lot of money.
The numbers are different.
You could make it work for us
for the rest of our lives.
Stop, Janie. If we don't report this,
it's a felony.
The same as stealing.
It's a blind alley.
With a big barred gate at the end.
Let's not try to use it, darling.
Let's just hide it some place.
And then not touch it
till we know it's safe.
It'll never be safe.
It just won't work.
What is it, Jane?
I just don't understand you.
I've tried to give you
everything you wanted.
Everything I could.
Yes. You've given me a dozen
down payments and installments
for the rest of our lives.
We won't touch it, Alan.
We'll simply leave it where we...
Hide it.
Hide it quick.
- Hi.
- Hello, Kathy.
Pete said you were asking about me.
Oh, yes. Alan was wondering
if you were home.
Well, I am. And since you're twisting
my arm, I'll come in.
- Where's my dear brother?
- Oh, he'll be out in a moment.
How are things at the office?
Well, they gave my boss
a promotion the other day.
Maybe they'll get around
to giving me a raise later.
You sound as if you're going to make
a life's work out of it.
You sound as if you haven't heard
of the man shortage.
On second thought,
maybe you haven't.
- Greetings, Kathy.
- Hi.
How are you?
Well, don't say fine,
'cause you look awful.
That's why I love to come here.
Everyone's so gay, so voyante.
I did get the impression from Pete
that you wanted to see me
about something.
Oh, we were thinking of running up
to La Mole's for a snack but...
we've changed our minds.
Alan doesn't feel well.
What is it, Alan?
Oh, nothing.
It's just a headache.
Well, I hope you both
feel better in the morning.
Good night.
- Good night, Jane.
- Good night, Kathy.
That did it.
I ought to have my head examined.
I was almost sold for a minute.
We've got as much right to that money
as if we went into a bank
and lifted a bagful off the counter.
My little sister drops in
and pays us a visit.
Scares us to death.
Of course we were frightened,
because the money's right here.
But once it's hidden
and out of our hands,
there's nothing to be afraid of.
- Nobody knows we have it...
- Nobody knows?
How about that banshee
that chased us down the mountainside?
If he can read,
he's got our license number.
He wasn't close enough
to see our license.
Listen to me, Alan.
I love you, darling.
And if you decide we should never
touch the money,
we won't.
But do we have
to make up our minds now?
Can't we just hide it some place
where it can't be traced to us and...
give ourselves time
to think it out?
Please, help me hide it.
I'll leave the rest to you.
If you don't think
we should ever touch it...
we won't.
You mean that, Jane?
There'll be no more talk about it.
No bitterness.
I mean it, Alan.
We'll keep it a week.
Last call.
passengers to San Bernardino,
train number 42 leaves at 10:10...
entering through gate F.
This is the last call.
The Union Pacific, City of Los Angeles,
train 103,
is now arriving.
It's done.
Everything's all right now.
- Isn't it, darling?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Where is the ticket?
It's all right.
It's here down in the lining.
There's a hole in the pocket.
It's safe there.
What did you say
to the man at the counter?
I didn't say anything
You did. I saw you.
Oh, yes.
I told him I was going to the hospital
and wouldn't be picking up the bag
for awhile.
He said it was all right.
Fuller, Detective Bureau.
Yes?
Does an Alan Palmer live here?
Yes, my husband. He's at work.
Well, this is just a routine check,
Mrs. Palmer.
We have a license number but we're not
absolutely sure of the accuracy of it.
May I come in?
Mind if I look around a bit?
Why?
You haven't anything to hide,
have you?
No, I can see you haven't.
What's this all about, Mr. Fuller?
I told you. Routine check.
I'd like to look your place over.
Looking for what?
I didn't bring a warrant with me,
Mrs. Palmer.
Maybe I should go get one.
If I let you look around without one,
will you promise to tell me
what it's all about?
Perhaps it'll give me something interesting
to talk about at bridge tonight.
Sure, Mrs. Palmer.
Thanks.
Leave them alone!
Those are presents.
So you've already started
spending it, huh?
- Spending it?
- Yes, honey, spending it.
I don't think I like that.
I'm sorry, but you're not making sense.
If you were an innocent housewife
with nothing to hide but the iceman,
you'd never let me in here.
You'd have been screaming
for that warrant.
sending a wire to your congressman,
so let's cut the small talk.
Where's my dough?
- Then you're not a policeman.
- Only on my mother's side, honey.
Where's the dough?
Those things in my kitchen
happen to belong to my sister-in-law.
And I let you in because...
Well...
housewives can get awfully
bored sometimes.
But believe me, I've no idea
what you're talking about.
You're too smooth, honey.
You're much too smooth.
Where's the dough?
Where's that money?
What did you do with it?
- We sent it to the police.
- You're a liar.
You would have told me that
before now.
- I was afraid to.
- You should be. It was mine.
Why would anyone give up
that much hard cash?
I don't get it.
- In fact I don't believe it.
- It's the truth, I swear it is.
And I'm supposed to get up now
and walk out, is that it?
Well, maybe I will.
If you turned that money over
to the cops it'll be in the papers.
- If you didn't...
- It will be...
we sent it back last evening.
All right.
I can wait a few more hours.
And I doubt that you or your husband
will cry copper.
I'm gonna buy an evening paper.
And there'd better be something in it
about money or I'll be around again.
And I'm afraid I'll be awfully
peeved at you, honey.
Bye, now.
Alan, you're home early.
FitzSimmons called me
from the bank today.
It seems as if your checks
have started coming through.
He thought I might like to know
that our accounts
are down to a couple of hundred dollars.
I was going to tell you tonight.
They were things I needed, Alan.
$580.00 worth of necessities?
That was yesterday.
How much today?
How much have you spent altogether?
$790.00.
About one tenth of one percent
of the money we have.
You're counting the money in the bag.
We aren't going to touch it.
Just leave it there and forget about it.
Now you're spending it like mad
and keeping books on it.
Because the money's ours.
If anyone knew we had it
they would have been around by now.
I'm sending the claim check to
the district attorney's office right now.
- Tonight.
- Don't I have something to say about that?
I won't let you do it.
I'll take the money and go off
by myself before I let you give it away.
And that's something
I won't let you do.
I'm in this now.
If you're caught, I'm caught.
But I wouldn't want you
to do it anyway, Jane.
The money won't buy you anything.
It'll only make you miserable and unhappy.
Let me be the judge of that.
Were you happy
when you married Blanchard?
I'm sorry, Jane.
I didn't mean that.
Jane, Jane, what's happening to us?
What's happening?
The money sits down there
in an old leather bag...
and yet it's tearing us apart.
It's poison, Jane. It's changing you,
it's changing both of us.
I wish it were that simple, Alan.
But I haven't changed.
It's the way I am.
You've got to let me keep
that money.
- Don't, don't, Jane...
- No, Alan.
I won't let you just give it away.
Chances like this
are never offered twice
This is it. I've been waiting for it,
dreaming of it all my life.
Even when I was a kid.
And it wasn't because we were poor.
Not hungry poor at least.
I suppose in a way it was far worse.
We were white-collar poor,
middle-class poor.
The kind of people who can't
quite keep up with the Joneses
and die a little every day
because they can't.
That's why I married Blanchard.
I married the first man who asked me
because I thought he had money.
It's true, Alan.
And you're right.
I wasn't happy.
- I was almost glad when...
- Jane!
But...
things have changed now, Allan.
This is different.
We'll be happier than we ever dreamed
we could be.
Sure we will, Jane.
But the money won't help.
There'll always be Joneses
with a little more.
The only thing worth having
is peace of mind.
And money can't buy that.
But...
You agreed to wait for one week.
All right, we'll wait.
But we're not going to keep it.
It's almost wrecked us, sweetheart.
But I figure it'll take more
than a hundred grand to do that.
How about it, hm?
I got an idea.
We'll go on a date.
Not tonight. I've got to see
old man Baird tonight.
But tomorrow night we'll do
the same things
we did on our first date, remember?
We'll have dinner at La Mole...
then we'll go down to the lake
and get one of those fancy little boats
and go for a ride.
How about it?
Is it a date?
It's a date, Alan.
You got a good lock.
I don't usually have so much trouble.
Did you think of knocking?
Yeah. But then I thought
about the dull reading
I found in the newspaper.
Nothing at all about a bag
full of dough
turning up at Police Headquarters.
Would you care for a drink,
Mr. Fuller?
You know, honey,
you got quite a flare.
I like you.
Too bad you're a chiseler.
At the risk of seeing me
peeved at you,
just where did you stash my cash?
You didn't tell me
if you wanted that drink.
where you put my dough.
I don't have your dough.
- Let us not haggle.
- We're not going to.
My husband has the money
and two days from now
he's going to turn it over to the police.
You don't tell me!
Nice story.
Better than yesterday.
I like that trick with your eyes too.
I'm just taking my cue
like a little gentleman.
- You're taking it a little too fast
- Isn't that what you wanted?
Did you notice where the liquor was
when you went through my kitchen?
- Sure.
- Go make us a drink.
Stalling, honey?
What do I call you besides stupid?
Stupid will do
if you don't bruise easily.
Otherwise you might try Danny.
If you're not stalling, get to the point.
What's on that lovely blond mind?
I told you. My husband is going
to give the money up.
- I don't intend to let him give it up.
- Neither do I.
I swear if you go near him
neither one of us will ever see a cent of it.
I'll take my chances.
I'm telling you the truth now.
You won't be able to beat it out of him
or scare it out of him.
If I told him you were here yesterday,
the police would have the money now.
And I don't think I could take it
if I lost it.
Let's get something straight, honey.
That's my dough you're talking about.
Only half of it.
You haven't a chance of getting it
without my help.
And how do you get it?
I don't know.
I'll work out something.
I have to.
When I think of losing it
I get deadly sick inside.
You know?
I think you're leveling with me.
Maybe I'll string along.
I'll think it over.
I thought it over.
- What's your name, honey?
- Jane.
One thing.
When you get that dough
I've gotta be in on it.
Right at the time.
Otherwise I might make
a nuisance of myself.
All right.
I may need your help.
How can I get hold of you,
say about 5:00?
Call that number.
For your sake, beautiful,
I hope you're not trying
to soft soap me.
I wouldn't take kindly to it.
What's the matter with you?
That's just to remind you, honey,
you're in a tough racket now.
Hello?
Lady, is that you?
I'll take that, Mac.
- Hello?
- Danny...
It's all worked out.
We'll get it tonight.
But I've got to know something first.
How do I know
you'll be fair with me?
Listen, this is very important.
How do I now?
You don't.
But I'll tell you something.
You've got ten times the chance
to get a straight deal from me...
as I've got from you.
Now what's the layout?
Well, be at Westside Park
at 9:00 tonight.
There's a big palm tree
at the west end of the lake.
A palm tree.
Be there.
I'll come along the shore
in one of those boats
and signal you with a flashlight.
Be watching. I don't want
to have to do it more than once.
Yes, yes, I'll have the money.
Then why all the complication?
Why can't you just meet me somewhere?
I don't think I like your setup.
It sounds like a snipe hunt.
It's not a trap
or whatever you're thinking, Danny.
I had to choose a place where
you'd have to play fair with me.
Danny!
Are you still there?
Yep.
All right, I'll be there.
West end of the lake
under the palm tree, 9:00.
Alan, let's get one of the big ones
like we used to.
Them's for four people, lady.
Here, the lady wants
one of the big ones.
Like I said.
Here comes one now.
What's the matter, sweetie?
You seem all tied up tonight.
There's nothing the matter.
I feel fine.
Remember what we used to call
these rides?
Cruises into nowhere.
Seems a long time ago, doesn't it?
It was.
A long time ago.
We haven't changed a bit, Jane.
Not a bit.
Alan, I...
I want to go back to shore.
Why, Jane?
We just got started.
Please, darling, I'd like to go back.
Something's wrong, what is it?
Maybe you're right.
Maybe something is wrong.
I feel...
chilled.
Let's go back.
Alan, let's put the claim check
in an envelope and put it in the mailbox.
I don't want to keep it anymore.
So that's it.
The money again.
Look, sweetheart, let's forget it.
I have.
Now that we're here, let's...
let's relax and have a...
Oh, doggone it, I must have left
my cigarettes at La Mole's.
- Do you have a...
- No!
What have you got in the bag?
It weighs a ton.
There are no cigarettes
in there, Alan.
Did you hear something, dear?
Uh-uh. Stop hearing things
when you kiss me.
Your timing is late.
What's the idea...
- What happened?
- It's Alan, my husband.
He's dead.
Don't move, Danny.
So that's what I heard.
A shot, not a backfire.
Yes. And I need your help.
Some other time.
I don't want the money that bad.
Will you take me back to shore
or do I swim?
If you move, I'll shoot you
and tell them you killed my husband.
If I go along with you
I get the gas chamber.
I wonder how good a shot you are.
There'll be no gas chamber
for either one of us, Danny.
They saw me get on this boat
with my husband,
they're going to see me
get off with him.
You'll be wearing his hat and coat.
You've got nothing to worry about.
Until his body comes floating up.
We're going to see that it doesn't.
You're quite a gal, Mrs. Palmer.
- That's for being so sweet.
- Thanks. Come again.
We intend to.
- What are you going to do with it?
- Never mind.
- Let's go quick.
- Sure, let's go get the dough.
Listen, we're not in the clear yet.
They've got to see you.
They've got to think Alan
brought me home.
I'll meet you at 11:45
at 6th and Beachway.
Then we'll go get the money.
Where?
Over in Monterey Canyon.
It's hidden there.
Yeah, this afternoon you said
you'd have it in the boat with you.
You're in no position to pull
another cross-up, honey,
you know that, don't you?
Yes, I know it.
Danny, please hurry.
Pete.
Mr. Palmer would like to have the car
washed tonight, could you do that?
Sure thing, Mr. Palmer.
Oh, Alan, get me some cigarettes
while you're there, will you?
- Did I get you up?
- No, I was reading.
I guess I must have dozed.
Alan's gone down to the corner
to get a bottle.
Why don't you come in
and have a nightcap with us?
Oh, I'd love to.
I was beginning to think you were
in rift with me or something.
I can't see why.
You mean to say Mr. Palmer
didn't come in there at all?
Well, thank you.
I don't understand it.
Pete says he hasn't seen him
since he drove out of here
a half hour ago.
And the people at the drugstore
say he hasn't been there at all.
Well, don't worry about it.
Maybe he went over to the drive-in
for some hamburgers.
Yes, I suppose so.
I don't understand it.
What could have happened to him?
It's over an hour. If nothing's happened,
why doesn't he call?
I don't know, Jane.
Let me fix you a drink.
Will you connect me
with Police Headquarters, please.
Yes, it's an emergency.
Hello, I'd like to check
on automobile accidents.
It's my husband.
He's missing and...
Lady, the Missing Persons Detail
closes at 5 p.m.
You mean you can't do
anything for me tonight?
How long has he been missing?
Lady, we can't do anything tonight.
If he doesn't show up by tomorrow
you come down here
and make a report in person
and we'll go to work on it.
Yes, ma'am, okay.
Jane, here's your...
Jane, you have a whole shelf
of whisky out there.
You told me Alan had gone out
to get a bottle.
That's right.
That proves it.
He never intended to go
to the drugstore at all.
There... there's something
I haven't told you, Kathy.
I've known it for a long time.
Alan doesn't love me anymore.
- He's beginning to get tired of me.
- That's ridiculous and you know it.
It's true, Kathy.
We've been quarreling a lot lately
about little unimportant things.
I bought some clothes the other day
and it made him terribly angry.
Please, Jane...
Alan will be home soon.
I think I'll go to bed now.
Good night.
Good night, Kathy.
All right, tiger.
Let's have that gun you were
waving around down at the lake...
and I'll take it butt first.
Danny...
the gun was Alan's.
It would be a bit silly of me
not to put it back where it belongs,
wouldn't it?
And you don't have a gun either.
If you did, you wouldn't be hiding it
in your pocket like that,
would you?
You know what, tiger?
I didn't know they made them
beautiful as you are and as smart.
Or as hard.
Here, you can have the gun.
Take it easy, will you?
You're not on Sunset now.
I can't take any chance on being
found missing, you know that.
Don't tell me you buried the dough.
- What else?
- Almost anything else.
Where did that money come from,
Danny?
Why was it being paid
to you like that?
I'll tell you when I see the dough.
Maybe.
I hope you're not planning
to pull a fast one on me,
it won't pay off.
Don't quarrel with me, Danny.
We're not out of trouble
until I get back to my apartment.
Slow down or you'll never get back.
Look out!
Not this time, tiger. You didn't
bury that dough and I know it.
I'll see you some time in the daylight
and a million people around.
Danny!
Danny, come back, the...
The ticket's in that coat.
Danny!
Nobody here.
Yeah. Key's in it too.
- Do your feet hurt?
- You kidding?
What are we waiting for?
Hello.
Jane?
Alan's home, isn't he?
No.
But I'm sure I heard the elevator.
No one came in, Kathy.
It must have been someone
across the hall.
Oh...
Well, I'm sorry I disturbed you, Jane.
Good night.
Like you said, honey,
this should have been put back.
What did you do with the coat?
Alan's coat?
- How did you get here?
- In a cab.
You know what I mean.
How did you find me?
I found the place where you eat.
You can guess the rest.
What did you do with Alan's coat?
Forget it, tiger.
I took care of the coat.
Let's talk about the money.
Isn't that why you're here?
How? Just how
did you take care of it?
Don't you see? If the coat turns up
in the wrong way, we're lost.
What did you do with it?
Why just the coat, tiger?
Why not the hat too?
It had his initials in it.
Yes, and the hat too.
What did you do with them?
Not a thing, angel.
I'll let you get rid of them.
All I did was take the label
out of the coat
and the hat band out of the hat.
- You wanna take them, huh?
- Yes.
Sit down, honey.
On the bed.
Sorry it isn't tidy. I didn't know
you were gonna drop by.
- Please, we haven't a minute to lose.
- I know.
All I want is time to look
the coat over.
Time to find what's
so special about it.
Sit down, honey.
There's a hole in the first pocket.
Maybe there's something
in the lining.
Shall we look, tiger?
Well, what do you know?
Something is in the lining, tiger.
There's no one home.
Well, it's hard to believe.
Could I just touch you to make sure?
I mean, were you looking
for anyone in particular?
A man named Palmer.
But I can hardly remember why.
Are you a friend of Mr. Palmer's?
- Are you?
- Well, I asked you first.
We flew together in England.
In a weak moment he asked me
to drop by if I ever got to Hollywood.
Oh.
I live across the hall.
I'm Alan's sister.
I was pretty sure you weren't Jane.
Oh, you've met Jane?
Well, I've seen pictures of her.
Mother told me
there'd be times like this.
- I don't know what to say.
- Well, why say anything?
We could wait till they're gone
and I could just leave... maybe.
They?
Well, whoever it is we're avoiding.
Jane, I gather.
What's it all about?
It's Alan.
He's missing.
Missing? Since when?
Last night, about 10:00.
What did you expect to find
with your pass key?
I suppose I had to expect
that question.
That's why I pulled you in here.
I didn't want Jane to know...
when you ran into me.
I gathered that.
I have ten days coming to me
and I looked forward
to going to a happy coma
in one of your beaches.
But if there's anything I can do.
I don't know.
I just don't know.
Where's Jane?
She went down
to the Missing Persons Bureau.
She hasn't come back.
Why the pass key?
Why couldn't Jane know
what you were looking for?
You didn't tell me your name.
- Don Blake.
- You know my name?
Well, Alan mentioned it
a few times, but I'm not quite sure.
Elizabeth?
No, it's Katherine.
I know what you're thinking.
I can almost hear
that mind of yours churning.
You're wondering why
I'm so eager to help.
Or maybe you're wondering why
I'm so willing to believe the worst of Jane.
Well, I never met Jane.
But I never liked her either.
You know her first husband
killed himself?
Jane had nothing to do with it.
The man had had money once
and he just couldn't stand being broke.
Uh-huh.
Anyway, getting back to Alan.
You obviously think
there's something wrong.
And I wouldn't like to feel
I'd walked out on him.
So, if there's anything I can do
or anything that ought to be done,
I'd appreciate your telling me
about it.
All right, Mr. Blake.
Better?
Feel like talking now?
It's cold in here.
I'll turn on the oven.
Maybe I shouldn't bother
to light it, huh, tiger?
So hubby pulled a cross-up,
is that it?
The dough is checked somewhere,
I gather.
- Yes.
- Where?
Is it possible to get the bag
without the ticket?
I know exactly what it looks like.
Sure. All you gotta do
is describe the content.
Then the cops come and take you away.
The ticket's some place
in the apartment.
I know it.
I've got to get back.
And I've got to have that gun.
Sure, I'll give you the gun.
All you gotta do is ask
and Danny gives.
Remember the ride
we took last night, tiger?
The money was buried up in the hill.
You were taking me up there
to give me my half, remember?
to kill me, tiger.
You were gonna kill me.
And now I give you back the gun.
Sure.
I'll give it to you.
But first I'm gonna get
to know you better.
I think probably some day
you will kill me.
And I wouldn't want that to happen...
unless we were...
good friends.
Go ahead, scream.
Get the cops in here.
That's all we need.
Where have you been, Jane?
Is there any news?
No.
Why aren't you at work?
Work? With Alan just swallowed up
some place.
- Where have you been?
- Walking, thinking,
trying to figure this thing out.
Jane, I thought of something
this morning.
If Alan, just...
well, just went away, don't you...
What do you mean
if he just went away?
What else could have happened?
I don't know.
Nothing seems to make any sense.
Does it ever?
I thought of a way we might
be able to tell. Alan's gun.
He loved that gun.
It was the only thing
he saved from his Army days.
If he'd known he was going away,
I think he'd have taken it
with him, don't you?
We can easily find out.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing, I...
I think know who it is, Jane.
It's a friend of Alan's.
I ran into him in the hall.
He said he'd be back.
Are you Mrs. Palmer?
Lieutenant Breach, Homicide Division.
May I come in?
You don't seem to have expected me.
- Should I have?
- Well, didn't you report a...
Oh, my apologies, Mrs. Palmer,
I see what's wrong now.
The Missing Persons Detail is part
of the Homicide Division.
I've been assigned to the case
you reported.
Oh, I'm afraid you frightened me
for a minute, Lieutenant.
I was afraid something had happened.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Lieutenant Breach,
my sister-in-law, Miss Palmer.
Won't you sit down?
I've been trying you get you
by phone, Mrs. Palmer.
I have some information for you
you might prefer to discuss privately.
Miss Palmer is my husband's sister.
Go ahead.
Is there anything
you would like to add?
Something you didn't put into
your report.
No, not a thing.
Mrs. Palmer, there's nothing illegal
about being missing.
We only work on a missing person's case
if it's a juvenile or...
if there's some evidence of foul play,
or suicide, or an accident.
Until we get evidence that it is
something else, and it usually is,
we don't touch it.
So you see, Mrs. Palmer,
it isn't exactly playing ball with us
to hold anything back.
Hold what back, Lieutenant?
The other woman, Mrs. Palmer.
What...
what do you know about her?
Well, it's the only thing
we've uncovered so far.
A Belair resident,
a vice-president of a furniture
plant out in Vernon,
was pulling out of a driveway last night
when his car, your car,
driven by a woman,
almost crashed into him.
A man, dressed like you described
your husband,
same size, everything,
gets out of the car.
I kind of believe they'd had a quarrel.
Well, that's about all
our informant saw.
All he did was spot the license number.
It might have been foul play...
but I doubt it.
I suspect they passed it up.
Do you know anything
about this woman, Mrs. Palmer?
Not very much, I'm afraid.
I've only seen her once or twice.
She... she's a little taller
than I am.
Hair a little darker.
Brown eyes, I think.
But...
I don't know her name
or where she lives.
Jane, you never told me.
Why?
Because I didn't think it meant...
Hello?
Yes.
It's for you.
Oh, I told the Bureau I'd be here.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Okay, thanks.
Good bye.
I'm afraid that wraps it up.
If you really want some action
on your husband, Mrs. Palmer,
I'd suggest you bring in
some private help.
Your car was located
12 miles south of San Diego
just this side of the Mexican border.
Your husband wasn't in some kind
of trouble, was he, Mrs. Palmer?
No... or not that I know of.
- Are you sure it was our car?
- Yes.
I'll see that it's sent back.
- Good luck.
- Thank you, Lieutenant.
Good bye.
I know Alan wasn't seeing
another woman and so do you.
For Alan's concern, my dear,
you're blind.
It's time you knew it.
Your description of this
other woman, Jane,
it sounded very much like you.
What do you mean by that?
What are you trying to imply?
I'm not quite sure.
Well, hello again!
We seem to be colliding
in hallways, don't we?
Yes, we seem to.
Jane, this is the man I mentioned
to you. He flew with Alan.
Mr. Blake, my sister-in-law.
- How do you do, Mrs. Palmer?
- How do you do?
I'm sorry to hear about Al,
but I'm sure he'll turn up soon.
Thank you.
Will you excuse me, Jane.
Mr. Blake.
Well, she seems to be a bit upset.
Has there been some news
about Alan?
No, but they were very close,
you know?
Oh, I know.
Did you want to see Alan
about anything special?
Oh, no. We were just
very good friends.
I see.
Would you like to come in?
All right.
Kathy didn't tell me much
about you, Mr. Blake.
- Did you know Alan well?
- Well, I thought I did.
It would be hard to believe Al
took after some wild geese.
He was always an advocate
of the home at heart.
I always thought so.
- Won't you sit down?
- All right.
Uh...
Go ahead.
Well, I was about to say I'm here
on a vacation and...
I was wondering if I might help
in any way.
I think the police are doing all
that can be done.
What did Alan usually call you,
Mr. Blake?
Don.
When there were ladies present.
Which wasn't often, I hope.
What squadron were you flying with?
Same as Alan's, Mrs. Palmer.
Wouldn't you rather call me Jane?
All right.
- Would you like a drink?
- I didn't think it was that noticeable.
- What?
- The thirsty look.
Come on, let me help you.
Or let me watch.
Where were you stationed
in England?
- Don't you know?
- Of course. I keep forgetting.
Stonehurst, or something
like that, wasn't it?
Yeah, something like that.
Ipswich. I didn't know we had
any operations in Stonehurst.
Well, all those places in England
used to sound alike to me.
I seem to worry you,
Mrs. Palmer. Why?
Why do you say that?
Oh, I don't know, I...
I sense a third degree
to this conversation.
Could I be wrong?
Yes, you're wrong.
I'm just curious about you,
Mr. Blake.
No, you don't worry me.
But it's possible you're beginning
to intrigue me.
Oh...
That's why you were sure
Al isn't coming back, huh?
You made quite a bit about
that remark of mine, didn't you?
Why, do you think I made any more
out of it than I found there?
I'm afraid you did.
If I should hear from Alan,
where can he get in touch with you?
I'm staying at the Bela Vista Hotel.
Oh, by the way, uh...
on my way out shall I take the guy
in the plaid suit off your back?
What did you say?
Looks a little pale.
I think I can handle him all right.
What are you talking about?
The guy in the plaid suit.
He was lurking around
the dark end of the hall
making like a tenant
trying to find a key.
I watched him for a while
as I got off the elevator.
- It made him nervous.
- He must be from the police.
Sure!
That's right. They're looking for Al.
They probably figured the best place
to find him is where he lives.
Thanks for the drink.
- Oh, hello.
- Hello.
How did you make out with Jane?
She's crazy about me.
Do you know where
they went last night?
- Before Alan disappeared?
- Yes?
Do you happen to have
any pictures around of Jane and Alan?
Why yes, why?
The police won't do anything
until they're convinced something's wrong.
We're going to find
something to convince them.
How did you know that
about the police? Did Jane...
Get into your coat, Miss Palmer, honey.
We're going sleuthing.
Waiting for a boat, mister?
Not right now, but I would like
to ask you a couple of questions.
Look, I don't know
what makes them run, mister.
I ain't no good with motors.
Well, maybe you're good with faces.
Remember the last time
you saw him?
Yeah, I've seen him,
but I'll be darned if I remember when.
Maybe this will help.
Yeah, last night.
They was here last night.
Hey, you a cop?
Do I look like one?
I never seen any that did.
I just happen to be a friend of his.
And he disappeared last night.
Do you remember anything
about them, how they behaved?
Like they were quarreling,
or anything?
Oh, they acted like any corny people.
Here you are, buddy.
Thanks very much.
Are you sure there isn't
anything else you can tell us?
They were pretty fast
with a buck too.
He gave me one
to get one of the big boats...
When they came back she gave...
Hey, I just thought of something.
She paid.
He helped her out of the boat,
real polite like...
he goes upstairs and she goes
over there and pays.
- Hm, some guy.
- Well, they're married, you know.
Oh, that explains everything.
Thanks.
You know, a man usually
pays for things
even when he's married with a girl.
Uh, did Alan happen to be
an exception to that rule?
He is rather absent-minded,
you must have noted that.
Oh, sure, that's right.
Well, I think we'd better
say good night here.
I think it's better if Jane
doesn't see us together too much.
All right.
Well, I sort of made you saying good night
sound like quite a project, didn't I?
Yes, I thought so.
Oh, ten days in town.
I don't think you'd go
for that kind of a deal, would you?
I might.
But I see what you mean.
Good night, Miss Palmer, honey.
Did you really fly with Alan?
Hey, what kind of a question is that?
An honest one.
I hope you'll give me
an honest answer.
You seem so terribly concerned
about what happened to Alan.
Yet you never talk about him
as though you really knew him.
Well, uh...
maybe there's a reason, Kate.
Maybe I'm afraid if I did,
I'd be talking about him
in the past tense.
- Why do you say that?
- Oh, I don't know.
It's just a peculiar feeling I've had.
About Jane.
Now look.  Let's get
squared away on her first.
And then I'll talk about myself
till you cry uncle.
- You know, I'm one of my favorite topics.
- All right, Don.
- Good night.
- Wait, wait.
There's just one other thing.
There's something going on here,
Kathy, and it's not very pretty.
Don't ask me what it is
or why I think so, but...
Bear with me, Kate, will you?
I have to trust someone, Don.
I'd like it to be you.
Good night, Don.
Good night, Kathy.
Who is it?
You really want me to answer that?
Right out here in front of...
You're drunk.
It takes one to spot one.
Did you get it?
The best, duchess.
Nothing but the best for you,
duchess.
I say let's kill these people in style.
There's enough there
to kill most of the people you don't like.
Now, let me hold that little bottle
while you go fix me a drink.
You've had enough to drink.
Get out of here and get yourself sober.
I don't like you this way.
You know what the man said
who sold me this?
He said I didn't look like the type of guy
he's used to dealing with.
I looked him right in the eye.
And I said, you mean
I don't look like a killer, huh?'
You know what he said?
He said, 'No, you don't.'
I wonder what he would have said
if you'd bought the stuff, tiger.
- Hi.
Well...
How did you know I was gonna
ask you out to dinner?
- I didn't.
- Well then, why do you look so nice?
Well, thank you, sir,
I just got home from work...
I look a fright and you know it.
Oh, sure you do.
I know just the best place for us.
All the best frights go there.
And I was going to settle
for a glass of milk.
Oh, no, it'll keep.
You go ahead. I'll put it
in the refrigerator.
Don, after dinner I'd like you
to take me down to the Union Station.
Kind of sudden, isn't it?
Planning to be gone long?
I found...
I found this yesterday.
It was hidden in the drawer
where Alan keeps his gun.
What do you mean after dinner?
Maybe this is the answer.
Oh, I was just about to knock.
What did you want, Jane?
As a matter of fact, I wanted
to get a hold of you, Mr. Blake.
There's someone in my apartment
I'd like you to meet.
A man named Sharber.
Well, maybe some other time,
Mrs. Palmer.
There won't be another time.
I'm leaving tomorrow, perhaps soon.
- Jane, did you hear from Alan?
- No.
They brought the car back today.
I found a note in it from Alan.
He's somewhere in Mexico
and I intend to find him.
May I see it?
What did he say?
It was rather personal, Kathy, he...
He asked me to forgive him...
and told me a could do
whatever I wanted with his things.
- That's all?
- That's all.
Won't you come, Mr. Blake?
It's only for a minute.
All right.
You two don't seem
to know each other.
Should we?
Mr. Sharber, this is Don Blake.
He was stationed
with you and Alan at Ipswich,
He said.
I say that to all the girls.
Let's go, Kate.
You never flew at Ipswich,
what are you trying to pull?
Not a thing, Mac.
I'm leaving, Kathy.
I'd like to have you come along with me.
No. And I'd like what I gave you
a minute ago.
Let's talk about it outside.
I've already kept you
too long, Mr. Sharber.
I've found out
what I wanted to know.
Are you sure you're all right?
Quite all right.
Good night, Mr. Sharber.
- Good night.
- Thank you.
And now I'll take that ticket,
please.
The ticket belongs to me,
Mr. Blake.
If I have to shoot you to get it,
I'll be quite within my right.
I'm afraid you won't be.
You can have your ticket.
All you have to do is reach
into my pocket and take it.
Turn around.
Get me the Hollywood Police.
Quick, it's an emergency.
Hello, I'm calling
from the Château Michel,
you've got to send someone
up here quickly.
514, hurry.
Katherine Palmer, hurry!
Doctor Adams, Katherine Palmer.
Could you come up to 514
right away?
Hollywood Police, emergency.
This is Katherine Palmer again.
You've got to send a patrol car
to Union Station.
A woman will try
to claim something there.
The Union Pacific, City of Los Angeles,
train 103 is now arriving.
Union Pacific train number 1
is now arriving.
- Hello.
- Hell-o!
- You by yourself.
- Not anymore, if I can help it.
How'd you like to...
How'd you like to do a lady
a big favor and earn 5 dollars?
What kind of a favor?
My ex-boyfriend is over there
waiting for me to claim my bag.
If you get it for me,
I can avoid him.
If you like, I'll let you spend
the 5 dollars on me.
Well, what are we waiting for?
- Here I am.
- I'll take my fin now, lady.
- What?
- My 5 bucks.
All right.
- How long have I been out?
- You took quite a jolt.
Kathy, did you send the police
down to the Union Station?
I tried to, they wouldn't go.
They said they couldn't hold anyone
unless there was a crime committed.
Isn't cracking skulls a crime?
Don't look at me.
I just drive a patrol car.
Do you want to file charges
against somebody?
Can you get an address
from a license number this time of night?
Sure we can.
You got a homicide man
at the Hollywood Station?
They didn't kill you.
You'll live.
Come on. Let's go.
Am I coming? I seem to recall
we had a date for dinner.
We did, but...
I guess you'll have to settle
for that milk after all, Kathy.
Could I have two minutes
before you go?
We can cover it in ten seconds.
You were right, Kathy.
I don't know your brother
from Adam.
I could expand on that, but I think Janie
still has some unfinished business.
Thanks, Doc.
I found the ticket, Danny.
I found it.
It's all clear sailing now.
Go away. Creep back out.
Lock the door, Danny,
Pull the blinds.
What's the matter?
I'm worried. I don't get it.
The money's in that bag, Danny.
We're leaving for Mexico with it.
Like I say, I don't get it.
- Why we?
- I need you.
A woman traveling alone would attract
too much attention.
Now, I've got to know
about that money.
Where it came from.
That's better.
Don't ever change, tiger.
I don't think I'd like you
with a heart.
Open the bag, Danny.
It's all ours.
- Let's have a drink.
- In a minute, Danny.
But first of all I've got to know
where the money came from
and if we can use it safely
There should be sixty grand
in there, tiger.
Sixty grand.
- I gotta have a drink.
- Wait, Danny.
Somebody threw that money
into our car. Why?
Because you don't go into a guy's office
and their blackmail payoff, sweetie.
Besides, he didn't know
what I looked like.
And I wanted to keep it that way.
- But who is it, why did he...
- Never mind who it is, tiger.
But it's the kind of a thing
you come across only once in a lifetime.
I stumbled onto a racket.
A big man in town.
Three floors of mahogany
in the Monarch Building.
Big insurance agency.
Sells policies on bridges,
and aqueducts and stuff.
Who ever heard of anything
happening to a bridge?
So the policies never
went back to New York.
They're just pieces of paper my benefactor's
been collecting premiums on for years.
I cut me a slice of last year's premium.
That's it.
Then...
then the money isn't marked.
We can spend it.
You said it, tiger.
Now...
Let's have that drink.
Wait, Danny.
We'll make it a toast.
I'll get the glasses.
They're right there on that bench.
Here's to crime.
It pays.
And pays.
Look at this, partner.
Take a sniff.
The whisky bottle wasn't spiked.
He took it like a good boy.
Right in his glass.
Go out and call the lab
and the meat wagon.
Tell them it's a suicide.
It's no suicide. Your friend Mrs. Palmer
arranged this tableau.
- Any idea why?
- Yeah.
He helped to kill her husband.
If you've got something
to tell me, let's have it.
I think you'll find her husband
at the bottom of the lake at Westlake Park.
You don't say.
You know, I'm only a cop.
When I checked the lake
I found they went there
the night he disappeared.
And they also left it together.
Oh now, look.
When they left the boat Palmer was
in a great big hurry.
He left the paying to his wife
and dashed up the steps.
And now I think I know why.
Palmer never got off that boat.
This guy did.
Then he drove Palmer's car
to San Diego.
I could point a dozen things
wrong with that, but why bother?
If you're right, the body
will come up in a day or two.
Oh, no. I'm afraid
you'll have to drag the lake.
Jane's a pretty smart girl.
If she put him there,
she put him there to stay.
Anyone besides you
ever seen them together?
Look, what's the trouble?
Don't you want to lick this thing?
Do you know what it would cost
the Department
to close that lake and drag it?
We'd have to get an okay
from the Police Commission...
and the Bureau of Budget and Efficiency.
And if the lake management
raised enough of a hassle,
we might even have to go
to the City Council.
Hay, Chief, come here a minute.
What's the idea?
I haven't done any...
All right, all right.
She starts up the walk
and notices the door's open.
Then she sees our car
and decides to go away.
I was just trying to ask her
a polite question.
Polite, he says. How does he act
when he's being crude?
- Are you a friend of Fuller's?
- Friend of who?
Come on inside.
What happened?
Did you ever see this before?
Was it with that?
You know anyone
who would have wanted to kill him?
He killed himself.
Oh, God have mercy on him...
What makes you think
he did it himself?
You got any reason?
He had a big deal on.
Fifty or sixty grand, he said.
But something went wrong.
I was with him
when he got that stuff.
He didn't think I knew
what he was getting but I did.
- Oh, I wanna go home.
- Parker.
Take her home, get her name...
and find out where Fuller
got that poison.
Right.
As for you, brother,
I'm going to let you off
with a little friendly advice.
Don't ever try to involve the Department
in your private quarrels.
If you get any facts,
bring them around.
But until you do,
Palmer's a missing person
and this guy killed himself.
Now get going.
Palmer's a corpse.
How much would it cost me to have
the lake dragged and prove it to you?
What did the lady do to you, Blake,
besides sap you down?
It must have been something big.
Sure, son, you can drag the lake.
A guy did it about four years ago
looking for his wife.
When he got through with it
it had cost him $4.000,
the park officials were suing him,
and his wife turned up in Modesta
with a truck driver.
Having trouble?
It's all fixed now, thanks.
I had a flat.
- Sure I can't help any?
- No, no, thanks very much.
It's a bad place to get stuck.
Blow out, huh?
Yes.
This small fortune belong to you, ma'am?
Yes, it must have dropped from my bag.
Suppose there's any more
from where that came from?
With all that money, lady,
you ought to have some male protection.
Anything wrong, miss?
No, I had a flat but everything's
all right now.
- Good night.
Good night, everybody.
It was nice meeting you.
And after dinner we'll go
to the front lawn for the Jai-Alai game.
I'm sorry, Carlos.
No.
I'm rather tired.
Of course.
Mañana.
Well, nice place you have here,
Mrs. Palmer.
Oh, excuse me.
It's Miss Petrie now, isn't it?
That happens to be
my maiden name.
I've filed a suit for divorce.
That's a nice touch.
But widows don't need divorces,
do they?
I wasn't aware that I was a widow.
Doesn't matter.
I really came here
to talk about money.
I'd like, say,
half of what you brought
down with you.
That would be about $200, Mr...
What was your name?
It was Blake when you knew me.
You brought down about $60.000.
According to Danny's girlfriend.
I don't know any Danny and...
I haven't got any money.
I think you'd better leave.
I swear I'll scream to wake the dead
if you don't get out of here.
Oh, it's too bad you can't
wake the dead, Jane.
It might save you.
You see,
I found your husband's body.
I told the Los Angeles Police
where I am.
If there was any news of Alan,
I would have been notified.
Not about this you wouldn't.
You see, I let him drop back in.
Drop back?
Where?
Where you put him.
The lake.
Looking for something?
My lipstick.
Colt or Smith 'n Weston?
Now...
what's this about lakes?
Just one lake.
And if we can't make a deal,
I'm going back and drag him up again.
Oh...
How much do you want?
I told you.
Half.
It's in the hotel safe.
I'll have to go get it.
Go ahead.
Aren't you afraid
I might not come back?
You'll come back.
How do I know
you won't take it all?
That would make me a cad, Jane.
I couldn't do that.
Get the money.
I'll be satisfied with half.
It has a nice cool look,
hasn't it, Jane?
It tempts me.
But this will cover it.
What do you mean by that?
Giving you a strict accounting
of refunds, Mrs. Palmer.
I had to know for sure
if your husband was really in that lake.
This is the price
for having the lake dragged.
What do you mean?
What are you trying to say?
I'm trying to tell you, Jane,
you're all washed up.
You can't take my money and...
- You're not...
- The law?
No. Just someone who couldn't
let you get away with it, Jane.
A killjoy.
Here it is!
You want it, don't you?
It's yours.
All you have to do is take it.
You can't see it, Mrs. Palmer,
but I'm riding a big white horse.
This is a vendetta.
But it's over now.
Please page Teniente Rivera.
He's in the lobby.
Rivera, I'm in her apartment.
She has the money here.
All of it.
Yes. Right away.
You'll have to forgive me, Jane,
but I made formal charges
that you stole that money from me.
Now, you can sue me later
for false arrest but...
I had to figure some way of keeping you
in town till the L.A. Police get here.
Why, Mr. Blake? Tell me why?
Not Blake, Blanchard.
Does that mean anything to you?
I...
I once married a man...
named Blanchard.
Yeah, it's my brother.
I was overseas when it happened
but I never really believed
Bob killed himself.
- You killed him.
- I swear I didn't kill him.
He found out I didn't love him
and he killed himself.
I swear it!
I swear I didn't kill him!
There are many ways
of killing a man, Jane.
And now that I know you...
I can believe
Bob probably did kill himself.
But then there's Alan Palmer.
And your friend Danny.
You're all through killing now, Jane.
Wait, he's lying!
The money is mine!
Please, señorita, we wish no trouble.
- You come with us, eh?
- No! I tell you he's lying!
Someone get a doctor!
No need for a doctor.
She's dead.
- How did it happen?
- She fell from the balcony.
Vamos, muchachos...
Well, it was a short honeymoon,
Kathy.
We're going home now.
- Jane?
- Yeah.
Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes