25.000
Does it look familiar, son?
I remember that ridge over there.
Yeah. Cowhands ride over there in that big gap.
You know, it was right around here where
I picked you up, twelve years ago.
You was more dead than alive.
I'll never forget that night, Dusty.
Flash o' guns, shouts o' murdering men...
And the courage of my dad.
Shielding me and fighting a hopeless fight.
Riddled with bullets, he fell across me, whispering...
'Lay still, Ted boy. They'll think you're dead.'
He didn't know I had a slug through my lung.
Well, when they rode up, somebody lit a match.
And I laid still.
And I heard somebody say, 'They got 'em both.'
And the match died out.
And then somebody laughed.
I'll never forget that laugh, Dusty.
The laugh of a crazy man.
A killer.
Well, the next thing I knew, it was morning.
I was in your arms.
Yep, and I carried you all the way to Big Bend.
For two years, I didn't know whether you was
gonna live or die.
But you sure pulled through alright.
If we could just find some trace of my
kid brother...
Well, it's doubtful.
We did learn, however, that your dad
had a hired man and his wife.
I remember... a woman did the
cooking and took care of Jim.
you see, Dusty, my mother died when Jim was born.
And he's the only relative I have.
If he's alive.
That hired man and his wife disappeared.
We couldn't find hide nor hair of 'em.
Finally, there was a feller that moved on
the ranch by the name of...
Let's see... What was his name?
Gentry, that's it! Gentry.
But he didn't know nothing.
Anyway, it ain't gonna do you no good living
this all over again.
We'll be in town tomorrow and we'll start
our investigating.
Hey, Dusty.
Poison!
Water hole.
I didn't know.
I wonder who he is.
We better open it.
'Hello, Gentry.
This'll introduce Gat Ganns.
He's just the man for the job you mentioned.
Sorry I can't do it, but I got a couple of
star trackers on my tail.
Gat's plenty tough, as this enclosed poster will prove.
Good luck, Bill.'
Gentry.
Gentry!
He's evidently planning to kill him.
Well, that's the fella that's got your dad's ranch!
Certainly is funny, but you sure do resemble
this bozo.
Maybe fate's kinda taken a hand in this deal, Dusty.
Maybe so.
We don't know what this Gentry's up to, but...
We're gonna find out.
What do you mean?
I mean that from now on, I'm Gat Ganns.
Murderer.
Gentry, my daughter and I have considered
your offer for the ranch.
And have decided not to sell.
We've developed the best spring in the country.
And someday I hope to make this a fine ranch.
I'll admit it's dry wire, Mr. Winters,
and I don't blame you for holding onto it.
However, this country is still wild, and rustlers are pretty numerous.
That's why I have sold half the herd.
And we're going to sell the other half next week.
- Excuse me just a moment, Mr. Gentry.
- Go ahead.
- Everything check up alright, Mr. Hornsby?
- Everything's right.
They're on their way.
I think you'll find that's right, Ms. Winters.
That's quite right. Thank you so much,
Mr. Hornsby.
Too late for the bank now, Dad. I'll have
to deposit this first thing in the morning.
I've got some two-year-olds I'd like
to have you take a look at.
Alright!
- How do you do, Mr. Gentry?
- Fine. Very happy to see you, Ms. Winters.
Your father told me that you decided not to sell.
That's right. We're quite happy here, and
it's the kind of a ranch that Dad's always wanted.
So why shouldn't we keep it?
Well, if you're happy here, that's all that matters.
As your neighbor, may I be permitted
to call sometime?
Why, of course. Dad and I will be delighted
to have you.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Good morning.
- Hello, chief.
- Hello.
- Hi, boys.
Well, Winters refuses to sell.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, but I'm going to force him.
I'll ruin him.
The Winters girl's leaving the ranch
in the morning with a large sum of money.
Now, Joe and Hank, I want you to get it.
But remember, no harm must come to her.
I'll own that ranch no matter what it costs!
- There you are, honey.
- Alright, Dad. Now, I'll be right back.
Be careful!
If you hadn't have missed her, I'd have got her.
Well, it ain't too late yet.
- Can't get her now.
- Why didn't you keep her when you had her?
We never had her, you lassoed fool!
Drop that gun! Are you going crazy?
Cool down, now, before I go try it,
you pink-eyed weasel.
Come on, get in your saddle. We gotta go tell
the chief.
Them fellers is sure in a hurry.
Well, I reckon it's deserted.
We can camp here temporarily.
Dusty, come here.
Blood.
Hey, son. Get up here, quick!
Hey, son.
Bullet holes.
Fay Winters. It's mighty curious, Dusty.
We've gotta hurry and get her to town.
Let's take it easy now, son.
Got her here just in time.
A small artery's been severed.
However, I don't think it's very serious.
How did this happen?
Don't know. We found her just outside of town.
A horse must have thrown her.
We left our pack running loose.
I reckon we better get going.
- Yeah, we may be back later.
- Alright, boys.
I know the young lady'll be very grateful.
You've probably saved her life.
Now, listen, I hadn't better be seen around here,
so you take this money down and deposit it for her.
- And I'll meet you at the shack.
- Alright.
I'll tell you, boss, we couldn't catch her.
She just outrode us, that's all.
Well, I got another plan.
Get back to the hideout. I'll see you tonight.
Hello, Winters? This is Dr. Silsby.
Your daughter wanted me to tell you
she may be late getting home.
She's met with a slight accident.
No, not serious. I'll bring her out to the ranch a little later.
Thank you.
Who were the men that brought me in, Dr. Silsby?
They said they were prospectors.
It's lucky they found you.
A small artery has been severed.
And eventually, you may have bled to death.
As it is, the way you are, nobody'll ever
know that you have a scratch.
I certainly am grateful, but did they say anything about money?
Not a word.
I had three thousand dollars on me to deposit.
And it's gone.
Three thousand!
Your name Gentry?
Yeah, I'm Gentry.
We're from the border. Bill said to give you this.
He'd have come himself but he had a couple of
star packers on his trail.
So, you're Gat Ganns, eh?
That's what they call me.
- And this is my friend, Dusty.
- Hi.
- Howdy.
- We always work together.
Bill tell you what I wanted?
No, he just said there was gonna be some
gun-throwing.
How much do you want for the job?
What's the job?
There's a fella I wanna have disappear.
Well, whatever you're gonna give Bill'll be okay
with us.
- Eh, Dusty?
- Yeah.
Alright.
I'll take you over to meet the boys.
- Hello, Mr. Gentry!
- Hello, Spuds.
- Where's your dad?
- He's gettin' himself ready for dinner.
- Where are the boys?
- They're over at the corral.
Hey! Spuds! Spuds, get in here and get to work!
Hey, Spuds!
Oh, hello, boss.
Hey, Butch. I want you to meet Gat Ganns,
and his friend Dusty.
- Hiya, boys.
- Hi.
These boys have joined up with us for a while.
Come on, I want you to meet the rest of the boys.
Get in there! Get in there and get to work!
Hey, boys.
This is Gat Ganns, and his friend Dusty.
They're gonna be with us for a while.
I've got a little job to do tomorrow night.
You boys are taking all of Winters' cattle.
Taking 'em through the passe into Round Valley.
There's plenty of feed there. We'll dispose o' them later.
You boys can watch the house.
Winters'll be sure to come out when he hears
the racket.
Now, he's the man you want and you know
what to do.
Be sure it isn't the girl.
We're leaving about midnight.
Hank, show the boys to the sleeping quarters.
We're out of provisions, chief.
Yeah, well, here's fifty bucks.
And by the way, Butch. We're taking Winters' cattle
tomorrow night. You better get in on the drive.
- I'll be there, chief.
- Okay.
- I'm riding back with you, Gentry, to get my pack.
Hey, Spuds!
Come out here.
Tell the boys to hitch up the horses.
You're driving to town for provisions.
- Thanks.
- Is that Winters a tough hombre?
Just stubborn. I've tried to buy the ranch for
two years. Now I'm taking it.
Hasn't he any relatives?
A daughter.
I'm taking her along with the ranch.
Oh, I see! Like a dime novel.
We eliminate the old gent. You marry the gal and
get the ranch. Is that it?
You guessed it.
Go the way you always go. Don't ask any
questions and don't answer any.
And if you ain't back by dark, I'll tan you good.
- Get going!
- Giddyup!
Won't you come in, Dr. Silsby?
No, thank you. I got to be getting back.
- Well, thanks for the lift.
- Oh, that's alright.
Oh, Dad!
I lost the money!
Nevermind the money, dear. It's you I was worried
about.
We've got the rest of the herd to sell. That'll carry
you through til spring.
But tell me, Fay. What in the world happened?
Well, you see, there was two men that followed
me out of town.
And that's the last thing I remember.
I don't know. Doc said they were a couple of prospectors.
Well, fella, we sure had some ride, didn't we?
Come on, son. Let's go sit down and kinda pull
ourselves together.
I knowed you was gonna get me when
I passed you.
Oh, don't worry, Spuds. We're alright.
You're safe.
I know. But that's not what I'm thinkin' about.
I'm thinkin' o' what's gonna happen to me when I get back.
Butch'll beat me.
Oh, I'll have something to say about that.
You can't stop him. No one can. They have tried it.
Well, I'll get your provisions and then go back
with you and explain things.
Don't worry. Your dad isn't gonna whip you.
Now, I was beginning to think I'd have to come in
after you.
Where are the buckboards? What happened?
The horses got scared. I managed to stop them,
but the buckboards got wrecked.
What about the provisions?
They're in my pack.
Here's your change.
Get in the house.
I told 'em that kid couldn't hold them horses.
I've seen that fella someplace before, Dusty.
But I can't think where.
I couldn't help it, I swear! I tell you, I couldn't!
- I'll tan you good --
- I couldn't help it! No, please! Stop!
- I'll take care of --
- Stop, please!
I've'd licked the rest of 'em.
Now I reckon it's just --
Come on, Ted!
You ever whip that kid again,
I'll break every bone in your carcass.
Oh. Alright, then. Let me go.
He won't whip you again, Spuds.
You're the only friend I've got.
Gee, you can fight!
I'm gonna bet you busted his gizzards!
Gentry sent word that no one was to leave
the ranch.
And tonight's the night we're supposed
to get Winters.
How we gonna warn him?
Well, the only chance we got's when we get there.
Move over to the house from here.
But, remember. Don't mistake the girl for the man.
I'll get the boys started on the drive.
Gimme your knife, Dusty.
- What's wrong, Fay?
- Come here, Dad.
Look!
This just came through the window.
Why, it's our bank book!
The lost money has been deposited!
'Don't come... Don't strike a light.
They're waiting to shoot you down.
Your life's worth more than your cattle.
Let them take them. A Friend.'
They're stealing our cattle.
- I can't let --
- Dad!
Don't you understand?
They're waiting out there for you.
You wouldn't have a chance.
I saw the flash of a light.
I'm sure they got the note.
I don't think there's anybody home!
Well, that's mighty strange.
Well, I've got the cattle anyway. Let's go.
They're gone.
And our cattle with them.
Don't worry, Dad. Thanks to someone
we've got enough in the bank to carry us through.
Go over to Winters and ask him for a job.
He'll tell you about the cattle being stolen.
Tell him you'll help trail them.
I'm sure he'll take you up.
When you get out of town, well...
Accidents happen.
That's a mighty smart idea, Gentry.
You sure know how to work things out.
Now, come on, Dusty. Let's get this over with.
Oh, how are you?
I reckon you're the owner here.
- Yes, I am.
- Could you use a couple of good cowhands?
Well, I could've used you last night.
Rustlers run off all my cattle.
Well, they couldn't have gone far.
Cattle has to eat, you know.
Why don't you trail him?
I've phoned the sheriff, but he won't be back
til this afternoon.
Well, we'll make you a little proposition.
If we bring your herd back, will you give us
our jobs taking care of it?
I sure will.
Well, that's fair enough. You better go with us
til we sight 'em.
Then you can come back and get the sheriff.
We may lose your rustlers, but we'll sure
get your cattle.
Alright, I'll saddle up right away.
Oh, Ms. Winters...
- Oh, good morning, Mr. Gentry.
- Good morning.
Is your dad around?
Why, yes. I think he's over at the barn.
- I'd like to see him.
- Alright.
- Good morning, Gentry.
- Good morning, Mr. Winters.
Rustlers run off my cattle last night, and I've
just hired these two boys to help trail him.
We'll take care of him, Ms. Winters.
When we sight the cattle, he's coming back
after the sheriff.
Oh! Oh, I see!
Don't worry, dear. I may be late getting back,
but I'll be here.
Good luck.
Oh, I do hope they find our cattle!
In case your dad is late getting back, I'd be very happy
to keep you company this evening until his return.
Thank you, but I'm not afraid.
And I wouldn't like to inconvenience you.
Oh, that wouldn't be an inconvenience,
Ms. Winters.
In fact, it's going to be a real pleasure.
And here's the letter we got from Ganns.
'Hello, Gentry. This will introduce Gat Ganns.
He's just the man for the job you mentioned.
Sorry I can't do it, but I got a couple of
star packers on my trail.
Gat's plenty tough, as the enclosed poster
will prove.
Good luck. Bill.'
Gentry!
That dirty smick!
I don't know how I can ever repay you boys.
I hate to think what would've happened if you
hadn't taken a hand in this.
Oh, gosh, Mr. Winters. We're glad to help you.
The question is what to do next.
I got it!
You go tell Gentry that we've disposed
of Mr. Winters here.
If he wants proof, take him and show him Ganns.
And then...
Alright, get outta here before I shoot
the pants offa you.
- Well, Dusty's taken the shovel, but I guess
I can...
- Nevermind that.
Where is your partner?
He beat it for the border. We figure that the
sooner we get outta here, the better.
And I suppose you want your dough.
That's all I'm waiting for.
Well, the bank's closed, but I'll have it for you
at the hideout first thing in the morning.
Fair enough. I'll stay at the Winters' place tonight.
Got a few things I wanna pick up.
Alright, but don't let the girl see you.
I won't let anyone see me.
Okay.
- Hello, boys.
- Hi, boss. Hi, chief.
Well, I got some good news for you.
The Winters' ranch'll soon be mine.
Ol' man Winters is dead.
- Well, that is good news, I'd say.
- I'll say it is, boys.
Wonder what happened to him.
And now we're gonna collect five thousand dollars
reward.
- Five thousand?
- How?
Gat Ganns is at the Winters' ranch,
but he'll be over here in the morning.
There's a price on his head of
five thousand dollars, dead or alive.
- Dead men tell no tales.
- That's my job.
I don't care who does the job, just so it's done.
Peewee, you're gonna fly your tail outta here!
They're laying plots and it's up to us to tell 'em!
Why, Spuds! What're you doin' over here?
I come to tell you, they're gonna shoot you,
soon's you come to the hideout!
Gentry says there's a reward for you and he's
gonna get it.
Double-crossed, eh?
Oh, you don't have to worry, Spuds. There's no
reward out for me, and they're not gonna get me.
What's that?
That was Aunt Marthy's.
She gave it to me when she died.
Marthy?
Yeah, she was Butch's wife. She was the only
friend I had until you come.
Marthy, Butch...
Now I know where I've seen 'em. He and his
wife worked for my dad!
Say, Spuds. Did Aunt Martha ever tell you
about your father?
She said he was dead and that Butch wasn't
my real dad.
She left me a letter and told me not to open
it until I was grown up.
Well, where is it?
I brought this with me, 'cause Butch said he was
gonna shoot me and I ain't never going back there.
Here it is.
I'm gonna open this, Spuds. It may mean a lot
to both of us.
'Dear boy, your real name is Jim Hayden.
Your dad and his brother were killed by Gentry
and his gang when you were a babe.
Don't think hard of me, son. I've had no hand
in this.
Aunt Martha.'
Jim!
Jim, do you know what that means?
It means you're my brother.
My own little brother.
Gee, ain't that swell!
You know, boys, in a way this isn't any great
surprise to me.
I've suspicioned Gentry for a long time.
But I've never been able to get anything on him.
Years ago, right after Hayden was killed...
We suspected him of being the secret leader
of a band of rustlers.
But we were never able to prove it.
After reading that letter, there isn't a doubt
in my mind...
... but that he was guilty of Hayden's death.
We've got enough on Gentry now!
Why should we wait?
Well, give Ted a chance to play his hand, Sheriff.
He'll get word to us when he needs us.
There's Gentry now.
No matter what happens, son, stay right here.
Mrs. Winters?
I hardly know how to tell you, but...
this poster will speak for itself.
Why! That's the man that went with Dad!
- And he's a killer!
- That isn't the worst of it.
Word just came to town that they found
your father --
No!
Don't say it!
Don't cry, Fay. I want you to know that I'll take
care of you.
Why, I've loved you since the first time I saw you.
- Please, Mr. Gentry --
- Don't you understand, Fay? I'm crazy about you!
I'll give you everything you want!
Please don't talk like that!
Listen. I want you to be my wife.
Oh, take your hands off me!
Take your hands off, Gentry.
- You!
- What have you done with my father?
Your father's safe, Ms. Winters.
Call the sheriff. I'm holding this man for murder.
Murder?
My name's Hayden. Ted Hayden.
Son of the man you and your gang murdered
twelve years ago.
You left me for dead, too, Gentry.
But I lived.
Lived to even up the score.
Why, he's crazy!
That poster proves who he is.
Then call the sheriff, Ms. Winters.
Hello?
No, give me the sheriff's office.
You're mighty brave behind a gun, aren't you?
Why, hangin' or shootin's too good for you,
Gentry.
Hello, is this the sheriff's office?
- This is Ms. Winters. Is my fath --?
- Yes, your father's here.
He's alright.
What's that?
We'll be right over.
It's your daughter, Winters. We'll have to hurry.
- When Dusty comes, lead 'em right
to the hideout.
- Alright, Ted!
I'll be alright, dear. Don't you worry.
Hey, Dusty! Ted said to follow me!
Come on, Winters!
It's Ganns. He's got himself in a trap.
Gimme that gun.
Listen, Gentry. Twelve years ago,
you killed my father.
Separated me from my brother and took
everything outta my life that a kid could have.
You know, I oughtta give you what
you gave my dad.
But I'm keeping my hands clean, Gentry.
I'm taking you to the law.
Alright, boys. Let's riddle him with bullets.
Why, it's Gentry!
Up in the air, men!
Where's the man called Ganns?
He's in there.
Well, boys! I've been tryin' to meet up with you
for sometime!
I reckon you got here just in time, brother.
What're you thinking about, Jim?
You know, Ted meant that.
And he said when you married 'em,
it was gonna be twice as big.
Oh! He has it all worked out, has he?
Sure, and you better accept his proposition.
'Cause it'll be the only one you'll ever get.
Well!
What's my little brother been tellin' you?
Well, I was tellin' her what you said you didn't
have the nerve to.
Is my face red!
Well, it oughtn't to be! 'Cause Fay said she'd
accept your proposition.
Why, I --
Gosh, now you're both burnin' up.
I think your brother needs a good lecture.
Lecture? He needs a good spanking!